<TEI.2><div1 id="iln42.001" n="Illustrated London News: Volume 42" type="Volume"> 
            <head>Illustrated London News: Volume 42</head>
            <docDate>Jan to June 1863</docDate>
<div2 id="iln42.001" n= "America."
            type="Article"><head>AMERICA.</head> 
<bibl>
<title> The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.42</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issues">

<pb n="2 AMERICA"/>
<p>By the arrival of the Steamers North American and Hansa we are in
receipt of New York journals of the 20th ult.</p> 

<p rend="center">WAR NEWS."</p>

<p>The great battle of Fredericksburg, in which the Federal
armies sustained a disastrous repulse, is described in the
Supplement, page 18.</p>
<p>On the night of the 15th the army of the Potomac was withdrawn
to the north side of the Rappahannock, "because," reports General
Burnside "I felt fully convinced that the position in front could not
be carried, and it was a military necessity either to attack the enemy
or retire." This perilous movement was effected during a stormy night,
and was not discovered by the Confederates until it was too late to
interrupt it. The wounded were all saved, and the pontoon bridges
removed.</p>
<p>The Confederates have advanced their pickets in Fredericksburg to
points near to the banks of the Rappahannock, have increased their
intrenchments in the rear of the city, end thrown up rifle-pits on the
left of the city near the river.</p>
<p>Official reports of the Northern losses put their casualties at 1400
killed, and 8000 wounded, to which may be added 800 taken prisoners.</p>
<p>The Confederate commander General Lee has drawn up his report
of the engagement. He acknowledges a loss of 1800 in killed and
wounded. Among the former he names Generals Cobb and Gregg.</p>
<p>The Federal Senate has ordered inquiry to be made into the facts of
the Fredericksburg disaster.</p>
<p>There have been some movements in North Carolina. The Confederate
General Evans had telegraphed that the Federal General attacked
Kingston, on the 13th, with 15,000 men and nine gun-boats. The fight
lasted ten hours and the Federals ware driven back to their
gun-boats. The Northern accounts admit that they lost 500 prisoners
and eleven pieces of artillery. The Southerners were eventually
compelled to retire from the town, the Federal bombardment having
greatly injured it.</p>
<p>The Confederates have made a demonstration against Harper's Ferry,
but were repulsed.</p>
<p>Five disabled vessels of Banks's expedition have put into Port Royal.</p>
<p>The Confederates have sunk the Federal gun-boat Cairo with torpedoes
off Yazoo River.</p>
<p>Twenty thousand men have deserted from the army of the Potomac, and the
number is every day increasing.</p>

<p rend="center">NEW ORLEANS.</p>
<p>General Butler has issued an order that no person be allowed to land
from any vessel arriving at New Orleans without taking the oath of
allegiance. General Butler had ordered a further assessment of the
cotton-brokers for the support of the poor.</p>

<p rend="center">WASHINGTON</p>
<p>The New York journals simultaneously report that Mr. Seward has
resigned, in consequence of a vote of want of confidence in the
Cabinet passed by a caucus of Republican senators.</p>
<p>Attorney-General Bates has given an opinion in opposition to the Dred
Scott decision, and to the effect that coloured men are citizens of
the United States. The case arose from the detention at Perth Amboy,
by a revenue cutter, of a schooner commanded by a coloured man, who,
if not a citizen of the United States, would have been incompetent to
act as her captain. The Attorney-General decides that all free persons,
without distinction of race and colour, if native born, are citizens.
The question of citizenship is distinct from that of political rights.
A child or a woman is a citizen, though not privileged to vote or take
office. The opinions in the Dred Scott case are pronounced to be of
no more authority than the <hi rend="italic">obiter dicta</hi>hi> of
eminent lawyers as the question before the Supreme Court in that case
only involve1 the jurisdiction of the Circuit Court. The master of
the schooner is pronounced to be legally competent to command the vessel,
and the embargo laid on her is ordered to be quashed.</p>

<p rend="center">THE CONFEDERATE STATES.</p>
<p>President Davis has left Tennessee to visit Mobile and the army of the
Mississippi.</p>
<p>The Commander of the French corvette Yuaalan lately visited Fort
Sumter in company with General Beauregard.</p>
MISCELLANEOUS.
<p>The popular feeling runs high in the North against General Halleck and
Secretary Stanton, to whom the late reverse of the Federal arms is
attributed.</p>
<p>Mr. Rarey, the horsetamer, has been appointed Commissioner of Horses
in the Federal States. His that official act was to go to the army of
the Potomac under Burnside. There he inquired fully into the health of
the horses, and has adopted a new system to check the mortality among
them.</p>
<p>The British Consul at Fredericksburg was arrested by the Federales on
the 11th, on suspicion of being a rebel spy but was in a short time
released. On the 12th, at the request 0f General Howard, he was again
arrested, on the charge that he had secreted armed rebels. in his
house and then aided them in their escape.</p>
<p>The commercial intelligence states that Congress and the leading
bankers are agreed in the condemnation of Mr. Chase's plan for the
reconstitution of the banks of the country. Gold remains nearly
stationary at about 32 per cent premium.</p>

<pb n="7"/>
<p>The Confederate Sumter was sold at Gibraltar, on the 19th
ult., for 16,5OOdols.</p>


<pb n="10"/>
Advices from Philadelphia state that the fibre of the plant
hibiscos moscheutos is occupying the attention of the merchants at
that port as a substitute for linen rags and jute. This plant is
indigenous to the Northern States, said grows in abundance in the
swampy lands of Pennsylvania, New Jersey, New York, &c. At a
moderate calculation, and taking into account the probability of loss
from unforeseen causes, three tons and a half of disentegrated fibre
can be derived from one acre of ground. Two prominent paper
manufacturers of New York have estimated the fibre to be worth 100
dollars per ton, to be used as a substitute for linen rags in the
manufacture of paper.- <hi rend="italic'>Liverpool Journal of Commerce.</hi> 

TEE BATTLE OF FREDERICKSBURG.

The New York Times appears to contain the best account of the great battle which took place at Fredericksburg- on the 13th of December. - The account is dated Fredericksburg, 13th at December, We give copious extracts;

THE THEATRE OF OPERATIONS.

The theatre of operations to-day extended from Fredericksburg on the right and down the south side of the Rappahannock for two miles. Immediately behind the town of Fredericksburg the land forms a plateau or smooth field, running back for about a third of a mile. It then rises for forty or fifty yards, forming a ridge of ground which runs along to the left for about a quarter of a mile, where it abuts at Hazel Dell, a ravine formed by the Hazel River, which empties into the Rappahannock -west of the town. At the foot of the ridge runs the telegraph road, flanked by a stone wall. This eminence was studded with rebel batteries. To the right, along and up the river, the ridge prolongs itself to opposite Falmouth, and beyond; and here, too, batteries were placed on every advantageous position. Back of the first ridge so another plateau and then a second terrace of wooded hills, where a second line of fortifications was placed. Between the rear of the town end the first ridge of kills was the theatre of operations of the right grand division of the Army under General Summer.

A word now on the scene of operations of the left grand division. From the lower part of the town the ridge on which it is built slopes abruptly down to a comparatively level or undulating country, which stretches for some miles down the Rappahannock. About a couple of miles back of the river it rises into a wooded slope. At a point a mile and a half below Fredericksburg two pontoons had been thrown across on Thursday morning, and on Friday the whole of the left grand division, under the command of Major-General Franklin, had marched over the river. Daylight on Saturday found the force drawn up in battle array on this broad plain skirting the Rappahannock.

 The battle-ground, though very marshy in some places, presented a fine field
for military evolutions. The turnpike leading to Fredericksburg runs about half a mile from, and nearly parallel to, the river. Beyond is the railroad, and, still further beyond, the wooded range of hills in which the enemy were strongly intrenched. About a mile and a half from Fredericksburg, nearly on the river edge, is situated A. N. Barnord's stone mansion, after the English style. 

DISPOTION OF THE TROOPS
The line of battle, as it appeared In the morning, was as follows: -The 6th
 Army Corps, under General Smith (Franklin's old force), on the right, composed of three divisions. The 1st Army Corps (General Reynolds's) extending still further to the left, drawn up in the following order:-General Gibbons's division on the right, connecting with General Howe's, General Meads's centre, and General Doubleday left, fronting to the southward and resting nearly on the river. This constituted the order in which our forces were drawn up, there being three distinct bare of battle.

Opposed to our right, under General Summer, was the rebel left, under command of General Longstreet. Opposed to our left, under General Franklin, was the rebel right, under General Jackson. General Lee, Generalissimo of the Southern army, was in person in command of the Confederate forces during the whole day.


The plan of General Burnside, agreed upon be council of war, was to endeavour to pierce the rebel centre. Early on the morning of Saturday the order was given that Summer's left, composed of the 9th Army Corps, under command of General Willcox, should be extended until it reached Franklin's right-thus forming a continuous line of battle along the river for two miles, the left resting on the river at the point where the lower pontoons Cress, and the right on Fredericksburg.

The left wing, comprising the whole of Franklin's command (50,000 men), should then be swung round as on a pivot, formed by Summer's extreme right, resting on Fredericksburg. If successful in this maneuver, Franklin would divide the rebel line, taking possession of the railroad (the line of retreat), and come in on the flank of the rebel works back of Fredericksburg. While this movement was being developed, a division was to be sent up from General Summer's command by the plank read to storm the ridge. If there should be any failure in this, it was hoped that the co-operation of Franklin would presently make success certain. Hooker's corps was designed to art as a reserve.

 THE BEGINNING OF THE BATTLE.

The dawn of Saturday found the forces distributed as thus indicate. It was a fine Virginia morning, mild and balmy as a September day, though the mist and fog of a late Indian summer hung over the field of battle.

It was with alarm and pain I found a general want of confidence and gloomy
foreboding among some men whose sound judgment I had learned to trust. The plan of attacking the rebel stronghold directly in front would, it was feared, prove a most hazardous enterprise, and one of which there is no successful example in military history. It was doubted that the co-operation of the right and left, according to the programme, would admit of practical execution, and things were generally at loose ends.

About half-past eleven o'clock I crossed the Rappahannock on the upper
patoon-bridge, and passed through the town of Fredericksburg along the
main street. At this time brisk skirmishing was going on in the outskirts of the town, the rebel sharpshooters stubbornly contesting every inch, of the ground as our skirmishers advanced. -Caroline or Maine street was occupied by General Kimball's, General Ferrero's, and Acting-General Zook's brigade, with portions of Hancock's division. The latter, with his artillery, lined the bank of the river in the neighborhood of the middle crossing, which is just below the railroad bridge. Other troops from the corps of Generals Willcox and Couch occupied the other streets of the town nearer the line of advance. Our batteries replied across the river, covering the advance of our forces. In the meantime, Franklin had been for a couple of hours briskly engaged with the enemy on the left. The force in Fredericksburg had driven the rebels out of the suburbs of the town and rested their column no the canal. The time had now come to attempt an advance on the rebel position. The orders were to move rapidly, charge op the hill, and take the batteries at the point of the bayonet. Orders easy to give, but, ah ! how hard of execution! Look at the position to be stormed ! There is a bare plateau of a third of a mile which the storming party will have to cross. In doing so they will be exposed to the fire, first, of the enemy's sharpshooters, posted behind a stone wall running along the base of the ridge; of a double row of rifle-pits on the rim of the crest, of the heavy batteries behind strong fieldworkers that stud the top of the hill, of a powerful infantry force now lying concealed behind these, of a plunging fire from the batteries or the lower range, of a double enfilading fire from "cannon to right of them, cannon to left of them." Sebastopol was not half as strong.

THE CENTRAL ADVANCE.

The line of battle was formed by Conch's corps (the 2nd), composed at the divisions of French, Hancock, and Howard, the left of the line abutting on Sturgis' division of Willcox's corps (the 9th). The first advanced was French's composed of the brigades of Kimball, Morris, and Weber, supported by Hancock's division, consisting of the brigades of Caldwell, Zook, and Meagher. Forming his men under cover of a small knoll in the rear of the town, skirmishers were deployed to the left towards Hazel Dell; Sturgis, supporting at the same time, moved up and rested on a point on the railroad.

The moment they exposed themselves on the railroad forth bursts the deadly hail. Preen the rifle-pits came the murderously-aimed missiles; from the batteries, tier above tier, on the terraces shot planes of fire from the enfilading cannon, distributed on the arcs of a circle two miles in extent, came cross showers of shot and shell. Across the plain for a while they swept under this fatal fire. They were literally mowed down. The bursting shells made great gaps in their ranks; but these are presently filled by the closing up of the line. For fifteen immortal minutes at least they remain under this fiery surge, Onward they press, though their ranks grow fearfully thin. They have passed over a greater pact of the interval, and have almost reached the base of the hill, when brigade after brigade of rebels rise op on the crest and pour in fresh volleys of musketry at short range. They fell back, shattered and broken, amid shouts and yells from the enemy.
General French's division went into the fight 6000 strong; but at night he told me he could count but 1500.

THE FEDERAL BATTERIES FIRE ON THEIR OWN MEN. 

The fire of the rebel batteries was not the only thing from which our men had to suffer, Thinking to silence the enemy's guns, our batteries planted on the bluff on the north side of the river embracing some 41 siege guns, some batteries of 20-pounder Parrotts, and the artillery of the left and left centre, opened fire. The intervening space is between 2700 and 3000 yards-too great a distance to calculate on the projectiles carrying with accuracy, particularly contractor's ammunition. If shell should short or take an oblique direction and explode among our troops, it would be difficult to see how a panic could be prevented. Promptly seeing this danger, General Hunt, Chief of Artillery, instantly dispatched orders to cease firing. It was well he did so, for immediately afterwards an Aide-de-Camp came galloping from General Couch, from the other side of the river, begging that our batteries should cease, as they were actually firing into his command.

THE BATTLE CONTINUES.

While the broken column retires to its original position in the outskirts of the town to reform for a new encounter, let us see what goes on to the left. At daylight the forces comprising the left grand division of the army appeared, drawn up in battle array on the broad plain below Fredericksburg, and skirting the Rappahannock. No sooner had the heavy mist cleared away than Captain Hall's battery (2nd Maine), planted at the right of Gibbons's division, opened fire upon the rebels. Artillery fire now became general along the whole line, which was returned by the rebels. Heavy siege guns in our rear; the 1st Maryland, 1st Massachusetts Batteries, and Battery D, 5th Artillery, on the right; Captain Ransom's and Captain Walker's in front: and Cowan's New York, and Lieutenant Hahn's 3rd Now York Independent on the left, and other batteries, kept up a terrific fire on the rebels. Orders now came to advance, and about nine o'clock Gibbon's and Meade's divisions commenced moving slowly forward.

The advance resulted in almost straightening our lines, which were before somewhat of a crescent. Considerable resistance was met with, yet the forces continued to move forward until, at midday, the line of battle was three quarters of a mile in advance of where it had been at the outset. But now came the reserve fire of the enemy with terrific force.  Shot, shell and canister were poured into our men from various points, while the rebel infantry appearing, fired with rapidity. Still they continued to press on. Several batteries moved forward at the same time. As our troops saw the enemy giving way, cheer after cheer rent the air.

About one o'clock General Meade ordered a charge, which was well executed, the men pressing on the edge of the very crest, and skillfully penetrating, by a movement on the flank, an opening which happened to occur between the division of A. P. Hill and Early's brigade, captured several hundred prisoners belonging to the 61st Georgia and 31st North Carolina.

While the light was progressing at this point the enemy sent four heavy columns down on our left, near the river. They were handsomely repulsed and driven back, however, by General Doubleday's division. Owing in the lack of reinforcements, General Meade's command was obliged to fall back a quarter of a mile-three-quarters of a mile beyond the ground first occupied. Very heavy musketry-firing continued along the line, neither side gaining any materiel advantage. About half-past one o'clock the first line of battle in General Gibbons's division was relieved by the second, when Tower's brigade, now commanded by Colonel Root, charged over an open field beyond the railroad and down into the edge of the woods, occupying the breastworks which the enemy had constructed there, said capturing 200 prisoners belonging to the 36th North Carolina end a South Carolina, regiment. General Gibbous was severely wounded in the right hand. They held their own for some time, but were eventually compelled to fall back. It was while the fight was progressing at this point that General Bayard was fatally wounded. About two o'clock General Hooker's division of General Hooker's grand division, which had been delayed for some time in crossing by the enemy's shells, moved forward to the left to the support of Meade's division, Gibbons's had become much cut up. The musketry fight was then very heavy, and this division suffered severely.

 Adjoining the first corps under Reynolds were the sixth corps under General Smith, presenting the following formation, in three lines of battle -General Newton at the right, General Burke at the centre, and General Howe on the left, connecting with Renyold's corps.

At sunrise the skirmishers commenced moving forward, General Vinton commanding. About eight o'clock the rebels opened a heavy cannonade upon the men. Some of their batteries were but a short distance away. A burning dwelling, vehicle attracted considerable attention the night previous, was destroyed by them in order to make better their range. Martin's New York Battery, Frank's 1st New York, and Snow's 1st Maryland replied to the rebel gnus with much spirit. At three o'clock General Newton's was withdrawn from the extreme of this corps, and took a position on the extreme right of Reynolds's command, where it was actively employed daring the remainder of the day. About four o'clock the 4th New Jersey were ordered to charge upon a force of the enemy near the railroad, which they did, driving them back for one hundred yards or more. A superior force then appearing against them, they were forced to retire. Colonel H. B. Hatch fell, wounded in the leg. The rebels ceased their artillery fire on this position of the army about ten o'clock in the morning. Toward evening, however, they sent a full brigade in the direction of Martin's battery, who came on with a yell, expecting to capture it. The warm reception which they received from the battery and the 2nd and 4th Vermont Regiments, which were acting as skirmishers, compelled them to fall back. At the same time the three lines of infantry, composed of Pratt's end Vinton's brigades, stood to arms, and advanced with fixed bayonets. Night put an end to further operations on each side, with the exception of occasional discharges from our heavy guns.

 The result of the day's fighting on the left, so diversified in its character, was to give the left possession of about five hundred yards in extent. So far as stubbornly holding its own, and even gaining groused, the left grand division deserves credit. It had, however, wholly failed to perform the tactical manoeuvre assigned to it.

The Condition of the Right.






Returning to the right I found General Sumner seated on the front seat of an unyoked ambulance at the Lacey House, directly opposite Fredericksburg, at the point where the first pontoon bridge spans the stream. The old man looked anxious and fearful. Things were not going well with his command. For three hours his men bad been fighting at fearful odds. They were much exhausted, their loss was excessive, and nothing had been accomplished.

Indeed, to the test of the ear at the point where we were located, it seemed as though they wore being badly pressed. The batteries had been brought down and planted at the heads of the streets. The troops were hugging- the city closely to escape the fearful fire. "Where is Franklin?" was the eager inquiry. "Everything depends on Franklin's coming up on the flank,"

Franklin's position was plainly observable by the line of smoke said fire a couple of miles to our left below. He was coming no nearer.

At three o'clock an Aide arrived from General Couch to say that his (Conch's)
troops are advancing finely, but that Willcox was not keeping up. "Tell General Willcox," replies General Sumner, "tell him he must make the 9th Army Corps keep pace with the 2nd, if he can."

At half-pest three o'clock, Sturgis, who had been clinging to the valley amid showers of fire, is so hotly pressed that he hardly thinks he can hold his own till Griffin comes up. At four o'clock French reports that his right is held by a brigade (Mason's) which is without ammunition.

 Summer sends a message begging Burnside that Franklin be directed to advance. But 3rrranklie, cannot advance. He has enough to do at this moment to hold his own, for Jackson has just thrown in reinforcements, and is pushing hard to turn his left. Meantime the reserves have not been touched. Hooker's central grand division, 50,000 fresh men, have not yet been engaged; indeed, are yet mainly on this side of the river. "Tell General Burnside that he had better, by all means, throw some of Hooker's in." Burnside replies that he has directly ordered Hooker to go in, and that every man on this aide of the river shall cross.

At four o'clock General Hooker, who had not yet been across the river, proceeded over, and, in half an hour, prodigious valleys of musketry announced that Hooker with the reserves is engaged.

The Day is Lost.

This last assaulting column consisted of the divisions of Humphrey, Monk, Howard, Getty, and Sykes. They had, however, hardly got fairly engaged before the sun went down, and night closed around the clamorous wrath of the combatants. At this time General Burnside, who had remained all dray at the Phillips House, came down to the Lacy House, and in the garden facing the city followed the progress of the light. Externally calm, the leading player in this tremendous game was agitated by such intensity of feeling as no one can conceive, and he paced the garden gloomy as night. "That crest," he exclaimed passionately, "must be carried to-night." The brevity of time into which the stupendous issue of the day had to be crowned seemed to add redoubled energy to the fury of the combatants,  

Not "Night, or Blucher !" as Wellington exclaimed at Waterloo, but rather Ajax's prayer for "more light," was the prompting of every heart. 
Creeping up on the flank by the left, Getty's troops succeeded in gaining the stone wall which we had been unable all day to wrench from the rebels. The other forces rushed for the crest. Our field-batteries, which, owing to the restricted space, had been of little use all day, were brought vigorously into play. It was the fierce, passionate climax of the battle. From both sides, two miles of batteries belched forth their fiery missiles athwart the dark background of the night. Volleys of musketry were poured forth such as we have no parallel of in our experience of the war, and which seemed as though all the demons of earth and air were contending together. Rushing up the crest, our troops had got within a stone's throw of the batteries, when the hilltop swarmed forth in new reinforcements of rebel infantry, who, rushing upon our men, drove them back. The turn of a die decides such situations. The day was lost. Our men retired. Immediately cannon and musketry ceased their roar, and in a moment the silence of death succeeded the stormy fury of ten hours' battle.

Recrossing of the Rappahannock by the Federals. 

At daylight on Sunday, the 14th inst., heavy artillery firing took place in front of the divisions of Generals Hooker, Sumner, and Franklin, and continued until late in the forenoon, bet no general action occurred. The object of both parties was evidently to fool the other.

During Saturday night and Sunday morning the Confederates considerably extended their works and strengthened their position. Large bodies of troops were to be seen on Sunday where few were to be found on the previous day. The Federal dead which were killed in front of the enemy's works still remained on Sunday morning where they fell. When an attempt was made on Saturday night to remove them, the enemy would open fire with infantry; the wounded, were, however, all removed from the field.

The weather on Sunday was bright and cheerful, and the fog had entirely disappeared. It was ascertained by inspection through a powerful glass that there were six distinct lines of works behind the city. Whether some of these were rifled redoubts simply, or have the double capacity of affording protection to light infantry, and having embrasures for light field-guns, could not be discovered. The appearance of the works, however, would lead to the latter belief.

The New York Herald of the 15th ult, gives the following account of the recrossing of the Rappahannock by the Federals. 

There were 40,000 of our troops engaged in the battle of Saturday. What force the rebels brought against them it is impossible just now to determine, but from the desperate nature of the resistance offered it is net improbable that they fully equalled if they did not outnumber our forces.


With the exception of some heavy firing between the outposts of both armies
there was no fighting on the Rappahannock on Monday (15th inst.) Everything was quiet, and the terrible battle of Saturday was not renewed. The Federal troops were busy removing the wounded to the river side, lest the enemy should shell the city. The Confederates meanwhile were actively engaged strengthening their defences. At one time they made a faint to attack General Franklin's forces, but did not accomplish it. General Burnside inspected the Federal troops in the afternoon in the town, and was greeted with load cheers. Activity throughout every department indicated that a battle woe imminent. The Irish brigade assembled in and around the theatre, where the ceremony of presenting to it a set of beautiful colours, just sent from New York, was gone through, General Meagher making an address. The enemy kept up a regular fire from their batteries upon the upper crossing, in order to retard the passage of the troops. The surgeons were ordered to be in readiness to receive and care for a large number of additional wounded, and red flags were displayed on the tops of many of the large houses in the town which were to be used for temporary hospitals.

The withdrawal of the Federal forces from Fredericksburg had, however, been determined on at a council of all the corps commanders during the day. It was regarded as a perilous undertaking but one that, if successful, would rescue the army from the necessity of risking another battle with the prospect of accomplishing little except the destruction of valuable lives.

The troops had received no intimation of their having to retreat, and had laid down to rest upon their arms for the night. The order for them to fall in was therefore supposed by many to be for a night assault upon the enemy's works, and they were not undeceived until they found themselves upon the pontoon bridges actually returning across the stream. A heavy gale of wind which blew all sound away from the rebel lines greatly facilitated the movement. Bridges were covered with earth to deaden the sound of the moving artillery, and a dark night bid every object from view. General Franklin's grand division, occupying the extreme left, began to move as soon as it was dark; and the right and centre of Generals Sumner and Hooker took up the line of march almost simultaneously, moving in good order but silently away from under the very guns of the enemy. All three of the crossings were need, making six bridges. No accident of consequence occurred. The troops obeyed with alacrity every order, and waited with patience their turn to cross. The artillery and infantry alternated in moving column, very much in the order in which they went into battle. Two brigades belong to General Butterfield's corps were left to occupy Fredericksburg as advanced pickets. The Federal Artillery placed on the hither bank of the river co-operated in keeping possession of the town.

The same paper, of the 17th ult., says, in its summary of war news:-

The retreat and evacuation of Fredericksburg, which were rendered necessary by the disaster of Saturday, and the ascertained strength and extent of the enemy's fortifications, was a perilous adventure, but was conducted in safety. It may be consoling, however, to know that, although the Union forces suffered a loss of some ten or twelve thousand men in this fruitless attack upon the enemy's position, General Burnside did not fall too deeply into the trap laid for him by General Lee, but retired in time to save his army from the chances of annihilation. It is but just, perhaps, to General Burnside to say that the adverse movement upon Fredericksburg was not undertaken in accordance with his own judgment, but was peremptorily ordered by the military authorities at Washington, who, of course, are alone responsible for the result. It is stated upon reliable authority that the rebels sent a notification to our army on Sunday that they intended shelling the town, and requested that our wounded should be removed.

We have before us another work which is also peculiarly suited to the moment. It is written by Mr. D. W. Mitchell, an Englishman who has been a resident in Richmond, Virginia, and is entitled Ten Years in the United States. Being an Englishman's View of Men and Things in the North and South (Smith and Elder). The author states his object to be to explain, if possible, the most active and powerful causes of the great revolution which has taken place in the country in which he lived, working for his livelihood, and, at the same time, observing human nature as developed in Americans and American politics. The residence of Mr. Mitchell in the States commenced in 1848, that year of European convulsions; and he states with confidence that he has better opportunity than common of observing and understanding the people of whom he has written, their habits and feelings, their private and public life, and believes himself cable of pointing out the causes of the split between North and South the less because he, with some few others, had marked their rise and progress, and reflected upon the tendency of the life, political and social, of the United States. The author declares that, in considering and explaining the facts which he has here collected, he had to abandon many preconceived ideas and theories of his own, formed before he went to the States; and he admits that it is more than probable that some of the statements he has put forth will conflict with the prejudices and principles of many of his readers; but he protests that he has written carefully and conscientiously, with a desire to arrive at the truth as to the right and wrong of the momentous struggle now going on, sinking for the time sectarian and, party prepossessions. The conclusion to which he arrives is that the separation of the North and South are not only natural but desirable; that it therefore inevitably follows, as a matter of course, he does not hesitate to add, that true liberty and real progress will suffer no drawback from such a change, There will probably be those who, in learning these premonitory confessions of a writer on this vexed question, who has been almost a citizen of the Southern capital too, will at once conclude that he is a writer in the Confederate interest purely. Well, perhaps he is so, but to a great extent unconsciously, if not unavoidably ; and if his work is taken up with just so much qualification as is implied in these two circumstances of avowal of opinion on the broad question and local tendencies, we think, on the whole, that it will be found to have dealt with the case as nearly fairly and impartially as possible. Apart from the political disquisitions which the volume contains, there is a good deal of characteristic local colouring, The plan of the book is founded on the notion of endeavouring, as far as possible, to let the people of the United States describe themselves, and to let the parties and factions state their own views; and we are informed that many remarks and reflections which are not printed as quotations may be taken to be the deliberate opinions of enlightened Americans, expressed in conversations and discussions at times when hackneyed professions of party were for the hour forgotten. It should be observed that the work contains sketches of life and manners, social and political, at Richmond, at Washington, and at New York mainly, and some chapters are devoted to somewhat remote-for America-history, from which deductions are drawn and brought to bear on modern and immediate circumstances. Even if it bad no other merit, the earlier chapters, which do something for raising the close veil which now envelopes the South, its inhabitants, and their ways, would make this book acceptable; but we venture to think that, as a whole, it is a contribution of some value to the knowledge of the United States of America,, which most of us are glad to come across at this particular juncture.

American Maps.

Series of American Maps, published by Bacon and Co., Paternoster-row, 1862 :-1. "Army Map of the Seat of War in Virginia, showing the Battle-fields, Fortifications, &c., on and near the Potomac river. "This map gives with the greatest clearness all the physical features and military positions between the Shenandoah River on the west and Eastern Maryland on the east. Northwards it extends as far as the Confederates reached its their recent foray into Maryland, and southward as far as the Rapidan and Fredericksburg. Within these limits this map leaves nothing to be desired in the minuteness, and at the same time lucidity, of its topographical details. It is brought down to Sept. 1, and gives the site of the battle in which General Kearney was killed. The successive chains of mountains, the rivers, railroad, and common roads stand out with great distinctness. Of all military maps of Eastern Virginia which we have seen we prefer this for reference. 2. "Bacon's New War Map."-This covers a larger field than No. 1. It includes a portion of Southern Pennsylvania, all Maryland, Delaware, all Eastern end a part of Western Virginia, and terminates at the northern boundary of North Carolina. A pink dash under the names of notorious places materially assists the investigator in his hunt after localities.--3. 0 Bacon's Military Map of America."-This map is a handy map of the United States, British America, and adjoining portions of Mexico. It extends from ocean to ocean. Although entitled "military" by virtue of its showing the forts and fortifications, it is mainly civil in its character. The loyal Slave States and parts of States and territories are coloured yellow, interposed between the Free-labour States in green, and the Confederate States and parts of States in pink.-4. 'Bacon's Steel-plate Map of the American States, showing the railways, forts, and fortifications." This map terminates about 100 miles west of the Mississippi. It includes the adjacent part of Canada, and retains this threefold division as to colour which characterises No. 3.

American Maps, published by W. and A. K. Johnston, Edinburg, 1862 :-1. "Map of the Battle-fields of America, including portions of Virginia, Maryland, and Pennsylvania." This neat map extends south of Richmond, James River. A blue line under the names of noted places aids the eye. Appended to this snap is a smaller one of the United and Confederate States, British America, and part of Mexico. The Free-labour, Border, and Seceded States are distinguished from each other by separate colours. 2. "Johnson's map of the United States" -This map is a converse of the previous one. It consists of two parts. The larger part gives the United states to 100 miles west of the Mississippi: the smaller section map is a lucid map of the seat of war in Eastern Virginia, from Harrisburg and Philadelphia, in the North to below Richmond and Norfolk in the South. The maps of this series are made to fold conveniently in bookform, or they may lie extended sheetwise.

Colton's Series of Maps. Guns and Co., Craven-street.- "2500 Miles Around Washington."-At the distance of each 100 miles from the centre a circle is drawn, to enable the inquirer to measure the distance at a glance. The principal places are indicated by a large dot adjoining their names. The population of the United States, as they were according to the three last censuses, is given in tabular form.-"500 Miles Round Cairo, showing the Seat of War in the West." -The same division by circles is adopted here. Both the maps of this series give every county and county town in clear type.

ILLUSTRATIONS OF THE WAR IN AMERICA.

Our Special Artist and Correspondent at the head-quarters of the Confederate army of Northern Virginia has forwarded to us some Illustrations, which we have been fortunate enough to receive. This, it seems, is far from being the case generally, many of his sketches and letters being intercepted. For example, writing on the 15th of November last, our Artist states that he had just heard of the capture of so vessel winch had some of his despatches on board, and also of the arrest of a messenger carrying letters and sketches from him across the Potomac into Maryland. Indeed, our Special Artist on one occasion recently ran a great risk of being taken prisoner, having galloped past a cross-road only a few minutes before a Federal scouting-party dashed through. Two of our Artist's Illustrations are presented on the preceding page.

Advance of the Federals Towards Lee Town, Jefferson Country, Virginia. 

Respecting this Illustration our Correspondent writes as follows: 'While visiting General Stuart at his head-quarters the Federals crossed the Potomac at Shepherdstown and advanced in large force to within a mile and a half of our camp. Gradually our pickets had to retire, making a good fight as they fell back, step by step, on their supports. The night we passed was a most anxious one, as at any moment the Federal cavalry, had they possessed anything like the dash of the two or three regiments opposed to them, might have forced our lines and probably taken most of us prisoners. In the morning, Oct. 16, the General was in the saddle at dawn, and, taking with him Pelham's flying artillery, brought one of the pieces into a commanding position, on a hill, and opened it with great effect on a brigade advancing on Lee Town, driving back the skirmishers thrown forward against his own pockets. The Illustration shows the gun coming into action under the fire of the Yankee skirmishers, surrounded and followed by the mounted gunners, one of whom is falling, wounded, from his horse. The cavalry reserves are moving up in the rear.

RETREAT OF THE FEDERALS FROM JEFFERSON COUNTY.

"This Engraving (Says our Special Artist) gives a new feature to the triumphal advance of the 'Young Napoleon' on Winchester, so boastfully published to the world in the Northern papers. The onward movement' has now become a retreat. In the distance the Federal artillery has taken up a covering position in the road at the entrance of the woods, and their cavalry is seen flying across the fields on each side, seeking the shelter of the timber from the shells which Pelham is liberally sending after them, General Stuart is on a rise in the centre of the picture, giving orders and making dispositions for his troopers to charge, the reserve cavalry having come up. By night not a Federal remained on the Virginia side of the Potomac of those who formed part of this triumphal expedition."


Confederate Flag.

Our Special Artist inclosed in one of hoe despatches a flog which he had begged for us as a trophy, and of which we herewith give an Engraving. This is its history, as supplied by him:-"When Banks, commanding the Federals, was attacked by Jackson last spring, and driven pell-mell through the streets of Winchester, Miss Laura Lee, of that city, boldly stood forward in the street amidst the flying bullets and waved this little flag of her own make, cheering on the Confederate soldiers as they charged through the flying ranks of those who had covered her and her fellow-citizens with abuse for months. More than one Confederate fell at her feet as they swept triumphantly past, and, still waving her little flag in one hand, with the other assisted the wounded men. This lady is a fair type of all her Southern sisters-womanly, but brave in her country's cause, and now praying by the dying beds of those brave men who have fallen victim to their patriotism.'

Claiming Exemption from the Draught in New York.

Though the draught is postponed in New York it has not been formally abandoned by the Government. The consequence is that there has been a great rush to the offices appointed by the judge Advocate-General to examine claims of exemption. The claims allowed are firstly, age under eighteen or over forty-five; secondly, physical incapacity; thirdly, colour (no negroes or mulattoes being accepted); fourthly, alien birth and non-naturalisation ; fifthly, membership of the scholastic end clerical professions. A popular caricature recently represented one of the unwilling conscripts as saying, in answer to the commissioner's question why he claimed exemption, "I am sixty years of age; I am an Irishmen; my mother was a nigger; I have a humpback and a clubfoot; I sin a confirmed drunkard; and I am a preacher of the gospel," "You may go, Six," replied the commissioner. "Your case is but too complete." The most numerous claims of exemption have been made by Irishmen and other foreigners, armed with their passports and consular papers to prove their nationality. At least fifty thousand such claims are said to have been allowed. Another numerous class is that of which the members could only plead their physical disability-such as deafness, short-sight, malformation of the hand or foot, and, in some instances, inveterate and incurable dipsomania, proved on the oath of the wives of the unfortunate delinquents. Another large class is said-but perhaps it is a libel-to have been composed of men who before the draught was threatened represented themselves to be from thirty-five to forty years of age, but who suddenly discovered, after perusal of Mr. Lincoln's demand for 300,000 conscripts, that they were certainly forty-six. In all these cases the commissioners insisted upon the certificate of birth. Our Engraving represents the interior of the Office of Exemption in the fifteenth ward of the city during the time when the draught was considered imminent and had been positively fixed to take place at the end of November.
The West Indies, Free Labour, and Cotton.

Ever since the commencement of the cotton dearth, and, indeed, on more than one occasion anterior to it, certain gentlemen whose names we need not specify, but the authenticity and adequacy of whose information on the matter we propose submitting to the notice of our readers cannot be reasonably doubted, have done their utmost to direct the attention of the British public to the capabilities of the West Indian islands and mainland, and more particularly of Jamaica, for the culture and preparation of cotton for the European market.   According to their testimony, it would be difficult to select within cotton-growing latitudes any other area of equal extent possessed of so many recommendations for the cultivation of the precious staple.   It has been proved by actual experiment that the plant grown in the West Indies may, with ordinary care, be so reared as to exhibit all the superior qualities, and to command at Liverpool the best prices, of Sea Island cotton.   It is notorious that in Jamaica and Guiana immense tracts of suitable land lie waste, partly in consequence of the ingrossing care devoted to the production of sugar but chiefly to a lack of a sufficient number of labouring population. It is obvious that the position of the Antilles in relation to Europe is but little less favourable for the transport of merchandise than that of Slave States of America.  It is asserted that even now the labour requisite for cotton plantations can be secured at a rate of wages which would leave to all parties engaged in the culture and carriage of the article ample remuneration; but it is admitted that a large accession of hands would be required to enable the West Indies to develop, to anything like the extent of which it is capable and which the wants of Europe demand, a new cotton-growing interest which shall fully compensate for the loss of the old one.
 Now, it happens that, to the powerful arguments urged in favour of any well-considered scheme for realising the above-named advantages, the course of events having its course in the American civil conflict furnishes a series of nearly equal cogency. It was well known that the fortune of war has placed in the hands of the Federal Government above 200,000 "contrabands," -i.e., slaves who have either been captured by the invading troops or who have escaped for their Southern masters to the Federal camps. These coloured people have become  burden upon the hands of Mr. Lincoln, and a cause of serious perplexity to his Cabinet. What is to be done with them? There seem to be strong objections, physical as well as social, to using them as soldiers. To transport the whole of them to Liberia would require a respectable navy, and would 

entail upon the North an enormous expense.  The jealousy of the Free States against allowing negro labour to come into competition with the labour of whites is too strong and active to admit of a gradual absorption of the African element into the industrial population.   Meanwhile, they have to be fed and sheltered at the public expense.   During the continuance of the war, it is true, a large number of "contrabands" may be employed in the construction of military works and in performing the duties of the more menial camp offices.   But their number is constantly on the increase and what shall be done with them when the present struggle has ceased is a problem which the lapse of every month renders at the same time more pressing and more difficult of solution.
Here, then, we have two conditions which, whenever they can be united, will realise a consummation equally advantageous to us, to our West Indian colonies, to the Federal Government and people of America, to the captured and liberated negroes, and to the cause of humanity. There is a soil waiting for labourers, and there are labourers waiting for a soil. They are not far distant from each other. The negroes themselves appear willing enough to go, for the great success of the black emigrants to the Northern States of Hayti has proved that in this instance deportation has no necessary connection with misery. The authorities and planters of the West Indian Islands are not only willing but eager to receive them, and to give such reasonable security as may be demanded for respecting their personal freedom and giving them profitable employment. The Government at Washington, on such securities being entered into, will not only let the coloured labourers depart, but will themselves convey, or be at the expense of conveying, them to their new home. Mr. Adams, the American Ambassador to the Court of St. James's, has broached the question to Earl Russell, her Majesty's Secretary of State for Foreign Affairs, and has intimated the readiness of the Federal Government to enter into a convention with that of the United Kingdom for the removal, to any of the West India colonies, of the blacks in America to whom the present war has given or may give liberty.

Where, then, is the obstacle, and of what kind is it, that a proposal which meets the wishes of so many parties is not forthwith carried into effect? From the tenour of a despatch forwarded by the Duke of Newcastle to the Lieutenant-Governor of Jamaica it appears that the British Government are not prepared to enter into such a convention as that suggested by Mr. Adams; and, from the published diplomatic correspondence of the American Ambassador, it seems, that our Cabinet, after discussing the subject with fitting seriousness, came to the conclusion that, "on the whole, it might be the means of entangling them in some way or other with the difficulties in the United States, by possible reclamations of fugitives, or in some other way-a danger which they were most desirous to avoid." However much the decision is to be regretted, the evident anxiety of the British Government to avoid furnishing a pretext of quarrel to either of the belligerents in America will command the approval of the English public. How far this excessive caution should be carried is a question not very easy to be determined; and perhaps it is better that those who are responsible for the maintenance of international amity, should err on the side of apprehension rather than of recklessness. But, supposing the reason assigned by Earl Russell for declining the offer of Mr. Seward to be the only one that exists, it is a fair question for consideration whether our Government are not abnegating national rights, or, at any rate, abstaining from the exercise of them, beyond the limits imposed by the exigences of the situation; and whether, on the ground of what we now refuse to do, demands may not be made upon us hereafter which we shall certainly resist, even at the cost of war. -

It is matter of notoriety, besides being in strict accordance with international law, that, as opportunity occurs, we make valid contracts, whether of purchase or of sale, with both the parties to the civil war. The tobacco, the rice, or the cotton which reach us, though in but small quantities, through the North, are just as likely to have been the property of Confederate planters, and to have changed hands by other than commercial means during the war, as are the fugitive negroes. On the Constitutional principles of the Southern States these now homeless "contrabands" are in precisely the same position with regard to the outer world as any other article of property would be which the chances of war had transferred from its former owner to its present possessor. No nation can pretend, at the close of a contest with some other nation, that it has a right to reclaim from those who were neutrals all commodities and "chattels" of which its citizens may have been deprived by military force, and which have thereby found their way into the hands of a third party. Besides, we do not in this country recognise the right of property in man. Should any one of the African labourers whom our Government declines to receive in the West Indies, with the double consent of the Federal Cabinet and of the wretched captives themselves, have found his way to any part of her Majesty's dominions, even before the period of the Secession, he would thereupon have become a free man, and we should have refused the rendition of him to any Power on earth, and at any risk of consequences. We did so but recently in the case of John Anderson, who had taken refuge in Canada; and, unquestionably, we shall do so again and again whenever and by whomsoever reclamation is made upon us for fugitive slaves. We trust her Majesty's Government have not, in the excess of their caution, laid ground for the urging of some such demand upon us when the war shall have ceased. We should be sorry that an inference could he justly drawn from any decision of theirs to the effect that the British Government recognise the doctrine that slaves are property which may be reclaimed, as such, by one Power from another. That we should surrender or even seem to ignore an iota of our own national creed in this matter for the sake of showing our delicate impartiality, does not strike us as dictated by a far-seeing wisdom. And if, on any question affecting international relations, no decision can be wholly free from risk, it does appear to us that a convention with the Federal authorities for the effectuation of an object so desirable to all parties and in all senses as the one proposed should not have been refused, lest at some time hereafter we may be asked by an irritated nation to do what we never have done and never shall do.

The question will be sure to come up in other shapes before long, and will probably be determined by Parliamentary authority. The last advices from Jamaica inform us that notice of motion had been given in the Assembly of that island for the appointment of a committee to consider the best means of promoting the immigration of the coloured and black people of the States. Our own Legislature can hardly evade, or wish to evade, so important a question. The operatives of Lancashire who are now subsisting, not without a bitter pang, on public charity, magnanimously scorned to lessen their own distress by giving their sanction to the continuance of negro slavery. If, then, their prospects can be brightened, and the staple of their manufacture largely increased, by a process which, so far as it goes, will convert slaves into free man, we cannot but think that they have a genuine claim upon the consideration of their countrymen. Are we entitled to shut them out from the most promising advantages which have hitherto been offered them, lest, by acting upon right principles, we may hereafter be called to account by a Government founded upon wrong principles? Of course, we take for granted that, should Parliament show a disposition to assume the responsibility of accepting Mr. Seward's offer, the Ministers can urge no further objection to it. To the arrangement itself, whereby the negroes captured by Northern arms may, with their own consent, he sent across to the West Indies, they can offer no opposition but that which arises out of apprehension for the future; but if the country is resolved to face the risk of war with the yet unrecognised Confederacy, on grounds which it can fully justify and be proud of, the Government, we cannot doubt, will cordially concur in its decision.

AMERICA.

By the arrival of the steamer Norwegian we are in receipt of Boston and New York journals of the 27th ult.

War News.

The army of the Potomac, though for the moment inactive, will not, it is said, under its present commander, be suffered to go into winter quarters.
General Burnside has published a further report in which he accepts the whole responsibility of the reveres at Fredericksburg and exonerates the President, General Halleck, and Secretary Stanton from all blame. He attributes the defeat to the fog and the delay in building the bridges across the Rappahannock, which gave the Confederates twenty-four hours more to concentrate their forces in their strong positions.

The number of wounded on the side of the Federate is finally given, on the authority of the medical director, to be 7000 instead of 9000, as previously reported.


The committee appointed by the Senate to inquire into the disaster of at Fredericksburg have presented their report. They examined Generals Burnside, Hooker, and Franklin, and have presented the evidence without comment. The Generals agreed that the delay in the arrival of the pontoon train was fatal, yet it has been impossible to discover the guilty party, as General Halleck considers his responsibility terminated with giving the order for their despatch immediately after the receipt of the request. General Burnside denied that the troops were demoralised; but General Sumner thought his were, and that the army required rest.

The report that General Footer had been defeated in North Carolina was inaccurate. The General pushed on from Kingston and captured Goldsborough, where he tore up the line of railroad connecting Wilmington with Richmond, and then retired to Newbern. He fought four successful engagements, with a loss of about 500 men. En revanche he captured 500 prisoners and eleven pieces of artillery, with a large number of small arms. 

General Banks's expedition has been sighted on the Gulf of Mexico. It is confirmed that he will supersede General Butler in the commend of the south-west department. 
The Confederates have recaptured Holly Springs, Mississippi. The Federals lost in this affair 200 killed and wounded and 150 prisoners, also 500,000 dols. worth of stores. 
President Davis has issued a proclamation retaliatory upon Butler. He and all his officers are to be hung if taken, but their soldiers are to be paroled. Negroes taken in arms and their officers are also to be hung.

A large steamer, bringing a heavy stock of shoes, blankets, and cloth for the Confederate Government, got safely into Charleston Harbour recently.

General Bonham has been appointed Confederate Governor South Caroline, in place of General Gregg, killed. 

Washington. 

A full account of the interview between the President and the caucus of Republican senators, who passed a veto of want of confidence in a part of the President's Cabinet, has been published. The President heard what the senators had to say, and then respectfully declined to accede to their request, on the ground that what the country needed was military success and that his Cabinet Ministers, "even were they angels," could not guarantee that. The resolution was principally levelled at Mr. Seward, on account of his conservation in home politics and his irritating attitude in the management of foreign affairs. The latter ground was urged by Senator Sumner, the chairman of the Senate's Committee on Foreign Affairs. In consequence if the refusal of the President to accept the resignations; of Messrs. Seward and Chase, those gentleman continue to hold office. This is the first attempt in the course of American Constitutional history to make the personnel of the Administration dependent on Congress. It has failed in the present instance.

The President hesitates to sign the bill admitting Western Virginia as a separate State.  
The efforts of the representatives of the Border State men to induce the President to cancel his proclamation of the 22nd of September have been futile, but he thinks favourably of their petition that Tennessee and portions of Eastern Virginia, where manifestations of loyalty have been made, be excepted from its operation.

Congress, by a vote of 77 against 33 has given leave to report a bill appropriating 20,000,000 dols. to Missouri to aid her in emancipating her slaves.  


A bill embodying Secretary Chase's proposals for raising 300,000,000 dols. for the service of the current year, and 600,000, 000 dols. for the service of the next fiscal year, has been introduced into the House of Representatives.


Miscellaneous.

Mrs. Harriet Beecher Stowe has published in the current number of the Atlantic Monthly a reply to the appeal made to the women of America by the women of Britain on the subject of slavery ten years ago. She says that those who felt the weight of that appeal have had hitherto no leisure to reply to it:

All their time and en ergies were already absorbed in direct efforts to remove the great evil concerning which the minds of their English sisters had been newly aroused, and their only answer was the silent continuance of these efforts. The time has come, however, when such an astonishing page has been turned in the anti-slavery history of America that the women of our country, feeling that the great anti-slavery work to which their English sisters exhorted them is almost done, may properly and naturally feel moved to reply is their appeal, and lay before then the history of what has occurred since the receipt of their affectionate and Christian address.

After giving her version of the anti-slavery contest in the United States during the past ten years, and charging English public opinion with a leaning in favour of the establishment of a slaveholding Confederacy, she apostrophises the women of England thus:-

And now, sisters of England, think it not strange, if we bring back the words of your letter, not in bitterness but in deepest sadness, and lay them at your door. We say to you, -Sister you have spoken well; we have heard you; we have heeded; we have striven in the cause, even unto death. We have sealed our devotion by desolate hearth and darkened homestead-by the blood of sons, husbands, and brothers. In many of our dwellings the very light of our lives has gone out, and yet we accept the life-long darkness as see own part in this great and awful expiation, by which the bonds of wickedness shall be loosed, and abiding peace established on the foundation of righteousness. Sisters, what have you done, and what do you mean to do? In view of the decline of the noble anti-slavery fire in England-in view of all the facts and admissions recited from your own papers-we beg leave, in solemn sadness, to return to you your own words.

The reply is signed by Mrs. Stowe "in behalf of many thousands of American women,"
Orders for the supply of the French army in Mexico continue to be executed in New York. The Mexican Minister has protested, but Mr. Seward declines to interfere.

Thirty-nine out of the 300 Sioux Indians imprisoned at Dakoa, Minnesota, were to be hung on the 27th for their complicity with the massacre of the whites, and fears are entertained that the whites will "lynch" the rest. The colonel commanding the post has invoked the aid of the law-abiding portion of the citizens.

CALIFORNIA.

The British steamer Scotland has arrived at San Francisco from Hong-Kong, Shanghai, and Kanagawa. The Scotland is the pioneer of a new British line of steamers which are to make a monthly trip between San Francisco, Japan, and China. The charge for freight is 12 dols. a ton, and for passengers 250 dols. each. The Scotland brought 700 tons of freight from China, and 300 tons from Japan, principally teas.

Messrs. Bacon and Co., of Paternoster-row, have just issued a coloured plan of the Battle-field of Fredericksburg, in which the position of the Federal and the Confederate forces are clearly marked. 

London; Saturday, January 10, 1863. 

The attitude of the Federals up to the time of sending away the last mail resembles that of the crew of a vessel which has just sustained a most terrific shock from a monster wave. The fierce blow has been delivered, the ship has reeled, and there ensues a moment of paralysed wonder. By this time, no doubt the public mind has recovered its elasticity, and is engaged with the fearful details of the Fredericksburg disaster; but we have only evidence how the people have been, for once, stunned by a defeat. And no wonder. A nation that did not feel deeply wounded and humiliated by such a blow would, indeed, be unworthy. It is not the mere fact that a fine army has been crushed and its remnant sent in disgrace across the little river that had been absurdly called its Granicus-heavy reverses have been sustained ere this, and the beaten side has lost nothing save the day and many men, and has rallied and retrieved its laurels ; it is that the Fredericksburg disaster is a blow driven home to the very heart of the American system-a blow which has demonstrated to the world that the institutions under which such an event is possible can no longer be relied upon as State mechanism. It is not that an accident has happened to machinery ; it is that the machine has proved a failure.

General Burnside has had the courage, or tact, or recklessness to declare himself solely responsible for the movements which ended in the carnage of Fredericksburg. But the people are not to be deceived by any such transparent advice. It may be perfectly true that the final arrangements for the attack were the General's own; they could hardly be otherwise; but it is notorious that the advance itself was a political as much as a military movement, and was a necessity of party. This is the fatal truth ; and in the fact that, in order to meet the exigencies of party, as understood in America, it is permitted to slaughter 10,000 men, is or should be the death-sentence of the present system. It was well known that the attack could be successful only by a miracle, and M'Clellan had preferred to sacrifice his own position as head of the army rather than hurl it upon almost certain destruction. But the party found a General who owned himself no great master of war, and who did not hesitate to rush upon the Confederate intrenchments in a way that proved that he had not under-estimated his own professional ignorance. He was not even supplied with the means of making his mad attack in the best way; his pontoons were "forgotten;" and the whole chapter, from the beginning to the end, was one of misfortune. Still, and here is the most lamentable thing of all, the politicians of the North do not appear to consider that anything discreditable has been done. They are staggered by the magnitude of the slaughter which a party move has caused, but they are unable to see that such a step was one of guilt, or that the conduct of a campaign should be dictated by military considerations and not by the momentary need of a faction. It is difficult for English readers to realise this state of things. Perhaps they may form a very rough idea of it by supposing that we are at war with France; that a French army lies in a very strong position near Boulogne; that the Government, say Lord Palmerston's, is very unpopular, and public credit not good; and that Mr. Disraeli's friends have, been winning a great many elections, and threaten a crisis. At this moment, and desirous to please the people by a sign of vigour, Lord Palmerston and the War Secretary intimate to Lord Clyde that at all hazards he must attack the French. Lord Clyde obeys, and leads the army into a semicircle of fire, where, throughout a whole day, our men are mowed down by artillery against which he can do nothing. At night he retreats, leaving ten thousand soldiers on the field; but Lord Palmerston has asserted his reputation for being in earnest, and Mr. Disraeli does not give notice of a vote of want of confidence. That is not a parallel case, but it is sufficiently like what has occurred to make an English reader indignant that such a state of things can be held compatible with Christian civilization.

 This fourth defeat of the North is no doubt very important, but it is not one which adds much to the glory of the South. The day could not have gone otherwise than as it did, and Lee and Jackson must have been astounded at the madness which delivered over the troops of the North to such inevitable destruction. The Confederates had really little to do but to serve their guns, and this they did admirably. Such part of the affair as partook of the nature of a battle did no discredit to either side, and Jackson himself was either forced back, or chose to retreat for a considerable distance. We do not believe the majority of the stories that impute bad fighting to the Northerners. If they fought badly at all it was because they were badly led; and the murderous system-there is no other word for it-of intrusting important movements to officers who have never been educated and have been chosen by election, is responsible for anything like disgrace that may have attached to any of the regiments. The individual American fights excellently while he can depend upon himself; but the moment he is asked for the soldier's faith in his officer he is helpless, for he is in the habit of thinking, and his reason tells him that the officer will probably lead him to be knocked on the head to no good purpose. Then, very likely, the American walks away or runs away; but it is sheer insolence to call this cowardice. Give him officers, and teach him to obey them unhesitatingly, - and the chronicle of this war will tell another story.

But it is the system that is ruining the fortunes of the Republic, in the field and out of it. There is no such thing as political conscience; and the soldiers are as much made the counters in the game as they ever were in the old monarchical wars of Europe, against which so many well-deserved taunts used to be launched by popular writers. Only, upon the old kingly vices the Republicans have engrafted new ones of their own. The Kings sent their men to the battle, but it was at least under commanders who knew their business, and who did not throw away life unnecessarily except under circumstances of a very peculiar description. Generals were sometimes accused of not utterly defeating an enemy because it was highly desirable that he should be left strong enough to ensure another year's campaign; but when they fought him they did so in a rational manner, had an object in view, and either gained it or retired in fitting time if the object were unattainable. But the American system sends men into the field under the leadership of officers who are chosen because they have political influence, or can make loud speeches, or are very liberal with their liquor at the tavern bar; or even because they have kept a tavern bar, and have not been over harsh in insisting on the payment of scores. With such machinery of war the enlightened people of America are content, or have been content, to fight the greatest contest which the present generation has seen. It is hardly conceivable that they will not one of these days make short work with a system which makes a battle a mere savage scramble, to which (again thanks to the system) men are hounded on to satisfy the exigencies of faction.

- The annual stocktaking of the Liverpool cotton market shows a total of 392,000 bales, against 622,565 last year. Of the first-mentioned quantity 70,000 are American and 260,050 Surat cotton.

An American paper says that a great grandnephew of Oliver Goldsmith was shot through the head and died at Antietam
.
It is rumoured that Captain Semmes, of the Alabama, intends to shift his cruising-ground to the India and China sees

ILLUSTRATIONS OF THE WAR IN AMERICA.

Our Special Artist and Correspondent in America, having, in common with the correspondents of other European journals, been curtly refused permission to accompany the Federal forces, has pitched his tent in the opposite camp, whence, as opportunity serves, he forwards to us his Illustrations of the War. Thus it happens, without say intention of the kind on our part or on that of our Artist, that his Sketches illustrate the varying aspects of the war from the Confederate instead of from the Federal point of view, and have possibly, in consequence, a colouring somewhat different from that which would have marked sketches taken by the same hand in the camp of the army of the Potomac. However that may be, his Illustrations cannot fail to be of interest, giving, as they do, glimpses into what is wellnigh a sealed book-tbe doings in the Confederate camp, Our present Number contains three illustrations by our Speaal Artist, umgetin which j POSITION OF THE FEDERAL AND THE OONOTDSRATE PICKETS AT  PIISDBRIC1CS]IURG.

he writes as fellows:- 5'aEDEOOCcSOeleO ON DEC. 4. The little town of Frederitkobnr, which has been rendered fameu by the NIGHT AZOETEENUS UT THE CONFEDERATE CAMp. The flappahenneck at Fredericksburg (writes our Artist on the day he great battle fought noar it on the 11th ult., hid previously suffered rough "Every evening, when we cluster around our pine-log fires, the 'darkico' took the above Sketch) is scarcely more then a hundred yards in width, and usage, having been alternately in the hoossie v' Confederates and lode, ale two I

I this is the distance that divides the Confederates Irons the Federals. The I or three times. It is tl'e thief teen of Snottovi'aeia county, Virginia, and

press in amongst us and listen to the yarns their masters spin. In our camp pickets of each army are within earshot end in foil view of each ether, and is situated on the riadst hank of the llsppshoeoork Sliver. cc the he'] of tide- I we ore fortunate enough to possess the most famous banjo-player in the they frequently indulge in remarks that might be token exception to in polite water. It is between fifty ant sixty miles from Richmond by ruilresd, and

tide

Southern States, and when Sweeny strikes up one of his quaint old Virginian society. While making the accompanying 5k-etch o sentinel who was leaning eirty-five mike by the turnpike, in a northerly direction. The town is I

hrcakdcwns, some nigger is sure to 'wade' in end put his legs through a

series of msrvellons gyrations, to the delight of the sympathetic leakers-on, on his musket, locking over me, suddenly tolled out to a blue-coated German J pleasantly situated in a fertile calley, and has advantages for commerce and I

 who beat time for him. Although the enemy is within cannon-shot, no sue on the other aide, 'Yew many men have you got over thor, Yank?' 'Dos or I manufactures. The railroad from Washington, c-it Acqsde Creek, posses


experiences the least -uneasiness, and the universal refrain is, 'We'll Bills dree donsond,' grunted the Teietoc, 'Oh bring them. along; that's nothing. I through it, and as the throughtrams generally slop at Freslesickobtsrg Station I

We reckoned ynsohad an srmy!' It is whispered at head-quarters to-day that P for about an hour on each trip, a not inconsiderable chance trade was caused

to-ought and fight to-morrow-bssllyboys, oh. an attempt will be made by the enemy to cross the river at three different thereby in the Immediate locality of the f6p"t. .5. good canal has been con- I GENERAL LONGSTRESrO CORPS CROSSING THE SLUT EDGE, TIIRGIh'IA. points during the night. Everything is ready for them when they come, ctr,octcd from the town to a paint on the Rappahcnuock River about forty I

"Of the entire Confederate army encamped near Winchester Jarkso,fe corps and the battle that will possibly take plate within the next few days must miles above, by which large quantities of wheat, flour, and tobacco were I

alone remains, and that, I preosinte, will soon fullowthemain bcdyinto London I determine, ca farce the Federals are concerned, whether the war is to continue formerly received for exportation. The river affords extensive water power, I County, where Bnrnside menaces with an immense army theline of the Rappa- I or net: it will be by far the largest .and meet important of the whole cam- which, however, has not been conch used. The hub in the neighbourhood, lsonnookin thin, the third, advance of the Federals on Richmond. The subject psicn. Frsbably not less then 210,000 men will be engage d. I am lying out I  varying from forty to one hundred feet high, abound in fine granite and free

of the Engraving ie one of the Picturesque. passes in the Blue Ridge with 1 mfie pine-wood's at the advance, ready to wield my pencil 'when the efruggit stone.

GtoeralLongetrett'e corps-d'armie paecing'thodgh a its-MYto Cnlpejiper begins. E+erythot we hear' at we lie with our feet th'th&firedui-big the long ' About thirty years since the prospect of Fredericksburg being a'rapidly-' to hoist in oheds the Northern forces. The scenery of these Virginian mean- cold tights starts us on our logo, for we how the enemy has his pontoons rising town was vary great; out it suddenly stopped in it nrssperity and I

talus reminds me forcibly of fib Apennines, and recalls many scenes which ready to cross in the darkness. What a bursting of shells over my bed after, as it were, stsnilino- still for about twenty pests, gradue'lly retrograded.

T have i,itnssset with Gaoibaldf's for Iso Scum= Itasy." so, wtu be wEe,, The bell epeee 5" i 1940 it. o.onuteOj,,,, e,eefleea nc'r5v .5000 mule, ena
1850, ten years after, it had only increased eighty-eight persona-less than nine each year, and being about two per cent in the decade--a remarkbly email lnrrcaae. Before the war it contained five churches, one orphan asylum, two eemtocsios. four newspaper-offices, end two banks. Such macFredericksburg. The carrospcodent of the New Yard Times reports:-"It is 'living' Frederickoberg 'no more.' A city, soulless, rent by the wrack of war, and shooting op in florets athwart night's sky. is the pretty little antique spot by the Parpthsnnnck, erewbile the peculiar scene of dignified ease and retirement."

The Rappebannoek liver rises in the Blue Ridge, but a few miles from the south fork of the Shenandoah, and pursues an easterly course to Preelerieksbora some sixty miles aouth-southweet of Washington eity, where it is within teas miles of the Potomac. It has here become a broad navigable stream, though its er'rsme soorcee are hardly eighty miles distant. Prom Fredericksburg it has e g, moral south-east course till it is lost in Chesapeake Day, come twenty-fire enilee below the mouth of the Potomac. For the present its course below Ti edeniclrsbnrg is commended by the Union gun-boats, but above that city it banmea disputable, and has for months in good part divided the Union from the Confederate forces, Itnaturaily forks towards its Scores into innumerable strums and vuiets, but at first, gems tao miles anveedecksbnxg, into two u nhee,'ssbsrocttbad coining fronts north-west retains the non's ci Itappsbsnnnth, 'ecba that from the swathwest in known en the tepid
The latest measurement of those freshwater seas, American lakes, are as follows :-The greatest length of Lake Superior is aijj miles; the greatest breadth Is 100 miles; mean depth 9SOft.; elevation, Bd7ft.. I area, 32,000 square miles. The greatest length of Lake Michigan is 000 milea its greatest breadth, 108 miles mean depth, 900m; elevation, 08710.; aw CL

20,000 square miles. The greatest length of Lakolthress is 200 miles; Is greatest breadth a 100 miles; mean depth, 10010 elevation, 07400.; 20,000 square miles. The greatest length of Lake Brie Is 200 miles; tt I greatest breadth 1080 miles; its mean depth is 2000t.; elevation, 2820t. I 6000 square miles. The greatest length 1 Lake Ontario is 100 miles; I greatest breadth is 66 miles its mean depth is 00000.; elevation, 2e200. 6800eqoars miles. The total length of all five is 1140 miles, covering an N  altogether of upwards of 04,000 square miles.
THE CAREER OF THE ALABAMA.

Mn, S. lii. Thonflanun, writing from St. Thomas, Went Inches, fur

nishes the Scoten-san with a short history of the career of the Con

federate war-steamer Alabama, obtained from the late boatswain of

the "200":

The "290" was built by bin. Laird, the sminont shipbuilder at Itirkenlstod, under contract with a Mr. Butcher. She was regularly contracted and paid for; and as nothing transpired doting her construction to warrant the sup. position that she was destined to hoist the ensign of the Southern Confederacy, no laws of neutrality were Infringed, indeed, it was hinted that the veseel was intended for the service of the Emperor of Ohms. Her heal was laid in the beginning of this year (1502), and she was launched in April thereafter, though she was not ready for ass for the scoceednig three months. The "100" Is simply a large wooden screw goal-boat, such a vessel as is in European navies styled o corvette. She is very etroegy built of the best materials, and is constructed to carry ten gnus--Via., see rifled 100-pounder, one 00-pounds" , and eight Ilpeendem-i.e., fete l12-pesmdera so each broadside, throwing collectively 120th. solid shah at each discharge, end two pivot gene. She is barqaa-rigged, s,,d is fitted with a pile of very powerful engines, by Penn, of London. Ohs loft Birkenhead towards the end of only, ostensibly ass a trlcl.telp, having oil heard a large party of ladies end gentleman. On getting out of the Men'ey, this party was sent beck in a tssg-beat, mitt the "2150," as hod been previously arranged, neglected to return to Birkenhead, but steamed direct for the island in the Atlantic whore she was to hobo in her gnus, ammunition, Lii. On leasing England, the "200" had a crew of sdncty-thecr nice, for the most part belonging to the English Haiti Baser"., all being trained gunners, and the majority old men-of-war's men. She was temporarily :onunendrd by Captain Bullock, who had under him the pruner complement of commissioned and petty officers. Captain Bullock, having learned that the Tuecarnrs lay in wait for him in St. George's Channel, teak hon departure by what is known as the Heath Channel, thus eluding his Pederal enemy; though gem had he been intercepted the h'ortbener would have found hionselt in adilemme, as the" 2109" had sect of ]lngltshpapera, and atborpresamptiva proofs of harneutvality, in the face of which it might have been difficult for her captor to have acted. The "190" at this time carried no ge.en or other warlike stores, but consisted merely of the hull, spars, and engines, exespt, of coarse, coal end other requisites to enable her to reach her dasthiat(en, which was Tacisea, one et the Azores or Western Islands, belonging to Portugal. This destination tha "290" duly reached, after s too ran of eight days, and coma to an anchor too Toris,oa floods, nothing of any moment having occurred to break the nasal monotony of assa voyage.  -

 Some time loafers the departure of the" 290" from the Meeaeyalarge berqne loft the Thames (cleared far Domerara, Went ladies) to meet the "100" at Tartos, and there transfer to the latter vessel the guns and stoves destined for her, and which formed the cargo of the be-rqtie. Some reason required to he assigned to the Partageeoo authorities for the " 290" having anchored In their bay, and accordingly the excuse furnished to them was that her engines had broken down. This plea was accepted as a valid one, and during the week that totsrveeed betwixt the arrival at Taa-tass of the " 290" and the harqne the crow of thefermer vessel west engaged ostensibly in repairing her engines, but really in preparing her to rosette bar gone, lie. About the lapse of a week from the arrival of the "210" the bnrqoo above mentioned sailed in and anchored, her captain alleging as a reason to the Portuguese ostolals that his vessel load sprang a leak, which would require to be repaired ere she could resume her -voyage; and on this inodsrstanding the Portuguese at cuss placed bar to ssarantina (which in the Azores lasts three doyal. Ca the day after the barqne s arrival,-Csptatn Bullock, of the "200," being anxious to get his gnus on beard, hooted alongside of the bareins, and emoted a pair of large shears to effect the transfer of her cargo from the barqno's bald to the "290's" dock. This brought off the Portuguese in a fiery than their rides should have been broken by the "200" having dared to cent' munieato with a vessel which had still two days' quarantine to run, and they

 angrily demanded to know the reason why their regulations had-.been They were told that tho bargue was in a sinking slate, and the erection of the shears-iran accounted for by urging the necessity for an immediate temporary transfer of her mrge, that the leak might to reached and stopped; and Captain Bullock finally succeeded in bearing dawn all apposition by feigning to get in passion, saying be was doing no mass for the boa-qne than any Englishman wosdddo for n, countryman hi distress. The Pociogueao left the vessel, and the transhipment proeesdad without farther hindrance from these on shore.

About the afternoon of the second day, and when the transfer was nearly complete, the British aerew-stcaanorllahoona coats In, baring on hosed CaptoinSommeo and the other lots officers of the Stinter, besides the remainder of the "290's" armament, end an addition of twenty odd men to bar crew. Co Use Balsmiaoa'e arrival and anchorage on a somewhat similar pretext to them given to her two predseesonro, the Portuguese fairly lost oil patience, and peremptorily insisted on lIsa instant departure of all tInts vessels. The bahsuna at ones communicated with the "290," and, having handed over to the latter vessel oesryllohsg destined far bar, got up simm and left, fehlewal by the "ass," towing the now empty harqne. All three wont, not to are, as they had horn ordered to do, but to Angra Bay (a bay in the same island, and only a few leagues distant from Tarissa Roads). Hero they remained unmolested until noon the following day (a Sunday), when, for the second time, all three vessels were ordered out of the Portuguese waters. All the "290'," gone being now mounted, and the vessel otherwise ready for a cruise, the older was obeyed, and all took their dspae'tas-s, the barque, as before, in tow of the" 1115," which, having conveyed her well out in sea, met liar off, and with. a favouring breeze else steer ed far Cnedtll, to bring out a further supply of coal for the" 200's" future use. The "200" and the Bahasne now steamed round the island, and Captain Sommes, coming out of his cabin, ordered his Pint Lionteaant to muster the crew alt. This having been done, and all the officers assembled on the peep in their felt uniform (is., Confederate grey frock-cost and trousers), Captain Smiles, sm4eined silence, end raid late cemuaiaalan an Pest Captain in the Confederate Navy. It was a dosnnoent duly attested at Richmond, and bore the signature of "Jeff, Davis, President Confederate States of America." life then opened and read his sealed orders from the President, directing him to assume command of the Confederate oloap of war Alabaasa, hitherto known as the" OIIO," In which (having been duly eonnnisaloned) be was to lisiet the Confederate ensign end pennant, end "sink, firm, and destroy everything which flew the ensign of the en-roiled United States of America." Captain Semnsos then ordered the Pint Lieutenant to fire a gun end ran up this Confederate tag and 1ieenint. The gun wan deed by the Second Lieutenant (Armstrong, a relation of the famous inventor), aid ore tin resets hod cleared away the stars and hare of the young Confederacy were floating on the brseae, and the esrcmony woo completeCaptain Soesmea declaring the vessel henceforth to he Imowu as the Alabama to have been duly mmmissioned. The next step was formally to engage the crew to serve and fight under the Southern tag, which having been dons, the men were addressed by them captain In an eloquent and stirring speech, in the count of which ho said there wore on iy fear vessels in the United States' Nary that were more than a match for the Alabama; but he said that in an English-built heart of oak as shoe was, and surrounded so he then saw himself by British hearts of eels, ho wouldn't strike his newly-hoisted flag for any one of the four. Of coarse this elicited a hearty burst at cheering for Praaldtnt, States; and Captaist, and, when it had subsided, Captain Srmsnm said the Bahama was on the point of leaving for England, and lntimatnl that it any of his crew repented of the stop they had taken, they were free to return in her. This alternative none would accept; and Captain Bullock and a few of the other officers who bell token the "190"from England to the Azores, finding their occupation gone, through this arrival of these who had hold similar appointments in the Soustar, having gone an beard the Bahama, that vessel and the Alabama, amidst hearty cheering from ties crews at both, parted company, the -former pursuing her course tuck to England, the latter to chase of a Yankee whaler, which she captured and burned. This was her first prize, and her subsequent career is now so famous en to render a single remark thereon superfluous. The Alabama's crew receive from the Confederate Government half the value of every American ship and. cargo they destroy, and each of her crew is now-inertIa several hundred paaeds. All obligations to them have hitherto been faithfully dtaolsarged In gold.. The Alabama is supplied with teal from Wales by threu aslhbsg-smarlo thins

constantly employed. -
AMERICA., By the arrival of the ltoainsre Etna and Bohemian we hate Now York journals of the 3rd met, and telegrams to the afternoon of that day The meet important item of intelligence is the issue of rItE BOLONCIPATION PROCLAMATION. After reciting the previous conditional proclamation of Sept. 22. the President proceeds to declare as follows;Now, therefore, I, Abraham Lincoln, President of the United States, l, vietne of the power in me rooted as Cemsnaader-In-CtleS of the Army, anti Navy of the Drifted States, in time of actual armed rebellion against the, autism. rip oaf Govereseont of the Dotted States, and as a fit and necessary w measure for acpprcesleg raid reodlilsa, do, en chic cast day of January, in the proc of our Lord coo ti,creand eight hundred and sixty-three, and in accordsues with my pcrpcre en Is do, publicly j,ronlsbn for the fall period of can hundred days teen the day of the first aboycmentlsuod order, and designates as I ho Stales sod pacts of States whsreln the psopie thereof respectively arc this day in retrllien against the United States, the following, to wit Arkansas, Tc,sas, Loulslssea-eaceptthsposlsheeef St. Bernard, Pbsotlsseoainof, ,Trdceods, St. yohn, St. Chsxioe, ft. Mmcc, Ascension, Assumption, Terra fleinse Lnfenrrl,s, St. Mary, St. aces-tin, and Orleans, including the city of Now rlrcne-Mlssioalppl, Alabssua, Florida, Georgia, Ssuth Carolina, North Curdles, aid Virgicia-srcopt the ferty-elcht coenltloo dselgnated sic 'Yect Virginia, and also the counties ci ]torkley, Arrumue Northampton, ]Cllsnbotlt City, York, Prineree An,,, end Nergelk, eluding  ho cities of Norfolk and Part-huiseith, end which excepted pouts are for the present loft precisely as it this precfsmatluc were net Issued. And, by virtue of the power, and for the purpose aforesaid, I do aver and drelnu that all persons held as slaves within said designated States and parts of Slates are and henceforward shall be free, and that the Sxeontlve Government of use United States, Including the military and s,aral authorities thereof, will rsregche end maintain the freedom of said porcine. And I hereby enjoin open the people so declared to be free to abstain focus oil violence unless In necnoorp selfdefence, and I recommend to them that in i all rorrr, when allowed, they labour faithlelly for reasonable wages. con And I further drclasw and make known that such persons cc suitable . dhteu will be received into the armed service of the United Slates, to garrison tens, pssltioco, stations, and other places, said to mini vessels of all sorts lit raid orrvirr.  And, upon thissincerely believed to be an act of justice, warranted by the

rtnahtutleo, upon military necessity-I invoke the considerate judgment o mankind and the cruetene Career of Almighty Cod.

5 The Virginian is counter signed by Mr. Sswnrd. Of the  Vsrgsmeu counties mentioned by name therein, only one, Berkeley,


- 15 on the Potomac. The others are on the eastern shire of hssnpeake flay, or at the month of the James River. The State of Tennessee, although a cccoded State, is not touched by this proclamation.
ITS 5Cen'T1O.

no Federal Generals in the South seem to interpret the pro

clau'etien each according to his coon hens. Thus, General Barton, the

Overnor, at Pt Ilcysi, South Carolina, has issued a pro honat-jon to the negroosi in bus department stating that it is their duty to carry the news of their freedom to their brethren still in slavery. On the other hand, General Banks,- who has supareded ilseeral Butler at Now Orleans, has addressed the people of Louisiana, informing thorn "that the changes suggested therein" o not take effect on the lot f January, nor at easy precise, period, lo public

mauttrations will be allowed, aril the alayes are -advised to

remain en their plantations "Until their privileges shall have been definitively oetablisll." No man will be allowed to take the la into his own

Coloured soldiers are to be put under surveillance, and

aseither allowed to make nor receive, visits. No fugitives are to be

rctornsd to their masters, but no engouragement is t be given to the slaves to leave their masters.

General lIurnside's army has already received a number o! fugitives,

gica in Norfolk the freed men have celebrated the great event. They

rest together on the last dcy of the old year need formed a recession

of at least 4000 persons. Roaded by a and of music, they paraded through the ptireipal streets of the city. They carried several Union

sBe, end oheered loudly for emancipation.

-  w.o.1o rerwE.

u_lie army of the Potomac is still inactive.

On the last day of the old year a battle commenced between General

 oeeucranz'o army and that commanded by Generals Joseph rohneton

arid Bragg. The battle took place near Murfreebcro', in Tennessee. It lasted two days, and at the close the Confederates still half their intrenohed positions within which they lead been driven on the drt day'edght. The losses onbotheidee are heavy. ThreaPederal Gocierais were wounded, and the Confederate Generals Cheatham and Rains . It is supposed that the attack will be renewed, We have none but Federal reports of this battle.


The iliebjeond papers say that the Federals attacked Violreburg on

the 27th, 28th, and 29th tilt., arid were repulsed each time.

TEE 00 EDI!IE4TE SaWSIES.  -

The Biotniond Whip contains a violent article upon England for


vefuaing to co-operate with Napoleon's mediation project. It sage,

and could have made fast friends with the South, but that

time ha now gone by for ever." -

General Barks has superseded General Butler at Now Orleans, The latter has been recalled to Washington at the instance of the French Government. General Butler publishes an address to the people of New Orleans defending his prooeedinge by reference to esvaittie practised by British arid French Generals in the lest three centuries,

e alludes to Great Britain and France "as the most polished end


the most hypocritical nations of Europe," and boasts that, though he may be eureed in the salon, he will be blessed in the cottage.

wAaalacuToie.

The President has signod the bill admitting Western Virginia as a


separate State. -  -

Mr. Smith of Indiana -Secretary of the Interior, and mombsr of Mr. Lincoln's Cabinet, Tim resigned his office, presumably beieue of his dieappxeval of the emancipation policy.

atIecPLtAn100.

The New York Chamber of Commerce ha passed resolutions to

the effect that the war made upon American commerce by the Alabama to not rebuked by the British press, nor the fitting out of 'reooels stopped by the British Government, and that American Merchants in the. rise of freights are subject, to a certain extent, to the evils -which would attend a state of war with England, while England enjoys the advantages of a neutral. is. committee was appointed to report -what action the Chamber shall take in the matter.

Mx, Horatio Seymour has been inaugurated Governor of New York. He made a speech declaring that has would uphold the State Constitution and see to it that the laws were respected; that his

U'ti n.gave Alin little control over national events, but he hoped the

0~ 0 ,

mon would be one arid indivisible before his term of service expired.

As first act was to order the trial of the New York Police Commissioners arid Superintendent Kennedy, for permitting the use of the New York Police Station for the illegal detention of citizens.

The Governor of Missouri, in his annual message, has recommended

the paesoga of on act providing for the gradual abolition of slave

ry

in that State, -with the pecirnlary aid of the leclera.1 Government, The State Legislature Is strongly in favour of carrying out the same policy, the only difference being 'whether floe Governor's plan is sufficiently speedy in its operation.

Captain Wynn, of the British Army, had been arrested in Baltimore,

on his arrival from Richmond, on the charge of acting as an emissary of the Confederates. Ills companion, another British officer, was not,

interfered 'with.

ThdDreat Eastern was to have left New York for England on the

3rd, but, in consequence of a heavy fog, the pilot advised that she

houhd be delayed until the weather cleared up.

A .despalah from] St. Paul, Minnesota, states that thirty-sight

Indians, condemned for taking part in the massacre, were hung, at ankato, en the morning after Christmas Day, and that the gallows

was so constructed that all fell at once.
The Alabama had played a bold trick. On the 7th of D=on-her she intercepted the New York and Aepinwall steamer Ariel, oft the east ama of Cuba, and took from her 0000 dole. The Axial was then allowed to praceof on bonds for 228,000 being given, payable thirty days after the recognition of the Southern Confederacy. The result of this proceeding was that on the return voyage the And did not bring the specie from Aapiawatl, and the lroderetosvoenmmt had mat a wer-oteasner to fetch it. the Wet tetha moul brian sue further intelligence of the doings of the Alabama. Captain Ssmoueo hod captured an American bsrqcoo, laden with poovuosona, and after having taken on beard his own ship so much of her cargo as he deemed nessosary, he oat fire to the vessel, Ho had also seized a Federal schooner, hot as her oaro was the property of British subjects she was allowed to preooeil upon the Ooptnin elgnlng a bond to pay a certain onus of msney to the Csnicle rots Government at the oboe of the war.

Tun CAREER OF THE Ax,ASAMA.-(To the Editor.)-Will

you runt me space to merest & few of the many errors cent sines in Mr.'. 1',

lieilrrhlll'e conononnbratien to the Scotsman referring to thu Caofelcmta oteumer Alabama, a copy of which appeared in your columns on Saturday lout? 1. She was not built under contract with a Mr. Butcher. 2. Her engisco are not by Penn, of Leaden, hot by LairS, of Itirkenhmd. lb. She did nut, after leaving Dickonhend, steam directly to the island to the Atlantic, too., hot peterS a day and two nights is Otoelfea Bay, on the must of We're, tskng in three is portion of her crow, bendndl stereo, ton. 4. Her destination w .t7 not

Textron," wherever hot may be, but Tarcctra, sun of the Ascrus. 0. She was never commanded by a Captain Bullock. The gnstlemsn who totr charge of her from the time she left the otorhi till she was delivered intothc lvcnis of Ccplrin Ermones, of the Crrfcferato navy, was C-apteiis St. II. Bolehcc, lt.N.it. 0. The Aisba,nu had no ErgItol, paper, to prove her neutrality toe foot, she rental no papers whatever. 5. She was not visited hotly by Hr;e part, of the isl,obitnnt.a of " Tories-a," or Treceira. Ossw ode too the 22,vl ci .t a rtoo) a rusts r.f Shoot ovvunty lorroocs, chief y e11oial, paid the tenet a vi

A.B., Hull, Jan, 12, ittO.
ZOZf 072 SATrJRDA r, JANUARY 17, 1865.

HA1 the proclamation with which the President of the Norllieru. States of America has inaugurated the New Yeaii been issued wider other circumstances than those which unhappily attend it, there is not a journal in the United Kingdom but would have given that document the place of honour, and have introduced it with the warmest words of congratulation, the most honest utterances of rejoicing, which it is permitted to the pen to express. The President has proclaimed instant freedom to the American slaves would have been an announcement to sot all hearts beating joyfully, and to call out a long exulting shout from British freemen. We should have set our bells ringing, and have kindled our fires

From Eddystoue to Borwiok bounds, from Lynn to Mllford Bay.

For, let a few calumniators write as they will, the people

of England have ever been of one mind upon the slavery question. They are as stanch and resolved in their hatred of the domestic institution as when we abolished the accursed slave traffic; as when, at a vast sacrifice, both of money and of colonial prosperity, we struck the last fetter from the last English slave; as when the women of England, hail a million strong, sent out a generous if not a wise remonstrance to the women of America. We detest the system, and every attempt to palliate its 'wickedness or to defend those who are its friends by any argument based on principle is offensive to the right-thinking people of this country. We repeat that, had this proclamation been issued in time of p3aee. and as the deliberate resolve of the Government of the United States, the day on which we 'write, or some day that would have been instantly and gleefully fixed, would have been kept as high holiday in England, and. the next mail would have gone out heavily laden with our sincerest congratulations to our American brethren upon their having given the de'sll,blo w to a cruel and blasphemous system. Our churches would have
resounded with thanksgivings of a still higher kind, and we should have rendered grateful homage to Providence for having strengthened a kindred nation to wipe away a stain upon humanity.

Even as it is, and in spits of the fact that for all practical purposes the proclamation is a sham, the words cannot be read without emotion. The President decrees freedom to the slaves in ten States. But the more we should have rejoiced had the measure been one of peaceful civilisation the more bitter is the feeling that the document was prompted only for the emberressment of an enemy, and that it will be in most instances a bretvee felmese, while perhaps in others it may bring on melancholy results. It is not the Government of America that issues this proclamation, but the chief of certain States that are seeking empire over others. The document is no noble State paper, the crowning of a deliberate and generous policy, but an experiment designed to help on a disastrous and unjustifiable wet. It is simply an attempt to eiplode a mine under the feet of those upon whom cannon have thundered in vain. The President of the North, if he believes that his proclamation will take effect, is in the position of a soldier who employs some new and barbarous method of exterminating his antagonists. Could the notification really effect what some of the Abolitionists profess to desire, the savages who poison wells, the miscreants who leave

- poisoned stores behind them, are humane and civilised enemies in comparison to these who sign and publish this document. But we will net believe that the Abolitionist doctrine is that of Mr. Lincoln, who has always been accounted a kindly, if coarse and shortsighted, men. He does not think that his notice that the slaves are free will set four millions of revengeful Africans Bring, plundering, and slaying; but he probably does hope that lie will embarrass the Confederate Generals; and, moreover, he has obeyed the dictates of the powerful faction that has hitherto made hit its tool, to the eternal detriment of the once mighty Republic which he was elected to govern.

 Yet it is impossible not to feel a greet and a now anxiety while we await information as to the results of this step. The President, true to his feeble character, hesitated to the last, and did not issue the proclamation until the second of the month. That the Confederates knew that it had been fin ally

 -resolved upon may be assumed as certain, and it is equally so that they will have taken the most determined means to meet it. Indeed, the counter-proclamation of President Davis, though ostensibly and mainly directed against a man who had been recalled before the Southern document was issued, is intended as a repressive agency. Mr. Lincoln tells the slave that he is free, and that he may take arms for what is curiously celled his country; Mr. Davis tells him that if be is taken in arms the officers under whom he serves shall be liable to suffer death, end that he himself shall be handed ever to the tender mercies of the State to which he belongs; and the slave knows what that means, and would, if captured, gladly compound for the more merciful doom decreed to his white officer. All this is truly horrible, and even if none of the fearful revenge thus menaced shall be taken, America will be glad hereafter to tear from her history the pages in which such documents are preserved-to destroy such evidences that the boasted advance of education and civilisation had done cc little for her nations that they had recourse in war time to menaces of indiscriminate massacre. But we doubt net that the President of the Southern States has done more then issue this proclamation. He has caused it to be understood wherever there is a negro who can carry arms. The

 Lincoln proclamation will have been kept out of the Slave States as much as possible, but Mr. Davis will not rely upon any such precaution. He knows that the Abolitionists are active and skilful, that they have e complex "underground" agency in the South, and that they will use every effort to make the negroes aware of the Washington manifesto, It will he impossible to prevent its coming to the knowledge of thousands of slaves. But we mistake the stern character of the Con

- federate authorities if they have not made preparations for

nling in the most terrible manner with the first Africans who c, may take advantage of Mr. Lincoln's verbal enfranchisement of the race. The Abolitionist may have cause to shudder at the pxample that will be made of those whom they have excited into an attempt to defy soldiers flushed, with four great victories over the North.
But, on consideration, we areinclined to retain our convictionwhich is, in all probability, Mr. Lincoln's (we hope so)-that if the slaves were to be moved by his documents they would have been moved much sooner. They showed no signs of insurrection, so far as we know, when their masters were weak; they now know that their masters axe strong and victorious, and it is improbable that the black man's inclination to rise will be increased by the news which he has been receiving for the last year. Still, there may be some slaves who may believe that their hour has come; and if there are, whether they are victors or vanquished, such things will be done as will make even the Abolitionists shudder. Regarded, therefore, at the very best-that is, as a. mere sacrifice to the petulance of a faction-this proolaaiationis contemptible; but if we look at it in another light, and believe that it is intended to do what the sword failed to, accomplish, we dare hardly trust ourselves

with expressions that would fittingly signify our sense of the

wickedness.

The New York 2l'lleune states that a telegram was recently

dispatched to the Federal army direotteg to whom the command of a brigade was to be totrueted, and that the operator at a telegraph station declared ths person selected to be Amjyedkewaaejew Deahrpoop.
THE ILLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS 7 77

)DT OF PARLIAMENT. to the tncompromfsing Pxotestathiem which flows elowlvlS g 6," but to " do good," to the fanaisbing, the destitute, and the solidjom their eteadicet opponent. It is taken for gi that a oted ; not forcing on the poor a sense of their " bitter dependpublic pursewhooc we know by the no= much at all that Mr. Newdegate says is rant 'whrit is not en ," or using them " os a kind of spiritual plate-powder to polish hequer there hangs a tradition that he cant, and tt his utterances are mere blindhesdefrmiiminatione up air smile ' ' withal, but dealing with them in a loving, tender, ou wbeao brow care cite brooding, d againet Bectoaiiem that is obnoxious to bi But one may lid spirit, as we are bound, by the meat solemn of commands, to/ I in recondite arithmetical calculatco s, venture to say tMjf doe attention be pat 4& him, he will be de, nth those whom we have "always with tie." Nothing can to reconcile icu anomalous juxbapeait u heard to pronounce ab*odne, well-worde*4nd well-rounded son- be e sloe then to laugh at a man of the world for loavin9'

H'T ybe imagined to be a hapless be g teocm, often based on asarch anc tauious with illustration for while the turmoil and bustle of society to di md oce waking thoughts are thv ad delivered with a ocolencholy o'seto wilish would be effective if into t a haunts of wretchedness and succour the forlorn ones of gre

and dread of financial critics, who a aft there was but one spark of five led with them; but, as it is, his cities, but this same world would become the dreariest of etonjpresentation of his annual balance e -s eet. speaking is a Iriod of smaoldpg, afr&Js tasted accordingly. Mr. hearts deserts if we did not all of us, from time to time , try o . age, pais with. a quenohless thirst of ld, , ewdegate, having last Sk discourseTh.4 hiBe eunty, has brought hand t such "district district visiting" as our vocations or our opp a'5 avaricious man who ic siways w flag this notice, such as itjs4pon which *s.il1 conclude bysaymg tunitis permit. Otherwise the rich men would sit, as Teriy 0 be a victim under the slow tort a of that all his repuMdh for dulnese and. .1. is not necessarily Taylor xpreesee it, " celibate like a fly in the heart of an apple, one)', with neither time nor thou t to desened.

 a to raise the wind to meat has lie flitS, of his lgwtOxford; but, having brought tobear suprsmel indifferent to mundane affairs, and quite as usel as

dwelling indssd, in perpetual sweetness, but eodned and dyin in )t_ Nor does this idea apply e to a Mr. Use has been again laboriously declaring th piest hoot singcilari ; " while your philosopher would be as superbly end

5 applieablo to one who has rose Gas in npoj.m last week, we will only express a hope that on thea)ess the jaded

Too is full his dioultios range big eat, for }fl0 hour his ecuetitusntefoflncaiprecatod. at the top of the steeple in Tinny Boursoe's poem:

avenue descends like a plenteous nd reHe ores that this greet roundabout,

Ly that most perplexing of questio s-what ' Church, army, pbysio, low, /

The uercd, with all its motley rose:

gthe Parliamentary vacation, ow fast as tcus, so far from playing the art of a ECHOES OF THE WEEK. its customs end its bes'oemss,

is ice concern at e21 of his, Be soul would siolcen as heartily s that of IT, is not often that people make us peouniery presents ; but happen- says-What And says he?-" CAW 'hag music of a street hand, and he seeks bag to be the other day in Paris with a Northern-American friend-is 'Th easy t croak "Caw " in the most classic al mau$u' ; but stinating his coming Budget, as seemed "Black Republican," peer sang-he made us a New-Year's gift of a " dth10t tin g " or "casual din" is a little more ecter of travelling repreeenta vs of the bank-note. It here neither the honoured signature of the cashiers of difficult, and be held of more account in the Great Au* eaeeed but the newspapers h s produced the Bank of Euglaudnor Francs bcot it was, nevertheless, a legitimate / odor of the Exchequer on'1 emetbing- public security, immediately convertible-in its native lend diets ilomacy, sooial statistics-is erything by ciclendcs-fer the amount stated on its face. We should have very "THE HOL FAMILY." GOBELINS TAPE STE ' AFTER .or than that eloquent t gas -should much liked to engrave this note for the ILLUSTRATE) Inemots Nxwe, RAPHL. RESENTED TO T SOUTH KUSINGTd MUSEUM

 pleased ears of rapt enese, he but, felling the burin, the pen must sane our torn. Imagine, then, BY TEE BOIl? icoit NAPOLEON III. ag like, the tsiak of Schshere de, and tout a diminutive parallelogram of--yellow, gritty paper two inches long, the semi-rustic oompreh sion, he tells portrait of George Washington, with the numeral "6," on either side taken every opp stunity to assure end reassure a per4ps tee sue-travelled in Sicily, and ow the simple and the initials "U.S." beneath. Within an elaborately- execoated picious British p lie of his sincere, ish to cement the )sagle-Frsneh mild uoagio, akin tot hat redcshty which border, the following inscription appeared:-" Postage ourrency. alliance. It s ho d not be forgotten that he did so before the volunfly cattle with the mutt d curses of a Furnished only by the assistanttreasurers and designated depoei- teer move mont, when almost every British British rsgimsst was sent out the good fairy Liberty ving taken pos- tense of the United States. Receivable for postage-stamps at any of this coontry to upprees the Indian mutiny. Thie, not the time nee, and superstition, a d credulity have post office." The back bore a larger medallion, with a fat i," or the place, hewe r, to estimate the political vain or Significance isople have become so ju cioue, and indeed rounded by twelve emallar ones. The value of this bank or govern- of the French Em re conduct, consistent thong it has always it even their idol Gorib dtwhen he makes mental postage nets was five cents, or twapence balfponny sterling, been. We have oni to draw the reader's attentic to the feet that induced to follow bin,, w en he only shines As we fingered the queer little coupon our thoughts reverted to the in the year of On great International Exhibiti the Emperor appy nation, when the events, inthe face revolutionary aeeignate current during the Reign of Terror, and Napoleon, with goes good taste, presented to the n 'nnal institution Teases on the year b two millions, and which were sold until recently, as curiosities, by the old men who which is charged to svelop artistic taste in our anufactcsres very Erchoquer, in sportiv mood, unbends his kept the pninteteil beneath the portooilhissd arch at the Bibliothbqne choice specimens of t n of the French imperial ofacturee which esantly telling pretty once to his country Impiiriale, in the Rue Richelieu. And then we recalled to mind the are acknowledged to b unrivalled-is beaiotiiul ex ple of Beauvais lour psnny and sixpenny notes which were issued in Austria in the tapestry, as applied t the decoration of chairs, and  the more im

am eruption of Mam are of Parliament all troublous days of '48, to say nothing of the innumerable portent specimen of Go e tapestry in on I a famous picture, week, but they ha been evoked by the plasters," "bogus, " end "wild-oat" notes emitted in the various which we have engrave ban of legislative duty, and a shape American crises, and our own tradesmen's tokens, one -pound notes. It may not be genera known that the ecleb toil outcry at 1.11t-tee is their o work, in the shape Likswfse did a certain Eussian roubls note present itself in cur Paris of tapestry end pets, known as th ' "Gcbslins," dates a at the recent a aster Seseiens. Not a memcrya note given us m change by an hctel-ksepe; and ee greasy, from the fourteenth oen At that early eriod dyers of wool i asteristica which spire the notes which or rotten, end so tattered that it woe ensconced in a pasteboard were estobliehed in the aubourg St. Mercel upon the Bilve, the e Sen prominent, ut there are gleanings frame for safety. After all, we thenght, "mency is money ;" and water of that stream be g favcurpbla for d eing. One of thorn, y, et one dwell f a moment on an sage- so long as the Federal Government forbears te apply the spengo to its Jean Gobellu, who lived 1480, wae parti  ar y successful, en

 rot on the part f Colonel Ncrth, who, ebligationo a pocket-book full of these little postage parallelograms is acquired oonsiderabla prep in the nacghb heed. His deeeendth 'repreeentati cf Oxfordahirs by the as valuable in degroo as a bundle of the cciapset "flyers" that Mv. ants continued his opeeislit with equal same , end, becoming in turn ala Mr. Henley, tends presminent as tho Ferraby or Mr. Gattie ever signed, or as a portemonnaie overflowing extremely rich, reined fr tbo trade, so e cf them afterwards oom c-of the my in the Houoa of Cern- th nareleoss ,f4 1 filling various offices in t Stats. To hem succeeded Messrs. Ar y generall a about as appreoiativa of .Ancthor reflection ocoorred to us as we contemplated the eleesy Canaye,,whc, not oundnin thenascives to dyeing wool, fabricated igus vantry o its behalf as was Dulcinea a lmowladgment of indebtednees. Paltry as was the amount of e tapestry for hangings, a nfacture un that period nonfined to tande poeeisn the Knight of La Menoha. n a, we recognised in its oxcoutisn a disploy of artistic skill end Flanders. The establishm eontinuing o prosper, Lcuia flY., at 11 on nseions f the devotion it inspires; cx cisc of mechanical ingenuity which we have sought for in vain the suggestion ef Colbert, termined convert it intc a Royal could robably be more amused than eym- the des of the lordly oatablishnrent in Threadneedils-etreet. e menufaotcry. In 1667 it had equtrod so nob importance .that tbs ion of Lirtot ant-General, who has been trnt is, as we have eaid over and over again, the English bank- ote celebrated painter Le Brent w appointo director. As Raphael had enter the y in 1822 (this is all the is as lain as A B C, whereas it should properly, be so elabor tely designed his cartsocs now at pton C ext for the tapestry-workers ie milit ry c ser), who is a Lieutenant- oxocu d as to defy the most aecomplishfdfurger. wnon the had of Flanders, so Ia Brun designe his fam "Battleo otAlexondor tho lets M tia, d who, in these days of free men- riffiths, Burnett, Bunchar, and Williamsreceived sent cc at Great," in the Louvre, as past s for menufactory. Tho celee, holds to e stock of the period when the Con ci Criminal Cuurt, Mr. Justice Blackburn tcok ccc ion to bratod oarpetnianufaitory now era to the Gubeiins wee mode a bslisve a hs has a right to assert that remark at Griffiths (who 11 doomed to penal servitude for e) was Royal establishment in 11104 by erie e Medieis, in favour of Pierre ems of my. And who arc the mere the only erton in England copablo ci fabnioating a bank-no so us in Dnpcnt, who invonisd the process or g the carpets, and who was may gal e y hint? Bat seen such poor enable it be passed into circulation and defy detection b ordinary alec placed at the heed ci this d ar ant as director, The carpets Ittcd to ' eo with him in the indignant observers; ut this, we think, proves much less that G ' the was ,. man,rfaotoredheresre coneidersd f' e ,eriortothe Persianfor Iheevenored the her day to the atiekin.p of gnne skilful eng ver then that no ordinarily competent pr soeer of a ness of their snrfaus and the ttnsaes d strength of their texture. The tin the C coin all sorts ci inappropriate noble and te ntkol art would condescend to torn ha g vor to the colours and designs are srtrornslyb iiful. flameoftheoarpststakcss thing but amcntal, and ao tnophiee are dirty work of orgeny. It cannot be denied that our esent bank- long as from five to ten years to b made, and coot turn dO,tlOOf. to can appn s te l'do elsqnent deoonipiiun of nets' is an av age sample of. writing-master's round- and, German 1611, OCOI.; and even at these hi prices the workmen ore very as sndd y ume upon the spoils torn from tort, and,fiouri ' g. and that the medallion designed v fIr. Maclisa, inadequately paid. The prcdac no of the Gebeline are ehiofly dee np e Highstreet of Little Pod- albeit excellent iii severe purity, is so realistic dGcrmancsqna destined forthe palaces of tue 610 none are sold, The Gobohus og bins so eat fuse the metal, which as to be ensceptr lo af imitation by the morsst tyr in delineation, work is called the leonte-lisse, to th warp being placed vertirally, in nlllise in tie pot end pan way instead of We would males as diifloult ta counterfeit a bank ate as to cock a contradistinction to the basss-Iiss do e at Beacvas, where the warp

iy stan ag onacs and insult. Theos, the sole '1 Is ,Norinon e, that nnlinany ciax of cocdsn f'lcin. is honisontal. In the tapeotry-w k, hich is celled f icon, the worktrmy, aving eon enunciated by Colonel A distinguished gb-Parisian hoe just fa d away, at the man stands at tho back ci the vas n which he is employed, with Guar - Scsoi us, were indorsed in a few patriarchal, age of ' sty. Moat students of t works of Oavarni the medol, behind him, to wino be o casionaliy refers, in order to y Mr Hanic ; and certain guns which will remeinbcr a skot by that inimitably chanac nistic droughteman, adjust the roiom of ins woollen r silk thread to that pert ci the ,the ounty, p bablybscauss no "Bowb" entitled " U/c ..cftigla tel a JesuIt! Pails dsp is Ia pitsa tIe .Paris picture hs to copying. The nbj ct of t procssa bseng to present as if th m, have csn doomod to ha in cold pa,' lea Aaglais." e don't know whoth the pcrirait, which smooth and eshoatc a surface possible, all cuttings and fastenings ilese some ben dent inarino-sture dealer represented an old gen amen in a spencer, tore, and a hs1h-dreod are performed at the back. T o visitor  tho Golehns manufactony

- h,,t +e ,ie,e,4,,+.ion oaeasetbroaah five ronmsflll with sptenoof rich tapee cad
TIED BATTLE-FIELD OF FEBDE1UOIESBUBG.

THE BATTLE OF FREDERICKSBURG. tog to Ilk. Itaxys, and are commonly called Maoye's lloigbto. At their base a At half-pact eight n.m. General Lose, accompanied by his foil Staff, rode load wiesde, promoted in one side by the hills and on the other by a solid atone slowly along the front of the Confederate linoe tram left to right, and tonic up To the account of this great battle, from a Federal point of view, wall, abortloor foot inhoight,ovor which a brigade of Confederates, themselves his station torn time beyond Hamilton's Crooning, and to rear of the batteries already given in. tine Journal, we add a description of it token from a perfectly sheltered, pureed the deadliest surd most effective of tine. A on the extreme Confederate right. It would be presumptuous in me to say Confederate etondpoint. The Southern correspondent of the lisoes little further book, to the south-snot at lOan us Heights, stands another one word in commendation of the serenity, or, if I may so express it, the send o from General Loe'e headquarters the following paxtiodilaxe of and higher hill, from which the most commanding view of the entire unconscious dignity of General Leo's courage whoa lie is under fire. No one field is attainable, and which, anti to the canal elation of the Commander-to- who sees and knowahia demeanour to ordinary life woald expect anythtog else the Battle of Fredmriokohorrg Chin?, is now known no General Lee's hill. From this hill during a large from one so calm, no undemonstrative, and unassuming. But the description The morning of the 11th of Dcnomher-a memorable day to the historian of poa'tlaco sO Satorctoy a 30-pounder Parroti gun, coot at the Tredrgor Works, applied otter the tattle at Alma to Lord Region by Marshal St. Arnaud, and the Decline and 11011 of the American Itopotlic-broke sitU and worm, while, in ltiohnimd, poured a destructive fire into too Fedorala. Suddenly, about In which, noticing Lord Raglan's unconsciousness under fire, he speaks of hi, as on the preceding day, a think haze enveloped the town of Fredoricbahnrg three in the at'erooon, antis thio-ty-sovonct discharge, this put burst with a "antique boaoisos," seems to mean applicable to General Lee that I cannot and the cbcomjsmnt valley, and delayed the opeolagol fire by the antogooiatio dreadful explosion, but happily did no injury to any ol the b otandore. At forbear recalling it here. At o subsequent pcvted of the day General Lee batteries until the sun had been up oaths thins or four hours. It was strange the moment of its explosion Captain Phillips, of the Gr,-oodier Guards assumed his notion on the hill which taken its name from him, and thence, in to contrast Saturday, the 11th of September, with Saturday, the 0th, and to (favourably remarked this day for his behaviour under fire), Major Vensbles company whb General Longatrmt, calmly watched the repulse of the repeated compare the intense, cold of the earlier Saturday with the spring-like warmth of General Let-'s Staff, and Major tfoeketl were eomwroiog within a foci feet Federal allortu agoteest the lseigbta on which be stood. Occasionally Genorsl and estnmmo of the later. The day which I sun describing was one of those of the gee. Their oocapowtrhaat injury was little lass than miraculous. As Jackson rode up to the spot and mingled in conversation with the ocher two outbursts of that Indian streamer which liagrra long and fondly in beautiful the Confederate tine trends away to the sight, the batteries of General heed's leading Generate. Once General Leagatreet exclaimed to him, "Are you not Virginia; the morning ham which slornodod heath, and plain, and forest, division were actively engaged against the advancing columns of FennsylFeared by that file of Yankees you have before you down there?" to which was the ordinary prelude to the warmth and glow of the sun at noonday. As venions; hot, next to the batteries on Macyen Heights and General Lees General Jackson replied, "Walt till they come a little nearer, and they shall the fog tilted about ten in the morning, and the sun burst through the clouds, hill, I should say that the artillery commanded by Colonel Walter took the either score me or I'll soon them. the long ham of the Federal army, which hod passed the whole preceding day most effective part in the action, m it peered a flanking are tools the The battle opened when the sun had let in enough light through the mist in deploying and preparing for the attack, were distinctly visible in the plain, anosey's loft. One other battery deserves davoorabte mention, which 10 to disclose the near proximity of the Federal lines and field batteries. The and gave awful indications of the amount of the Federal heat which had crossed obtained in the short and modest report of the battle which emanates first shot was fired shortly before ten a.m. from the batteries in the Federal too river. The Confederate army, wholly undaunted by the extravagant from the pen of General Lee. On the extreme right of the Cm- Centre, and o'os directed against General Heed's division. The Iennsylvoxtan stories about the strength of their fee, waited calmly, drawn Rio for the most federates, in front of the position escupled by General Stance's cavalry, Reserves advanced boldly onder a heavy fire against the Coofrderatcn, who part within the fringe of the weeds, confidant intlseirpositiun ooedin the valour a tesv ba)tortoo at Stoort'e Home Artillery were thrown fee ward, to flank the occupied one of the repeoaooed spurs, and were for a time permitted to held it, which low never failed them. And here it may be an well finally to dispel those Fodenalo, between Walter's Artillery nod the river. General Stuart ordered but presently the Confederate batteries opened oa them, and a determined Moslem under winds Ic is the custom a t the Northern pa-eon to veil she disgrace Major John Prihuss, his Chief of Artillery, to advance 000 pan considerably charge of the Texans drove the Yankees out of the wood in o confusion from of defeat, when the fact itself salmim of no dental. The whole number of towards the enemy, and to open upon him. Major Felbom obeyed, and opened which netting cupid subsequently rally them. Simultaneously a heavy firs Cenfoderatca in the field this day did not exceed from 19,000 to 90,000 man. the firs of s 12-posador Napoleon goon with great precision and deadly effort Issued from the batteries at General A. P. Hills and General Daily's 01 those, some 20,000 mass, taking the very highest estimate, took part in the into the Federal flank. The galling discharges of this gun quickly drew upon divisions, which was vigorously replied to by the Federal told bat. light. it the fin of three F,derst field batteries, while, tones acre so the river, two tories. The only advantage momentarily gained by the Federate do II is imperniblo far rue to describe the roeitloos of each of thu numerous other heavy batteries joined in the strife and made Major Fellosen and his gnu this quarter, and which Is noticed in General Lee's report, was on the Confederate batteries which stretched along the length of their six-nub lineal their target. For hours not less then, thinly Federal cartoon strove to silence occasion of the collapse of o regiment at North Carolina Conscripts, battle. It will suffice if I indicate the batteries which were most hotly Mojac Poths.m's papgsu, and alcove in vain. The unyielding and undersea- who broke and rue, but whose pines was rapidly taken by more intrepid sec. engaged, end born the brunt of the action. By far the most important Iwsltion strarivo Courage of Major Fasham, his composure under the deadliest fire, have monaco. The cannonading new became general along the entire line. Such a was occupied by tb's Washington Artillery, commanded by Colonel Walter of bog mode him conspicuous, but never were his noble qualities the subject of scene, at once terrific and sublime, mortal eye never rested on before, unless New Orleans, and pasted an the heights in the immediate oeigbbasachocml of more glowiasg eulogy than upon this occasion. General Los exclaimed, "1110 the bombardment of Sebootoical by the combined batteries of France end Fredericksburg, not more than 400 yards from the town. These loelgkte, inspiriting to we such gloriooi carnage too ane so young" (Major Fslbam to England revealed amore tearful manifestation ci the hate and fury of man. which arc precisely of that altitude which Is most favourable for the ploy of not more than twenty-two) General Jsuksou ramorkad, "With a Felbam The thundering, bellowing rear so hundreds of pieces of artillery, the bright artillery, are surmounted by o brink hones, now riddled by round shot, belong- upon either flock I could vanquish the world;" jets of Imoing flame-the screaming, hissing, whietling,shrieking projectiles
the wreathe of smoke, as shell after alien burst into the still air, the savage ca li of round ehot among the trees of the shattered forest, formed a scene likely to sink for ever into the memory of all who witnessed it, but utterly defying verbal delineation A direct and enfilacUog fire swept each battery upon either side as it was unmasked, volley replied to volley, crash succeeded crash, until the eye lost all power ref distinguishing the lines of combatants, and the whole plain teemed a lake of fire, a seething mass of molten lava, coerced over by incarnate fiends drunk with fury and revenge.


Twice the Federals, gallantly led and encouraged by their officers, dashed against the forces of General A. P. Bill and General Early, and twice they recoiled, broken and discomfited, and incapable of being again rallied to the fray. The eager Confederates drove them with horrid carnage a mile across the plain, and only desisted from the pursuit when they came under the fire of the Federal batteries across the river. Upon the extreme Confederate right General Stuarts Horse Artillery Pressed hotly upon the fugitives, and kept up a firs, subsequently understood to have been very effective, until after dark. Tjpon the Confederate right, where the antagonists fought upon more level terms, the equality of lose upon both sides was greater than on the Confederate left; but even here the Federal lose in officers end men far outnumbered that of their opponents. General liayard, the best cavalry officer in the Federal service, fell dead almost on the eve of the day which was to have witnessed his nuptials. General Jackson, of Pennsylvania, shared his fate. Many other general officers were carried to the Pederal rear grievously wounded; -whereas of the Confederates only one officer of rank-General Grogg-fell upon the right, and only one-General .Cobb__npoxi the left.


Meanwhile, the battle which lead dashed furiously against the lines of Generals Hood, A. P. 11111, and Early, was little more than child's play as compared with the onslaught directed by the Federals in the immediate neighbourhood of preericksburg. The impression that the Confederate batteries would not fire heavily upon the Federals advancing in this quarter, for fear of injuring the town of Fredericksburg, is believed to have prevailed among the Northern Generals. How bitterly they deceived themselves subsequent events served to show. To the Irish division, commanded by General lileagher, was

9rincipEaly committed the desperat-a task of- bursting out of the town of rederiulosburg and forming, under the withering lire of the Confederate batteries, to attack Marye's Heights, lowering immediately in their front. Never at Foutenoy, at Albuertt, or at Waterloo was more undoubted courage displayed by the sons of Drin than during these six frantic dashes which they directed against the almost linpreg liable position of their foe.

That any mortal men could have carried the position before which they were wantonly sacrificed defended as it eves, it seems to sue idle for a moment to believe; but the bodice which liii in. dense masses within forty yards of the muzzles of Colonel Walton's guns are the best evidence what manner of men they were who pressed an to death with the dauntlessness of a race which has gained glory on a thousand battlefields, and never inure richly deserved it than at the foot of Marye's Heights on the lath day of December, 1862.

An opportunity, of sending this letter, with an encouraging prospect of its reaching England, compels me to doer afurther account of the gallant defence on the Confederate left of the town, of Frederickksburg and of the battlefield until a subsequent letter.
AMRIOi.

]3y the steamer Europa we have journals from New Yo to the Gill inst., and telegrams vit Halifax to the 8th inst. WAR oriuwe.

The struggle before Mmlreeeboro', in Tennessee, ended-after a fiws

days' struggle and severe slaughter on both sides-in the retreat at
the Confederates, during the night of the 3rd inst., to Sullahoma,

thirty miles di,A ant, on the line of the Nashville and Chattanooga Railway. The Federal General Rosenoranz has oocupied Murfreesboro', but was not able to pursue General Brag's array, which retired in good order. The Federals acknowledge a loss of 1000 killed and 5500 wounded-of several thousand prisoners and 23 pieces of artillery. Generals Willich and Fry are among the prisoners. The Confederate loss is estimated at 4500 killed and wounded and 1000 prisoners. Twenty negro teamsters surprised in the rear of the Federal array by the Confederate cavafry, were immediately shot by their captors.

Five thousand Federal cavalry have made a raid from Kentucky

into Fast Tennessee, and destroyed nine miles of the East Tennessee and Virginia Railroad, near Knoxville, thus preventing reinforcements from Richmond reaching General Bragg.

]Despatches from General Grant to General Halleck report that General Sullivan defeated the Confederates under Genera]. Forrest, at Lexington, Tennessee, on the lot inst., capturing six cannons and many prisoners. The Confederate loss in killed and wounded is put down at 1400 men, and that of the Federals at 800.

General Sherman invested Vieksburg, in the Lower Mississippi,

with 40,000 men, Commodore Farragut's gun-boats co-operating. The fighting lasted five days, with varying success. The Federals fought their way to within two miles of the city, capturing three lines of works, when they were assailed by fresh forces under General Joe Johnston. After a hand-to-hand fight, the Federals were driven back to their first line of defence, with the loss of General Zetorgan and 3000 men. The Confederates have concentrated their forces from Jackson and Grenada at Vicksburg.

 The celebrated iron-clad Monitor, the first-born of Mr. Ericsson's

iflitaa'y genius, sprang a leak, while off Cape Hatteras, on the list., and sank. The Monitor was. being towed by the steamer Rhode Island, which succeeded in savng a portion of the officers and crew. Five officers and nineteen men belonging to the two vessels were lost. One theory of her loss is that the sea rushed down her turret,

At New Orleans General Banks had released 112 State prisoners sentenced by General Butler. Re had also issued an order permitting the clergy of New Orleans to resume their functions under certain restrictions.

A large proportion of the officers of the Kentucky regiments had sent in their resignations in consequence of the issue of Mr. Lincoln's latest proclamation. The volunteers from this State share the acntiments of their officers,

sonI,LA.'cEovs.

General Haileok has rescinded the order of General Qrau!i exoluiing all Jews from his department.

General Butler had arrived at Washingon, and dined with Mr. seward. He was also the object of a popular manifestation in his favour at the National Hotel.

The large hall of the Cooperlnatibute, NewYork, was crowded on the 5th inst. to its fullest capacity by an audience of white and coloured people of both sexes to celebrate the Emancipation Proclamation. Representatives of the European, African, and mulatto races occupied the platform. Speeches were made by the Rev. Dr. Cheever, Lewis Tappan, end the Rev. Mr. Donison of the white race; and by the Rev. H. H. Garnet, the Rev. 3.5. Raymond, Professor W. 3. Brown, the Rev. Mr. Kane, and other speakers of the African or mixed races.

The returns of the annual immigration at the port of New York show that the number of immigrants was 76,000, or 15,000 more than in 1861. The German immigration exceeded the Irish in 1862. That from England fellows third.

Owing chiefly to the astonishing and sudden development of the American grain trade with Europe, 1862 was a peculiarly favourable year to the interests of American railroads and canals. The New York canals, which only earned 900,000 dole, surplus revenues in 1868, paid over to the State which owns them 4,000 000 dols. in 1852. The principal lines of railroad have paid higher dividends than during the former years of peace. Some of them, as the New York and Erie, and Illinois Central railroads, which either never paid, or long since ceased to pay, dividends, commenced to pay them in 1362,

Geld has risen to 36 per cent premium.
GOVERNOR SEThOUre'S MESSAGE.

The message of the newly-elected Democratic Governor of the State of New York was delivered to the Legislature on the 11th. He says, when commenting on national affairs :

'The truths of the financial and military situation must not be kept bno

'There must be no attempt to put down free expression of public opinion.

 Affrighted. at the ruin they have wrought, the authors of our calamities, north end South, insist that it was caused by an unavoidable contest about slavery. This has been the subject, not the cause, of the controversy. We are to lookforthe causes of the warin the pervading disitgard of obligations of laws and constitutions, in disrespect for constituted authority; above all, in the local prejudices which have grown op in the two portions of the Atlantic States at the two extremes of our country. There is no honest statement of our dlcultIes 'which does not teach that our people must reform themselves as well as the conduct of the Government and the policy of our rulers. It is not too late to save the country if we will enter upon our sacred duty in a right spirit and in the right way. When we do, the effect will be soon felt throughout

the land and by the civilised world. We shrill then strengthen the Govern-ment, weaken the rebellion, and mitts our people; and the world will recognise our capacity for self-government when ve show that we are capable of selfreform.

The Governor condemns the exercise of martial power as destructive

of the rights of States and of the judicial and legislative powers of

the general Government. He declares the President's proclamation to be

Impolitic, unjust, end unconstitutional; calculated to raise many barriers to the restoration of the Union; likely to be misconstrued by the world as an abandonment of the hope of restoring ita result to which New York is nobly opposed, and -which will be effectually resisted. The Union will be restored by the Central and Western States, both free and slave, who are exempt from the violent passions which bear control at the extremes. Those central Slave States which rejected the ordinance of secession, -which sought to remain in the Union, and which were driven away by a contemptuous and uncompromising policy, moist be brought book. The National Constitution must be held inviolate, and the rights of States must be respected as not lees sacred. A consolidated Government -would destroy the horns rights and liberties of the people. The rnppreseion of journals and the imprisonment of persons have been glaringly partisan.

The Governor contends that though the seceded States may have

forfeited their right to appeal to the Constitution, not a single right

of the people of the loyal Stales can be suspended. He denies that

the civil war in the South takes away from the people of the loyal

North theenefita of one principle of civil liberty. He promises sup

tort to the armies in the field, and obedience to all the constitutional demnnds of the general Government. Under no circumstances can the division of the Union be conceded.
LONDON; SATURDAY, JANUARY 24,1883.

WHATEVER may be the strategic value of the recent operatione in America, there can be no doubt that they will have moral weight, and we could almost wish that the success of the Fedemle had been more marked, inasmuch as there might then be more hope of their being brought to relinquish a useless and hopeless war. It might be too much to expect that a high. spirited people, accustomed to vaunt its superiority over Creation generally, would be inclined to listen to any terms for pacification while four unmistakable defeats were unbalanced by any proof that the North could fight well. Though we believe that nearly altexcept professional politicians and others, whose profits lie in the continuance of the struggle, have ceased to speak of the reconstruction of the Union as one of the objects of the war, we have no right to blame the dogged obstinacy with which the Federals Insist on going on with it until they can find opportunity for a decorous "rest in the. accounts." Nobody likes to be completely defeated, and many a mass who has privately made up his mind that he is so will cling to his adversary, and struggle, and wrangle, rather than accept the situation. A small success will often serve him as an excuse for retiring, flushed and angry, and declaring that he should have gained the day but for a chain of accidents which took the strife out of the lists of fair play. We have no right to expect the Americana to rise superior to humannature ; nobody but themselves ever supposed them at each a moral alritude, and Englishmen have been ready to make every allowance for exacerbated and discomfited men. Bat this Murfressbcre' business, although we lack accurate details of it, has shown that the Federals, if decently led, can fight as well as their antagonists, and can almost gain a victory. The battle was protracted and sanguinary; but, 15t the Confederates make the very best of it, they had to abandon the field. The affair must count on the Federal side; and we repeat that we are Inclined to hope that this will he placed beyond dispute by the despatches, because mediation might then address itself to the victors with a good chance of being listened to with something
more than tolerance. We should like to be able to say to the North that it had at length vindicated its military character, and might now be expected. to show that it was governed by reason, and was prepared to abandon an attempt at impossible coercion.

We do not for a moment contend that the time has come for England to say this. Our Government may or may not be more inclined than heretofore to reconsider the situation, but it is impossible to say, just. now, what our Government thinks. Mr. Glalstone has said his say upon the American question, arid believes that the South is a nation; while his colleague, Mr. Miler Gibson, assures his constituents that the North is winning, because it occupies more territory than it did in the earlier stage of secession. We may hear a third voice, of more potency, in the course of the next three weeks; but, on -the whole, it would seem that the Premier does not believe that the time has come for any general European demonstration against the continuance of the war.

But we must call attention to another phase of the question. It is one which the journalist has watched for some time, and it is creditable to the reticence and discretion of the British press that no irritating use has been made of the facts. There can, however, be no object now in disguising the truth, whichis, that France has become an object of both dislike and apprehension on the part of the Federals. - It is not many months since such a state of things would have seemed impossible. It had ever been the habit with the Americans to speak of the French as the most advanced nation of the Old World, to heap adulation upon the wisdom of the Emperor Napoleon, and to profess a sort of belief that one day France and the Republic might, in union, direct the destinies of the world. It is nt now worth inquiring how far these sentiments were dictated by what Sir Philip Francis calls the only excuse for flatterynamely, the cd*uum tertii. Whether England was the third party who was so hateful that it was pleasant to flatter her supposed enemy, is now beside the question. The case was so, and the Emperor had a right to believe that his influence was very powerful in the North. It is gone, and the Emperor knows that it is gone, and does not trouble himself to disguise that knowledge. The journals of the North have for some time been full of taunts and sneers at the Tuileries, and these expressions of feeling have lately deepened into downright abuse, and even menace. The Emperor is told that heis 'fond out," and is warned that it is not for a despot (the discovery of whose despotism is curiously coincident with the establishment of another) to interfere with the will of a great and free nation. He is told that his attempt at drawing England into a joint mediation was an "insolence," and England herself is actually praised for having been too "deep ' for the Sphinx of Paris. He is further assured that, hou1d be presume to interfere further, and especially should he give the slightest sign of using other than moral force, he will be suddenly confronted by a tremendous coalition. As the constituents of this coalition might not be easily guessed, we had better say that it is to consist of Russia, England, !pain, and the Federals, and that it is to replace upon the hroae of France the house whose Princes fought so nobly for Republican institutions. We are simply reproducing the angvae of various Northern papers, and those who are unEortuuately obliged to peruse such publications will testify to

the accuracy of our statements. 0 - -
The Emperor of the French does not appear to be very much erdfied by this fearful programme, or, if he is, he con;lnues to practise the art of veiling his alarms. He continues 0 treat mediation as a thing to be attempted again as soon as )pportuuity shall serve; but, without insisting too much Ipon. this, he orders the publication of a documeht in rhich he distinctly enunciates his intention of opposing the force of France to what is not very properly called the Monroe loctrine. The despatch to General Forey is about as significant 1 document as need be, and it lays down as part of the Imperial )Olicy a resolve to repress Amrican ascendency in America.


as Sir Walter Scott says of another Louis of France, "he a just the man to give a lively colour to his avowal by follow. ag it up by an. execution.." The Mexican expedition, largely ein,fored, is going to work in thorough earnest; the apjtal. is to be seized at all cost; and perhaps the occupation f. Rome may be paralleled by an occupation of Mexico hat will "protect" the throne of the Incas against all corners, specially such as come from any part of the American Coninent. The gauntlet is fairly flung to all who cry "America or the Americans;" and it may be an additional reason lgaiust an. attempt to reconstitute the Union that the first step f the new State must in honour be an armed protest against ?rench action, or the swagger of twenty years is even more 'sin than it was believed to be.

In noting the history of the war, therefore, we may observe hat it has called into existence a new element of opposition to he extension of American "Empire;" arid, although at the resent moment this may not seem so important a fact as it is, he fact will be a very grave one when the time comes, as come t must, for settling by treaty the principle of the Partition of tmei'ica. Into how many portions the vast continent will be livided it is now impossible to say, but it is quite clear that ?ranee proposes to erect barriers against the unity of the con. inent.
And no the lax-famed Monitorhes gonetothe bad! But a fewinontho have gacced since the lnnrsrnsvsm Loanico Fairs contained an Engraving of the momentous fight in Hampton Roads, depicting both the Mcnimao send the Monitor-the ironclad that destroyed a Soot, and the ironclad that saved one. And now, of the two monsters of the deep-the Federal and Confederate Kilkenny onto-not so much


as a tail, by way of vestige, remains. The Mornmao, indeed, com-mitted suicide; but the Monitor was the victim of sudden death. An

aqueous apoplexy overtook her off Cape Hatteras; she sprang a leak; pumps were in vein; she became waterlog'S, and wont down like a stone. We ore reminded of the warrior &d in Milan steel, who, as Onicoisrdiai tells no, in me of the Italian civil were of tim middle ages, was irgulfed, horse, iron panoply and all, by moro force of recitation, in a morose, and was the only man killed in the particular battle in question. 'floors was an English Earl of Saudwioh, too, Admiral and General at Sea, who, venturing in a small boat during a naval engagement, was drowned by the weight of his armour,

Old tars of the Benbose ochool, nay, old landomon, asnatoors of

Dibdin'o songs, and believers in the solo efficacy of wooden walls, will donhtlnoo rub their hands and chuckle at the catastrophes which have overtaken the two model ironolade of America. The


that-irons," the "hogs in armour," have certainly come to oigna'I grief. Ay, but they were net oonotrnctodsnthoRues of the Worrier or the, moire; and if the Aunrrican wise ones of Goth an well go tn sea in a bowl covered with railway iron, they must oxpoot doo.gorons oquolls. Once upon a time, we saw the into Mr. Tom Barry, clown at Actloy'e, heating on the bosom of the Thomas in a woohfxg-tub drown by trw geese; but the pantomimic navigator would ccnrcoly have ventured upon a trip to the Bay of Biscay in his eccentric craft. After all, the essence of naval construction in metal is in its infancy, and will be liable to error end sniolsap for come time to came. A gentleman calling upon Bean Brssminoll one moming met his valet coming down stairs with an armful]. of crumpled white neebrlotlss, 11 These are one failures, Sir," the gentleman's gentleman explained, when interrogated. The Bean bed only opsilt a couple of doom cravats bolero he found one to suit loin. In like meaner armour-plating re novol arolsitenturo must, we euppcee, have its "failures" before before the golden mean, or the iron Due, as found.
THE AME1tICA1'T PHILOSOPHICAL SOCIBTY.-The suit of the

city of Philadelphia against this corporation, claiming to tar the ball, baa been decided in favour of the society. Our readers will be Interested in reading the concluding lines of the judgment given by Judge Read:-11 The first president of this society was the originator of the first fire company, the first

fiblic library, the first hospital; and the first academy, now the University of crinsylvania; a signer of e,Iw Declaration of Independence, Minister to France, one of our Mlnsetrrs Plenipotentiary who signed the provisional articles and the definitive Treaty of Peace between the United States and Great Britain; and, finally, one of the framers of the Constitution of the Tufted States. This was Dr. Benjamin Franklin, the patriot and the phhloeophcr; and I cannot but express a confident hope that the city and the state of which he was so distinguished an ornament will never permit the hands of the targatherer to diminish the fund devoted to the interests of science In every part of the world, both in peace and in war, and belonging to a society of which be was the founder."
