<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI.2//EN" "iln.dtd"
[<!ENTITY % iln-entities SYSTEM
"/Beck-files/ILN/ILNCVS/ilnxml/iln_entities">
 %iln-entities; ]>

<TEI.2>
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated London News
Perspective</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Compiled and edited by</resp>
               <name>Sandra Still</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent/>         
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Emory University</pubPlace>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine>
            </address>
            <availability>
               <p>2005 Emory University.
Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce,
distribute or display the contributions to the work claimed by Emory
University for non-profit educational purposes, provided this header
is included in its entirety.  For inquiries about commercial uses,
contact the Lewis H. Beck Center, Woodruff Library, Emory University,
Atlanta, Georgia 30322</p>
            </availability>
            <date>2005</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated
London News Perspective</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
               <biblScope type="volume">Volume 47</biblScope> 
 <date>July to December 1865</date>
</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p/>
         </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	<change><date>November-December 2005</date>
          <respStmt><name>Robin Conner, </name><resp>Beck Center Staff.</resp></respStmt>
          <item>Encoded text according to TEI guidelines.</item>
	</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div1 id="iln47.001" n="Illustrated London News: Volume 47" type="Volume"> 
            <head>Illustrated London News: Volume 47</head>
<docDate>July to December 1865</docDate>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence:
      United States." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE:
      UNITED STATES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 2</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">UNITED STATES.</p>
<p>The blockade of all United States ports, including Galveston, has
been raised, and they are now open to foreign commerce.</p>
<p>Mr. Seward has announced that, in consequence of England not
absolutely withdrawing the twenty-four hours' rule, the Federal
vessels will not pay the customary courtesies to vessels of the
British Navy. The Federal Government also refuses to recognise any
transfer of rebel cruisers, and claims the right to capture them under
whatever flag they may be placed.</p>
<p>President Johnson has appointed Andrew Hamilton of Texas, James
Johnson of Georgia, and Louis B. Parsons of Alabama, provisional
Governors of those States, in accordance with the programme adopted in
North Carolina and Mississippi.</p>
<p>Immense numbers of negroes, past work, have been expelled from the
cities of Georgia. Great mortality prevails among the negroes in
Charleston.</p>
<p>Provisional Governor Holden, of North Carolina, has issued a
proclamation calling for a Convention to amend the State Constitution,
to elect a Governor and Legislature, and to restore the complete rule
of civil law in that State. The Governor exhorts the people to become
loyal, good, and useful citizens. He officially announces to the
coloured people their freedom, and hopes they will become industrious,
as otherwise their race cannot escape extinction. He promises to be
their friend if they do right, but declares that he will aid in
inflicting prompt punishment upon the idle and vicious.</p>
<p>The message of the Governor to the Virginia Legislature urges the
avoidance of all legislation calculated unnecessarily to irritate she
people. He recommends fewer restrictions in the regulation of the
white elective franchise. As neither himself nor the Legislature has
the control of the negro suffrage, they will not deliberate on that
question. An extra Session of the Virginia Legislature was convened on
the 19th ult., at Richmond.</p>
<p>The Governor of Tennessee has ordered the election of a full
Congressional delegation.</p>
<p>Orders have been issued to dismantle the defensive works around
Washington, except twenty-two forts and three batteries, which will be
strengthened and permanently garrisoned.</p>
<p>The Government had ordered a further reduction of the army by
50,000 men.</p>
<p>The 25 per cent restriction duty on cotton west of the Mississippi
had been removed.</p>
<p>The country is now divided into five grand military divisions--the
Atlantic, under General Meade; the Mississippi, under Sherman; the
Tennessee, under General Thomas; the South-west, under General
Sheridan; and the Pacific, under General Halleck.</p>
<p>The grand jury of San Francisco has dismissed the complaint against
the parties charged with organising an expedition to Mexico.</p>
<p>Mr. Breckenridge and six others reached Cuba, on the 11th ult.,
from the Florida coast. They crossed in an open boat.</p>
<p>Mrs. Lincoln has taken up her residence, for the summer, at Hyde
Park, six miles from Chicago.</p>
<p>Mrs. Seward, wife of Secretary Seward, has died of bilious fever,
at Washington.</p>
<p>A delegation of Poles has had an interview with President
Johnson. They say that 20,000 expatriated Poles desire to emigrate to
America. Efforts are being made to get them to settle in Virginia.</p>
<p>The reading of the argument for the defence, in the conspiracy
trials, was continued before the military court in Washington on the
21st ult. Mr. Doster, counsel for Payne and Atzerott, admitted the
guilt of Payne, but urged the Court to consider how far his punishment
should be mitigated on account of his manifest conviction that he was
doing right in attempting to kill Mr. Seward. Payne had, by reason of
his Southern education, his participation at a tender age in war, and
by his residence in districts wherein the Federal troops had caused
great devastation and suffering, become a deadly enemy to the
North. He had erroneously regarded Mr. Lincoln as a tyrant and
usurper, and Mr. Seward as a mortal enemy to the South and her
institutions, and he therefore believed himself right in attempting
his life. The accused was, in his guilt, only a consequence of the
evil teachings of slaveholders, and was no hired tool, but a fanatic,
an enthusiast, and a hero. Apart from his crime, which he (Mr. Doster)
abhorred, he saw much in Payne's character to admire. Mr. Doster
strongly urged the Court to consider the extenuating circumstances of
the case before pronouncing sentence, although the prisoner desired to
die, in the fanatical belief that, by suffering execution, he would
gain a crown of martyrdom.</p>
<p>In behalf of Atzerott, Mr. Doster claimed that the prisoner had,
although at first he considered Booth's propositions, finally shrank
from participation in their execution, merely maintaining an
appearance of co-operation therein to escape Booth's indignation.</p>
<p>An additional argument was read by Mr. Aiken in behalf of
Mrs. Surratt, and the Court adjourned. In consequence of her serious
illness, Mrs. Surratt has been removed from her cell to more
comfortable quarters in the penitentiary.</p>
<p>Mr. Reverdy Johnson has submitted an argument denying the
jurisdiction of the military court for the conspiracy
trial.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.002" n= "Havannah advices announce" type="Article">
<head>[HAVANNAH ADVICES ANNOUNCE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 3</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Havannah advices announce the arrival of General John
C. Breckenridge in Cuba, after an adventurous voyage, in company with
six other persons, in an open boat, from the coast of Florida. The
persons accompanying General Breckenridge were Colonel Wilson, an aid
to Jefferson Davis, Captain Taylor Hood, formerly commander of the
Tallahassee; Corporal Russell, two Confederate private soldiers, and a
slave of Breckenridge's who refused to leave his master. General
Breckenridge and Colonel Wilson were within forty miles of Mr. Davis
when he was captured, and Captain Hood was actually with him, but
succeeded in making his escape, and on the following day joined
General Breckenridge, and the party at once started rapidly towards
the coast. Crossing Georgia into Florida they descended the St. John's
River in a boat to Jupiter's Inlet, where they met a party of Federal
deserters, from whom they secured a better boat, which they hauled
across the country to an inlet of the sea. After performing Divine
worship the little party launched their boat. They had a narrow escape
from capture on the first day of their voyage. They had beached their
boat on a sand-reef, some sixty miles from their point of departure,
in order to hunt shellfish, which, with Indian corn, constituted their
sole food on the voyage. A Federal steam-transport came in sight, and
a boat put off towards the reef. Captain Hood and the two privates met
the boat, some distance from the reef, and succeeded in convincing the
officer in charge that the party consisted of paroled soldiers, who
were looking down the coast for old wrecks, and they were left
unmolested. After a voyage of three, or, according to some accounts,
eight days, involving great exposure and privation, they reached
Cardenas, on June 11. They were very kindly received by the people,
and the authorities furnished them transportation to Havannah. Colonel
Helm, formerly United States Consul at Havannah, presented
Breckenridge to the Captain-General of the island, who received him
with cordial hospitality and great courtesy, and is said to have
assured him of a safe asylum in the island.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.003" n= "Imperial Parliament." type="Article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 10</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF LORDS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Monday.</hi></p>
<p>Lord Brougham, referring to comments which had been made with
regard to his views on the subject of slavery, denied that he had ever
been favourable to the slaveowners of the Southern States of
America....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.004" n= "On the 16th of June" type="Article">
<head>[ON THE 16TH OF JUNE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 11</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>On the 16th of June a stone monument, 27 ft. high, was erected,
with due ceremonial, on a crest a little south of Henry-house, "in
memory of the patriots who fell at Bull Run, July 21, 1861." The spot
selected is where Heintzelman's division made their hardest fight, but
were finally driven back by Kirby Smith. A considerable force of
troops was on the ground, and a large company of civilians; proper
religious exercises were gone through, some addresses delivered, and
then a salute was fired by Captain Smith's Massachusetts battery on
the same spot where Rickett's battery was captured. The battle-field
itself presents few evidences of the engagement. Here and there a
mound indicates a grave, but they are not numerous; and the only relic
found was an old musket barrel.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.005" n= "The Island of Sombrero." type="Article">
<head>THE ISLAND OF SOMBRERO.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 17-18</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">THE</hi><lb/>ISLAND OF
SOMBRERO.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Our</hi> Engraving represents one of the
Leeward Islands, in the Caribbean Sea, containing the richest natural
deposit of phosphate of lime at present known. The island was first
visited by an English gentleman about the year 1814, and again by him
in 1825, on which latter occasion a report was made to the British
Government, but did not meet with that consideration which subsequent
events prove it to have deserved. In 1856 the Americans took
possession of the island, and in the course of a very short time
exported to the extent of 100,000 tons of this valuable fertiliser, to
resuscitate the exhausted lands of the Southern States. Subsequently
their proceedings attracted the attention of a British surveying
expedition, at that time engaged in the West Indies, as may be learned
from a communication to the Royal Agricultural Society<pb n="18"/> of
England, by Sir Roderick Murchison, who, in describing the geological
structure of the island, says:--"I have often regretted that I have
never had it in my power to communicate anything of importance to the
British farmer; I am now, however, enabled to make an announcement
which will, I have no doubt, be as acceptable to agriculturalists as
it is likely to become very valuable to the merchant and shipowner."
It appears that the Americans have already quarried away a
considerable part of the island, and sold the substance in New
York. This transaction led to an official correspondence between the
British and American Governments, and eventually the right of the
British Crown to the possession of this valuable deposit was
acknowledged by the United States Government. Sir Roderick Murchison
considers our holding the Island of Sombrero to be of great national
importance, in providing our agriculturists, from a British
possession, with a plentiful supply of a good substitute for the guano
of Peru.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.006" n= "Willie Pape" type="Article">
<head>[WILLIE PAPE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 18</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Willie Pape, the celebrated young American pianist, gave a
"pianoforte recital" at the Hanover-square Rooms, on Friday evening,
the 23rd of June, which was under the special patronage of their Royal
Highnesses the Prince and Princess of Wales, and was attended by a
crowded and brilliant assemblage. The programme included Liszt's
"Grand Paraphrase on Verdi's Jerusalem," Beethoven's Grand Sonata
op. 31, Weber's "Motp Perpetuo," Mendelssohn's "Introduction and
Fugue," Thalberg's fantasia "The Last Rose of Summer," Benedict's
"Where the bee sucks," and several compositions by Master Pape
himself. The whole performances were most warmly and justly
applauded. Willie Pape has been engaged to give a series of pianoforte
recitals at the Dublin Exhibition.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.007" n= "The Theatres." type="Article">
<head>THE THEATRES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 19</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">THE THEATRES.</hi></p>
<p>....On Monday the new actor from America appeared at the New
Adelphi, in an American play and an American character. Mr. Owens
then, for the first time, presented himself before the British public,
and produced a new drama, entitled "Solon Shingle." The hero is an
American farmer who, in paying a visit to an American village, makes
himself at home wherever he is, and practises a familiarity so free
and easy that he scarcely recognizes any distinction between <hi
rend="italic">meum</hi> and <hi rend="italic">tuum.</hi> The
nonchalance and provincialism of the character are very striking and
novel; the make-up is admirable. The old man toddles about, and
interferes in every thing, intruding himself into a merchant's store
at a late hour in the evening, and even into the Court of Justice,
standing up as a witness in a cause with which he had nothing to
do. In these different situations he spins a variety of yarns, in
which the most is made of nothing, the peculiarities of character
being brought out by minute details, which have no importance but as
they illustrate an individuality. Altogether, this is a remarkable
performance, and may make a sensation....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.008" n= "A 'Shoddy' Millionaire at New York." type="Article">
<head>A 'SHODDY' MILLIONAIRE AT NEW YORK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 19</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">A "Shoddy" Millionaire At New York</hi>.--One
day, when Tommy was "doing" New York, he strode into Tiffany's
magnificent jewellery establishment, on Broadway, and startled the
assembled salesmen with a loud "Show us a diamond!""Here is one, Sir,"
responded an elegantly modulated voice from the "diamond department."
"Eighty dollars, Sir." "Pooh! not such a speck as that; something
bigger." "Allow me to show you this; very pure stone, Sir, 160 dols."
"Nonsense, bigger!" Herewith the gentlemanly salesman (who I have
always suspected to be a noble Lord in difficulties) produced the
brilliant of about the size of a small pea. "Exquisite stone, Sir;
first water, 800." "Look here!" cried Tommy, becoming exasperated, "If
you've got a reg'lar diamond, fetch it out; if you haven't, just say
so." My Lord, half amused, half vexed, here, by way of totally
annihilating his rough customer, brought out the Koh-i-noor of the
place. "Will this suit you, Sir? Moderately fine stone; price, 15,000
dols." "Now you're coming to it!" cried Tommy, decidedly
mollified. "Is this the tip-top biggest?" "It is, Sir," replied his
Lordship, coolly (stroking his beard at the same time, as if to say,
"Now, my rustic friend, I have wasted quite time enough upon you, you
may go.") "You ain't got nothin' bigger, now?" "Nothing, I assure
you." "Then I'll take it." M'Lord, I grieve to say, lost his presence
of mind, and stared; but Thomas at once produced a huge roll of
"greenbacks," counted out the money, and the sale was concluded. This,
as I have been told, occurred more than a year ago. Now, my Lord,
having become somewhat familiar with the ways and means of Shoddy,
would scarcely lift his eyelids were his coalheaver to propose to buy
out the entire concern.--<hi rend="italic">Cornhill Magazine</hi> for
July.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.009" n= "The Queen has approved" type="Article">
<head>[THE QUEEN HAS APPROVED]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 19</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The Queen has approved of Mr. George T. Morehouse as Consul at
St. John's, Canada, for the United States of America.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.010" n= "Sixteen years ago" type="Article">
<head>[SIXTEEN YEARS AGO]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 22</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Sixteen years ago San Francisco was a petty hamlet, lying on the
sandy slope that curved its yellow crescent behind Clarke's Point. A
few whalers and United States men-of-war had touched there at long
intervals and an occsional merchant vessel had taken aboard a cargo of
hides and tallow. The interior was a <hi rend="italic">terra
incognita</hi> to all except its simple natives and the few travellers
and emigrants who had partly explored it. In one year after the
discovery of gold had become universally known San Francisco had a
population of about 30,000, and its harbour was filled with ships from
every quarter of the world. Ten years later its population had more
than doubled; and five years later it had nearly doubled again, being
hard on to 120,000.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1323.011" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1323</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 27</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-08">July 8, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....We may add that the <hi rend="italic">Westminster</hi> also
unearths a new American novelist, a Theodore Winthrop, one who fell as
a private volunteer in the early part of the war and left several
novels, many times rejected, which, having been since published, turn
out to be works of real genius. It is the old story of discovering
merit when it is too late to reward it!</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1324.001" n= "Reconstruction, British and American." type="Article">
<head>RECONSTRUCTION, BRITISH AND AMERICAN.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1324</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 29</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-15">July 15, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">RECONSTRUCTION, BRITISH AND<lb/>AMERICAN.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">A Great</hi> work of political reconstruction
is in mid progress in the United Kingdom. We are not, indeed,
refashioning our Constitution. The three estates of the realm, their
proper sphere and limits of action, their mutual duties and
responsibilities, remain what they have been, and are unchallenged by
public opinion. We are meddling with none of our great national
institutions. We are shifting nothing of importance from its ancient
basis. Nevertheless, we have been engaged throughout the week now
closing, and we shall be more or less generally engaged for the next
fortnight, in building up again that part of the machinery of
government which, because it bears the chief stress of legislation and
has a predominant influence on its character and results, is wisely
submitted to periodical renovation with a view to adapt it to such
change as may have passed upon the public mind. The Crown, acting in
conformity with law, has dissolved one House of Commons, and the
country is busy in putting together another. Strictly speaking, the
work is one of reconstruction, but reconstruction in an extremely
limited sense.</p>
<p>In the very thick of the turmoil inevitably occasioned by a general
election there is ground for satisfaction in the knowledge that the
process is attended with no danger. The legislative mechanism which on
Monday morning last was nonexistent, and which even yet is but half
refitted, will be framed on the same model, with two or three trifling
exceptions, as that which has served the use of the present
generation. Such alterations as are now being made will affect merely
the materials of which it is composed. The leading wheels and
principal levers in the machine will, for the most part, be replaced
from the old one. They will, no doubt, be cleansed of some of the
deposit which during six years' work has accumulated about them, and
which had helped somewhat to clog their movements. Friction against
the great outside public will, perhaps, rub away some soil and rust,
and fit them for accelerated action. But no great change is desired or
will be effected as regards them. In conjunction, however, with these
more important parts, there are a considerable number and variety of
minor pieces, all having something to do towards the general result,
and each susceptible, in doing it, of improvement or decay. It is here
that the chief alterations are to be expected. Old and untrustworthy
appliances, or, what in effect amounts to the same thing, those which
are thought to be such, will be cast aside for new and more promising
material. That which is suffered to remain will in many cases be
passed through the fire, hammered into more convenient forms, polished
and lubricated, and, refitted to its former place. There will be a
deal of scouring and cleaning, the substitution of not a little that
is untried for that which after trial is found wanting, and, it is to
be hoped, a general improvement of the machinery in regard to the
parts of which it is composed; but that will be the whole amount of
positive change accomplished or sought. There is nothing in all this
calculated to unsettle public confidence, nothing to excite misgivings
as to the future, no empiricism of which the most timid need to be
afraid.</p>
<p>Of course, we do not mean to imply that change even to this extent
may not or will not involve some change in the action of
Parliament. We shall not assume to judge what may be the character of
the future House of Commons, or what will be the drift of its
policy. Only events will bring either the one or the other fully into
light, But we do regard it as matter of satisfaction that, on the
whole, the process which is being now resorted to will tend rather to
abridge than to widen the distance between the legislatorial power and
the settled convictions<pb n="30"/> and will of the country. Whatever
these latter may prove to be, after the criticism, the siftings, and
the verdict of a general election, they may be embodied in law without
imperilling anything which commends itself to sound sense and just
feeling, and almost as certainly without producing so much as a jar
upon the nervous system of the community. We may anticipate just so
much expansion in the aims and proceedings of the Government as will
be rendered necessary by any expansion which has taken place in the
thoughts and wishes of the public. That is all; and that is an issue
to which every intelligent and well-trained mind will be content to
submit. So that, as far as the United Kingdom is concerned,
reconstruction is but a renovation of means and apparatus, with growth
as the result. The process is far from unimportant. Upon those who
conduct it rests a grave responsibility, but, at least, it is
unaccompanied by serious apprehensions for the future.</p>
<p>Our kinsmen on the other side of the Atlantic are also intent just
now upon the business of reconstruction--but under what different
circumstances and on how much wider a scale! Let it not be supposed
that we allude to the contrast for the sake of self-glorification--we
do so merely, with a view to deepen our own sense of
thankfulness. That they have to face and master, as we can hardly
doubt they will do, a much more searching and difficult problem than
ourselves, cannot be attributed to the superiority of our
qualifications, or of our mode of using them, in any respect. Our good
fortune is, that we long since passed through that stage of national
discipline which they have but just reached, and our hope is that they
will get through it without more permanent suffering than we. Still,
as a simple matter of fact, the processes which are at this moment
operative in the two countries differ so widely the one from the other
in depth, intensity, and duration, that one cannot help viewing then
side by side. The reconstructive work now absorbing the energies of
American statesmanship is not only difficult, but it touches close
upon several dangerous issues. Whereas, in our own case, the past, and
especially, the proximate past, is our mainstay, it is in theirs the
source of disquietude. They have to reconstitute the South, not merely
of new materials, bu after a new model. They have to lay again the
very foundations of society. The civil war has broken up the
pre-existing social system, and has pretty well levelled to the dust
the political edifice. It would seem impracticable to reconstruct the
latter in conformity with the provision of law, and, happily, as we
think, impossible, as well as impolitic, to base society on the
maintenance or rather the restoration of slavery. The consequence is
an immense amount of present confusion, collision, and misery--the
inevitable <hi rend="italic">d&#x00E9;bris</hi> of an armed conflict
on so gigantic a scale. Some time will be required before the dust and
smoke have sufficiently cleared away to allow of a definite plan being
adopted and brought into operation. Much suffering will, doubtless, be
endured meanwhile; but our Transatlantic cousins are not deficient in
a talent for organisation. We believe they will work out the questions
before them in much less time, and much more satisfactorily, than has
been generally expected, and that the social difficulty will, after
its first pressure, yield to the appliances which robust common-sense
will bring to bear upon it.</p>
<p>The contrast between the two countries at the present moment
suggests matter for profitable consideration. A theory has been
advanced by some, that no great nation can fully develop its
capabilities until it has passed through the ordeal of a civil war,
and that, in the course of its history, one such convulsive intestine
struggle is inevitable. We shall not discuss this theory, neither can
we assent to it. It may be true of certain stages of civilisation, but
we question whether it can be predicated as a law applicable to
nations which are, or will hereafter be, the growth of offshoots from
a population already educated and trained in the principles and
practice of self-government. Be this, however, as it may, every fresh
instance presented to us by history of the attainment of political and
social results by violent means makes us doubt whether the process be
not more costly than the end will repay, and whether the mischief done
by it be not so great that the time, the anxiety, the exertion, and
the self-sacrifice required for the work of reparation might not have
sufficed, if employed in conformity with law, to accomplish, within a
given period, all that may have been achieved by the sword, and
without anything like the attendant suffering. The upward and onward
destinies of a people are seldom, if ever, permanently hastened by
force. They are the result of moral culture, and in very few and
exceptional instances is moral culture quickened by the destruction of
property or the effusion of blood. The reconstruction rendered
necessary by mortal conflicts is always difficult, often
disappointing, and sometimes slower in arriving at its
consummation--namely, the settlement of the vital question in
dispute--than the patient use of milder methods would have been. We
may well be thankful that the business on which our fellow-countrymen
are now engaged is one which less than a month will be required to
effect, and which, when effected, will place the country a step in
advance; and we may sincerely sympathise with our American cousins
that their work does not more closely resemble ours in the ease and
certainty with which it may be dispatched. To bind up and heal deep
wounds is a serious affair--to wash and be refreshed is but a trifling
demand on exertion. Such, however, is the difference between what they
and we are engaged in doing at the present time.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1324.002" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence:
      America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE:
      AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1324</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 30</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-15">July 15, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>Telegrams from New York, to the 1st inst., state that the
conspiracy trial in Washington has been concluded. The Military
Commission has agreed upon the verdict, but it will not be made public
until after it has been either approved or rejected by the
President. The Judge-Advocate previously submitted an argument
asserting that four of the prisoners were fellow-conspirators with
Booth. He contended that the evidence showed that Davis, Sanders,
Tucker, and others, planned and assisted the assassination.</p>
<p>Owing to too close application to his duties, President Johnson has
been indisposed for several days past and unable to take part in
Cabinet meetings.</p>
<p>Colonel Mosby, the celebrated Confederate cavalry raider, has been
pardoned by the President, and has commenced practising law at
Culpepper, Virginia.</p>
<p>A deputation from South Carolina has had an interview with
President Johnson to request the appointment of a civil
governor. Johnson replied that no State would go out of the Union. He
must deal with restoration, not reconstruction. The people of South
Carolina could not be admitted to Congressional representation until
they called a convention and adopted the Federal and State
Constitutional Amendment abolishing slavery. He thought if negro
suffrage were now granted employers would control negro suffrage to
the detriment of the poor whites. He would, after consultation with
his Cabinet, consider the appointment of a governor.</p>
<p>President Johnson has ordered the military authorities at
Charleston not to prohibit political assemblages of coloured
people.</p>
<p>General Terry has issued an order at Richmond that the negroes will
enjoy the same personal liberty and be subject to the same restraints
as whites.</p>
<p>The Virginia Legislature has adjourned, after extending the
franchise to those excluded by the Alexandria Constitution.</p>
<p>There have been serious affrays between the Federal soldiers and
the blacks at several places. At Norfolk the troops, aided by the
white inhabitants, had driven the negroes from the town. At Charleston
there had been a fight between the white and black soldiers, and
several were wounded on each side, At Savannah a New York regiment had
mutinied, and refused to do duty with the black troops; forty-three of
the mutineers had been apprehended, and imprisoned in Fort Pulaski. A
serious affray took place at Portsmouth, Virginia, between the white
and coloured people. Many persons were wounded.</p>
<p>General Herron, commanding in Northern Louisiana, has forbidden the
slaves to leave the plantations.</p>
<p>The Governor of Kentucky has addressed the people, declaring
slavery to be dead and urging the adoption of the constitutional
amendment.</p>
<p>General Hooker has superseded General Dix.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1324.003" n= "It is estimated" type="Article">
<head>[IT IS ESTIMATED]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1324</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 47</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-15">July 15, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>It is estimated that upwards of 9000 steam-engines, for oil wells
and other purposes, have passed over the Atlantic and Great Western
Railroad into Pennsylvania "Oildom."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1324.004" n= "Ruins of the Carbine Factory and Railway
      Station at Richmond." type="Article">
<head>RUINS OF THE CARBINE FACTORY AND RAILWAY
      STATION AT RICHMOND.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1324</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 48</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-15">July 15, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">RUINS OF THE CARBINE FACTORY AND RAILWAY<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">Station At Richmond.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> scenes of havoc and ruin in the city
of Richmond after the great conflagration which ensued upon the
retirement of the Confederate army and Government, in the first week
of April, have already been made the subjects of some of our
Illustrations. We present in this Number a view of the ruins of the
building which had been occupied as a carbine factory by the military
department of the Administration, Richmond being a place where large
quantities of arms and ammunition were manufactured during the
war. Our second Engraving gives a view of the ruins of the buildings
of the Richmond and Petersburg Railway, which here crosses the James
River by a bridge already described. Some further Illustrations of
this subject, as well as of the flight of the Confederate President
into Georgia, will be published on a future occasion.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1324.005" n="Richmond, Virginia: Ruins of the Carbine
      Factory.; Ruins of the Railway Bridge." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1324</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 48</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-15">July 15, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v47p48a">
<head>RICHMOND, VIRGINIA: RUINS OF THE CARBINE
      FACTORY.; RUINS OF THE RAILWAY BRIDGE.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1324.006" n= "The Monuments on the Battle-Field of
      Bull Run." type="Article">
<head>THE MONUMENTS ON THE BATTLE-FIELD OF BULL RUN.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1324</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 48</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-15">July 15, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE MONUMENTS ON THE BATTLE-FIELD<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">Of Bull Run.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Two</hi> battles--that of July 21, 1861, and
that of Aug. 29, 1862--were fought between the Confederates and
Federals in the plain traversed by the small river called Bull Run,
which crosses the main road from Washington to Richmond, a few miles
north of Manassas Gap. The scene of the first conflict, one of the
earliest of the war in Virginia, would now scarcely be recognised as a
battle-field. Four years have obliterated nearly all the marks of the
struggle, and the relic-hunter only now and then finds in the grass a
memento of the event. Very few shot and shell remain upon the surface,
the trees are hiding the blotches on their trunks made by bullets, and
the only bones that are found, with few exceptions, are those of
horses, which visitors have not thought of sufficient importance to be
carried away. Some of the fences have been rebuilt, and corn is
planted in many places; while the rapidly-growing bushes hide nearly
all the original features of the field. The battle-field of Groveton,
two miles beyond, towards Warrenton, is more distinctly marked with
traces of battle. Here the shot and shell are thickly strewn, the
trees are splintered, and in many places the forest looks as if it had
been visited by smallpox. The bones of the soldiers of both armies are
scattered over the fields, and the phrenologist may find skulls
enough. A monument has now been erected on each of the Bull Run
battle-fields. These monuments are of chocolate-coloured, sandstone,
thirty feet high, and were erected by the officers and men of General
Gamble's separate cavalry brigade, camped at Fairfax Courthouse. The
monument on the first Bull Run field is situated on the hill in front
of the memorable stone house, on the spot where the 14th Brooklyn, 1st
Michigan, and 1st and 2nd Maine were most hotly engaged, and where
Ricketts and Griffin lost their batteries. The shaft is 27 ft. high,
and bears upon its top a hundred-pound shell. On the pedestal, at each
corner, is a shell of similar size. On one side of the shaft is
inscribed, "To the memory of the patriots who fell at Bull Run, July
21st, 1861," and on the reverse, "erected June 10th, 1865." The
monument at Groveton is similar in its proportions, bearing the
inscription, "To the memory of the patriots who fell at Groveton,
August 29, 1862," and on the reverse, "Erected June 10th, 1865." Our
Illustration represents the scene at the consecration, or
"dedication," as it is called in America, of these monuments. The
religious exercises were conducted on the first Bull Run field by the
Rev. Dr. M'Murdy, who read an appropriate service, which was followed
by a hymn written for the occasion by Pierpont; a military parade by
the 5th Pennsylvania heavy artillery, Colonel Gallup; and a salute by
the 16th Massachusetts battery, Captain Scott. At the close of these
ceremonies, eloquent addresses were delivered by Judge Olin, General
Wilcox, General Heintzelman, and General Farnsworth. At the second
monument the services were similar to those described. A large party
of visitors had come from Washington to be present on this
occasion.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1324.007" n="Dedication of the Monument on the
      Battle-Field of Bull Run, Virginia." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1324</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 48</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-15">July 15, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v47p48b">
<head>DEDICATION OF THE MONUMENT ON THE
      BATTLE-FIELD OF BULL RUN, VIRGINIA.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1324.008" n= "The twenty-fifth report" type="Article">
<head>[THE TWENTY-FIFTH REPORT]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1324</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 51</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-15">July 15, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The twenty-fifth report of the Emigration Commissioners was
published last Saturday. The Commissioners state that, since the year
1814, the numbers that have left the United Kingdom amount to
5,691,709, of whom 3,450,531 have gone to the United States, 1,255,554
to British North America, and 867,802 to the Australasian
colonies.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1325.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence:
      United States." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE:
      UNITED STATES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1325</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 54</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-22">July 22, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">UNITED STATES.</p>
<p>The assasination trials are over, and the sentences partly carried
out. Payne, Harrold, Atzerott, and Mrs. Surratt were hanged on the 7th
inst. The Judge of the Supreme Court had previously served a writ of
habeas corpus on General Hancock, in Mrs. Surratt's case, which, by
President Johnson's order, was not obeyed. It is stated that Payne,
previous to his execution, exonerated Mrs. Suratt, and that another
person had subscribed to an affidavit impeaching the testimony of an
important witness against her. Dr. Mudd, Arnold, and O'Laughlin are to
be imprisoned, with hard labour, for life; and Spangler, the stage
carpenter, is to be imprisoned, with hard labour, for six years.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia the Provost Marshal having, by order from
Washington, surrendered a prisoner named Cozzens to the Sheriff, Judge
Thompson has since released him, declaring that the President's power
to suspend the habeas corpus conferred by Congress terminated with the
war.</p>
<p>President Johnson's health is somewhat improved, but he is still
unable to receive visitors. The health of Mr. F. W Seward continues to
improve.</p>
<p>Independence Day, the 4th of July, was celebrated with more than
usual demonstrations of loyalty.</p>
<p>President Johnson has issued a proclamation appointing Benjamin
F. Perry Provisional Governor of South Carolina. All the seceded
States, except Florida, have now either provisional or elected local
governments. The details of reconstruction, however, are much more
copious than interesting.</p>
<p>General Grant authorizes the statement that all the white volunteer
troops of the army would be mustered out of service at the earliest
possible day. It was probable that, by the middle of August, there
would not be 10,000 remaining in the whole of General Meade's military
division of the Atlanta.</p>
<p>Advices from the west report the capture of several desperate
guerrillas and murderers.</p>
<p>The military authorities of Richmond had taken precautionary
measures against an apprehended negro insurrection.</p>
<p>The Government are making arrangements to send to Atalanta a
sufficient quantity of supplies to relieve the necessities of the
people in that district, who for some time past had been reduced to
the last extremities of famine.</p>
<p>A committee of delegates, presenting the coloured population of
Virginia, was to meet in Alexandria on the 2nd of August, to consider
the condition and prospects of the race.</p>
<p>The number of applicants to the President for pardon average
between 200 and 300 a day. Papers were issued one day granting pardon
to 180, mostly North Carolinians.</p>
<p>The States of Wisconsin and Iowa have been visited by terrible
tornadoes. The village of Virogna, Vernon County, Wisconsin a place of
about 1200 inhabitants, was nearly destroyed. Seventeen persons were
killed and more than a hundred badly injured. The loss of property was
very great. In Iowa the crops were badly damaged, railroads and
bridges destroyed, and serious damage done in several counties. Heavy
rains succeeding had caused disastrous floods.</p>
<p>Large numbers of Federal troops were landing along the Texas coast
and the mouth of the Rio Grands. Six thousand troops, mostly coloured,
had arrived at Brazos. A detachment had been sent up the river, and
occupied Eagle Pass.</p>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">Herald</hi> states that the Government had
received official information that Spain would surrender the Stonewall
to the United States.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1325.002" n= "The Great Eastern" type="Article">
<head>[THE GREAT EASTERN]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1325</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 62</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-22">July 22, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The Great Eastern, laden with the Atlantic telegraph cable, left
the Nore last Saturday evening, and arrived off Valencia on Wednesday
morning. The Caroline, with the shore end of cable, twenty-seven miles
in length, was detained at Falmouth by bad weather until Monday, and
had to be taken in tow by the Great Eastern off Land's-end the same
day, and taken to Valencia during a heavy sea. The Terrible and the
Sphynx are also off Valencia. In consequence of a heavy rolling sea,
the Great Eastern was unable to communicate with the shore, and went
for shelter to Berehaven Harbour, Bantry Bay, where she will lie until
the shore end of the cable is laid--an operation which will occupy
about two days, and which was to be set about directly the weather
improved. Once started for the Newfoundland coast, the only danger to
be feared i a storm severe enough to drive the Great Eastern from her
course. Messages will be transmitted from the ship on paying out each
fifty miles, so that the public will be able to watch her course from
day to day almost as closely as those on board. On arriving at
Newfoundland a message, already prepared, will be transmitted to the
directors, and the receipt of ths will be considered proof that the
line has been opened.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1325.003" n= "The Theatres." type="Article">
<head>THE THEATRES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1325</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 63</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-22">July 22, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">THE THEATRES.</hi></p>
<p>....We have a report of the progress of Mr. and Mrs. Charles Kean
in St. Louis, where their reception appears to have been
prodigious. On the 23rd of June Mr. Kean addressed the audience,
promising to revisit them in November. On the 27th they appeared in
"Henry VIII." and "The Jealous Wife," at the theatre in Chicago, which
was filled in every part. The tragedies of "Hamlet" and "Louis XI."
have also been performed with &#x00E9;clat. Altogether, they may be
congratulated on their success.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1325.004" n="The Last Days of the Confederate
      Government.--From Sketches by our Special Artist. The Flight of
      the Confederates: A Sudden Alarm and Stampede.; The Train of the
      Confederates Crossing the Pe-Dee River, North Carolina.--See
      Page 70." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1325</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 64</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-22">July 22, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v47p64">
<head>THE LAST DAYS OF THE CONFEDERATE
      GOVERNMENT.--FROM SKETCHES BY OUR SPECIAL ARTIST. THE FLIGHT OF
      THE CONFEDERATES: A SUDDEN ALARM AND STAMPEDE.; THE TRAIN OF THE
      CONFEDERATES CROSSING THE PE-DEE RIVER, NORTH CAROLINA.--SEE
      PAGE 70.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln47.1325.005" n="The Last Days of the Confederate
      Government.--From Sketches by our Special Artist. Mr. Jefferson
      Davis Signing Acts of Government by the Roadside.;
      Mr. Jefferson Davis Bidding Farewell to his Escort Two Days
      Before his Capture.--See Page 70." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.47</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1325</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 65</biblScope>
<date value="1865-07-22">July 22, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v47p65">
<head>THE LAST DAYS OF THE CONFEDERATE
      GOVERNMENT.--FROM SKETCHES BY OUR SPECIAL ARTIST. MR. JEFFERSON
      DAVIS SIGNING ACTS OF GOVERNMENT BY THE ROADSIDE.;
      MR. JEFFERSON DAVIS BIDDING FAREWELL TO HIS ESCORT TWO DAYS
      BEFORE HIS CAPTURE.--SEE PAGE 70.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>



THE LAST DAYS OF THE CONFEDERATE

GOVRNMEItT.

Tnotrcrr published at a somewhat late period, the series of four Illustrations which we give this week cannot fail to prove of much interest to our readers. It must be taken into consideration that our Special Artist at the head-quarters of the Southern army bad numerous difficulties to contend with in the transmission of his correspondence to this Journal! and it is only now that, by his arrival in this country, we are placed in a position to avail ourselves of the last of his experiences in the Southern States of America.

After the capitulation of General Johnston there was virtually no armed force left east of the Mississippi; and President Davis, already a fuve from Richmond, having been driven from the capital of Virginia by the surrender of General Lee, found himself again a wanderer by the wayside, seeking some means of escape from the Federal columns which were closing in upon him in all directions. Our Special Artist, as we have already stated, accompanied Mr. Davis in his flight to within forty-eight hours of his capture. A. few of the sketches he made, while following the ex-President, are now given to the public.

One of these Illustrations shows the ex-President's train crossing the Pc-Dee River, in North Carolina This was a long and tedious operation. There are usually no bridges over the swift watercourses in this part of America, and very frequently no fords. Each waggon, with its team of mules, had in this instance to be ferried across separately, and this delay, with an enemy following in the rear, was, to say the least of it, a very anxious affair. In fact, more than one alarm of the approach of the Federal cavalry was given before half the train bad crossed the river, and the excitement amongst the rearguard and teamsters was excessive. The horses of the cavalry escort were made to swim the stream, being stripped of their saddles and their riders of most of their clothes. The confusion at the landing-place was enormous, as many of the frightened animals were scarcely in the water before they threw their riders and struggled to the bank, chargin through the crowd of attendant cavalrymen. Notwithstanding all this, the entire than used safely over the Ps-Dee and many other

streams while our Artist was in its company, and the only misfortune that happened to him was two or three good duckinga.

Another fllustration shows Mr. Davis and his Cabinet halting by the

roadside; the en-President engaged in signing papers which Mr. Benjamin, his Secretary of State, is handing to him. This was probably the last official business transacted by the Confederate Cabinet, and may well be termed "Government by the roadside." Our readers must bear in mind that at any moment the alarm might be given of the enemy's advance, and, to say the least, such a condition of matters was scarcely calculated to give calmness to the delibe

rations of the fugitive Government.

The subject of another Illustration is the scene presented by a

sudden alarm, or stampede, which was a very frequent occurrence,
owing to the proximity of the Federal cavalry, who were frequently within three miles of the camp of the flying President. A scout had

01 to dash in and give the alarm when everything went heltern3l to along the road-President, Ministers cavalrymen, four-muled

A te wag.gons, and.teraified negro servants, all jum' bled up together.

The last of these -Illustrations shows the farewell of Mr. Davis to his escort and gaff in the square of Washington, Georgia. It was here that he determined to continue his flight almost alone; and, assembling those round him who had sacrificed everything to the defeated cause, be, with tears in his eyes, begged them to seek their own safety and leave him to meet his fate. Undoubtedly, it was an ill-advised arrangement which brought an escort of 1500 men in the train of a man fleeing for his life; and, when boo late, Mr. Davis saw the error of thus attracting the attention of the entire country through which he passed, and disbanded them but forty-eight hours before his capture.
TAnd so hera Eastern is fairly of and if in the ensuing fort

night the telegraph cable is successfully laid down, amongst the

earliest news that mm along the line at the rate of four words a minute will be that which relates the trial of Mr. Jefferson Da',-is. There is now plenty of force in America, and the admirers of Mr. Carlyle and a strong Government have their wish. No one can look at a photograph of President Johnson without seeing that he is a roan of great capacity and of iron will. By-the-way, with what fervour would the news be received, in America (were it only true) of the assertion that Qarlyle had undertaken the Life of President Lincoln. "Two men I honour," said that writer; "and no third: first, the toil-worn craftsman that conquers the earth. Venerable to me is thy hard hand, hardly-entreated brother I The second is the mspixed thinker . . . . These two, in all their degrees, I honour; all else is chaff and dust." "Unspeakably touching" is the Oarlylese expression for the effect the sight of the two labourers united in one person has on him; and in Abraham Lincoln, the eloquent rail-splitter and the martyred President, surely these were so. The life of a mad despot like Frederick might possibly be atoned for by the really deeply instructive life of Abraham Lincoln. Will Mr. yle take it in hand?
The America Protestant church at Aspinwall w83 con.

secreted on June 1, the ceremony being performed by Bishop Potter, of Pennsylvania. A large number of the residents of Panama, both native and foreign, including the President of the State, the French Consul, and other prominent inhabitants were present at the service. Thisis the first Protestant church ever erected on the isthmus of Panama. It is built of stone brought from the Pacific Ball road Company's quarry on the isthmus, and has been erected at the coat of the company. -
IJ1cIThD STATES,

It is reported that the Governmentl.s determined to try Mr. ])iwis

by a military commission in consequence of the discovery of additional

evidence implicating him in the assassination plot.

Slowly, yet surely, the work of reorganising the southern States

continues.

Judge William Marvin, formerly Southern District Judge of Florida,

lies been appointed provisional Governor of that State, with like instructions to those issued in relation to previous similar appointments. This appointment completes the work of supplying all the southern States with civil executives, and in once more placing the entire sisterhood of the Union under the direction of Governors, either elected or appointed, aeknowledgthg and in accord with the general Government.

A Virginia delegation waited on the President and asked him to

ame] the snnie4y pTeci nstou by striking out the clause excluding
rebels with over 20,000 dols. Mr. Johnson replied that he saw 110

reason for granting their request.

Judge Sharkez, of Mississippi, has announced that the delegates

to the State convention will be elected on Aug. 7.

General Howard, the chief of the Freedmen's Bureau, has instructed

his subordinates throughout the south to see that slavery is not reins..

posed in the form of apprenticeship.

It j officially estimated that the supplies of cotton in the country, amount to two million and a quarter bales, exclusive of the new crop

The: "Confiscation Department" has seized much property a

Richmond; and the publication of the .Richmond Whig has been sm.

pended by the military authorities.

An international trade convention, assembled at Detroit, Michigan, on the 11th inst. There were about 600 delegates present, composed of representalives of the board of trade said commercial association' of various cities of the northern, eastern, and western States, and

the British provinces. An organization was effected, and other

business of a preliminary character was transacted. General Hiran.

Waibridge, of New York, was chosen president, and vice-preside

for each of the States and provinces were chosen. The object of the convention is thus set forth:-Discussion and conference upon, first, finances; second, commerce; third, lines of transit from east

west; fourth, the reciprocity treaty. The deliberations extended over several days. Various reports and resolutions were submitted, but the convention adjourned without important action.

There is an evident attempt on the part of some members of the Government and leading politicians to create an excitement on the question of Imperialism in Mexico. Secretary Harlan and Mr. Montgomery Blair had. made speeches denouncing the French inter.. ,ention in Mexico and advocating the maintenance of the "Monroe doctrine."

Barnum's Museum and many adjoining buildings, in New York

have been destroyed by a fire which was suspected to have been caused

by  isry. BRITISH NORTH AMBRICA,

A meeting of the Canadian Cabinet was held at Quebec on the 14z inst., and the GovernorGeneral has summoned Parliament to assemble on the 8th proxinmo.

A report preeeted, on the 14th inst., by Mr. Howes, of Nova.

Scotia, contained the declaration that the annexation of the British

provinces to the United States has no place in the minds of the people of those provinces, and that should. anyone attempt to go to the hastings as an advocate of such a scheme he would be treated as a revolutionist.
THE ATLANTIC TELEGRAPH.

Thizos are looking favourable for the Atlantic Telegraph. The

shore. end of the cable was successfully landed at Valencil OR Saturday morning last. Connections were made with the inZtrUfli.t room at 12.45 p.m., Greenwich time, in the presence of a large 00* course. The Knight of Kerry and Sir Robert reel made congr$. tulatory speeches. Three cheers were given for her Majesty an(L three for the President of the United States. The paying-oat of the heavy shore cable, twenty-seven miles in length, was completed bT. the Caroline late in the evening. Shortly after four, on Sunday
afternoon, the splice with the main cable on board the Great Eastern was completed, and the paying-out began from the Great Eastern. Disquietirg rumours were circulated on Tuesday to the effect that the cable was in danger of failure. We are glad, however, to learn that the hitch which occurred had been put right, and that at the time of our going to press all was working smoothly. Telegrams continue to be received from the gentlemen on board the Great Eastern, signailing that the work of laying the cable is proceeding satisfactorily; and this gigantic vessel, herself one of the wonders of the world, which is bearing across the Atlantic the 'wire that is to make thought simultaneous in the two hemispheres, has so far advanced on her 'voyage that we may indulge in hopes of its successful issue.

A despatch from St. John's, Newfoundland, states :_c, In antici

pation of the successful laying of the Atlantic cable a telegraph line

has been constructed from this place to Heart's Content, the point selected for the landing of the American shore end of the cable. An office has been fitted up there, and everything that can be done to advance the securing of the shore end of the cable has been per. formed."
Silver Peak is believed to be a pre-eminent over all silver

mountains as the Iron mountain of Missouri is superior to all other iron

deposits. Silver Peak is situated east of San Francisco, on the eastern side of

the Sierra Nevada, and nearly one degree south of the city of Austin. It Is

some two miles from Castle Mount, an old extinct crater, about 5000 ft. above ocean level. Near Silver Peak is an extensive deposit of salt, and not far distant a bill of pure sulphur. The whole country has a naked appearance, being piite destitute of vegetation, and bristles with mountains scattered over a plain of great extent. The dreaded "Valley of Death," upon the plains of which, along the "old Spanish trail," travellers have suffered so much, lies but a short distance to the south-east of the crater of Silver Peak. Little Salt Lake, in Southern Vtab, lies directly east of Silver Peak. At rst the searchers after deposits of the precious metals confined their searches to the Paciffc side of the Sierra Nevada; but discoveries in New Mexico, Arizona, and Virginia city induced a thorough examination o

the east side of the Sierra Nevada. This resulted in great success, the most brilliant of which is found in the neighbourhood of Austin, on the line of the great overlend mail, where a city has sprung up within three years which, Senator Wye says, contains a population of 10,000. From along this line of exploration the miners are rapidly extending their operations, both north and south. Recently (within six months) they came upon this immense deposit near Castle Mount. Twelve exceedingly rich lodes, or "ledges" as the miners call them, were discovered on that single mountain. This discovery in an unexpected region is believed to be the most valuable yet developed. The specimens--a great number of which have been brought to New York by Colonel Catherwood-are certainly very remarkable, and merit the attention of the whole financial community. If there is no mistake-and with the specimens actually before us we do not see how there can be--a new deposit, superior ef en to the CDmstoOk lode, which has furnished so many millions of silver, is about to pour into our market its limitless supply of this precious metal.New Thric Journal of Commerce.
- UNITED STATES. -

The election at Richmond has resulted in the success of the Seces-sion ticket, Lee's paroled soldiers voting.

The New Jersey Republican Convention has nominated Mr. I,. Ward for Governor. Resolutions wore adopted indorsilig President Johnson's policy and the amendment abolishing slavery, and also the resolutions of the Baltimore Convention in favour of enforcing the Monroe doctrine. A resolution in favour of negro suffrage was do-. bated by a large majority.

Formidable guerrilla bands continue to infest the Teohe district of Louisiana.

The Provisional Governor of South Carolina, Mr. Parry has issued a Union proclamation announcing the election of a state donvention to meet on the 6th of November next.

General Lee, who is now at a country residence in Charlotte County, Virginia, is engaged in writing a history of his campaigns.

In our obituary notice, last week, of the Prince Frederick

EmiJius .&uguatns, of Sehlcswig.B:olstein, Usually styled the.Prince de air

who died at Jicyrout, in Syria, on the 2nd ult., we omitted to mention his

sccond marriage. The Prince married Miss Mary Lee, of Now York, at tin

Church of the Redemption, at Paris, on the 3rd of November 1at
TEE LAYING OF THE ATLANTIC LEGBPH GABLE.

IN the Supplement to this Number,

we have given an account ot all the Operations connected with it till the afternoon of Sunday, the 23rd nit., when the Great Eastern, having joined the main length to the shore-end of the cable, twenty or thirty miles from the Irish coast, started on her voyage across the Atlantic. Next day, as we mentioned in our last week's Paper, a telegraphic message was received from the Great Eastern, then lying to, in 1st. 52, long. 10, about eighty miles from shore, to say that some defect had been found lit the insulation of the telegraphic wire. This mischief was supposed to exist about two or three miles west of the shore-end of the splice, and it was believed to be caused by the 0-rest Eastern pulling on her end of the cable with too much strain before the shore-end splice was properly completed. The time at which this message was sent from the Great Eastern was half-past four on the Monday afternoon. There was no apprehension expressed regarding the complete and immediate repair of the damage, and the signals to the telegraphhouse at Valencia continued very distinct. The Hawk was sent out that evening to go to the Great Eastern and see what was the matter, while the Caroline was made ready to pick up the splice, if needful, and repair the fault. Next day a telegram from Mr. Glass, at Valencia, announced that "the cabin was all right there had been a hitch, but all was now right." The Great Bstern, being in list. 52, long. 12, telegraphed on that day (ruesday, the 25th) that "a small fault had been discovered and cut oat; she was now paying out again, and the signalling was perfect; the weather very fine." The nature of the accident was further explained next day when the Hawk had returned to Valencia. In cutting oil the loose ends of the twisted iron wires, which form the external covering of the cable, a tiny shred of such wire had been allowed to adhere to the composition which surrounds the central electric wire at the core of the cable, and having come In contact with the latter, had partially destroyed its insulation. This piece of the cable, however, being submerged at a depth of not more than two miles, could be raised again withoat much difficulty, and, the faulty part having been cat out, a fresh splice could be made. On the Wednesday morning the managing director at 'Valencia made the following announcement

 The Great Eastern telegraphs that the distance run at 11.00 am. today was

110 miles (nautical). The length of cable paid out at 6.50 a.m. was 100 miles

(nautical). The signals are perfect. Weather very fine.

At half-past seven on the same (Wednesday) evening, he agin reported," All well. Two hundred miles of cable wets paid out from the Great Eastern at 8p.m. to-day. All veil."

The following despatches have since been published, from Thursday week to last Thursday

VALPECIA, Thursday Morning (July 27).-The Great Eastern telegraphs that 800 miles were paid out at 5.51) a.m. to-day, and that 111)0 miles were ran. at 9.80 a.m. All Is gong well. The signals are perfect.

VALENOLt, Thursday Afternoon (July 21).-Three hundred and fifty nautical miles of cable were paid out from the Great Eastern at 12.50. p.m.

to-day, and 350 miles were run at 4.51) p.m. Greenwich time. All well.

ON BOARD TIlE GREAT EASTERN, Friday Morning (July 28).-Five hundred

nautical miles of cable were paid out at 10.50 a.m. to-day. The distance

run at 93O a.m., wa 4130 miles. The signals are perfect, Weather fine.

Friday Afternoon (July 28).-650 nautical miles of cable paid out St.

4.10 p.m. to-day. All right.

ON BOARD TUE GREAT EASTERN, Saturday (July20) 10.45 am.-600 miles of cable were paid out at 6,50 am. to-day. The distance run, at 0.50 am., was 600 miles. The signals are perfect.

VALENCIA, Satmuilay (July 29).-Accident to cable. Cause unknown. Total Ices of insulation. No information from, or communication with, Great Eastc-rn. 700 miles paycd out at 1.50 p.m. today.

VALENCIA, Sunday-All is going on well. The fault was removed at

ISO n.m. The insulation is perfect.

ON BOARD TIlE ChEAT ILt.STERN, Sunday, 4.15 a.m,-700 miles paid out.

6130 miles run by Great Eastern. Continuity perfect. lasulaticin perfect.

All going on well.

ON BOARD 'ills OnseT E.&smrnc. Monday Afternoon-900 miles paid uCt

at 1,00 p.m. to-day. 7130 miles run by Great Eaatoru at 7.130 am. All going

on well.

ON BOA DI) TIlE GREAT EASTERN, Tuesday Morning.-1030 miles paid out

at 10.50 a.m. 000 Miles run by Great Eastern at 9.50 a.m. All going on well.

ON BOARD TUE GREAT EAsTnnN,Wednesday Morning-1200 miles paid out at 7.30 am. 1050 miles run by Great Eastern at 0.00 a.m. All going on well.

'VALENCIA. Wednesday, S p.m.-The signals from the Great Eastern

bccr.nje unintelligible at noon to-dcslr. No communication has been had with the hipince, end no Information has been received. Cause unknown.

'VALS'NCLS, Thursday, 11.30 a.m.-No information received from ship..

Cause unknown. No communication with ship.

The Canadians are getting up a petition cal]in on the

Governor-General -to investigate a charge made against the American Consul

at Detroit of having been engaged in secret efforts for the annexation of Canada to the United States.

The announcement is made in a Warsaw journal that the

long-talked-of vchcmo for connecting the eastern shores of the Russian empire with the western coast of North America has been so far matured that it has met with the approval and signature of the Czar. The Iiussiau Government agrees to complete the line as fat- as Nicolmijewsk, the American company t

continue it from that point to San 1"raacisco California
- On Sunday morning some American. and Liverpool tec!1 ye

cfficers captured a banker's clerk who had run away from America with

ICO,000 dollars, the property of his employers. The thief, whose fliim

is Townecod, had been traced to Newhaven In Connecticut, to Havaunah, whence he 'went by the West India mail-steamer to Southampton. From there be travelled to Liverpool, and in the mean time two Philadelphia detectives crossed to England by a New York steamer, and, obtaining the assistance of some Liverpool officers, captured their man at the Ps1icit boarding-hoose. A. quantity of jewellery and 98,000 dollars were found Ca him. Lie attempted to draw a revolver, but the officers dioermed him.
Mc.nii(an is scarcely so interesting as usual, though it has some valuable papers. The most important is Mr. Ludlow's sketch of the Presidents of the United States somewhat one-sided in its apprerations, but as lively and vigorous as most of the productions of title very earnest writer. Jefferson scarcely receives justice; the recent reaction in favour of the long-neglected Hamilton having naturally operated disadvantageously to the statesman who represented the opposite order of ideas. Both were eminent men; but it is Jefferson's

=glo to have comprehended the genius of republican institutions e hi. ivil scarcely diguimd his preference for a limited monarchy: The practical good sense of the American people soon ascertained which of them was to be trusted, and we have no doubt that its verdict will be ultimately confirmed by posterity. Mr. Ludlow makes a strange mistake in calling President Adams a Calvinist: he was precisely the reverse. Professor Catracs, in his paper on negro eurage, discusses the most difficult question of contemporary American politics. It is certain that the President cannot confer the franchise on negroes without a violation of law, and it remains for the advocates of the measure to show that such an infringement is demanded by an imperious necessity. Professor Cairries argues the question very forcibly; but it is one that can only be determined after the most mature consideration. The existence of such difficulties is President Johnson's sufficient justification for continuing to keep a tight grasp on the leading men of the south. -
Mere is very little news from A)nertca in the absence of

new facts, may we speculate upon the fate of the Queen's letter and the shoals of addresses of condolence from England to Anieiioa on Lincoln's murder? Did they all go down in the Atlantic? or are we waiting till the completion of the telegraphic cable to hear that there is some response to the first at least-to an act so spontaneous, graceful, womanly, and Queenly?
fl As most of our readers are probablr aware, the shore-end of the cable, extending 27 miles from land on this side of the ocean, was manufactured separately from the main length of 2300 miles, by Mr. W. T. Henley, of North Woolwich, and was conveyed to Valencia by a vessel belonging to him, the screw-steamer Caroline, which the Telegraph Construction and Maintenance Company had chartered for that portion of the work. This piece of the cable is the largest and heaviest ever made, weighing above twenty tons to the mile, and measuring 2 in. in diameter, at the shore end, but diminishing gradually, in the last 500 yards outwards, to the ordinary size of the main deep-sea cable, with which it has been joined. The core or heart of it is a cable precisely similar to the main length, but wrapped up in jute yarn, and covered outside by a winding of twelve strands of galvanised iron wires, three wires to the strand, and each wire a quarter of an inch thick. Its strength is estimated as equal to a breaking- strain of ninety tons. Such 'a the

shore-end le
on Saturday, July 15; and, with her insufficient steam-power, had enough to do in getting down the Channel, by screw and paddles, at the rate of six or seven miles an hour; but, when she came off the Land's End; on the Monday, she found the Caroline, which had started ten days before, and had lain weather-bound a week m Falmouth Harbour, unable to proceed without help. The Great Eastern was then obliged to take the Caroline in tow, from the Monday to the Wednesday morning, against a tough south-westerl 'wind and the tremendous swell of the open Atlantic, which, thoug scarcely felt by the huge Great Eastern, almost overwhelmed the unhappy Caroline. There was real danger of her being swamped, or rather dragged under the sea, as she went round the south coast of Ireland on the Tuesday night, the waves continually dashing over her decics from stem to stern, so that the men on deck were up to their waists in water. The officers and crew, who might have relieved themselves by casting off the tow-rope, endured this severe trial rather than fail to perform their part of the great work; but it must be considered that the Caroline was ill chosen for this service, and that, with better arrangements, the shore-end cable should have been safe at Valencia some time before the Great Eastern set forth. As it happened, the tow-rope accidentally breaking when a few miles off the Skeliigs Rocks, at five o'clock on the Wednesday morning, the Great Eastern first arrived alone at Valencia, which is about twenty miles distant, and the Caroline made her way in as soon as she could in the forenoon of that day. The Great Eaatorn, after landing two or three of the official gentlemen oonoerned in the enterprise went into Bearhaven, in Bantry Bay, where she was to lie securely till the Caroline should have completed the laying of the shore end, in readiness to meet the 0-rest Eastern and to form the junction with the main length of cable some twenty or thirty miles out at sea.

 The Great Eastern was accompanied by H.M.S. Terrible and Sphinx, which met her at Valencia, and are to keep with her in her voyage to. Newfoundland. It should have been mentioned above that the Great Eastern was assisted likewise in her start from the Note by another of the Queen's ships, the surveying-steamer Porcupine under Staff-Commander Calver, by whose guidance she was enabls to pass through a deep channel, recently explored and veryseldom used, much more convenient for her than either the Swin or the Alexandra channel, Ordinarily frequented by vessels leaving the Thames or Medway for the North Sea. But we must return to the Caroline, where we left lier, at Pofihonimerum in Port Magee, a narrow inlet of the strait which separates the Isle of Valencia from the neighbouring coast of Kerry to the south. To that remote part of the United Kingdom, thirty -or forty miles west of Killarney, had the Telegraph Construction Company suddenly removed the scene of its operations, which we noticed so lately at East Greenwich and in the Medway prosperously tarried forward under the eye of the London world; yet, by means

the pens of the reporters, and the pencil of our own Artist, the public we now made acquainted with the ininutest details of this mighty work.

The road to Valencia, either from Killarney or from Kenmare and

lengariff, at the head of Bantry Bay was travelled not without some delays by the few persons from London who, having made the best of their way to see the landing of the cable, succeeded in getting there on the morning of Saturday week. The local staff of the Telegraph Construction Company had seen engaged for some weeks past in various preparations on the spot. An encampment of the workmen was here or there to be seen along theroad;

 mess reucs

'of a'lonjthe shore of Dingle

ay towards Cahirciveen, at the foot of the Keragh mountains. The ientral figure in our Artist's sketch is Mr. Watlook, the superintendent )f the works of the Magnetic Telegraph Company, to whom belon the ineconnectingValenciawiththetelegrap]ijosystemthroughoutixeiand.

The poles on which the wire is stretched have, for the most part, been replaced by new and larger ones. It happened, rather unluckily, that one of these poles had been knocked down, some say by "an rmpul. ave Irish cow," others by a drunken Irish car-driver, on the very day the cable was landed, so that the news could not be transmitted to us in London quite so quickly as we should have been glad to receive it, but this defect was soon repaired.

and ntereFiti4L~ the actual landing of the cable __from the ship Caxolin in the small haven at Foilhommerun

esI71ise& This place lies just under and within Bray Read, the mountain promontory which forms the south-west corner of the Isle of Valencia, projecting into the Atlantic Ocean. it is distant six or seven miles across the island from Knightatown, the port, which occZ:..

a

paition on the strait like that of Sonderburg in the Isle of tak f, Lk high grow&d Thduw Cuialjeg

almoot at the extremty-of--the laud A contemporary reporter gives this description of the scenery :-" We now reach nearly at the summit of the last bill slow wooden hut, painted black, and not unlike the summer establishment of some watering-place photographer. This is the temporary office of the Atlantic Telegraph Company. Along the waste land, at some distance to the right, are half a dozen thatched hovels, while a few feet from the grass-grown turf-wail which divides the field containing this office from the cliff, you look down upon the Caroline, which is in communication with the land by a lengthy floating bridge of boats. To the right and left precipitous rocks rise nearly 300 ft. from the sea, so hollowed at each side as to

 Cto the securely-sheltered little haven, which is scarcely a mile M11 end to end, the conformation of a horseshoe. Rugged, steep, and utterly inaccessible, save where a rude and broken path has been formed by the cablemen, these cliffs are studded with wild flowers and ferns, and variegated by large patches of the brightest verdure, which alternate with masses of tangled seaweed and huge blocks of slate and partii-colouxed rock. Butler's Island, a large grassgrown strip of stony ground stretching from left to right, from the far point of the bay, lessens the opening to the sea, and materially helps to shelter this beautiful nook, though, as there is of course neither land nor breakwater between its entrance and America, it will be

=understood that in rough weather it presents a

Ynt appearance to the one it wore yesterday. Then all was

smiling, sunny, and calm. The spectator who, after drinking in the beauties before bun from the heights, scrambled down the rugged path and stood among the men hauling the cable onshore, orbalanced Math and on one of the crags arresting his downward. path, was in a magnificent natural amphitheatre, with toiling peasants, earnest savaaia excited seamen, and eager capitalists for his actors-priests, locsi gentry, electricians, and telegrapbiats for his fellow lookers-on, and the broad Atlantic for his stage. Mr. Creawiok never surpassed the rich hues and bright tints of the rocks and vegetation around; Preth never painted brighter eyes, more supple figures, or more picturesquely artistic costumes than those of the barefooted nymphs assembled to look at Pat or Mike 'helping the tlligrah gintlemin;' Stanfleld never transferred to canvas a more beautiful and varied sea-piece than the one before us. On the highest pinnacle of the cliff, to the right, the country people had planted a succession of improvised flags, consisting of coloured pocket-handkerchiefs, scarlet cloaks, blankets, petticoats, and what not, which fluttered gaily in the breeze, while all round the summit a long fringe of lookers-on stood out sharp and clear against the blue shy, some mounted, some squatted on the ground, dudheen in month, some gesticulating in little groups, and all manifesting the keenest interest in the proceedans of the day. The peasant's notion of the mysterious wire is that it will somehow bring him nearer to the land of promise. Every Irish labourer tells you of the relatives or friends who have prospered in America; and no man or woman here seems too old or feehie to hope

 for the day when their savings will amount to 'five or x pounds, yer honour,' that they may bid the old country good-by and begin the world anew. The telegraphic colours, represented b-v rosettes of red, white, and blue, made and presented bytsdy ca pe T Molvneu

decorated the coats or hats of those immediately interested in t'he en

terprise; and, out of the three or four hundred employed on the boats and shore to assist in hauling the-cable it, it is scarcely necessary to say no two figures were attired alike. The highcollared, swallowtailed blue coat-new, perhaps, before the electric telegraph was invented, said sadly soil ea and threadbare now-worked aide by side with the ragged nondescript garment which had been fustian, but had reached the stage of hardly-kept-together tatters. Shirts which blushed darkly at being exposed; jersies blue, red, and brown; caps and hats of every variety and shape; bare heads, bare legs, and feet, arid arms made up the line. The boats were similarly manned, and continued this line from the stern of the Caroline, some TOO yards off, so that the cable was passed literally from hand to hand from ship to shore." The appearance of this long rowof boats was very striking, and they varied from the smart cutters of the ships end the trim gig of the coastguard to the ordinary fishing-boat of the coast. Besides those which formed the line, having eight or ten men, labourers or fishermen, in each boat, to hand the cable along, there were detached boats passing up and down, with the experienced persons who were to direct the landing-about thirty-five boats in all. On shore, where a trench, 21t. deep, had been cut across the narrow beach and up the face of the cliff, to receive the cable, a hundred or more of the country people, encouraged by the presence of their popular landlord, ltfr. Fitzgeral the Knight of Kerry, were pulling and shouting in their xiah fashion, with the utmost enthusiasm, but with less discretion-for, not being aware that it was necessary to bring in and lodge upon the beach a certain quantity of cable in excess of the distance from the ship to the shore, in order that it might be passed up the cliff and across a couple of fields to the Telegraph House, these Irishmen, as soon as they got hold of the end of the future line of communication with America, threw it upon the ground, and raised a wild "Rurroo!" This was caught and repeated by the crews of the boats, who, concluding that their work was well done, at once proceeded to heave the massive rope into the sea. From at to boat the first bad example was followed by all unt1l to the dismay of the cablemen, who could not gain a hearing amid the continued cheers, every fathom no to the stern of the Caroline was thrown overboard. The result of this touching enthusiasm was that every foot had to be underrun, preparatory to the whole operation beginning tie nose. It took some time to effect this, during which the Irish were silent enough.

 "When the cable bad been underrun, hauled into the boats again,

and the shore end really began to come on land, and was stowed away in gigantic circles at the foot of the cliff, the scene was one of extraordinary animation. Numbers of men were in the water to their waists or shoulders easing the cable over the rocks, while ang the steep path up the cli was a close row of figures, men and boys, of every rank, from the well-to-do farmer down to the poorest cottier, all pulling at the cable with a will, and, as if in atonement for their first fault of enthusiasm, obecinz with silent and almost childlike docility every signal made by MrGla

or Mr. Canning as to when they were to haul or slack away." Mr.

Temple, assistant to Mr. Canning, with another of the staff, as in

the water up to his neck working as hard as any. By twelve o'clock the cable was well up the groove which bad been cut in the face. of the cliff for its reception- and from this mInt the work of carryng its massive coils acrose tue meadows to the Telegraph House= was soon accomalisbed; and at a little before one o'clock the end, taken overroads, liedgea, and ditches,was hronlit close up to the house, or hut, a plain wooden buildin ,already mentioned, which is shown in our fliustratlon on page l24. ere severa of the gentlemen clued7
interested in the great enterprise were assembled, with Sir Robert Peel,

Chief Secretary to the Government of Ireland, and Lord John Bay, who had both come with the Knight of Kerry, having, as well as Mr. Glass, the managing director of the Telegraph Construction Company (and manufacturer of the main length of cable) been the guests of the Knight of Kerry, at his mansion of Glenlears, Knightetown. The simple ceremony with which the cable was introduced to the telgra.ph station has not been noticed by other reporters, but our Artist says, "The cud of the cable was taken up by Mr. Glass and handed to Sir Robert Peel, who passed it through ahole left for the purpose in the

pro host,., WhO IatLon, WSACJ.C it was speedily connected with the batteries in the in etminentroom. A signal was then interchanged with the Caroline, proving that the electric communication was perfect. Three cheers for the Queen were called for meanwhile, and given with Irish warmth. The Knight of Kerry briefly addressed the large concourse of ladies and gentlemen, yeomen and

9asantry, now gathered about him. Ele expressed is gratification. at this auspicious commencement of the work, and called for three cheers for the Atlantic Telegraph gable, and three cheers for Sir Robert Peel. These were most heartily given, and, of course, were followed by a speech from Sir Robert Peel. (se lfluatraie ao-re. He. spoke, with his wonted energy, of the politica~

:ocial, and commercial benefits which wobld be ecured if the cable should prove successful; and, after invoking the aid, of Divine Providence, called for three cheers for the Queen and three for Mr. Glass. In replying, Mr. Glass said that all human skill could achieve had been applied to the furtherance of the object, which he hoped was now near its consummation. Sir B. Peel.haing called for three cheers for the President of the United States, and the Doxology having been sung, Mr Glass formally announced the success of the test that had been just applied, and then the men returned to the beach and filled in the trench in which the cable lay. Soon after twelve the Hawk arrived from Knightatown, and towed the Caroline out of the bay to lay the cable, which was done slowly but safely, under the able superintendence of Mr. Canning, chief engineer of the Telegraph Construction and Main.tenauco Company, assisted by Mr. Henley and Captain White, the officer commanding the Coaatguard stations along this coast, and who has devoted much care and attention to obtaining corect soundings along the route to be taken by the shore end. The Caroline started from the bay at 2.10 p.m. (Irish time). The muctration n page 121 iawa the people -watobig her front th s]lorL Telegrams were constantly received from the Caroline at Foi]hommerum station, showing that all was. going on. well.

 e page 117 sheirshe seQepUsa af the

-.talegrama, and. the interior of the instrumenJee

attbtation, which will, in fact, remj,in-ik similar state Ot4Lhe whole ocean.ia successfully laid, when th'-lie -will- handed over by the Construction and enance Company to the Atlantic Te1Wh Company, -a the instruments (Professpbnison's) now used, ad&-b1cli are correctlyahown in our present Engraving, will b taken awa and a different description of instrument niaa

of for the general purposea of trangnrusifln of

sagco It was nearly twelve o'clock at night-when a message was received by Mr. Glass that the Caroline had laid the whole of the shore-end cable with perfect ucceae,audthatitselectric continuity was quiteperfect.

On the next day (Sunday week) the operation of joining the shore end of the cable to the main length was performed at- about fifteen miles beyond the most western of the rugged rocks on the coast of Ireland. Here the Great Eastern, attended by the Terrible and Sphinx, was approached by the Caroline, bearing the last half mile of the shore end. The spectators of the work were on bcard the Hawk, a steamyacbt belonging to Mr. G1aa, which came upothe scehe as the cable was being drawn from the stem of the Great Eastern to the Caroline. Among those on board the Hawk were Lord John Hay; Six R. Peel, M.P.; the Knight of Kerry, with his daughtets, the
iisses'itzgerald; Captain White, B.M. ;and Captain Hamilton; with Mr. W. H, Russell and M.. Robert Dudley, who are appointed to be the historian and the artistic illustrator of the voyage of the Great Eastern across the Atlantic. -It L t M Ddl's enl iliad w owe the hutohoe cngrawcd Soon after one o'clock the coils of the deep-sea cable were safely wound on beard the Caroline, and the work of splicing them at once commenced. This was done by stripping both ends of hemp, outside wires, and gutta-percha for a short distance, till the copper conductor of. the line was laid bare, and pared down to a fine 'wedge-shaped point at each end.. The connecting

coucurs were ueu overlapped in the uriu known as a "scarf" joint, and firmly bound together with fine threads of copper wire, till the junction was made even stronger than the main portions of the line. The threads and conductor were then soldered totether thickly, and strips of soft gutta-perebh Eke bands of brown tape, were wound inyer over layer, and their edges closely pressed, so as to - form one homogeneous mass; till a certain thickness wai completed. Then came a coating of insulated ma

terial called Chatterton's compound, and then again

another layer of gutta-percha tpe, until. the whole was ixiclosed in -four rings of the guttaperoha sn& 'three of the compound. The joint was then lermersed in cold water for testing, and, the signals proving perfect , the last protection of hemp slid outside wire was added, and the joint sunk again into tlle sea, that its perfectness as to conductivity and insulation might be ascertained from the extreme end of the whole length of the cable on bo.rd the Great Eastern. It was past fbur o'clock before the last-of these tests was concluded, and in 'every case they proved to be most satisfactory. At 4.80 the signal was given and the last fastenings which held it to the Caroline were cast adrift, and, with a great splash, the final joint of the Atlantic telegraph and the first: thirty miles of its length went down uloicly into the blue water, the 'depth here being 100 fathoms. The Hawk then gave the Great Eastern a parting cheer; the Great Eastern fired a salute of three guns, took a turn ahead, and was fairly off; floating from her trunks she bore the white jeck, an American ensign, the burgee of the compnyi the union jack and American stars quartered, to

gether, the words "Atlantic Telegraph" being

the tail; a red ensign, a union jack, and the French flag; and from her peak the blue ensign, wbiC13 she fliesbecause Captain Anderson is an officer of t' naval reserve. In the five ships thus lying near togethersfl the British ensigns were used, the Cazohie having red, the Great Eastin and the Hwk hhiC the latter because she ranks as a yacht, and'th9to men-of-war white. Just before the start, the Captain of the Terrible, who was on board the Great Eastern, consulting with Captain Anderson, retimied to his own ship, which presently took her place on the starboard quarter of the big vessel, the Sphinx taking the port quarter; and 'so they 'went awa't* the West. The Caroline had before this turned her bead to the shore, and now the Hawk followed, and soon caught her; the Great Eastern and the men-ofwar, which had been passing out of sight on the horizon, were by this time discernible only by the bank of cloudlike smoke which lay in the golden pathway of the setting sun.

We expect to receive from our Artist; who is on board the Great Eastern, further Illustrations ,of the most interesting scenes in the progress of this grand enterprise.

