<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI.2//EN" "iln.dtd"
[<!ENTITY % iln-entities SYSTEM
"/Beck-files/ILN/ILNCVS/ilnxml/iln_entities">
 %iln-entities; ]>

<TEI.2>
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated London News
Perspective</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Compiled and edited by</resp>
               <name>Sandra Still</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent/>         
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Emory University</pubPlace>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine>
            </address>
            <availability>
               <p>2005 Emory University.
Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce,
distribute or display the contributions to the work claimed by Emory
University for non-profit educational purposes, provided this header
is included in its entirety.  For inquiries about commercial uses,
contact the Lewis H. Beck Center, Woodruff Library, Emory University,
Atlanta, Georgia 30322</p>
            </availability>
            <date>2005</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated
London News Perspective</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
               <biblScope type="volume">Volume 46</biblScope> 
 <date>January to June 1865</date>
</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p/>
         </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	<change><date>November 2005</date>
          <respStmt><name>Robin Conner, </name><resp>Beck Center Staff.</resp></respStmt>
          <item>Encoded text according to TEI guidelines.</item>
	</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div1 id="iln46.001" n="Illustrated London News: Volume 46" type="Volume"> 
            <head>Illustrated London News: Volume 46</head>
<docDate>January to June 1865</docDate>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.001" n= "The prospect westerly is not so auspicious" type="Article">
<head>[THE PROSPECT WESTERLY IS NOT SO AUSPICIOUS]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 2</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>....The prospect westerly is not so auspicious. Would that it were
in our power to foretell the certain termination of the struggle in
America before the year 1865 has closed! We can only look and sigh
over the ruin that is there running its course, and try to hope that,
when the end comes, whether this year or next, or even at some point
of time beyond them, it will bring with it some compensation, which
future generations at least may regard as commensurate with immediate
sacrifices and sufferings. It is to the West we look with most anxiety
in respect of our own international relations. The discharge of the
St. Albans raiders by Judge Coursal, upon a mere technical flaw, might
easily open the way to war between us and our transatlantic kinsmen if
the two Governments were not guided by a spirit of self-restraint
towards each other. Happily, as on the part of Canada the judgment of
its legal officer has been spontaneously repudiated, so on the part of
the United States the rash order of its military officer has been
discountenanced; and where there is a frank recognition of each others
good faith, and an evident desire on both sides to clear up accidental
misunderstandings, we need not allow our anxiety to deepen into
apprehension. Hitherto we have maintained our neutrality without
compromise, and, with it, amicable relations with Mr. Lincoln's
Government. There is ground enough in the facts of which we have
present information for regarding a rupture between the two greatest
maritime Powers in the world as a calamity which is equally and
earnestly deprecated by both, and is therefore
improbable....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.002" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 2</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>By the arrival of the Hibernia we have news from New York to the
afternoon of Dec. 24.</p>
<p>General Hood's defeated army succeeded in crossing the Duck river,
in spite of General Thomas's hot pursuit. On the 20th ult. Hood was
joined at Columbia by Forrest; and on the 22nd he had reached Pulaski,
seventy-five miles south of Nashville, still closely pressed by the
Federal cavalry. The Federal accounts estimate Hood's losses at 17,000
men, killed, wounded and taken prisoners; and represent Thomas's
losses not to have exceeded 5000 men.</p>
<p>General Sherman reports on the 13th ult., from Ossibau Sound, that
he had captured Fort M'Allister, opened communication with the fleet,
destroyed the railroads leading to Savannah, and invested the
city. His left rested on the Savannah River, three miles above the
city, and his right on the Ogeechee River, at King's Bridge. He had an
agreeable and unmolested march. His armywas in splendid order, and
amply supplied with provisions. During his march of 300 miles Sherman only
lost about 1000 men, and he arrived in front of Savannah with more
stores, provisions, and horses than he started with. About 700 negroes
joined him on the route. He destroyed 200 miles of railroad. He
estimates the garrison of Savannah, under Hardee, at 15,000, with
about 25,000 inhabitants. According to Confederate despatches "all was
well" at Savannah to the 19th ult.; and there was no further
intelligence respecting the progress of General Sherman's
operations. A letter from Admiral Dahlgren states that he is buoying
the Savannah River for an attack on the city in conjunction with other
forces.</p>
<p>The Southern journals alleged that General Breckenridge had
defeated the Federal General Burbridge, in the neighbourhood of
Saltville, in Western Virginia.</p>
<p>Admiral Porter's whole fleet was reported by a Confederate telegram
to have been in sight from Fort Fisher, near Wilmington, on the 21st
ult.; and the Confederate commander, General Bragg, added in his
despatch a confident declaration that he could hold Wilmington. It was
said that Porter's fleet had been crippled by a storm, and no
immediate attack on Wilmington was expected.</p>
<p>Advices received at New York state that the exchange of prisoners
at Charleston being ended, the bombardment of the city will be
immediately recommenced.</p>
<p>The Federal gun-boat Narcissus has been blown up by a torpedo at
Mobile.</p>
<p>Mr. Lincoln has cancelled General Dix's order as to the pursuit of
raiders across the frontier into Canada. Some of the New York papers
complain of this. In Congress it had been moved to prepare an armed
force for the Lakes.</p>
<p>A draught of 300,000 men has been ordered. All absentees are also
ordered to rejoin their regiments immediately.</p>
<p>Secretary Fessenden is about to contract a new loan of 100,000,000
dollars.</p>
<p>Mr. Seward has ordered that persons coming to the United States,
except immigrants, must have passports. This regulation applies
specially to persons coming from the British provinces.</p>
<p>Both branches of the Federal Congress had adjourned to the 5th
inst.</p>
<p>Gold was quoted at New York, on the afternoon of the 24th ult., at
220&#x00B7;.</p>
<p>In the Southern Congress there have been some noteworthy
movements. First, a resolution has been introduced to send
commissioners to treat with Federal commissioners upon the restoration
of peace. Mr. Foote, a member of the Confederate Senate, made a
speech, in which he declared the Confederacy to be on the verge of
ruin, and blamed Jefferson Davis for all the late military
disasters. Mr. Foote afterwards withdrew from the Senate. The <hi
rend="italic">Richmond Enquirer</hi> says that General Lee is in
favour of arming the negroes. The same paper declares that if
independence can only be attained by the sacrifice of slavery that
sacrifice must be made.</p>
<p rend="center">BRITISH NORTH AMERICA.</p>
<p>The Canadian Parliament is summoned to meet on the 19th inst.</p>
<p>A proclamation has been issued by the Governor-General of Canada
calling out a large force of volunteer militia to prevent raids from
Canada into the United States, and to maintain order on the
frontier. Thirty companies of Canadian volunteers have been sent to
the frontier.</p>
<p>Three of the St. Albans raiders have been recaptured. The discharge
of the raiders by Judge Coursal is condemned by both the Government
and rebel newspaper organs in Canada, and the majority of the people
appear to be indignant at the critical condition in which the
relations between the Northern States and the provinces have been
placed by it. Mr. Lamothe, the chief of the Montreal police, had
resigned, it was supposed, to avoid dismissal. The bankers and
merchants of Montreal had addressed a memorial to the Governor-General
setting forth their desire that a fair and honest neutrality should be
maintained between the belligerent States of America....</p></div2>



A ., ,
THE SIN=G OF THE OOEDEB.ATE TE1AMR FJORIDA., ) TBB 4S

IT would have been disagreeable -to the aaticalal pride- of the Americans i± the-Federal $oyernxnent at Washington, unable to answer the diplomatic reimonaucesDrovoked by the late violation of a neutral harbour of Brazil, had been obliged to send back the Confederate steamer Florida, captured illegally by the Wachusetts at Babia on the 7th of October, and. to replace their prize where she was taken, beneath the sheltering jurisdiction of the Brazilian sovereignty. From this aorcation they have been saved, as already reported, by- the happy accident or expedient of sinking the - Florida ten - fathoms under water in Bfi3±1ptou Roads, at the. mˆnth of the Janies River, where she was unaccountably ran down by a Federal transportsteamer, the Alliance, on the 19th of November , going to the bottom a few hours afterwards.

The Illustration we now

1blish is from a sketch by 11ri. Edward L, Henry, of New York, who witnessed the event. The Florida is shown as she appeared, having lost her mizenmast in the conflict with the Wachnsetts at Babia. The ship seen to the right hand is an ironclad or Monitor, named. the Atlanta, whiali was stationed as a guardship at the nouth of the river. In the distance Newport News, with n military camp onshore. The following atcount of the destruction of the Florida is given by the correspondent of a New York paper :

"On the 19th the Florida went to Norfolk to coal, and just before starting was run into by the transportsteamer Alliance. She was was in very bad condition when captured, and all the time since her arrival here she has leaked so badly as to keep the steam-pump engaged continually. The collision with the Alliance greatly increased the volume of the water which constantly poured into her. About nine o'clock on Sunday evening one of the pumps on board suddenly gave cut. Before more assistance arrived the -water had risen considerably above the fire-room floor, so that it was found, necessary to put the fires out. The pumpengine was thus stopped, and the water came pouring in at a fearful rate. It was impossible at anytime, after it was found the ill-fated ship was sinking, to move - her toward the shore, as there was but 7 lb. ressure of steam-justsufficieuttowork the pumps. Neither were there means at hand for towing her, ashore. In a few minutes after sending the two boats to the Florida, Captain Woodward, of the
board to see 'what could be done to keep her afloat. But it was apparent that she must soon sink , and the men were ordered to save their effects and prepare' to leave her to her fate. The Florida kept rapidly filling so that at seven O'clock the 'water was a foot above the jertb-deck. At the same time that Mr. Baker signalled the Atlanta he sent a te1etaphic nieseage to Admiral Porter at this place that the Florida was smktug. The Admirl immediately ordered the. tug Page to steam up to the Florida and tow her into shoal water towards the shore. The bu came alongside at 7.15, hut the Florida was by this time so near Binkmg that it was deemed dangerous to attach it, as in going down she would take the tug along with her. A few minutes after. with eight feet of water in her, she careened over, and disappeared stern foremost. Mr. Baker and Captain Woodward remained alongside in the tug until she 'went under. The Florida had all her guns and everythug on board just as wheus he was captured. There is a feeling of general satisfaction among naval officers here at her fate. It is considered much preferable to have her disposed of here, and then inderimity be offered to the Brazilian Government, than suffer the humiliation of taking her backs and seeing _her saluted as she would enter the harbour of Rio Janeiro in triumph, with the rebel flag flying. This would have been a most bitter pill to the American officers who would have had to accompany her.

MEMO
But they ny &a-in- at the cml's, too, that Lord Lyons will not return to l-iingtou. His Lordship has but recently returned to thifl country- on lenvo of sheence; but, 1i the sages o Pall-mall are to be believed, he -nil not resune his arthious and thankless mission. He s srtkl to b suffering from an affection of the eyes; and, crtain1y, the climate of Washington-scorching in summer and scariryingly cold in winter-is not -favourable to the cure of affections of any kind. But who is to replace an amiable and clisncet: diplomatet, wo, all

tll

hings considered, -has been the very best Minister w have ever accredited to the United States? Washington might be an agreab1e change from Madrid to Sir John Crampton; but, alas Sir Joir knows the District of Columbia but too well. Did not our cousin turn him out of it and out of the country to boot, ten years ago? Lord Napier; too, has been promoted; but were it possible to take bin from St. Petersburg, his return to America would eminently pleae the liorthcrners, among whom his frank and cordial manners have made him eceedjngly poinilar.

-,,tr ... i, - . ......
Au Atlas ofAmerica, iuustxutthg the physical and political

geography of North and South America and the West India Istaids, has

opportunely been published by Mr. Cotton, of New York, and Messrs. Bacon

and Co., of Paternoster-row. The maps and city plans, aixt,s-five in number, .admirably executed by George W. Cotton, are accompanied by desoriptions, ¥ geographical, statistical, and historical, by Richard Ssvainson Fisher, M.D.

At this eventful period in the history of the States, of Canada, of Mexico, and of parts of tho southern continent, this elaborate work supplies a great want.
The opening paper inTFrer, "President Lincoln," by an American

Abolitionist (Mr. Conway, we imagine), is remarkable as a manifesto

from that small but earnest band whose triumphant contest in the name of principle against oppression, supported by the entire strength of a mighty nation, forms as remarkable and as encouraging a chapter in thehistory of the world as the Reformation itself. We fear, however, that it is plain, on the writer's own showing, that the Abolitionist leaders were incompetent to carry out the movement they had so nobly inaugurated. An erroneous fallacy pervades his essay, he fancies that he and his friends represent the sense of the American people, and talks as though the chief magistrate of the nation were bound to make himself the mere instrument of a bare majority, of the people of Massachusetts. Had Mr. Lincoln done so, he and Massachusetts and the negro would long ago have been swept away together in a tempest of popular wrath, and his caution has been the salvation of the very men by whom he is so fiercely denounced. He has been to Garrison and Phillips what Peel was to Cobden, or Ca'vour to Mazzini-a practical, worldly wise man, standing on a far lower moral level, but without whom lofty principles and ardent imaginations would never have appeared in the guise of realities. "Spiritualism" is another remarkable pa

This months Bkckwsed witnesses the conclusion of

Butler," which has not wholly redeemed the promise of its commencement, but is still entitled to the praise of an interesting, animated tale. "The Man and the Monkey" is a most amusing story, of a kind almost peculiar to Blsckwood. "Cornelius O'Dowd" mites with sense and point, except when treating of America, when big remarks betray great flippancy and ignorance. The English officer's amount of his visit to the Confederate States is more satisfactory, though it is impossible to repress a groan over the stupidity which could turn such splendid opportunities to such poor account. Mowever, we must take him as he is, and be thankful. Charleston and the Chatanooga campaign are the subjects of his present instalment. With charae4wristic infelicity be managed to arrive at General Bragg' head-qnarters just toe late for the battle of Chicamauga, and to mt them just before that of Missionary Ridge. The article on the " S

Rocb,' 4- 4 .-J n,,hioM, ,.4,04, no,, ,,avrn- io satisfactorily settled
- ________ flUflJ53VU  ¥at

A company has been formed in New York-, styled "The

American and British West India Cotton Company," which has leased for a

term of years 2000 acres of land on Long Island, one of the group of Bahamas.

The seal of the Confederate States of AmericZili'om

position of which is by J. IL Foley, B. A., contains as a centre a represents ton of that statue of Washington which n-se executed by the Amerioai

sculptor, Crawford, and erected at Richmond. The figure is mounted and Ii uniform, as ooinmanding in an engagement. It is stuvounded by a wreath beautifully composed of the most valuable vegetable products of the Southern

soil, as tobacco, rice, maize, cotton, wheat, and sugar-cane. The rim bear the legend, "The Confederate States of America, 22nd February, 1582. iDe Vlndice." The seal is of silver, and its diameter is from three to four inches

There appears to be as large an amount of carelessness on tbs

part. of the letter-writing community in America as in the Old Country The report of Postmaster Dennison shows that 3,580,520 dead letter., wer received during the past yearover 9000 a day. Many of these letters can tamed money, deeds, bills of exchange, dratghts, cheques, jewellery, and otha valuables. Some of them were misdirected, others not directed at all, other, unstsanped, and others only r'nrtially directed. Thousands of these dew letters were returnrd to the writen. but the great majority badto txilestroyed
AMERICA.

By the Peruvian we have news from New York to the evening of Dec. 81.

Savannah has fallen into the hands of the Federals. General

Sherman thus pithily notifies the welcome fact to President Lincoln: Savannah, Georgia, Dec. 22.

I beg topresentyou as a Christmas gift the city of Savannahwlthlso heavy

guns and plenty of ammunition, and also about 25,000 bales of cotton.

W. 3. SsiEitMsic, Major-General.

General Sherman occupied the city on the morning of the 21st nIt,,.

and found the 20,000 inhabitants, he says, "quiet and well disposed."

The Confederate General Mardee had previously rejected a summons

to surrender; but during the 20th ult. he succeeded in transporting all Ids infantry and field artillery across the river from the city to a place called Union Causeway, and had thus escaped the assault which the Federals intended to make, and withdrawn his troops before the Federal works had advanced enough to impede his passage of the river. Savannah ad-vices of the 2flthult. report that an effort was being made to intercept General Hardee's retreat before he could reach the Broad River; but the Richmond journals stated that General Rardee had. arrived at Charleston.

 As a set-off against the Federal success at Savannah, we have to record the failure of the Federal attack on Wilmington. General Butler had returned, to Fort Monroe, and the transports with his troops on bpard were also arriving there. Admiral Porter, with his frigates and monitors, had proceeded to Beaufort, And was there awaiting further orders. Admiral Porter, in his report of the operations, stated that on the 24th alt., after a large powder-ship had been blown up under the walls of Fort Fisher, without doing any damage, his fleet bombarded the fort, and in an hour silenced the Confederate fire. Ore the afternoon of the 25th 8000 troops, under the command of General Weitzel, landed under cover of the fire from the fleet, captured two batteries and advanced within fifty yards of Fort Fisher,. some of the men even entering the outworks. General Weitsel,. however, deemed a successful attack impracticable, and reembarked on the same evening, though about 1000 men remained ashore during the following day, in consequence of the state of the weather. General Butler informed Admiral Porter, on the night of the 25th nit., that an assault was impracticable, as Fort Fisher wassubstantially uninjured as a defensive work by the navy fire, and could only be reduced by a regular siege; and he added that he should retain to Fort Monroe as soon as the transports for his troops were ready. Admiral Porter vainly assured General Butler that the fire of his ships could keep the Confederates inside the fort from showing their heads until a storming column should be within twenty yards of the works, and that the capture of the fort by assault, if attempted, would have been easier than was supposed. An interesting feature in Admiral Porter's report is his condemnation of the 100-pounder Parrctt guns, which he says were unfit for the service. Six of them burst, killing and wounding forty-five men.

The notion of the powder-ship which, as stated above, was blown upnear Fort Fisher with such trivial result, was suggested by the effect;

¥ of the explosion at Erith; and the-method of fitting out and firing thevessel is thus described

The United States steam gun-boat Louisiana was tskento the Norfolk Navy

yard about a month ago, and such changes made in her as would adapt her to receive ths powder. She was also disguised as much aspoesible, so as to give her the appearance of a blockaderunner. After all the required changes had been

made the Louisiana was towed to Cranny Island, where she was loaded. The

hold was left empty, as the powder at the explosion was desired to be As

much as possible above water. The powder was contained in a bulkhead

the b a to the r'i of er"' de au~cu~~ n Tly b`cil ~ape ~7els ea~ tak_ on"

ding the powder. c in 7

h gangway and =ft;

e

the h

=e r he te I. e fuse ljcompl~l

I

ocen g a tier 0' p d b F

th boil v, c ~h ac others the

- t purp~

Th the w_- 1. k- as 1. th ea of these n

rca v.a, termi o an

d a and t h.la d the

centre of the berth-deck. Any one of the fuses ignited would fire all the others, because each one crossed one of the others, and wherever they crossed they were grafted. There were no absolute soundings of the shore in the vicinity of Fort Fisher, and it was only a matter of conjecture how near the Louisiana could go before she ran aground. When her bottom first grated the sand her furnace-doors were to be thrown open, the engines left running, asia caps

o th d yh  ~au

th th~

e' bed af

on was ex~

ises the 0 ocks 6 en 67~

a up u  ~I - ' The I

h. the

h c d an the U PF

p k I n the b ts.

ak !.cc in tb g' _~ ut_, by t t

or forty -

st r abl v. w. P,

Ple7

t

-in launch , would prb be II e 0-  as

h ver, as . i.1 d C. some ace asat befall the la

r..th

a rsue eu'st~.'cstl to t the surf. ~~t and w for W.

n ir ev c

til.j
1%71 th±n the time for the erploaion, when they 'were to jump overboard, go 'opes and buoys as far as possible from the boat, submerge to the head, and, with cotton in their ears, await the 5]iQclc.

The Federals have been again repulsed in an attempt to land, on

Boanoke Island; and an expedition by Granger against Mobile had,

according to Confederate accounts, been driven back.  -

There are contradictory reports as to Hood's movement. One

account says that he had crossed the 'Tennessee. Another abates that

the Federal gun-boats had prevented him from crossing, and even

adds that the remnant of his army had been captured.

Although it was declared that the Federal Generals Storieman and Buthridge had been defeated in Western Virgin* it seems that they have cap Lured Saltvi]lc, the great manufactoryof salt for the South.

At Richmond there has been no new movement, but it was reported

that Lee was preparing to attack the Federals. The Southern press urge Lee's appointment as Commander-in-Chief of the armies of the Confederacy.

President Lincoln has been made an LL.D. by the College of New Jersey.

The President has remitted the sentence of the court-martial upon Admiral Wilkes to a period of one year from it date. The sentence suspended him three years from the service.

'1 he Brazilian demand for explanation and reparation for the seizure

of the Florida has been replied to by a note from Mr. Seward. Regret

is expressed for the proceeding at Bahia. Captain Collins is anspendeci sad ordered to be tried by court-martial. The United States Consul at Balm is dismissed, and the men captured in the Florida are to be set at liberty. Mr. Seward says the United States have a coinplaint against Brazil for recognising the Confederates as belligerents, but he adds that it is no part of the duty of an officer to take upon himself the redressing of his country's wrongs.

President Jefferson Davis has issued a declaration that B. a-.

Burley-who has been apprehended in Canada, and who headed the

men who endeavoured to take the steamer Michigan on Lake Erie arid then release the Confederate prisoners on Johnson's island-is a Confederate officer, and acted under the authority of the Confederate Government.

The estcenied veteran English actor, Mr. James William Wallack

a contemporary of Edmund Keen and E]liston-clied at New York on

ChriatmasDay, aged sixty-nine, having been born in London in 1705.

Be made his first appearance in America at the Park Theatre, New York, in 1818, and his great success and popularity with the playgoing public of that city induced him to divide his time thenceforth between England and the United States. In 1836 he opened the National Theatre, New York, and remained manager of it until it was destroyed by fire, in 1889. He then returned to England, and played for sometime at the Princess's Theatre. In 1851 he once more crossed the Atlantic, with the intention of residing permanently in America. The New York paperj record his decease with strong expressions of sympathy and regret.

The steam-ship North America foundered while on her voyage lrom New Orleans to New York. She had on board 203 sick soldiers, twelve cabin passengers, said a crew of forty-four men. Of these only

.sixty-two persons were saved. Among the lost were Colonel Saunders

and Lieutenant-Colonel Horn.

The Governor of Canada issued a proclamation offering a reward of 2(10 dollars for the apprehension of each of the St. Albans raiders.

More of the raiders have been re-apprehended in Canada, and sent

for examination to Montreal. Their trial began on the 27th ult., in

the Superior Court, before Mr. Justice Smith. It was stated that

three of the raiders had made their way into the United States, and

bad enlisted into the Federal service in New Hampshire, hut had been

recognised said arrested.

The Menu-sal iaaae . 
"From Erith to Wilmington" The cluieb little village, on the right bank of the Thames, with its interesting old. church au sundial thereon, itg yacht proclivities, and its water-side POP," latiori, who seem to get their living by leaning, in a bug ror,

against the wooden rails and, abusing one another in some dialect of Kent, was awfully astonished on the morning wiielt the powder blew up, by nobody's fault, and in a second Converted a scene of orderly industry into a hideous ruin. But it must be almost as much astounded to learn that the story O that expiosioc, having found. its way across the Atlantic; set
the 'ederal Admiral porter upon a scheme for reducing as trong "Confederate lortiess, Such, it appears, was the case; the ruin wrought by that Eiith catastrophe would, it was hoped, be paralleled at Fort Fisher. very cle-ver, precaution was taken to ensure success. A tre rnendous quantity of powder was stowed. on board a ship, and the most ingenious system of clockwork was devised to fire the train at the right moment. A grand expedition sailed against %ViJmixigton, bearing this floating mine with it, and in due ,course, andmder favourable circumstances, the powder-vessel was moored at the spot which had been judged the best. Brave men fixed her at her moorings, set the terrible clocks going, and escaped. The expedition watched with bated breath for t1ac ei'uption of the volcano. The clocks were faithful, The nitre fired, and, while the dreadful sowidj Responsive shook the yielding air around,

the assailants' hearts beat high; and, as thesnioke cleared, the Pederals hoped to see a ruin where Fort Fisher had been. "The shock was nothing like so severe as was expected," writes the frank sailor "it shook the vessel some, broke one or two glarses, but nothing more." Wilmington is luckier than Erith. However, Aduthal Porter, with a fine squadron, was not the

Mail to be satisfied with one failure. The experiment had been fruitless; but he had his guns, and plenty of them, and he

brought up his ironclads, and commenced a fierce boinbarct, luent, which he describes, in the language of the defender of Sebastopo], as a fm d'e/'. It silenced several of the fort batteries, blew up two magazines, and set the place on fire. But there was delay in bringing on the troops for the assault; -and when it was effected the assailants found that they could not succeed. When 3000 men had landed, the Admiral was -informed that they were re-embarking. Some brave feats were performed, but General Butler did. not see his way to storm. The Admiral was clearly disgusted. He uses the ordinarycivil language towards a brother officer, and is certain that the latter had good reasons for his cottthict, but the gallant Porter thinks that it "would have been worth while to make the attempt -after coming so far." But then he is only a smart sailor, while Butler,, who has been an attorney, may have known better when to issue his noUeprosequi. Finally, the attack was given up, the expedition returned to head-quarters, and Wilmington is

 ¥ urfe and defiant

This is an item which the Confederates are proud to set against the series of Federal successes that ma-rked. the close

¥ of the year. They have fairly beaten off one of the most

Ormidable squadrons ever sent against a fortress, and have been able to laugh at the failure of a new and, terrific-seeming en g-ine of war. They gain nothing, it is true; while Atlanta

has been destroyed, and Savannah has been captured; but they have saved a far more important port than either, and may reasonably be exultant.

As regards the state of the war generally, at the opening of 1865; we have less reason to be ashamed of stating that it is impossible for people here to form a decided opinion, inasmuch as it is clear that neither North nor South has an exact knowledge of the case. Sherman's brilliant retreat, or march,

'has proved this. The Americans do not know their own country. No one in the Federal district would speak confidently of the probable success of Sherman ; but those who did attempt to dculonstrate the truth were all wrong. They thought that he was to pass through a poor and needy country; and so sincere was their pity for the hardships he was to undergo that the most compassionate articles were written upon the state of his army, and a painful contrast was drawn between the meagre Christmas fare of his troops and the ample comforts provided for the grand army of the Potomac. The truth turned out to be that Sherman's men were marching through a rich agricultural 'cgion, had the best food, never wanted a meal, and arrived at Savannah in the highest health and strength. The Northern writers now admit that folk generally did not know the resources of Georgia. The truth is that the masses in America,

....¥_:*1_

of the South would be an injury to the cause of humanity, and. we trust that both the word and the idea will be alike discarded, The moment is not inopportune for the discussion of an. honourable peace, which must be obtained by mutual

ssions; and it could be wished that some Nestor could step in between the rtansatlazitjc Ajax and. Ulysses, and say,

1"xbear, my sow, your further niight to prove.
Savannah in the highest health and. strength. The Northern

writers now admit that folk generally did not know the

resources of Georgia. The truth is that the masses in America, with all their real sharpness and all their flood of cheap newspapers, are very ignorant about most things; and smart as is their talk, its chief cleverness is that it covers a singular

¥ absence of exact knowledge. But, on the other hand,, the Confederates seem to have been equally uncertain as to what Sherman could: or could not do. His able feints at Maoa and Augusta no doubt bewildered them; but they must have known, one might suppose, whether he

¥ could be encountered at all; and yet the most opposite statements on the subject proceeded from the Richmond papers. They know now that he marched all the way in triumph, his main body scarcely hearing a cannon, his detachments burning and laying waste, his whole force feeding on the fat of the land, and the negroes crowding to his ranks,and having to be sent -away sometimes by force. But until the event had occurred neither South nor North could give solid reasons for its anti

-

cipations. It is hardly to (be expected that English readers, even with the beautiful maps published under Federal authority, should know more; although we have some idea that our military men, with those charts before them, arrive

sounder judgments than many folk in America, and

that some of our journalists give far more complete and

truthful details than we find in the Northern or the

Southern, press. But, so far-as we can venture on a

decision, we must say that the enormous resources of the North are now telling distressingly upon its antagonist, and. that the admitted want of men in the South evidenced, too, by the renewed proposal to arm the negroes, seems to point' towards a. crisis. The splendid valpur which the Confederates have displayed is unabated, and must not only com.aud respect in Europe, but in the North, and, with a generous enemy, will certainly improve the terms on which the two parties will soon, we trust, confer. Our own Foreign Secretary has said that, though we are strictly neutral, the subjugaioa
THE TOWN AND PORT OF SAVANNAH,

town and port of Savannah, which General Sherman has captured tout a sicge. by the retirement of the Confederate General Hardee, se forces were unable to defend the place is situated on the right k of the River Savannah, eighteen miles from the sea. It is the ainus of three railroads connecting it with the neighbouring States Alabama. Tennessee, and South Carolina. The Savannah river, ied1 marks the frontier between South Carolina and the State of rgia, to which the town or city' of Savannah belongs. The popula

was, previously to the war, about 25,000, and the place was a

Lying mart for cotton, rice and lumber, but especially for the

Ialand cotton, the most valuable kind, that is grown. pro.."It except in the low lands along this coast. The bour is good, there being from 18 ft. to 21 ft. of water at

-tide over the bar at the mouth of the river, while vessels wing 13 ft. can get up to the wharves of the town, and those wing 15 ft. or lift. may go as far as Five-fathom. Role, cc uni b'Iow the town. There is steam navigation up the river &ugusta, a distance of 140 miles. The town itself stands upon a dy fiat, about 40 ft. above the water. It is laid out with great ulanty, in spacious streets and squares, crossing each other at right iles; the streets are lined with a double row of trees, and the squares re inclosed gardens in the centre, like those of London. There are rtcei, r fifteen churc1!e. one of which, the Ind'pr.dent Pres

byterian, is an elegant and costly structure of granite; a Jewish synagogue, an academy a courthouse, gaol, exchange, barracks, arsenal, theatre, market-house, and various charitable institutions. The accompanying Map or Plan will give tome idea of the capabilities of the place for military fortification.
ECHOES OF THE WEEL

Tin; explosion of fifty-five tons of gunpowder sufficed to frighten Erith out of its wits, Wake Woolwich to its foundations, and knock a considerable portion of the Thames. embankment into what is termed,

Hibetman parlance, " smithereens." But 215 tons of powder ex oloded by the Federals under the lee of a fort at Wilmington seem to lave made no more impression on its walls than the hundred plum buns full of oslereel end prossic acid made on Chunee, the mad elephant, at Exeter Change. Our cousins seem unfortunate in their blow-ups. What a disastrous failure was the springing of that mine before Petersburg last August! The superstitious among the warriors of the great armada, which is said to have returned to Fortress Moaroe, may ascribe the failure of the expedition to the presence of General Butler in a position of high command. Jonah should have been cast overboard. But many of those who arc not superstitious might feel inclined to augur that no success could attend an enterprise which was conducted on a Sunday and on Christmas Day.

The veteran James Wallack is dead. Not many weeks have elipsed since we saw him m his little bijou of a house in New York, siu

munded by the portraits of Macready, and Younge, and l.Cemble, with

his stalwart son tcator by his side, and a little grandson on his knee, looking as handsome , and as' digni–ed as of yore, and full of his old humour, vivacity, and grace. He bad been for many years i cruel sufferer from the most atrocious form of rheumatic gout; chslkstones exuded from him like drops of blood; his limbs were au swathed in silken bandages; but at seventy years of age, and all but bedridden, there were still in his eye and in his voice the vigour and cheeriness of a young man. It was no wreck you saw before yea. The gallant and chivalrous Don Caisar, the dashing Massaroni, the audacious Monseigneur, could still be recognised.

James W. Willack was something more than a brilliant and versa

tile actor. He was a high-minded and accomplished English gentle. man. In his own country the noblest in the land were glad to associate with him, and more than one of his sons end. nephews held commissions in the British Army. He was the proprietor of the most charming theatre in New York--a theatre wherein good English plays are performed by good English actors, and had realised, we believe, a handsome fortune. His son Lester, who is a great favourite as an actor in light comedy with the New York public, and

who is married to a sifter of Mr. Milleis the Academician, will, we presume, succeecito the management of Theatre. Some of the best traditions of the ]Lghsh stage in its best days die. with auges W Wallack
We -,,cry rarely allude to matters personal to ourselves; but there is an acme of ill-treatment at which even the most patient camel will groan. Among the multifarious publications of a Mr. Beeton we perceive that there is a magazine specially devised for the delectation of young ladies. We notice that Mr. Beaten, or Mr. Beeton's editor, has chosen to appropriate two lengthy extracts from the series of papers entitled "America in the Midst of War," written by the writer of these "Echoes," said to publish them in his magazine as distinct articles, appending to them the author's name. This is the more unseemly, as in the whole course of our life we never wrote a line for Mr. Beeton. The whole proceeding is exceedingly untradesmanlike. Every bookseller in London knows that the experiences of the author of "America in the Midst of War' arc about to be published in book form; and had Mr. Barton's magazine been published in February instead of January, an injunction in the Court of Chancery would very soon have taught him the difference between nnon and rsurn. Editorial scissors are excellent things, but they are !l employed in takn the breed out of a labouring men's mouth.

A fisherman recently hauled up a silver fork, marked

Atlantic," near the spot in Long Island Sound where the steamer Atlantic

was wrecked on Nov. 27, iSiS. It is described as a very heavy, old-fashioned silver fork, bearing marks of long immersion in water.

m., _.a 71--11 T1

,, n .c

Mr. Edward Watkin, M.P., president of the Grand Trunk Railway of Canada, had an interview yesterday week with Mr. Cardwell, at the Colonial Office, with reference to the recent raids from Canada, and to the consequent threatened proceeding on the part of the American Government to adopt a stringent paesport yetein for pa-eengers. and m rigid examination of

oods passing between the iitntcs and the British North American Provinces.

eri._ .-.,- 1 .. _.
AMERICA.

By the arrival of the Saxonia and the City of Manchester we have intelligence from New York to the 7th inst.

Everything was quiet at Savannah, and good order prevailed among the citizens. General Sherman is reported to be in occupation of both banks of the Savannah. It is believed that his next point of attack will be Branchville, where the Charleston and Savannah Railroad insets the Augusta road. The Confederates are preparing to defend this important position. The military authorities of Charleston have shown their sense of the near neighbourhood of Sherman by. lssuin

an order making it imperative on all slaves, not having permssion to reniiihi, to quit the city, and interdicting entrance to the city to all son-combatants not having proper passes. At the same time the engineers have set to work on the land defences of the place.

Adnthal Porter appears to have withdrawn from. Wilmington. General Br agg reports the Confederate losses during the bombardment as three killed and fifty-five wounded. Two guns in Fort Fisher burst, two were dismounted by the Confederates, and two by the Federal fire. Southern despatches contain a report that the Federals had five vessels sunk and fifteen disabled, and lost all their horses in the gale off Wilmington.

It appears that the Federals were to be supported in their attack on

'Wilmington by a gun-boat expedition up the Roanoke River. Ac

cording to Southern advices, this expedition met with a disaster. Six

sun-boats were blown up by torpedoes and 1000 men were lost.

General Hood's whole army succeeded in crossing the Tennessee

 River, and his head-quarters were at Corinth, whence he had reported

that his troops had sustained no material losses since his defeat near Nashville. The Richmond papers publish a story of the capture by Hood of a Federal brigade after his retreat from Nashville; but Hood; in his despatch, says nothing of such capture.

The only news of importance from before Richmond is the failure of Butler's Dutch Gap canal. An attempt was mace to open it on the 1st inst., when the earth fell in and closed the channel.

Guerrillas are becoming numerous and troublesome on the Potomac. It is reported that Mosby is rapidly recovering from his wounds, and will soon be again in the saddle. [We give on page 513 an Illustration, from a sketch by our Special Artist, of a rendezvous of Mosby'

men in a pass of the Blue Ridge.) No important military operations

in the valley of the Shenandoah are reported, but the movements of the Confederates in that region are said to be mysterious. Federal cavalry is scouring he London valley.

On the 24th ult. a force of about 2.500 Confederates, under General

'Wirt Adams was threatening Baton Rouge, Louisiana.

A special ‹espatch from Cairo states that General Donna's raid on

the Mobile and Ohio Railroad was successful. Twenty-five bridges

were burnt, and 4000 carbines, a large amount of ammunition, and 300 army waggona captured. Many officers and men were taken prisoners, and thirty-two railway cars destroyed.

Secretary Stanton had left Washington for Port Monroe, Hilton

Bead, and Savannah, in order to confer personally with Generals

Grant, Foster, and Sherman.

It is rumoured that the Confederate Congress has secretly given

power to the Commander-in-Chief to detail 50,000 slaves for service in the army as soldiers. Richmond papers continue to urge the Confederate Congress to appoint General Lee Commanderin-Chief of all the Confederate forces.

New-Year's Day falling on Sunday, the usual New-Year's laolida7

was observed on Monday the 2nd. At Washington, the Presidents mansion was freely thrown open, as is customary, and large crowds attended to pay their respects. Among those present were all the foreign Ambassadors.

The message of the Governor of Now York to the Lrislature

recommends a vigorous support of the war for the Union. Lise new Governor calls upon the citizens to fill up their quota of the draught.

In the Federal Senate, Mr. Wilson, of Massachusetts. presented a.

petition from officers of the army and navy asking for increased com

pensation. Mr. Sumner presented a petition from coloured citizens

,of New York asking for the abolition of slavery in the United States.

The Senate passed a vote of thanks to General Sherman and his army. y the House of Representatives, the joint resolution to abolish slavery by Constitutional amendment was debated without result.

Admiral Farragut has received a present of 50,000 dole, from the merchants arid people of New York.

The Hon. George Miffin Dallas, ox-Vice-President of the United

States, and more recently Minister to the Court of St. James's, died, at his residence, in Philadelphia, on Saturday morning, Dec. 81.

LATEST NEWS FROM ABROAD. -

The following telegrams have been received through Mr. Renter's

office

AMERICA.

NEW Voax, Jan. 7.-The Governor of Kentucky, in his Message

to the Legislature, recommends the gradual emancipation arid ultimate

removal of slaves -from Kentucky.

' '-,.---.- .- .,----- "S. ---------------------------------
Four persons were recently killed, and fifteen or tventy wounded, by the breaking through the bridge at Hudson, Ohio, of a passengertrain on the Pittsbnrg and Cleveland Railroad.

Mr. Fessenden is nominated Senator from Maine, and the Treasury

portfolio is virtually vacant.

The latest quotation of gold at New York was about 127 per cent premium.

The Olustee made her escape from Wilmington on the night of Dec.25 while the fleet was engaged in the attack on Port Fisher. On the following day she was chased by the United States gnu-boat Lsbsn, but finally turned upon her pursuer; and the Lilian, having only two guns against five carried by the privateer, was forced to reek sAfety in flight. The Olustee pursued for some distance, but the Lilian escaped.

The Shenandoah has burnt several more American merchant-ships.

The Queen has approved of M. Henri Du Ohcsnc as Consul at liong-Kong for the Emperor of the French. Her Majesty has also approved of Mr. A. Augustus Porter as Consul at Clifton, Canada; of Mr. Daniel IC. Hobart as Consul at Windsor, Canada; of Mr. James Weldon, as Consul at Freacett, Canada; of Mr. William H. tuestis as Comet at St. Lambert and iceaguell, Canada; and of Mr. Sylvanus B. Hence as Consul at Kingston, Conada for the United States of America. Her Majesty has likewise approved ti Den hancisco d'Uneil]a as Consul at Malta for the Queen of Spain,
-u*gwnot-exlcO.

Uny a gentleman who has Mad", several millions

euling Vig bloc alc-uenning auti who spoke of one of his

cruain ving l)otchmcn craft as having gone to resume her career vf fa1zes A new blockaderunner has just had her career cut

estably short in the Mexsey bse&szin" her back close to the north-Wt U.ht-sUp anti gong to pieces aLost instanter. A life-boat

which pet o to rescue her crew capsized by the violence of the

aaiti ueesly all her gallant boatmen were drowned. We read

that ther

U11. nf ;t" wtce mprovidel with life-belts, which, according to the

-

.hha Camlez, Hottr.n, whose curious volume on "Th History ajij" naiu a ye7 droll sketch of a pack supposed to - been desed by t late Count d'Orsav, is about to give us an n edition of the faaaoas work of American humour called Ward hiz Book," Three or four years have passed since . JoernaI v essadto netke occaelaIjyalittle comic paper

at New Tock called flerfty Fair. To this paper (which H. Browne, whose pseudouym is ns Ward," as ti.c chief neettrjl r. The "Book" itself is

pieos of drilery. Artemus Ward is suppose'l to be a se thnwaao. travc.leng through the Seates an't con1mentin.

as he, 90" Along. His apOca-yphalna0

a 1rac, .! en es a mti'.th
.WINTE1I SKETCHES IN NEW YORK.

A CORRESPONDENT in New York, to whose pencil we owe the Illustrations of skating and sleigbing in that city, 'writes as follows:

14 A few days before Christmas we had a heavy snowstorm here,

which brought out the sleighs and made things look seasonable, Some of the omnibus proprietors laid up their wheeled 'vehicles for the time, substituting for them immense concerns on runners, drawn by six horses, and capable of holding some forty persons each when

closely packed. I send herewith a sketch of one of these omnibussleighs. Their occupation is a transient and uncertain one in New York arid, even ast write, the snow has quite disappeared, and. mud is the order of things once more.

"The brief spell of cold weather also brought out the skaters in great

force. For two or three nights many thousands of persons enjoyed.

the sports of the ice in Central Park, the lakes and. ponds of which favourite place of resort were in excellent condition. The scene at night, on such occasions. is very striking. Powerful burners are placed so as to illuminate the whole surface, and the light from these is reflected with great splendour by' the clear ice. I send herewith a

sketch of one of these night scenes. The buildings on the further

shore of the lake contain accommodation for the skaters. There are

refreshment-rooms, a cloak-room, and. another room where skates are let

out on hire. Hero there is along counter, behind which a great array o

skates of every description is displayed. upon the wall. Groups of

persons are always collected round the great stove, which is a feature

of all public rooms in New York. Numbers of young girls, attended by their beaus, are to be seen here, as skating has become quite the

fashion since the opening of Central Park, some four or five years

ago. The last day I visited the place I noticed in the group around

the stove a 'very respectable looking negro woman, dressed in rather

an expensive set of furs. She had with her two small boys of colour, whom I afterwards saw wheeling about on their skates with great glee. The policeman in the sketch is one of the parkkeepers, who are picked from the metropolitan police, and are remarkably
ne, soldierly-looking fellows, dLessed. in a very becoming, light-grey

uniform. The Americans are a progressive people. I observed that. some of the boys here who assist skaters in putting on their irons have discarded the time-honoured gimlet, so long and favourably known in connection with skates; using instead of it a bit an brace."
