<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI.2//EN" "iln.dtd"
[<!ENTITY % iln-entities SYSTEM
"/Beck-files/ILN/ILNCVS/ilnxml/iln_entities">
 %iln-entities; ]>

<TEI.2>
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated London News
Perspective</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Compiled and edited by</resp>
               <name>Sandra Still</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent/>         
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Emory University</pubPlace>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine>
            </address>
            <availability>
               <p>2005 Emory University.
Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce,
distribute or display the contributions to the work claimed by Emory
University for non-profit educational purposes, provided this header
is included in its entirety.  For inquiries about commercial uses,
contact the Lewis H. Beck Center, Woodruff Library, Emory University,
Atlanta, Georgia 30322</p>
            </availability>
            <date>2005</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated
London News Perspective</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
               <biblScope type="volume">Volume 46</biblScope> 
 <date>January to June 1865</date>
</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p/>
         </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	<change><date>November 2005</date>
          <respStmt><name>Robin Conner, </name><resp>Beck Center Staff.</resp></respStmt>
          <item>Encoded text according to TEI guidelines.</item>
	</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div1 id="iln46.001" n="Illustrated London News: Volume 46" type="Volume"> 
            <head>Illustrated London News: Volume 46</head>
<docDate>January to June 1865</docDate>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.001" n= "The prospect westerly is not so auspicious" type="Article">
<head>[THE PROSPECT WESTERLY IS NOT SO AUSPICIOUS]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 2</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>....The prospect westerly is not so auspicious. Would that it were
in our power to foretell the certain termination of the struggle in
America before the year 1865 has closed! We can only look and sigh
over the ruin that is there running its course, and try to hope that,
when the end comes, whether this year or next, or even at some point
of time beyond them, it will bring with it some compensation, which
future generations at least may regard as commensurate with immediate
sacrifices and sufferings. It is to the West we look with most anxiety
in respect of our own international relations. The discharge of the
St. Albans raiders by Judge Coursal, upon a mere technical flaw, might
easily open the way to war between us and our transatlantic kinsmen if
the two Governments were not guided by a spirit of self-restraint
towards each other. Happily, as on the part of Canada the judgment of
its legal officer has been spontaneously repudiated, so on the part of
the United States the rash order of its military officer has been
discountenanced; and where there is a frank recognition of each others
good faith, and an evident desire on both sides to clear up accidental
misunderstandings, we need not allow our anxiety to deepen into
apprehension. Hitherto we have maintained our neutrality without
compromise, and, with it, amicable relations with Mr. Lincoln's
Government. There is ground enough in the facts of which we have
present information for regarding a rupture between the two greatest
maritime Powers in the world as a calamity which is equally and
earnestly deprecated by both, and is therefore
improbable....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.002" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 2</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>By the arrival of the Hibernia we have news from New York to the
afternoon of Dec. 24.</p>
<p>General Hood's defeated army succeeded in crossing the Duck river,
in spite of General Thomas's hot pursuit. On the 20th ult. Hood was
joined at Columbia by Forrest; and on the 22nd he had reached Pulaski,
seventy-five miles south of Nashville, still closely pressed by the
Federal cavalry. The Federal accounts estimate Hood's losses at 17,000
men, killed, wounded and taken prisoners; and represent Thomas's
losses not to have exceeded 5000 men.</p>
<p>General Sherman reports on the 13th ult., from Ossibau Sound, that
he had captured Fort M'Allister, opened communication with the fleet,
destroyed the railroads leading to Savannah, and invested the
city. His left rested on the Savannah River, three miles above the
city, and his right on the Ogeechee River, at King's Bridge. He had an
agreeable and unmolested march. His armywas in splendid order, and
amply supplied with provisions. During his march of 300 miles Sherman only
lost about 1000 men, and he arrived in front of Savannah with more
stores, provisions, and horses than he started with. About 700 negroes
joined him on the route. He destroyed 200 miles of railroad. He
estimates the garrison of Savannah, under Hardee, at 15,000, with
about 25,000 inhabitants. According to Confederate despatches "all was
well" at Savannah to the 19th ult.; and there was no further
intelligence respecting the progress of General Sherman's
operations. A letter from Admiral Dahlgren states that he is buoying
the Savannah River for an attack on the city in conjunction with other
forces.</p>
<p>The Southern journals alleged that General Breckenridge had
defeated the Federal General Burbridge, in the neighbourhood of
Saltville, in Western Virginia.</p>
<p>Admiral Porter's whole fleet was reported by a Confederate telegram
to have been in sight from Fort Fisher, near Wilmington, on the 21st
ult.; and the Confederate commander, General Bragg, added in his
despatch a confident declaration that he could hold Wilmington. It was
said that Porter's fleet had been crippled by a storm, and no
immediate attack on Wilmington was expected.</p>
<p>Advices received at New York state that the exchange of prisoners
at Charleston being ended, the bombardment of the city will be
immediately recommenced.</p>
<p>The Federal gun-boat Narcissus has been blown up by a torpedo at
Mobile.</p>
<p>Mr. Lincoln has cancelled General Dix's order as to the pursuit of
raiders across the frontier into Canada. Some of the New York papers
complain of this. In Congress it had been moved to prepare an armed
force for the Lakes.</p>
<p>A draught of 300,000 men has been ordered. All absentees are also
ordered to rejoin their regiments immediately.</p>
<p>Secretary Fessenden is about to contract a new loan of 100,000,000
dollars.</p>
<p>Mr. Seward has ordered that persons coming to the United States,
except immigrants, must have passports. This regulation applies
specially to persons coming from the British provinces.</p>
<p>Both branches of the Federal Congress had adjourned to the 5th
inst.</p>
<p>Gold was quoted at New York, on the afternoon of the 24th ult., at
220&#x00B7;.</p>
<p>In the Southern Congress there have been some noteworthy
movements. First, a resolution has been introduced to send
commissioners to treat with Federal commissioners upon the restoration
of peace. Mr. Foote, a member of the Confederate Senate, made a
speech, in which he declared the Confederacy to be on the verge of
ruin, and blamed Jefferson Davis for all the late military
disasters. Mr. Foote afterwards withdrew from the Senate. The <hi
rend="italic">Richmond Enquirer</hi> says that General Lee is in
favour of arming the negroes. The same paper declares that if
independence can only be attained by the sacrifice of slavery that
sacrifice must be made.</p>
<p rend="center">BRITISH NORTH AMERICA.</p>
<p>The Canadian Parliament is summoned to meet on the 19th inst.</p>
<p>A proclamation has been issued by the Governor-General of Canada
calling out a large force of volunteer militia to prevent raids from
Canada into the United States, and to maintain order on the
frontier. Thirty companies of Canadian volunteers have been sent to
the frontier.</p>
<p>Three of the St. Albans raiders have been recaptured. The discharge
of the raiders by Judge Coursal is condemned by both the Government
and rebel newspaper organs in Canada, and the majority of the people
appear to be indignant at the critical condition in which the
relations between the Northern States and the provinces have been
placed by it. Mr. Lamothe, the chief of the Montreal police, had
resigned, it was supposed, to avoid dismissal. The bankers and
merchants of Montreal had addressed a memorial to the Governor-General
setting forth their desire that a fair and honest neutrality should be
maintained between the belligerent States of America....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.003" n= "The Sinking of the Confederate Steamer
      Florida, in the James River." type="Article">
<head>THE SINKING OF THE CONFEDERATE STEAMER FLORIDA, IN THE JAMES RIVER.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 5-6</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE SINKING OF THE<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">Confederate Steamer<lb/>Florida, In The
James<lb/>River.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">It</hi> would have been disagreeable to the
national pride of the Americans if the Federal Government at
Washington, unable to answer the diplomatic remonstrances provoked by
the late violation of a neutral harbour of Brazil, had been obliged to
send back the Confederate steamer Florida, captured illegally by the
Wachusetts at Bahia on the 7th of October, and to replace their prize
where she was taken, beneath the sheltering jurisdiction of the
Brazilian sovereignty. From this mortification they have been saved,
as already reported, by the happy accident or expedient of sinking the
Florida ten fathoms under water in Hampton Roads, at the mouth of the
James River, where she was unaccountably run down by a Federal
transport-steamer, the Alliance, on the 19th of November, going to the
bottom a few hours afterwards.</p>
<p>The Illustration we now publish is from a sketch by Mr. Edward
L. Henry, of New York, who witnessed the event. The Florida is shown
as she appeared, having lost her mizenmast in the conflict with the
Wachusetts at Bahia. The ship seen to the right hand is an ironclad or
Monitor, named the Atlanta, which was stationed as a guardship at the
mouth of the river. In the distance is Newport News, with a military
camp on shore. The following account of the destruction of the Florida
is given by the correspondent of a New York paper:--</p>
<p>"On the 19th the Florida went to Norfolk to coal, and just before
starting was run into by the transport-steamer Alliance. She was was
in very bad condition when captured, and all the time since her
arrival here she has leaked so badly as to keep the steam-pump engaged
continually. The collision with the Alliance greatly increased the
volume of the water which constantly poured into her. About nine
o'clock on Sunday evening one of the pumps on board suddenly gave
out. Before more assistance arrived the water had risen considerably
above the fire-room floor, so that it was found necessary to put the
fires out. The pump-engine was thus stopped, and the water came
pouring in at a fearful rate. It was impossible at any time, after it
was found the ill-fated ship was sinking, to move her toward the
shore, as there was but 7 lb. pressure of steam--just sufficient to
work the pumps. Neither were there means at hand for towing her
ashore. In a few minutes after sending the two boats to the Florida,
Captain Woodward, of the Atlanta, came himself on<pb n="6"/> board to
see what could be done to keep her afloat. But it was apparent that
she must soon sink, and the men were ordered to save their effects and
prepare to leave her to her fate. The Florida kept rapidly filling so
that at seven o'clock the water was a foot above the berth-deck. At
the same time that Mr. Baker signalled the Atlanta he sent a
telepathic message to Admiral Porter at this place that the Florida
was sinking. The Admiral immediately ordered the tug Page to steam up
to the Florida and tow her into shoal water towards the shore. The tug
came alongside at 7.15, but the Florida was by this time so near
sinking that it was deemed dangerous to attach it, as in going down
she would take the tug along with her. A few minutes after, with eight
feet of water in her, she careened over, and disappeared stern
foremost. Mr. Baker and Captain Woodward remained alongside in the tug
until she went under. The Florida had all her guns and everything on
board just as when she was captured. There is a feeling of general
satisfaction among naval officers here at her fate. It is considered
much preferable to have her disposed of here, and then indemnity be
offered to the Brazilian Government, than suffer the humiliation of
taking her backs and seeing her saluted as she would enter the harbour
of Rio Janeiro in triumph, with the rebel flag flying. This would have
been a most bitter pill to the American officers who would have had to
accompany her."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln46.1296.004" n="The Confederate Steamer Florida Sunk in
      the James River." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 5</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv46p5">
<head>THE CONFEDERATE STEAMER FLORIDA SUNK IN
      THE JAMES RIVER.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.005" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 7</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....But they are saying at the clubs, too, that Lord Lyons will not
return to Washington. His Lordship has but recently returned to this
country on leave of absence; but, if the sages of Pall-mall are to be
believed, he will not resume his arduous and thankless mission. He is
said to be suffering from an affection of the eyes; and, certainly,
the climate of Washington--scorching in summer and scarifyingly cold
in winter--is not favourable to the cure of affections of any
kind. But who is to replace an amiable and discreet diplomatist, who,
all things considered, has been the very best Minister we have ever
accredited to the United States? Washington might be an agreeable
change from Madrid to Sir John Crampton; but, alas! Sir John knows the
District of Columbia but too well. Did not our cousin turn him out of
it and out of the country to boot, ten years ago? Lord Napier; too,
has been promoted; but were it possible to take him from
St. Petersburg, his return to America would eminently please the
Northerners, among whom his frank and cordial manners have made him
exceedingly popular....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.006" n= "An Atlas of America" type="Article">
<head>[AN ATLAS OF AMERICA]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 18</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>An Atlas of America, illustrating the physical and political
geography of North and South America and the West India Islands, has
opportunely been published by Mr. Cotton, of New York, and
Messrs. Bacon and Co., of Paternoster-row. The maps and city plans,
sixty-five in number, admirably executed by George W. Cotton, are
accompanied by descriptions, geographical, statistical, and
historical, by Richard Swainson Fisher, M.D. At this eventful period
in the history of the States, of Canada, of Mexico, and of parts of
the southern continent, this elaborate work supplies a great
want.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.007" n= "The Magazines." type="Article">
<head>THE MAGAZINES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 22</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE MAGAZINES.</p>
<p>....The opening paper in <hi rend="italic">Fraser</hi>, "President
Lincoln," by an American Abolitionist (Mr. Conway, we imagine), is
remarkable as a manifesto from that small but earnest band whose
triumphant contest in the name of principle against oppression,
supported by the entire strength of a mighty nation, forms as
remarkable and as encouraging a chapter in the history of the world as
the Reformation itself. We fear, however, that it is plain, on the
writer's own showing, that the Abolitionist leaders were incompetent
to carry out the movement they had so nobly inaugurated. An erroneous
fallacy pervades his essay, he fancies that he and his friends
represent the sense of the American people, and talks as though the
chief magistrate of the nation were bound to make himself the mere
instrument of a bare majority of the people of Massachusetts. Had
Mr. Lincoln done so, he and Massachusetts and the negro would long ago
have been swept away together in a tempest of popular wrath, and his
caution has been the salvation of the very men by whom he is so
fiercely denounced. He has been to Garrison and Phillips what Peel was
to Cobden, or Cavour to Mazzini--a practical, worldly wise man,
standing on a far lower moral level, but without whom lofty principles
and ardent imaginations would never have appeared in the guise of
realities....</p>
<p>This month's <hi rend="italic">Blackwood</hi> witnesses the
conclusion of "Tony Butler," which has not wholly redeemed the promise
of its commencement, but is still entitled to the praise of an
interesting, animated tale. "The Man and the Monkey" is a most amusing
story, of a kind almost peculiar to <hi
rend="italic">Blackwood</hi>. "Cornelius O'Dowd" writes with sense and
point, except when treating of America, when his remarks betray great
flippancy and ignorance. The English officer's account of his visit to
the Confederate States is more satisfactory, though it is impossible
to repress a groan over the stupidity which could turn such splendid
opportunities to such poor account. However, we must take him as he
is, and be thankful. Charleston and the Chattanooga campaign are the
subjects of his present instalment. With characteristic infelicity he
managed to arrive at General Bragg' head-qnarters just too late for
the battle of Chicamauga, and to quit them just before that of
Missionary Ridge....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.008" n= "A company has been formed" type="Article">
<head>[A COMPANY HAS BEEN FORMED]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 23</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A company has been formed in New York, styled "The American and
British West India Cotton Company," which has leased for a term of
years 2000 acres of land on Long Island, one of the group of
Bahamas.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1296.009" n= "The seal of the Confederate States of America" type="Article">
<head>[THE SEAL OF THE CONFEDERATE STATES OF AMERICA]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1296</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 23</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-07">January 7, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The seal of the Confederate States of America, the composition of
which is by J. H. Foley, R. A., contains as a centre a representation
of that statue of Washington which was executed by the American
sculptor, Crawford, and erected at Richmond. The figure is mounted and
in uniform, as commanding in an engagement. It is surrounded by a
wreath beautifully composed of the most valuable vegetable products of
the Southern soil, as tobacco, rice, maize, cotton, wheat, and
sugar-cane. The rim bears the legend, "The Confederate States of
America, 22nd February, 1862. Deo Vindice." The seal is of silver, and
its diameter is from three to four inches.</p>
<p>There appears to be as large an amount of carelessness on the part
of the letter-writing community in America as in the Old Country. The
report of Postmaster Dennison shows that 3,580,325 dead letters were
received during the past year--over 9000 a day. Many of these letters
contained money, deeds, bills of exchange, draughts, cheques,
jewellery, and other valuables. Some of them were misdirected, others
not directed at all, other, unstamped, and others only partially
directed. Thousands of these dead letters were returned to the
writers, but the great majority had to be destroyed.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1297.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1297</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 26</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-14">January 14, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>By the Peruvian we have news from New York to the evening of
Dec. 31.</p>
<p>Savannah has fallen into the hands of the Federals. General Sherman
thus pithily notifies the welcome fact to President Lincoln:--</p>
<p rend="right">Savannah, Georgia, Dec. 22.</p>
<p>I beg to present you as a Christmas gift the city of Savannah, with
150 heavy guns and plenty of ammunition, and also about 25,000 bales
of cotton.</p>
<p rend="right"><hi rend="smallcaps">W. J. Sherman</hi>,
Major-General.</p>
<p>General Sherman occupied the city on the morning of the 21st ult.,
and found the 20,000 inhabitants, he says, "quiet and well disposed."
The Confederate General Hardee had previously rejected a summons to
surrender; but during the 20th ult. he succeeded in transporting all
his infantry and field artillery across the river from the city to a
place called Union Causeway, and had thus escaped the assault which
the Federals intended to make, and withdrawn his troops before the
Federal works had advanced enough to impede his passage of the
river. Savannah advices of the 26th ult. report that an effort was
being made to intercept General Hardee's retreat before he could reach
the Broad River; but the Richmond journals stated that General Hardee
had arrived at Charleston.</p>
<p>As a set-off against the Federal success at Savannah, we have to
record the failure of the Federal attack on Wilmington. General Butler
had returned to Fort Monroe, and the transports with his troops on
board were also arriving there. Admiral Porter, with his frigates and
monitors, had proceeded to Beaufort, and was there awaiting further
orders. Admiral Porter, in his report of the operations, stated that
on the 24th ult., after a large powder-ship had been blown up under
the walls of Fort Fisher, without doing any damage, his fleet
bombarded the fort, and in an hour silenced the Confederate fire. On
the afternoon of the 25th 8000 troops, under the command of General
Weitzel, landed under cover of the fire from the fleet, captured two
batteries, and advanced within fifty yards of Fort Fisher, some of the
men even entering the outworks. General Weitzel, however, deemed a
successful attack impracticable, and reembarked on the same evening,
though about 1000 men remained ashore during the following day, in
consequence of the state of the weather. General Butler informed
Admiral Porter, on the night of the 25th ult., that an assault was
impracticable, as Fort Fisher was substantially uninjured as a
defensive work by the navy fire, and could only be reduced by a
regular siege; and he added that he should return to Fort Monroe as
soon as the transports for his troops were ready. Admiral Porter
vainly assured General Butler that the fire of his ships could keep
the Confederates inside the fort from showing their heads until a
storming column should be within twenty yards of the works, and that
the capture of the fort by assault, if attempted, would have been
easier than was supposed. An interesting feature in Admiral Porter's
report is his condemnation of the 100-pounder Parrott guns, which he
says were unfit for the service. Six of them burst, killing and
wounding forty-five men.</p>
<p>The notion of the powder-ship which, as stated above, was blown up
near Fort Fisher with such trivial result, was suggested by the
effect of the explosion at Erith; and the method of fitting out and
firing the vessel is thus described:--</p>
<q><p>The United States steam gun-boat Louisiana was taken to the
Norfolk Navy yard about a month ago, and such changes made in her as
would adapt her to receive the powder. She was also disguised as much
aspoesible, so as to give her the appearance of a
blockade-runner. After all the required changes had been made the
Louisiana was towed to Craney Island, where she was loaded. The hold
was left empty, as the powder at the explosion was desired to be as
much as possible above water. The powder was contained in a bulkhead
occupying a portion of the berth-deck and extending nearly to the
boilers. the first tier of powder was placed in the barrels with the
heads taken out, and the remainder was in bags. For the purpose of
exploding the powder, there were three clock-fuses placed in the
vessel, one in each gangway and one aft, near the boilers. From each
of these a patent Gomez fuse led completely round the vessel, and
terminated one in the hold and the others in the centre of the
berth-deck. Any one of the fuses ignited would fire all the others,
because each one crossed one of the others, and wherever they crossed
they were grafted. There were no absolute soundings of the shore in
the vicinity of Fort Fisher, and it was only a matter of conjecture
how near the Louisiana could go before she ran aground. When her
bottom first grated the sand her furnace-doors were to be thrown open,
the engines left running, and caps placed upon the fuses, the clocks
set, and everybody hurriedly transferred to the picket launch, the
tug, and the boats. The explosion was expected to take place in
thirty or forty minutes, and by that time the party, with their
steam-launch, would probably be five miles away. A provision was made,
however, in case something should occur--some accident befall the
launch. Under such circumstances they were to take the surf-boat and
row for life till<pb n="27"/> the time for the explosion, when they
were to jump overboard, go with ropes and buoys as far as possible
from the boat, submerge to the head, and, with cotton in their ears,
await the shock.</p></q>
<p>The Federals have been again repulsed in an attempt to land on
Roanoke Island; and an expedition by Granger against Mobile had,
according to Confederate accounts, been driven back.</p>
<p>There are contradictory reports as to Hood's movement. One account
says that he had crossed the Tennessee. Another states that the
Federal gun-boats had prevented him from crossing, and even adds that
the remnant of his army had been captured.</p>
<p>Although it was declared that the Federal Generals Stoneman and
Burbridge had been defeated in Western Virginia, it seems that they
have captured Saltville, the great manufactory of salt for the
South.</p>
<p>At Richmond there has been no new movement, but it was reported
that Lee was preparing to attack the Federals. The Southern press urge
Lee's appointment as Commander-in-Chief of the armies of the
Confederacy.</p>
<p>President Lincoln has been made an LL.D. by the College of New
Jersey.</p>
<p>The President has remitted the sentence of the court-martial upon
Admiral Wilkes to a period of one year from its date. The sentence
suspended him three years from the service.</p>
<p>The Brazilian demand for explanation and reparation for the
seizure of the Florida has been replied to by a note from
Mr. Seward. Regret is expressed for the proceeding at Bahia. Captain
Collins is suspended and ordered to be tried by court-martial. The
United States Consul at Bahia is dismissed, and the men captured in
the Florida are to be set at liberty. Mr. Seward says the United
States have a complaint against Brazil for recognising the
Confederates as belligerents, but he adds that it is no part of the
duty of an officer to take upon himself the redressing of his
country's wrongs.</p>
<p>President Jefferson Davis has issued a declaration that
B. G. Burley--who has been apprehended in Canada, and who headed the
men who endeavoured to take the steamer Michigan on Lake Erie and then
release the Confederate prisoners on Johnson's island--is a
Confederate officer, and acted under the authority of the Confederate
Government.</p>
<p>The esteemed veteran English actor, Mr. James William Wallack--a
contemporary of Edmund Keen and Elliston--died at New York on
Christmas Day, aged sixty-nine, having been born in London in 1795. He
made his first appearance in America at the Park Theatre, New York, in
1818, and his great success and popularity with the play-going public
of that city induced him to divide his time thenceforth between
England and the United States. In 1836 he opened the National Theatre,
New York, and remained manager of it until it was destroyed by fire,
in 1839. He then returned to England, and played for some time at the
Princess's Theatre. In 1851 he once more crossed the Atlantic, with
the intention of residing permanently in America. The New York papers
record his decease with strong expressions of sympathy and regret.</p>
<p>The steam-ship North America foundered while on her voyage from New
Orleans to New York. She had on board 203 sick soldiers, twelve cabin
passengers, and a crew of forty-four men. Of these only sixty-two
persons were saved. Among the lost were Colonel Saunders and
Lieutenant-Colonel Horn.</p>
<p rend="center">BRITISH NORTH AMERICA.</p>
<p>The Governor of Canada issued a proclamation offering a reward of
200 dollars for the apprehension of each of the St. Albans
raiders. More of the raiders have been re-apprehended in Canada, and
sent for examination to Montreal. Their trial began on the 27th ult.,
in the Superior Court, before Mr. Justice Smith. It was stated that
three of the raiders had made their way into the United States, and
had enlisted into the Federal service in New Hampshire, but had been
recognised and arrested.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1297.002" n= "'From Erith to Wilmington.'" type="Article">
<head>["FROM ERITH TO WILMINGTON."]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1297</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 30-31</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-14">January 14, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps"><hi rend="italic">London:
Saturday, January</hi> 14, 1865.</hi></p>
<p>"From Erith to Wilmington." The quiet little village, on the right
bank of the Thames, with its interesting old church and sundial
thereon, its yacht proclivities, and its water-side population, who
seem to get their living by leaning, in a long row, against the wooden
rails and, abusing one another in some dialect of Kent, was awfully
astonished on the morning when the powder blew up, by nobody's fault,
and in a second converted a scene of orderly industry into a hideous
ruin. But it must be almost as much astounded to learn that the story
of that explosion, having found its way across the Atlantic, set<pb
n="31"/> the Federal Admiral Porter upon a scheme for reducing a
strong Confederate fortress. Such, it appears, was the case; the ruin
wrought by that Erith catastrophe would, it was hoped, be paralleled
at Fort Fisher. Every clever precaution was taken to ensure success. A
tremendous quantity of powder was stowed on board a ship, and the most
ingenious system of clockwork was devised to fire the train at the
right moment. A grand expedition sailed against Wilmington, bearing
this floating mine with it, and in due course, and under favourable
circumstances, the powder-vessel was moored at the spot which had been
judged the best. Brave men fixed her at her moorings, set the terrible
clocks going, and escaped. The expedition watched with bated breath
for the eruption of the volcano. The clocks were faithful,</p>
<p rend="center">The nitre fired, and, while the dreadful
sound;<lb/>Responsive shook the yielding air around,</p>
<p>the assailants' hearts beat high; and, as the smoke cleared, the
Federals hoped to see a ruin where Fort Fisher had been. "The shock
was nothing like so severe as was expected," writes the frank sailor;
"it shook the vessel <hi rend="italic">some</hi>, broke one or two
glasses, but nothing more." Wilmington is luckier than Erith. However,
Admiral Porter, with a fine squadron, was not the man to be satisfied
with one failure. The experiment had been fruitless; but he had his
guns, and plenty of them, and he brought up his ironclads, and
commenced a fierce bombardment, which he describes, in the language of
the defender of Sebastopol, as a <hi rend="italic">feu
d'enfer</hi>. It silenced several of the fort batteries, blew up two
magazines, and set the place on fire. But there was delay in bringing
on the troops for the assault; and when it was effected the assailants
found that they could not succeed. When 3000 men had landed, the
Admiral was informed that they were re-embarking. Some brave feats
were performed, but General Butler did not see his way to storm. The
Admiral was clearly disgusted. He uses the ordinary civil language
towards a brother officer, and is certain that the latter had good
reasons for his conduct, but the gallant Porter thinks that it "would
have been worth while to make the attempt after coming so far." But
then he is only a smart sailor, while Butler, who has been an
attorney, may have known better when to issue his <hi
rend="italic">nolle prosequi</hi>. Finally, the attack was given up,
the expedition returned to head-quarters, and Wilmington is safe and
defiant.</p>
<p>This is an item which the Confederates are proud to set against the
series of Federal successes that marked the close of the year. They
have fairly beaten off one of the most formidable squadrons ever sent
against a fortress, and have been able to laugh at the failure of a
new and terrific-seeming engine of war. They gain nothing, it is true;
while Atlanta has been destroyed, and Savannah has been captured; but
they have saved a far more important port than either, and may
reasonably be exultant.</p>
<p>As regards the state of the war generally, at the opening of 1865,
we have less reason to be ashamed of stating that it is impossible for
people here to form a decided opinion, inasmuch as it is clear that
neither North nor South has an exact knowledge of the case. Sherman's
brilliant retreat, or march, has proved this. The Americans do not
know their own country. No one in the Federal district would speak
confidently of the probable success of Sherman; but those who did
attempt to demonstrate the truth were all wrong. They thought that he
was to pass through a poor and needy country; and so sincere was their
pity for the hardships he was to undergo that the most compassionate
articles were written upon the state of his army, and a painful
contrast was drawn between the meagre Christmas fare of his troops and
the ample comforts provided for the grand army of the Potomac. The
truth turned out to be that Sherman's men were marching through a rich
agricultural region, had the best food, never wanted a meal, and
arrived at Savannah in the highest health and strength. The Northern
writers now admit that folk generally did not know the resources of
Georgia. The truth is that the masses in America, with all their real
sharpness and all their flood of cheap newspapers, are very ignorant
about most things; and smart as is their talk, its chief cleverness is
that it covers a singular absence of exact knowledge. But, on the
other hand, the Confederates seem to have been equally uncertain as to
what Sherman could or could not do. His able feints at Macon and
Augusta no doubt bewildered them; but they must have known, one might
suppose, whether he could be encountered at all; and yet the most
opposite statements on the subject proceeded from the Richmond
papers. They know now that he marched all the way in triumph, his main
body scarcely hearing a cannon, his detachments burning and laying
waste, his whole force feeding on the fat of the land, and the negroes
crowding to his ranks, and having to be sent away sometimes by
force. But until the event had occurred neither South nor North could
give solid reasons for its anticipations. It is hardly to be expected
that English readers, even with the beautiful maps published under
Federal authority, should know more; although we have some idea that
our military men, with those charts before them, arrive at sounder
judgments than many folk in America, and that some of our journalists
give far more complete and truthful details than we find in the
Northern or the Southern press. But, so far as we can venture on a
decision, we must say that the enormous resources of the North are now
telling distressingly upon its antagonist, and that the admitted want
of men in the South, evidenced, too, by the renewed proposal to arm
the negroes, seems to point towards a crisis. The splendid valour
which the Confederates have displayed is unabated, and must not only
command respect in Europe, but in the North, and, with a generous
enemy, will certainly improve the terms on which the two parties will
soon, we trust, confer. Our own Foreign Secretary has said that,
though we are strictly neutral, the subjugation of the South would be
an injury to the cause of humanity, and we trust that both the word
and the idea will be alike discarded. The moment is not inopportune
for the discussion of an honourable peace, which must be obtained by
mutual concessions; and it could be wished that some Nestor could step
in between the transatlantic Ajax and Ulysses, and say,</p>
<p rend="center">"Forbear, my sons, your further might to
prove.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1297.003" n= "The Town and Port of Savannah." type="Article">
<head>THE TOWN AND PORT OF SAVANNAH.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1297</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 42</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-14">January 14, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE TOWN AND PORT OF SAVANNAH.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> town and port of Savannah, which
General Sherman has captured without a siege, by the retirement of the
Confederate General Hardee, whose forces were unable to defend the
place, is situated on the right bank of the River Savannah, eighteen
miles from the sea. It is the terminus of three railroads connecting
it with the neighbouring States of Alabama, Tennessee, and South
Carolina. The Savannah river, eed, marks the frontier between South
Carolina and the State of Georgia, to which the town or city of
Savannah belongs. The population was, previously to the war, about
25,000, and the place was a thriving mart for cotton, rice and lumber,
but especially for the Sea-Island cotton, the most valuable kind, that
is grown, produced nowhere except in the low lands along this
coast. The harbour is good, there being from 18 ft. to 21 ft. of water
at low-tide over the bar at the mouth of the river, while vessels
drawing 13 ft. can get up to the wharves of the town, and those
drawwing 15 ft. or 16 ft. may go as far as Five-fathom Hole, three
miles below the town. There is steam navigation up the river to
Augusta, a distance of 140 miles. The town itself stands upon a sandy
flat, about 40 ft. above the water. It is laid out with great
regularity, in spacious streets and squares, crossing each other at
right angles; the streets are lined with a double row of trees, and
the squares have inclosed gardens in the centre, like those of
London. There are fourteen or fifteen churches, one of which, the
Independent Presbyterian, is an elegant and costly structure of
granite; a Jewish synagogue, an academy, a courthouse, gaol, exchange,
barracks, arsenal, theatre, market-house, and various charitable
institutions. The accompanying Map or Plan will give some idea of the
capabilities of the place for military fortification.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln46.1297.004" n="The Environs of Savannah." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1297</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 42</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-14">January 14, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv46p42">
<head>THE ENVIRONS OF SAVANNAH.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1297.005" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1297</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 43</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-14">January 14, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> explosion of fifty-five tons of
gunpowder sufficed to frighten Erith out of its wits, wake Woolwich to
its foundations, and knock a considerable portion of the Thames
embankment into what is termed, in Hibernian parlance, "smithereens."
But 215 tons of powder exploded by the Federals under the lee of a
fort at Wilmington seem to have made no more impression on its walls
than the hundred plum buns full of calomel and prussic acid made on
Chunee, the mad elephant, at Exeter Change. Our cousins seem
unfortunate in their blow-ups. What a disastrous failure was the
springing of that mine before Petersburg last August! The
superstitious among the warriors of the great armada, which is said to
have returned to Fortress Monroe, may ascribe the failure of the
expedition to the presence of General Butler in a position of high
command. Jonah should have been cast overboard. But many of those who
are not superstitious might feel inclined to augur that no success
could attend an enterprise which was conducted on a Sunday and on
Christmas Day.</p>
<p>The veteran James Wallack is dead. Not many weeks have elapsed
since we saw him in his little bijou of a house in New York,
surrounded by the portraits of Macready, and Younge, and Kemble, with
his stalwart son Lester by his side, and a little grandson on his
knee, looking as handsome, and as dignified as of yore, and full of
his old humour, vivacity, and grace. He had been for many years a
cruel sufferer from the most atrocious form of rheumatic gout;
chalkstones exuded from him like drops of blood; his limbs were all
swathed in silken bandages; but at seventy years of age, and all but
bedridden, there were still in his eye and in his voice the vigour and
cheeriness of a young man. It was no wreck you saw before you. The
gallant and chivalrous Don C&#x00E6;sar, the dashing Massaroni, the
audacious Monseigneur, could still be recognised.</p>
<p>James W. Wallack was something more than a brilliant and versatile
actor. He was a high-minded and accomplished English gentleman. In his
own country the noblest in the land were glad to associate with him,
and more than one of his sons and nephews held commissions in the
British Army. He was the proprietor of the most charming theatre in
New York--a theatre wherein good English plays are performed by good
English actors, and had realised, we believe, a handsome fortune. His
son Lester, who is a great favourite as an actor in light comedy with
the New York public, and who is married to a sister of Mr. Millais,
the Academician, will, we presume, succeed to the management of
Wallack's Theatre. Some of the best traditions of the English stage in
its best days die with James W. Wallack....</p>
<p>We rarely allude to matters personal to ourselves; but there is an
acme of ill-treatment at which even the most patient camel will
groan. Among the multifarious publications of a Mr. Beeton we perceive
that there is a magazine specially devised for the delectation of
young ladies. We notice that Mr. Beeton, or Mr. Beeton's editor, has
chosen to appropriate two lengthy extracts from the series of papers
entitled "America in the Midst of War," written by the writer of these
"Echoes," and to publish them in his magazine as distinct articles,
appending to them the author's name. This is the more unseemly, as in
the whole course of our life we never wrote a line for Mr. Beeton. The
whole proceeding is exceedingly untradesmanlike. Every bookseller in
London knows that the experiences of the author of "America in the
Midst of War" are about to be published in book form; and had
Mr. Beeton's magazine been published in February instead of January,
an injunction in the Court of Chancery would very soon have taught him
the difference between <hi rend="italic">meum</hi> and <hi
rend="italic">tuum</hi>. Editorial scissors are excellent things, but
they are ill employed in taking the bread out of a labouring man's
mouth.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1297.006" n= "A fisherman recently hauled up" type="Article">
<head>[A FISHERMAN RECENTLY HAULED UP]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1297</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 43</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-14">January 14, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A fisherman recently hauled up a silver fork, marked "Atlantic,"
near the spot in Long Island Sound where the steamer Atlantic 
was wrecked on Nov. 27, 1846. It is described as a very heavy,
old-fashioned silver fork, bearing marks of long immersion in
water.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1297.007" n= "Mr. Edward Watkin, M.P." type="Article">
<head>[MR. EDWARD WATKIN, M.P.]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1297</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 43</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-14">January 14, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Mr. Edward Watkin, M.P., president of the Grand Trunk Railway of
Canada, had an interview yesterday week with Mr. Cardwell, at the
Colonial Office, with reference to the recent raids from Canada, and
to the consequent threatened proceedings on the part of the American
Government to adopt a stringent passport system for passengers, and a
rigid examination of goods passing between the States and the British
North American Provinces.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1297.008" n= "A son of Dr. Livingstone" type="Article">
<head>[A SON OF DR. LIVINGSTONE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1297</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 47</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-14">January 14, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A son of Dr. Livingstone, who enlisted in the Federal service
after the war broke out, was, in the latter part of last year, taken
prisoner by the Confederates.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 51</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>By the arrival of the Saxonia and the City of Manchester we have
intelligence from New York to the 7th inst.</p>
<p>Everything was quiet at Savannah, and good order prevailed among
the citizens. General Sherman is reported to be in occupation of both
banks of the Savannah. It is believed that his next point of attack
will be Branchville, where the Charleston and Savannah Railroad meets
the Augusta road. The Confederates are preparing to defend this
important position. The military authorities of Charleston have shown
their sense of the near neighbourhood of Sherman by issuing an order
making it imperative on all slaves, not having permssion to remain, to
quit the city, and interdicting entrance to the city to all
non-combatants not having proper passes. At the same time the
engineers have set to work on the land defences of the place.</p>
<p>Admiral Porter appears to have withdrawn from Wilmington. General
Bragg reports the Confederate losses during the bombardment as three
killed and fifty-five wounded. Two guns in Fort Fisher burst, two were
dismounted by the Confederates, and two by the Federal fire. Southern
despatches contain a report that the Federals had five vessels sunk
and fifteen disabled, and lost all their horses in the gale off
Wilmington.</p>
<p>It appears that the Federals were to be supported in their attack
on Wilmington by a gun-boat expedition up the Roanoke River. According
to Southern advices, this expedition met with a disaster. Six
gun-boats were blown up by torpedoes and 1000 men were lost.</p>
<p>General Hood's whole army succeeded in crossing the Tennessee
River, and his head-quarters were at Corinth, whence he had reported
that his troops had sustained no material losses since his defeat near
Nashville. The Richmond papers publish a story of the capture by Hood
of a Federal brigade after his retreat from Nashville; but Hood; in
his despatch, says nothing of such capture.</p>
<p>The only news of importance from before Richmond is the failure of
Butler's Dutch Gap canal. An attempt was made to open it on the 1st
inst., when the earth fell in and closed the channel.</p>
<p>Guerrillas are becoming numerous and troublesome on the Potomac. It
is reported that Mosby is rapidly recovering from his wounds, and will
soon be again in the saddle. [We give on page 56 an Illustration, from
a sketch by our Special Artist, of a rendezvous of Mosby's men in a
pass of the Blue Ridge.] No important military operations in the
valley of the Shenandoah are reported, but the movements of the
Confederates in that region are said to be mysterious. Federal cavalry
is scouring the Loudon valley.</p>
<p>On the 24th ult. a force of about 2500 Confederates, under General
Wirt Adams, was threatening Baton Rouge, Louisiana.</p>
<p>A special despatch from Cairo states that General Dona's raid on
the Mobile and Ohio Railroad was successful. Twenty-five bridges were
burnt, and 4000 carbines, a large amount of ammunition, and 300 army
waggons captured. Many officers and men were taken prisoners, and
thirty-two railway cars destroyed.</p>
<p>Secretary Stanton had left Washington for Fort Monroe, Hilton Head,
and Savannah, in order to confer personally with Generals Grant,
Foster, and Sherman.</p>
<p>It is rumoured that the Confederate Congress has secretly given
power to the Commander-in-Chief to detail 50,000 slaves for service in
the army as soldiers. Richmond papers continue to urge the Confederate
Congress to appoint General Lee Commander-in-Chief of all the
Confederate forces.</p>
<p>New-Year's Day falling on Sunday, the usual New-Year's holiday was
observed on Monday the 2nd. At Washington, the President's mansion was
freely thrown open, as is customary, and large crowds attended to pay
their respects. Among those present were all the foreign
Ambassadors.</p>
<p>The message of the Governor of New York to the Legislature
recommends a vigorous support of the war for the Union. the new
Governor calls upon the citizens to fill up their quota of the
draught.</p>
<p>In the Federal Senate, Mr. Wilson, of Massachusetts, presented a
petition from officers of the army and navy asking for increased
compensation. Mr. Sumner presented a petition from coloured citizens
of New York asking for the abolition of slavery in the United
States. The Senate passed a vote of thanks to General Sherman and his
army. In the House of Representatives, the joint resolution to abolish
slavery by Constitutional amendment was debated without result.</p>
<p>Admiral Farragut has received a present of 50,000 dols. from the
merchants and people of New York.</p>
<p>The Hon. George Miffin Dallas, ex-Vice-President of the United
States, and more recently Minister to the Court of St. James's, died,
at his residence, in Philadelphia, on Saturday morning, Dec. 31.</p>
<p>Four persons were recently killed, and fifteen or twenty wounded,
by the breaking through the bridge at Hudson, Ohio, of a
passenger-train on the Pittsburg and Cleveland Railroad.</p>
<p>Mr. Fessenden is nominated Senator from Maine, and the Treasury
portfolio is virtually vacant.</p>
<p>The latest quotation of gold at New York was about 127 per cent
premium.</p>
<p>The Olustee made her escape from Wilmington on the night of Dec. 25
while the fleet was engaged in the attack on Fort Fisher. On the
following day she was chased by the United States gun-boat Lilian, but
finally turned upon her pursuer; and the Lilian, having only two guns
against five carried by the privateer, was forced to seek safety in
flight. The Olustee pursued for some distance, but the Lilian
escaped.</p>
<p>The Shenandoah has burnt several more American
merchant-ships.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.002" n= "The Queen has approved" type="Article">
<head>[THE QUEEN HAS APPROVED]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 51</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The Queen has approved of M. Henri Du Chesne as Consul at Hong-Kong
for the Emperor of the French. Her Majesty has also approved of
Mr. A. Augustus Porter as Consul at Clifton, Canada; of Mr. Daniel
K. Hobart as Consul at Windsor, Canada; of Mr. James Weldon, as Consul
at Prescott, Canada; of Mr. William H. Euestis as Consul at
St. Lambert and Longueil, Canada; and of Mr. Sylvanus B. Hance as
Consul at Kingston, Conada for the United States of America. Her
Majesty has likewise approved of Don Francisco d'Uncilla as Consul at
Malta for the Queen of Spain.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.003" n= "Latest News From Abroad." type="Article">
<head>LATEST NEWS FROM ABROAD.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 51</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">LATEST NEWS FROM ABROAD.</p>
<p>The following telegrams have been received through Mr. Reuter's
office:--</p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">New York</hi>, Jan. 7.--The Governor of
Kentucky, in his Message to the Legislature, recommends the gradual
emancipation and ultimate removal of slaves from Kentucky.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln46.1298.004" n="The War in America: Rendezvous of
      Mosby's Men in the Pass of the Blue Ridge, Shenandoah
      Valley.--From a Sketch by our Special Artist.--See Page 66." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 56</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv46p56">
<head>THE WAR IN AMERICA: RENDEZVOUS OF
      MOSBY'S MEN IN THE PASS OF THE BLUE RIDGE, SHENANDOAH
      VALLEY.--FROM A SKETCH BY OUR SPECIAL ARTIST.--SEE PAGE 66.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.005" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 58</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....We met the other day a gentleman who has made several millions
sterling by American blockade-running, and who spoke of one of his
cunning Flying Dutchmen craft as having "gone to resume her career of
usefulness." A new blockade-runner has just had her career cut
lamentably short in the Mersey, breaking her back close to the
north-west light-ship and going to pieces almost instanter. A
life-boat which put off to rescue her crew capsized by the violence of
the waves, and nearly all her gallant boatmen were drowned. We read
that they were unprovided with life-belts, which, according to the
rules of the service, they should have worn....</p>
<p>Mr. John Camden Hotten, whose curious volume on "The History of
Playing-cards" contains a very droll sketch of a pack supposed to have
been designed by the late Count d'Orsay, is about to give us an
English edition of the famous work of American humour called "Artemus
Ward his Book." Three or four years have passed since in this Journal
we used to notice occasionally a little comic paper at New York called
<hi rend="italic">Vanity Fair</hi>. To this paper (which was
short-lived) Charles H. Browne, whose pseudouym is "Artemus Ward," was
the chief contributor. The "Book" itself is an exquisite piece of
drollery. Artemus Ward is supposed to be a wild beast showman,
traveling through the States and commenting upon men and manners as he
goes along. His apocryphal narrative of a visit to the Prince of
Wales in Canada is inimitably funny.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.006" n= "Winter Sketches in New York." type="Article">
<head>WINTER SKETCHES IN NEW YORK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 59</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">WINTER SKETCHES IN NEW YORK.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">A Correspondent</hi> in New York, to whose
pencil we owe the Illustrations of skating and sleighing in that city,
writes as follows:--</p>
<p>"A few days before Christmas we had a heavy snowstorm here, which
brought out the sleighs and made things look seasonable. Some of the
omnibus proprietors laid up their wheeled vehicles for the time,
substituting for them immense concerns on runners, drawn by six
horses, and capable of holding some forty persons each when closely
packed. I send herewith a sketch of one of these
omnibus-sleighs. Their occupation is a transient and uncertain one in
New York and, even as I write, the snow has quite disappeared, and mud
is the order of things once more.</p>
<p>"The brief spell of cold weather also brought out the skaters in
great force. For two or three nights many thousands of persons
enjoyed the sports of the ice in Central Park, the lakes and ponds of
which favourite place of resort were in excellent condition. The scene
at night, on such occasions, is very striking. Powerful burners are
placed so as to illuminate the whole surface, and the light from these
is reflected with great splendour by the clear ice. I send herewith a
sketch of one of these night scenes. The buildings on the further
shore of the lake contain accommodation for the skaters. There are
refreshment-rooms, a cloak-room, and another room where skates are
let out on hire. Here there is a long counter, behind which a great
array of skates of every description is displayed upon the
wall. Groups of persons are always collected round the great stove,
which is a feature of all public rooms in New York. Numbers of young
girls, attended by their beaus, are to be seen here, as skating has
become quite the fashion since the opening of Central Park, some four
or five years ago. The last day I visited the place I noticed in the
group around the stove a very respectable looking negro woman, dressed
in rather an expensive set of furs. She had with her two small boys of
colour, whom I afterwards saw wheeling about on their skates with
great glee. The policeman in the sketch is one of the park-keepers,
who are picked from the metropolitan police, and are remarkably fine,
soldierly-looking fellows, dressed in a very becoming, light-grey
uniform. The Americans are a progressive people. I observed that some
of the boys here who assist skaters in putting on their irons have
discarded the time-honoured gimlet, so long and favourably known in
connection with skates; using instead of it a bit and
brace."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln46.1298.007" n="Winter Sketches From New York: An
      Omnibus Sleigh.; Skating by Night in the Central Park.--See
      Preceding Page." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 60</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv46p60">
<head>WINTER SKETCHES FROM NEW YORK: AN
      OMNIBUS SLEIGH.; SKATING BY NIGHT IN THE CENTRAL PARK.--SEE
      PRECEDING PAGE.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.008" n= "Illustrations of the War in America:
      General Sherman." type="Article">
<head>ILLUSTRATIONS OF THE WAR IN AMERICA: GENERAL SHERMAN.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 65</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">Illustrations Of<lb/></hi>THE
WAR IN AMERICA.<lb/><hi rend="smallcaps">General Sherman.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> capture of Atlanta in October last,
followed by the march across Georgia to the seacoast, and recently, by
the capture of Savannah, has made General Sherman one of the most
notable officers in the Federal army. We give a Portrait of him and,
on the next page, a Map of his route from Atlanta to Savannah. William
T. Sherman was born in Ohio, in the year 1818. He entered, when young,
the United States Military Academy at West Point, where he graduated
in the same class with General Thomas and then obtained his Ensign's
cornmission. He was promoted to a lieutenancy in 1841; and his conduct
during the Mexican war in California won him the rank of Captain. Upon
the outbreak of the civil war in 1861, he had a fresh opportunity of
active service, being appointed Colonel of the 13th Regiment of
infantry, which he commanded at the Battle of Bull Run. He was soon
afterwards raised to the rank of Brigadier-General and succeeded
General Anderson in command of the department of Ohio, from which,
however, he was removed because of a difference of opinion between
himself and the War Department as to the amount of forces required in
the Western States. At the Battle of Shiloh he took so prominent a
part that General Halleck reported the victory to be mainly due to
Sherman. He was therefore promoted to be Major-General and intrusted
with the command of the fifth division of Grant's army, with which he
was engaged in the siege of Vicksburg. During the last twelvemonth
General Sherman has performed those important operations in the States
of Tennessee and Georgia which have made his reputation second to none
in the military service of the Federal Government.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln46.1298.009" n="General Sherman, of the Federal Army." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 65</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv46p65">
<head>GENERAL SHERMAN, OF THE FEDERAL ARMY.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln46.1298.010" n="Map Illustrating Gen'l. Sherman's March
      through Georgia From Atlanta to Savannah, Novr. &#x0026; Decr. 1864." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 66</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv46p66">
<head>MAP ILLUSTRATING GEN'L. SHERMAN'S MARCH
      THROUGH GEORGIA FROM ATLANTA TO SAVANNAH, NOVR. &#x0026; DECR. 1864.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.011" n= "General Sherman's March through Georgia." type="Article">
<head>GENERAL SHERMAN'S MARCH THROUGH GEORGIA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 66</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">GENERAL SHERMAN'S MARCH THROUGH GEORGIA.</p>
<p>The map of General Sherman's route from Atlanta to Savannah, which
is engraved on this page, requires but little explanation. It will be
perceived that the central region of the State of Georgia, an upland
country, open and well-watered, fertile of wheat, cotton, and Indian
corn, is traversed by two railroads, from south-east to north-west,
converging at Atlanta, but running for some distance parallel to each
other, and forming the chief link of railway connection between
Virginia and the States of Alabama and Mississippi, now the south-west
limit of the Confederacy. One of these railroads is the Georgia
Central, running from Savannah to Macon, 190 miles, thence to Atlanta,
by the Macon and Western Railroad, 101 miles, making the total
distance from Savannah to Atlanta by railroad 291 miles. The other is
the Georgia Railroad running tram Augusta to Atlanta, at from forty to
sixty miles north of the Georgia Central Railroad, and making the
distance to Atlanta from Augusta 171 miles. The plan of General
Sherman's march contemplated the covering of these two lines of
railroad, their subsequent destruction, and a concentration of his
forces at or beyond Millegeville, with Kilpatrick's cavalry force well
disposed in front, and vigilantly covering each flank. The movement
and route of his infantry columns were so well masked that, from first
to last, the enemy were in total ignorance of the position of his main
body, and only discovered the track of his infantry columns after they
had left their vigilant foes many miles to the rear. This strategic
deception was aided by a feigned approach to Macon with the cavalry of
his right wing, which completely occupied the attention of the
Confederate General Cobb, whose militia, collected at that point,
were the only forces from which General Sherman could expect any
opposition. It was on the 12th of November that the right wing of the
Federal army, under General Howard, moved out from Atlanta and began
its march, proceeding southward on the way to Macon, and then turning
eastward, while the cavalry harassed and provoked the Confederates
within a few miles of that town. Meanwhile, on the 14th of November,
the Federal left wing, under General Slocum, set forth from Atlanta,
moving almost directly east, through Covington and Oxford to Madison,
thence turning southward to the rendezvous at Milledgeville. On the
same day General Sherman himself, with his own Staff, took the road to
Macon, so as to come up with General Howard. The crossing of the River
Ocmulgee was the first step which indicated that he would pass by
Macon without attacking that town; and if the Confederates had been
aware of this intention, they might have been prepared to interrupt
his passage here; but on that very day, Nov. 20, the Federal cavalry
were at Griswoldville, only eight miles from Macon, cutting up the
railroad and telegraph, burning a foundry, and doing other
mischief. Hence the Georgia militia, under Cobb and Phillips, were
induced to stand on the defensive at Macon; and it was not until the
22nd, when Sherman was already at Milledgeville, that they made an
assault upon his rear-guard, which was merely a skirmish without
result, though it cost them 600 killed and wounded. The right and left
wings of the Federal army, having destroyed the railroads and the
public buildings of every town through which they passed, even to the
Methodist college at Oxford, with its fine library and museum, came to
a junction at Milledgeville, and remained three days in that city,
where the State Legislature had been holding its session a few days
before. On the 24th General Sherman left Milledgeville, dividing his
army as before; and it marched, by the routes shown in our Map for
each wing respectively, to Millen, a distance of seventy-five miles,
in eight days, obtaining vast quantities of forage and much cattle,
especially in the neighbourhood of Sparta, in Hancock County. The
active movements of the cavalry, under Kilpatrick, contributed greatly
to deceive the enemy as to the position of the Federal army. It was
necessary to conceal the real direction of the march; for had Wheeler,
who commanded the Confederates in this district, known in time that
Augusta was certainly to be avoided, the entire force there could have
been sent down to Millen and, being thus thrown in Sherman's front,
would have resisted or delayed his march upon Savannah, and supplied
in the end a formidable addition to the garrison of that
place. Kilpatrick, therefore, pressed Wheeler more vigorously than
ever, and the latter fell back towards Augusta, which put him out of
Sherman's way most effectually, again leaving him in the rear of the
very army whose advance he was endeavouring to resist. The remainder
of Sherman's march was from Millen to Savannah, a distance of
seventy-nine miles. By the 10th of December he had arrived within five
miles of that city, but, with sound military judgment, he made
preparations at once, not for an assault upon Savannah, but for the
capture of Fort M'Allister, thereby opening the Ogeechee River,
communicating with the fleet, and making a water base on that river at
any point he chose, directly in the rear of Savannah; and also cutting
off all communication between Savannah and the southern part of the
State, vi&#x00E2; the Savannah, Albany, and Gulf Railroad, which has
heretofore been an important avenue of supplies to the rebels, from
the vast numbers of beef-cattle from Florida transported over
it. Accordingly, a division of troops from the 14th Corps, under
General Hazen, was sent down on the 13th, and the fort was gallantly
carried by assault, with its entire garrison and stores. This rendered
the situation of the army perfectly secure. The lines were stretched
across the peninsula in the rear of Savannah, the left resting firmly
on the Savannah River, about three miles above the city, and the
extreme right on the Ogeechee river, at Kingsbridge. Having cut off
all the roads leading to Savannah and obtained command of the Savannah
and Ogeechee rivers, he had made it impossible for General Hardee to
hold the city, which was consequently abandoned by the Confederate
General and taken possession of by Sherman in time to present it to
Mr. Lincoln "as a Christmas-box."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.012" n= "Rendezvous of Mosby's Men in the Pass of
      the Blue Ridge, Shenandoah Valley." type="Article">
<head>RENDEZVOUS OF MOSBY'S MEN IN THE PASS OF
      THE BLUE RIDGE, SHENANDOAH VALLEY.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 66-67</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">RENDEZVOUS OF MOSBY'S MEN IN THE PASS OF THE<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">Blue Ridge, Shenandoah Valley.</hi></p>
<p>Our Special Artist and Correspondent now at the head-quarters of
General Lee, in Virginia, has sent us a sketch representing a
night-scene which he lately witnessed in his excursion up the
Shenandoah Valley--the rendezvous of Colonel Mosby's corps of
irregular cavalry in a pass of the Blue Ridge Mountains. But we may
leave our Correspondent to describe this subject himself:--"During my
late visit to the valley of the Shenandoah with Kershaw's division, I
was fortunate enough to fall in with Mosby and a party of his famous
band. Though I found it extremely difficult to meet with this renowned
partisan chieftain, there are those amongst the Federals who find him
when they least expect and much less desire it. Your<pb n="67"/>
readers, no doubt, have frequently read paragraphs from the American
war news mentioning that Mosby had made another swoop from the
mountains of the Blue Ridge, capturing a Yankee supply-train and its
escort. To my mind he is the most astonishing guerrilla leader in the
Confederacy; and the tales one hears of him sound more like the
romance of war than the reality; but when it is considered how few men
he usually attacks with, his achievements are perfectly
marvellous. With comparatively a handful of troopers, he does not
hesitate to dash on a train of two or three hundred waggons, fighting
and dispersing a guard four or five times his number, and
appropriating to the use of the Confederacy the supplies and
transportation intended for Sheridan's army. At other tunes he will
fly at much higher game, piercing the centre of a large column on the
march, and before either the van or rear are aware of the cause of the
momentary tumult, he will be flying to the mountains with a goodly
number of prisoners. It is impossible to describe the terror that he
excites amongst the Federals; and whenever a party of them are moving
through the valley they are most eager in their inquiries as to
whether Mosby is anywhere in the neighbourhood. Of course they get but
little information from the inhabitants, whose idol he is. Originally,
Mosby's band consisted of but one company, but it has lately been
raised to a thousand, and he himself made a colonel in the Confederate
army, though none of his men are regularly enlisted soldiers. They are
mostly sons of farmers and gentlemen, who prefer the ubiquitous life
and its stirring adventures offered by their chieftain to the
comparative monotony of the ranks in a Virginia regiment. They receive
no pay from the War Office, but, instead of it, they are allowed to
dispose of their captures for their own benefit, the Government being
the purchaser. As soon as an expedition has been resolved upon, Mosby
sends a summons to his men, who are dispersed in every direction, to
meet him at some gap in the mountains, generally at night, and few
fail to answer the call. If they should do so three times
consecutively they are immediately handed over to the authorities and
conscribed into the regular army. My sketch shows a rendezvous of the
band in a pass of the Blue Ridge; Mosby is seated on his horse in the
shadow of a rock, and troopers are galloping up on all sides; others
are dismounted, waiting the order to move. Beneath, the Shenandoah
river winds its course through the fertile valley of
Virginia."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.013" n= "A New York paper states" type="Article">
<head>[A NEW YORK PAPER STATES]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 67</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A New York paper states that a man named Colley, who died recently
at Lockport in that State, kept his money in an old boiler buried in
the cellars, and among the deposits in this vault were 50,000
three-cent pieces.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.014" n= "Current Literature." type="Article">
<head>CURRENT LITERATURE.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 70</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">CURRENT LITERATURE.</hi></p>
<p>....<hi rend="italic">The War in America</hi>--1863-64. By Edward
Pollard. (1 vol. Saunders, Otley, and Co.) Mr. Pollard, who was lately
editor of the <hi rend="italic">Richmond Examiner</hi>, has already
given his account of the first two years' war in America; and he has
now brought his narrative down to the critical moment when the
cautious Confederate General Johnston was superseded by the dashing
Hood. It will be seen, therefore, that he has left off at a point when
the campaign in Georgia became particularly interesting; but the
readers of the daily newspapers will easily supply for themselves what
Mr. Pollard's history lacks. Indeed, it is a question whether an
attentive perusal of the newspapers will not have given the peruser
quite as vivid and accurate an idea of the whole war up to the present
time as can be derived from Mr. Pollard's book. Mr. Pollard, as is
natural, is a warm partisan of the Southern cause and an ardent hater
of the Yankee. According to him, Yankee Generals are incarnate fiends,
and Yankee privates are not much better. Peace between North and
South, except the "wayward sisters" be allowed to have their desire,
is utterly impossible. And yet he is by no means a worshipper of
Mr. Jefferson Davis; he accuses Mr. Davis of conceit and obstinacy,
and attributes no less a disaster than the loss of Vicksburg to
Mr. Davis's headstrong partiality for General Pemberton. The story of
the war is told in a sufficiently sickening manner by the impassible
telegraph: whoever has the stomach to swallow it, warmed by passion
and spiced with virulence, will do well to try a dose of Mr. Pollard's
preparation....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.015" n= "A hopeful miner" type="Article">
<head>[A HOPEFUL MINER]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 71</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A hopeful miner, writing from Nevada territory, the land of silver
bricks, says:--"It is estimated that the silver mines of Nevada will
yield this year 25,000,000 dols. This amount will be taken out in two
years from now in this city and vicinity annually, as we are now
taking out and sending forward 150,000 dols. per month, which will be
nearly doubled after the 1st of next January."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1298.016" n= "A New York paper states" type="Article">
<head>[A NEW YORK PAPER STATES]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1298</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 74</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-21">January 21, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A New York paper states that Professor Silliman examined part of
Southern California in the summer, and found oil equal in quality to
the best in Pennsylvania struggling to the surface and running to
waste down the rivers for miles. It has been regarded as a nuisance,
rendering barren tracts of land of perhaps a mile square in the midst
of a fine agricultural district.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1299.001" n= "Canada and the United States." type="Article">
<head>CANADA AND THE UNITED STATES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1299</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 77-78</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-28">January 28, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">CANADA AND THE UNITED STATES.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> relations of our chief Transatlantic
colony to the United States are not quite so cordial just now as could
be wished. None of the ties which connect them together in
international friendship ae actually severed, but a process has set in
which, if allowed to go on much further, may very possibly end in
rupture. Symptoms of incipient inflammation are already visible, and
even where irritability of feeling is but slight, it greatly increases
reasonable apprehension of the effects which may result from
accidental causes. We believe that neither in the States nor in the
colony is war desired by either the people or their Governments. And
yet it cannot be concealed that, in opposition to the interests, the
policy, and the will of both, an extraneous agent of discord has
thrust itself between them, and has succeeded in giving to their
position toward each other an aspect of antagonism. The best of
neighbours are sometimes set together by the ears by the intemperance
of some third party, and nations are occasionally brought into
collision by the compulsory discharge of responsibilities which might
have remained dormant but for the follies and crimes of people whom
they both condemn.</p>
<p>There can be no doubt that the border States of the American Union
have suffered more from the raids of so-called Confederates from the
frontiers of Canada than any people would be likely to tolerate with
equanimity. The actual amount of damage done may have been small; but
the sense of insecurity, the apprehension, the suspense excited over a
wide extent of country, have been considerable, and have naturally
given rise to excessive soreness of feeling. The raiders were
political refugees from the Southern States, to whom Canada, nobly
imitating therein the policy of the mother country, had accorded
prompt and generous hospitality. Unfortunately, the guests who
received shelter in the colony do not seem to have recognised any
obligation of consulting the convenience of their host, and, under the
protection they have received, assert their right to levy war against
and harry a neighbour with whom she is at peace. Without inquiring
into the prevailing sympathies of Canada in reference to the pending
struggle in the United States, it is sufficient that her Govern<pb
n="78"/>ment honestly reprobated any such abuse of her hospitality,
and showed its sincerity by disclosing to the Government at Washington
every conspiracy against it of which it had an inkling of
information. This neighbourly loyalty was so far reciprocated that,
when the St. Albans raiders were captured by the Vermont militia on
the Canadian side of the border, the prisoners with their plunder were
unhesitatingly given up to the colonial authorities and their
extradition demanded in conformity with law. The unhappy decision of
Judge Coursal, by which the raiders were set at liberty and their
booty restored to them, gave a momentary appearance of collusion
between them and the government at Quebec. Momentary, we say, for the
judgment was repudiated at head-quarters the next morning, and fresh
warrants were issued against the accused, but quite sufficient to fire
susceptibilities and passions not easy to be quenched. In the full
blaze of this indignation General Dix issued his intemperate order to
the military under his command to pursue all future raiders across the
border if necessary, and to bring them thence to be dealt with as
martial law in the United States might determine--an order for setting
at naught the Queen's sovereignty which Mr. Lincoln had the good sense
immediately to command the General to withdraw. Nevertheless, although
the Canadian Government acted with the greatest decision and energy in
endeavouring to counteract the mischief of Coursal's judgment, have
since recaptured most of the liberated raiders, and have dispatched to
the frontier a force of volunteers competent to prevent future
depredation, the brief hurricane of anger in the States compelled the
unwilling statesmen at Washington, and afforded an opportunity to the
willing, to take some steps which have placed the relations of the two
Governments in a rather unsatisfactory position.</p>
<p>Canada is menaced with two serious evils by the President, and is
already galled by the infliction of another by Mr. Seward. Mr. Lincoln
is proceeding to give the six months' notice to the British Government
necessary to free the United States Government from the obligations of
the treaty which restrains both Powers from having more then one armed
vessel on the great inland waters that divide their respective
dominions. The wisdom of that treaty, and its effectiveness in
preventing needless expense and hostile collisions, have been fully
recognised by both parties, and incontestably proved by a long
experience. In what precise way the abrogation of it will operate for
the security of the American border States from the incursions of
lawless men, it is difficult to see. The only certain effect of it
will be to compel Canada to maintain on the lake flotillas of equal
strength, to involve both Governments in unnecessary expenditure, and
to multiply the chances of future misunderstandings. The step has
probably been taken partly with a view to threaten Canada, but chiefly
for the purpose of amusing irritated public feeling in the North, and,
possibly, the notice will not be followed up by action.</p>
<p>Mr. Lincoln has also intimated to our Government that the
Reciprocity Treaty, which will soon expire, will not be renewed in its
present form. It is a strictly commercial agreement between the two
Governments, under which great advantages have accrued to the people
on both sides. It may be that the balance of advantage has been in
favour of Canada; but, in truth, each country gets by means of it what
it most wants from its neighbour at a much cheaper rate. Here again
the political wisdom of the menace is lost in obscurity. Canada cannot
be punished by the termination of the treaty without including in her
punishment large and influential classes in the States themselves; and
the Chamber of Commerce at Detroit, to which the question was referred
for examination and report, have lucidly pointed out the mischief
which the execution of the threat will inflict upon the trade and
prosperity of the American Union, as well as its utter inutility as a
political expedient. Where the interests are mutual, and ample time
remains for deliberation, it may be hoped that sober judgment will set
aside the intentions of temporary exasperation.</p>
<p>But Mr. Seward has struck his blow at once. He has established a
passport system along the frontier, which, as the <hi
rend="italic">Toronto Globe</hi> observes, can be of no earthly use
for the prevention of raids; but which, by the heavy price demanded
for passes, not only prevents any American from passing into or out of
Canada who can possibly do his business in any other way, and thus
deprives her, to a large extent, of a large and lucrative traffic, but
which also taxes the trade which may be carried on in spite of the
regulation. In point of fact, the telegram sent over by the last mail
represented the overland intercourse between the two countries as very
nearly suspended, which statement, although pointing to a possible
truth, must be regarded as giving us a description of facts as they
are seen though the mist exhaled by anger. The commercial dealings
between Canada and the United States are too numerous, too various,
and too important, to allow of their being carried on satisfactorily
without the passing and repassing of commercial agents across the
border. A six-dollar fine each way is a heavy tax, no doubt; but
scarcely heavy enough, one would imagine, to stop all traffic
requiring personal superintendence. And, indeed, thus much may be
inferred from the <hi rend="italic">Globe's</hi> proposal to levy on
the Canadian aide, sum for sum, whatever is levied on the American
side. "No American," says that journal, "who can help it will, while
Mr. Seward's passport system exists, cross the boundary line either
way. But those whose business compels them to do so would not be
prevented therefrom by an additional six dollars. We have as good an
excuse for carrying out our plan as the Government of the United
States have for carrying out theirs. They wish to prevent raids; so do
we. They have instituted a passport system for the purpose; let us
follow their example; let us make all the passports they have issued
worthless, so far as we are concerned, until they have been
vis&#x00E9;ed by our agent to an equal charge to that of the United
States. We may just as well make money out of the business as
they."</p>
<p>We trust the Government at Quebec will think long and seriously
before they act on this advice. That the course proposed will not mend
matters is obvious. That it will contribute but little to the Canadian
Exchequer is confessed. It would be simple retaliation, which, in the
present state of affairs, is precisely what is least to be
desired. Mr. Seward, whose bias and habits as a politician are known
more than they are honoured, has committed the United States
Government to an act of petty vindictiveness. It would be bad policy
it the Canadian Government should suffer themselves to be provoked
into following his undignified example, and thus throw the sympathy of
American traders into his scale. The existing irritation is temporary
in its character and mainly factitious. Wise statesmanship will give
it time to die away. Just now, the most pressing duty of the Canadians
is to mature and set in motion the Constitutional machinery which will
make British North America a strong empire, and to put up, as best
they may, with the small annoyances inflicted upon them by regulations
which injure their neighbours as much as themselves. Great and
permanent interests are at stake, and it is by their regard to these
rather than by the impulse of angry excitements, even if justifiable,
that their present policy should be shaped. They have borne themselves
nobly hitherto; let them not descend to a miserable contest with
Mr. Seward, nor fight him with vulgar weapons. As a matter of fact,
although through no fault of theirs, the fire was kindled by sparks
from their own side, and they will, doubtless, recognise the propriety
of forbearing to add fuel to the flame.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1299.002" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1299</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 79</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-28">January 28, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>The news from New York, to the 11th inst., is unusually barren of
military events. We hear much of preparations, and some movements are
reported which may prove preliminary to important undertakings, but
there are no operations of consequence.</p>
<p>There were rumours of Federal expeditions on a large scale, to be
led by Generals Sherman and Thomas. The former is to operate in
Georgia and North Carolina; and another attempt to take Wilmington is
to be made, a land force being sent from Newbern to attack the city in
the rear while a combined naval and military force operates against
Fort Fisher. General Thomas was concentrating his troops on the
Tennessee, with the view of making a campaign through Mississippi and
Alabama. The Confederates were preparing to meet these aggressions;
and it was rumoured that General Lee had been placed in command of all
the Confederate forces, and that, putting Beauregard in command of the
defences of Richmond, he himself intended to go and confront
Sherman. General Hood was re-forming his army and getting in readiness
to meet Thomas or operate against Sherman.</p>
<p>The armies before Richmond and Petersburg have for some time ceased
to be the most active of the Federal forces; and the only change
reported from that quarter is the supercession of General Butler by
General Ord, an able and well-tried soldier. Butler has been ordered
to report himself at Lowell, Massachusetts, his native place. Various
charges, military and civil, have been brought against him, and his
disgrace appears to be complete. His removal gives rise to very little
difference of opinion. A few, however, remark that he is now out of
place, while a great number insist that he had been out of place for
the past four years. The committee on the failure of the great mine at
Petersburg has made its report. General Burnside is exonerated from
all responsibility for the failure, and Generals Grant and Meade are
censured.</p>
<p>General Sheridan has established his troops in comfortable winter
quarters in the Shenandoah Valley. Great scarcity of food is said to
exist in this once rich but often devastated district.</p>
<p>Up to the close of last year 3,604,743 men had been draughted into
the Federal armies by the conscription orders of the Washington
Government. In 1861 there were 664,743 men draughted; in 1862 there
were 740,000; in 1863 there were 700,000; and in 1864 there were
1,500,000, making the grand total as above. This embraces only the
several calls and draughts, and is quite independent of voluntary
enlistments and the 500,000 men called for a few days ago.</p>
<p>The Messrs. Blair, father and son, have again set out for the
capital of the Confederacy, on a supposed peace mission, not
official.</p>
<p>A bill passed by the Federal Senate emancipates the wives and
children of coloured soldiers.</p>
<p>The Washington Government has sent forces to the Canadian frontier
to prevent persons coming into the United States without a
passport.</p>
<p>The Governor of the State of New York, in his inaugural message,
delivered on the 2nd inst., stated that 182,766 alien immigrants
arrived at the port of New York in the course of the year 1864--an
increase of more than 25,000 over the number in 1863, and as large a
number as in any year since 1854.</p>
<p>The Rev. Henry Ward Beecher presided this year, as usual, at the
annual letting of pews and aisle-seats in Plymouth Church,
Brooklyn. The proceedings took place in the church on the 34d
inst. The premiums bid were much larger than ever before. The highest
bid last year was 200 dols.; this year, 400 dols., which, added to the
pew-rent, makes the largest total payment for the year for one pew 520
dols. Twelve pews were sold at prices (including premium and pew-rent)
exceeding 400 dols. each, and sixteen more brought above 300 dols. The
congregation have raised the salary of their pastor from 7500 dols. to
12,500 dols. per year.</p>
<p>Governor Cannon, in his annual message to the Legislature of
Delaware, again takes strong ground in favour of emancipation in that
State, as he did in his inaugural address.</p>
<p>The Missouri Convention have resolved to reorganise the State
Constitution.</p>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">Boston Traveller</hi> publishes a list of 103
persons in that city whose annual incomes are above 25,000 dols., as
returned under the special income tax. Ten taxpayers in the fourth
district are assessed upon incomes of more than 100,000 dols. each,
after the deductions allowed by law were made.</p>
<p>Governor Andrew, of Massachusetts, in his annual message, just
issued, calls attention to the excess of women in Massachusetts, and
to the surplus of men in Oregon, California, and other remote western
communities. In Oregon, having 52,160 inhabitants, according to the
Census of 1860, there were 19,961 males over fifteen years old, and
only 9878 females above that age. Its population is estimated at over
100,000, this disproportion yet remaining. In Massachusetts there were
257,833 males between the ages of fifteen and forty, and 287,000
females; or, a surplus of 29,166. The excess (the Governor says) of
women of all ages above fifteen years was 38,846. The absorption of
men by the military and naval service during the intervening four
years has aggravated this disproportion. He recommends the adoption of
some practical way by which young women may be enabled to emigrate to
useful fields of employment in the Western States.</p>
<p>A party of about 1600 Indians made an attack on Julesburg, Colorado
territory, on the 7th inst., robbed the overland mail and express,
dispersed a mule-train, destroyed the stage-station and a large amount
of the telegraph materiel, and killed nineteen soldiers and
citizens. A severe fight took place between the Indians and the
troops, the latter numbering altogether less than a hundred; but the
former were finally driven off, with the loss of their chief and
twenty-four others killed.</p>
<p rend="center">BRITISH NORTH AMERICA.</p>
<p>The Montreal Court (as stated in a portion of our Impression last
week) has reconsidered its decision in the case of the St. Albans
raiders, and has decided that it has jurisdiction in the matter.</p>
<p>It is said that the new Federal passport system has nearly put an
end to the travelling of Americans in Canada, the passenger-trains on
both the Grand Trunk and Great Western Railroads now running nearly
empty west of Toronto.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1299.003" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1299</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 86</biblScope>
<date value="1865-01-28">January 28, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....Talking of companies (limited), we hear that a boay of
gentlemen, long residents in, or acquainted with, or interested in the
United States, are about to try in London an experiment which in New
York has, of late years, met with triumphant success. It isn't
tramway; it isn't volunteer fire companies; it isn't paper
currency. But what will our readers think of a "London 'Delmonico'
Company" (limited)? Delmonico's at New York is simply the best and
most splendid restaurant in the world. There is nothing in Paris to
beat it; there is nothing in London, with all its plethora of hotels
and dining-rooms, to equal it. Delmonico's is a combination of the
Trois Fr&#x00E8;res, the Maison Dor&#x00E9;e, Philippe's (Rue
Montorgueil), Bignon's, the Trafalgar at Greenwich, the Star and
Garter at Richmond, the Hotel de Russie at Frankfort, Florian's at
Venice, the Ship and Turtle, Leadenhall-street, Darba's at
St. Petersburg, and the dining-rooms of the best Pall-mall clubs. You
may dine at Delmonico's for a dollar, and for a party of eight your
bill may come to a thousand dollars--precisely as you please. You may
be served off gold, and have pearls dissolved in your sauterne if you
choose. The projected "London 'Delmonico' Company" will of course
appeal chiefly to the wealthiest and moat luxurious classes. The
locale will be a splendid mansion at the West End, the furniture will
be gorgeous, the waiters irreproachable, the cookery simply
perfection, the wines:--<hi rend="italic">ne m'en parlez pas</hi>. The
servants will be superb in plush and silk stockings; and for a <hi
rend="italic">diner d'&#x00E9;l&#x00EE;te</hi> the major-domo will
bring in the first dish with a silver chain round his neck and a sword
by his side, according to the grand old traditions of the days of Ude,
and Car&#x00EA;me, and D'Ouix. The experiment is a bold one; but what
may not be tried in London the stupendous?</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1300.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1300</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 102-103</biblScope>
<date value="1865-02-04">February 4, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>By the arrival of the Nova Scotian we have news from New York to
the 21st ult.</p>
<p>Whilst General Butler was giving evidence at Washington of the
impossibility of taking Fort Fisher, that powerful stronghold fell
under a combined attack of Admiral Porter's fleet and an assault made
by General Terry in person. The Wilmington expedition arrived off Fort
Fisher a second time on the morning of the 13th ult. At an early hour
Admiral Porter dispatched a portion of his fleet to a point about
three miles and a half from Fort Fisher, with orders to shell the neck
of land which at this place separates the shore from the river, and
which was thickly wooded, whilst in the meanwhile the iron-clad
frigates and the monitors were ranged within a distance from the fort
varying from half to three-quarters of a mile. At nine o'clock in the
morning the landing of the troops was begun, and as 200 boats had been
told off from the fleet to convey the soldiers from the transports to
the shore, 4000 troops were safely landed in the course of an
hour. The vessels which had been engaged in shelling the woods
previous to the landing of the troops then moved in the direction of
Fort Fisher, continuing to shell the adjoining line of coast; and at
four o'clock in the afternoon, the disembarkation having been
completed, the Federal troops, to the num<pb n="103"/>ber of 6000,
advanced two miles up the promontory, thus reducing their distance
from the fort to a mile and a half, where they remained until the
15th, on the evening of which day the fort was taken by
assault. Whilst one portion of the fleet was engaged, on the morning
of the 13th, in covering the landing of the troops, the ironclads and
monitors opened a bombardment on Fort Fisher. This bombardment is
described as having been incessant during the greater part of that
day, and the guns of the fort were either silenced or the commander of
the garrison was convinced of the inutility of firing upon the Federal
ironclads. In the course of the same day Admiral Porter directed the
wooden frigates, which had in the morning been engaged in shelling
that part of the coast where the troops landed to take part in the
bombardment, which they did, without, however, provoking a return fire
from Fort Fisher. During the night shells were occasionally discharged
against the fort, and on the afternoon of the following doy the
bombardment was renewed in all its previous intensity. On the morning
of the 15th it was continued, and at four o'clock on the same
afternoon the troops made the assault. Whilst three brigades advanced
to the attack, a division of the Federal army, remaining on the ground
it had occupied for the preceding two days, held the promontory
against the Confederate forces, which, under Hoke, advanced from the
direction of Wilmington, and which would otherwise have taken the
assaulting column in the rear. The defence of the fort was obstinate,
but fruitless. A battalion of sailors and marines, which had been
landed during the day in order to co-operate with the land forces, was
repulsed; but ultimately the garrison, being outnumbered, was obliged
to evacuate the fort. Hemmed in on one side by the river and on the
other by the sea, the Confederates (to the number of 1200) could not
retire beyond the extremity of the promontory, and as a matter of
course, were there compelled to surrender. The Federal loss was
considerable, but it is more then counterbalanced by what is
unquestionably a substantial success. On the first day the monitors
alone were at first engaged, and from eight in the morning till four
in the afternoon poured in 2000 ponderous shells--at the rate of four
a minute; then both divisions of the fleet, iron and wood, were
engaged with 312 guns, and in one hour and a half fired 21,600
shots. Fort Smith, on the opposite side of New Inlet, was subsequently
abandoned and blown up by the Confederates. Wilmington was reported to
be held by 5000 Confederates, under General Hoke; and it was not known
that further operations would be immediately undertaken by the
Federals. The <hi rend="italic">Richmond Examiner</hi> thinks that the
capture of Wilmington is not a necessary, but a probable, consequence
of the fall of Fort Fisher, and urges the burning of all cotton in
Wilmington.</p>
<p>In consequence of this success, General Grant has ordered a salute
of a hundred shotted guns to be fired against Petersburg and Richmond
by each of the armies co-operating against those cities.</p>
<p>General Sherman had sent part of his army to reinforce General
Foster, who had occupied Pocotaligo, on the Savannah and Charleston
Railway, the Confederates having abandoned their works there. It was
reported that General Sherman was menacing Branchville. It was stated
that a considerable body of Federals was intrenched at Franklin Mills,
on the Dog River, and that serious operations were about to be
undertaken against Mobile.</p>
<p>Mr. Blair has returned from Richmond, and a general impression
prevails that negotiations in some form are afoot on the question of
peace. In the Confederate Congress, however, a strong determination to
prosecute the war is expressed. The <hi rend="italic">Charleston
Mercury</hi> of the 12th ult. says:--"The crisis of the Confederacy
has arrived in fatal earnest. The result of the next six months will
bring the Confederacy to the ground or will reinstate its
power. Without reform we are doomed. There must be no more Jeff Davis
foolery, but brains and nerve; reform, shooting, cashiering, order,
subordination; soldiers--not runaways, ragamuffins, ruffians."
Mr. Foote, the Confederate orator who denounced the policy of
Jefferson Davis within the walls of the Southern Congress, has been
captured in an attempt to reach the Federal lines. General Lee, it was
alleged, was urging the Confederate Government to order a conscription
of negroes, and to emancipate the conscripts and their families.</p>
<p>The monitor Patapsco has been destroyed off Charleston, while on
picket duty, by several torpedoes. Fifty of the crew were drowned.</p>
<p>The resolution of Congress to terminate the Reciprocity Treaty has
been approved by President Lincoln; and the Senate has ratified the
notice to be given to England for the termination of the Lake Naval
Force Treaty. Senator Sumner has introduced into the Senate a
resolution proposing that notice should be given for the termination
of the Extradition Treaty with England.</p>
<p>The Virginia Legislature had almost unanimously rejected a
resolution "to make peace through State action."</p>
<p>Slavery has been abolished in Missouri and Tennessee by State
conventions.</p>
<p>The Hon. Edward Everett, formerly Ambassador for the United States
at our Court, died recently, of apoplexy, in Boston. Mr. Lincoln
ordered the customary marks of respect to be paid to his memory. The
Government buildings in Washington were to be draped with mourning for
thirty days.</p>
<p>Captain Bell and three other Confederates, charged with the attempt
to burn the New York hotels in November last, have been arrested near
the Canadian frontier and consigned to Fort Lafayette. General Warren
has been ordered to convene a court-martial for their trial.</p>
<p>A considerable fluctuation in gold had taken place, prices ranging
between 199 and 206, the latter being the latest quotation.</p>
<p>A curling-match between Canada and the United States was played at
Buffalo on the 5th ult. At the close of the day the score was found to
be:--Americans, 478; Canadians, 658; showing a majority of 180 for
Canada. The curlers afterwards dined together in the American Hall. By
special order of Mr. Seward, passports were not required from the
Canadians at the frontier on this occasion.</p>
<p rend="center">BRITISH NORTH AMERICA.</p>
<p>The Canadian Parliament met at Quebec on the 10th ult. The
Governor's message announced that a bill to give the Executive further
powers to deal with political refugees who commit outrages on the
border and a plan for the constitution of the Confederation, would be
laid before the Parliament.</p>
<p>One of the Canadian raiders has been declared guilty of robbery,
and been adjudged to be delivered over to the Federal authorities. A
writ of habeas corpus had been demanded on his behalf.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1300.002" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1300</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 107</biblScope>
<date value="1865-02-04">February 4, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....The Hon. Edward Everett is dead. He was one of the best of
American classical scholars--the Hon. Charles Francis Adams is said to
be the strongest in Greek. Mr. Everett's character, during a long and
active life, was very pure and blameless, and he was in all respects
the model of a courteous and polished American gentleman. He was at
one period Minister Plenipotentiary from the great Republic to the
Court of St. James's, and was nominated (on the "Bell and Everett
ticket") for Vice-President of the United States. He was great at
orations. His grand discourse on Washington was delivered no less than
129 times in different parts of the Union in aid of the funds for
purchasing Mount Vernon; and a couple of years since he pronounced a
harangue over the graves of the Federal soldiers killed at Gettysburg,
which an enthusiastic old lady-listener declared to be "as smooth as
sarce and as sweet as maple-candy." The sayings of American old ladies
of the Mrs. Partington type are wonderful, and most of them are
unrecorded. Did you ever hear of the remark of the ancient dame whose
farm-homestead had been alternately ravaged by Federal and Confederate
troops? "North and South," she observed; "it's four pecks o' one and a
bushel o' t' other. I've had 'em both. Longstreet's 'walk' men, and
Wolford's 'critter' men, they both kem around, and, 'twixt the two,
they caved in my ash-hopper that I wouldn't ha' taken two dollars and
a York shilling for." The ash-hopper was all the world to the old
lady.</p>
<p>The amiable imperturbability of the Hon. Edward Everett was
marvellous, and rivalled that of Sheridan, or Sheridan's friend, who,
when he had sent the hot roast goose flying into the lap of the lady
in pink satin, observed that "he would trouble her for that goose when
she had done with it." Nothing ruffled, nothing disturbed Mr. Everett,
He went on, smiling and beaming, beyond three score years and ten like
a Beautiful Image. He was once president of Harvard University; and
there is a story that at one of the "commencements" or commemorations
of that institution a wicked undergraduate who had recently been
expelled contrived to ensconce himself in the musicians' gallery,
which was directly over the dais, and amused himself during the
delivery of the inaugural oration by sprinkling flour on the
presidential head. The Honourable Edward at last became aware of the
farinaceous shower. He just gently inclined his head upwards;
"spotted" the culprit; then, without a word of remonstrance, unfurled
an umbrella; and uttered under that canopy such beautiful sentences
about Moschus, Bion, and the Pilgrim Fathers, that the auditory, who
had been on the broad grin, were hushed to reverential silence. It is
to be hoped that the wicked undergraduate forthwith repented, became a
hermit, and lived for the remainder of his blighted existence on
Greek roots and Congress water....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1300.003" n= "The Right Reverend Thomas Church
      Brownell, D.D." type="Article">
<head>[THE RIGHT REVEREND THOMAS CHURCH BROWNELL, D.D.]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1300</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 107</biblScope>
<date value="1865-02-04">February 4, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The Right Rev. Thomas Church Brownell, D.D., Bishop of the American
Episcopalian Church at Hartford, Connecticut, died a few weeks since,
in tis eighty-sixth year, having been a Bishop forty-six years. He
was, till 1831, the president of Trinity College, in the State of
Connecticut.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1300.004" n= "The Magazines." type="Article">
<head>THE MAGAZINES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1300</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 110</biblScope>
<date value="1865-02-04">February 4, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE MAGAZINES.</p>
<p>....<hi rend="italic">Macmillan</hi>, as usual, aspires to and
attains a higher level, but fulfils its aim less perfectly. The best
article is undoubtedly that in which Professor Masson records his
recollections of his deceased friend, Agostino Ruffini....</p>
<p>Next in interest to this tribute to the dead is Professor Goldwin
Smith's professedly slight and imperfect portrait of a great living
celebrity--President Lincoln. The ludicrous falseness of the popular
estimate of this remarkable man must by this time have become apparent
to all capable of reflection. Mr. Smith has contributed towards the
formation of a better one by some judicious observations; but, in
particular, by simply letting us see how the President is wont to
express himself on great occasions. No man, it must be conceded by all
who read this paper, could have spoken more simply and nobly over the
dead at Gettysburg; more firmly, and at the same time wisely and
moderately, on the question of emancipation; more tersely and
unanswerably than in rebutting the charges of illegal arrests. The
same spirit pervades all these utterances--that of a magistrate
severely conscious of his responsibilities, disinterested, energetic,
circumspect.....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1300.005" n= "The British-American Confederation." type="Article">
<head>THE BRITISH-AMERICAN CONFEDERATION.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1300</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 118</biblScope>
<date value="1865-02-04">February 4, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>....It is precisely because we are sincerely solicitous for the
abiding welfare of the projected Confederation that we cannot join
some of our contemporaries in flaunting before the eyes of British
Americans the dazzling, but, in our opinion, improbable, prospect of
their one day becoming "the leading Power of the American continent."
It is a dream flattering to British vanity, and countenanced at the
present moment by some American malcontents. The British Americans
will do well not to import from this island the high-flying Imperial
ambition which once swayed Britons so powerfully, but which is now
somewhat out of date and fashion. "The leading Power on the American
continent," whoever it may be, will have the leading debt in the
American continent, will be the most prone to wars of empire, to wars
for a fanciful balance of power, or more probably for a real but
selfish preponderance. Such distinctions as these may be accepted as
the gratuitous gifts of destiny, but are not worth heavy sacrifices
for their attainment.</p>
<p>Still more important to the Confederation than its relations to
Great Britain and France (for we must not forget that Canada has a
hold upon the French heart also) are its relations to its powerful and
excitable neighbour. It is the instinct of danger in this direction
which has so rapidly brought to a head the idea of a British-American
Confederation. President Lincoln has given notice to the British
Government to terminate that stipulation of the treaty of Ghent,
which, in substance forbade the maintenance of a naval force on Lakes
Ontario and Erie. Congress has instructed, or is on the eve of
instructing, the President to give the requisite year's notice of the
termination of the Reciprocity Treaty with Canada. We will fling a
veil of oblivion over General Dix's passionate order, speedily
cancelled as it was by the President. The repeal of the Reciprocity
Treaty alone will exclude American vessels from the navigation of the
Canadian witers, natural and artificial, and place the disabilities of
the American fishing interests on the same footing as they were in
1852, when the American people were excited to a war point by the
simple enforcement of an almost unquestioned British right. The
birthday of the confederation will fall in no halcyon time of
security, but at an epoch when the minds of its citizens are brooding
anxiously about the future of their country and the various forms of
danger to which it may be exposed.</p>
<p>It is to be hoped that the free-trading interests of the Great West
will eventually outweigh in the political balance the Protectionist
tendencies of the Atlantic States, and that the repeal of one
reciprocity treaty will be only a step towards the conclusion of
another and an amended one. The pungent manifesto of the Detroit Board
of Trade, which has been recently republished in this country, gives
us an assurance that the men of the West will not allow their greatest
commercial interest, the export of grain and its free transit to the
seaboard, to go to the wall. That they will find willing allies in
British American statesmen the following well-conceived resolution
shows:--</p>
<q><p>The communications with the North-Western territory <hi
rend="italic">and the improvements required for the development of the
trade of the</hi> Great West with the seaboard, are regarded by this
Conference as subjects of the highest importance to the Confederation,
and should be prosecuted at the earliest possible period when the
state of the federal finances will permit the Legislature to do
so.</p></q>
<p>The improvements referred to are, we presume, the construction of
the Ottawa Canal and the deepening of the Welland and St. Lawrence
canals. Such being the highly precarious state of the commercial
relations between British America and the United States, it becomes
doubly incumbent on the former to establish that system of entire <hi
rend="italic">intercolonial</hi> free trade which is one of the most
prominent features of the new scheme. The sweeping away of four or
five provincial tariffs will be the best means of indemnifying the
British Americans for the possible loss of a reciprocity treaty with
the American Union.</p>
<p>To carry out this general system of free trade, as well as to
facilitate intercourse between the maritime provinces and Canada, it
is absolutely necessary that the missing links of the intercolonial
railroad, which is to connect Halifax with Quebec, be forthwith
completed. These missing links are two--viz., between Truro, in Nova
Scotia, and Shediac, in New Brunswick; and between Fredericton, N.B.,
and Rivi&#x00E8;re de Loup, the eastern terminus of the Grand Trunk
line, 114 miles below Quebec. The construction of this line was
recommended by Lord Durham in his celebrated "Report on the Affairs of
British North America," so early as January, 1839, at a time when the
present gigantic system of American and Canadian railroads ws yet in
embryo. We quote this curious passage:--</p>
<q><p>The completion of any satisfactory communication between Halifax
and Quebec would, in fact, produce relations between these provinces
that would render a general union absolutely necessary. Several
surveys have proved that it would be perfectly practicable the whole
way. It appears to be a general opinion in the United States that the
severe snows and frosts of that continent very slightly impede and do
not prevent the travelling on railroads; and, if I am rightly
informed, <hi rend="italic">the Utica Railroad, in the northern part
of the State of New York, is used throughout the winter</hi>. If this
opinion be correct, the formation of a railroad from Halifax to Quebec
would entirely alter some of the distinguishing characteristics of the
Canadas. Instead of being shut out from all direct intercourse with
England during half the year, they would possess a far more certain
and speedy communication throughout the winter than they now possess
in summer. The passage from Ireland to Quebec would be a matter of ten
or twelve days, and Halifax would be the great port by which a large
portion of the trade, and all the conveyance of passengers to the
whole of British North America, would be carried on....If the great
natural channel of the St. Lawrence gives all the people who dwell in
any part of its basin such an interest in the government of the whole
as renders it wise to incorporate the two Canadas, the artificial work
which would, in fact, supersede the lower part of the St. Lawrence as
the outlet of a great part of the Canadian trade, and would make
Halifax, in a great measure, an outport to Quebec, would surely, in
the same way, render it advisable that the incorporation should be
extended to provinces through which such a road would pass.</p></q>
<p>Although Sir Robert Peel's Government was favourable to this
project, and offered to guarantee 4 per cent interest to the
investors, it has not yet been carried out. The want of it was
grievously felt by the empire in the winter of 1861-2, when the 10,000
British troops made their famous passage on sleighs between
Fredericton and Quebec. The same motives of economy and speed in the
conveyance of troops, military stores, and the mails which have
prompted the Indian Government to guarantee a certain rate of interest
upon the vast sums invested in Indian railroads, has at length
impelled both the Imperial and Colonial Governments to renew their
offers of a guarantee and grant of land to any capitalists who will
supply the missing links in the railroad chain between Halifax and
Quebec. As the surveys have long since been made, and the estimated
outlay is only &#x00A3;3,000,000 for a length of 350 miles, and
inasmuch as its execution is a condition precedent of the proposed
Confederation, we may soon expect to hear of its introduction on the
Stock Exchange....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1300.006" n= "The mail from Sherman's army" type="Article">
<head>[THE MAIL FROM SHERMAN'S ARMY]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 46</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1300</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 118</biblScope>
<date value="1865-02-04">February 4, 1865</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>The mail from Sherman's army, by the Arago, reached the New York
post-office at half-past six o'clock on Friday night, and the last of
more than 200,000 letters was dispatched by the Erie line at a quarter
past four the next afternoon. The stamps not having been cancelled,
this labour was necessarily performed in the New York post-office, and
employed fifteen men throughout the night and up to noon on
Saturday. Twenty men were required to sort the letters. This is the
largest mail that the New York post office ever received.</p></div2>


The Rev. Mr. Greene's congregation in Hatfield, Massa

chusetts, made their pastor "surprise visits" on Christmas evening end on

New-Year's Eve, and left him 508 dols. in money, a barrel of auger, a barrel of flour, 110 lb. of butter, and wood enough to supply him for a year, besides many other articles for family use, This was in addition to many other valesable presents in money and family supplies during the year. These "surprise visits" would not be taken amiss by many clergymen in this country.
AMERICA.

By the Meravian, we have intelligence from New York to the

28th lilt.

Mr. Blair had returned to Washington, having, it is said, altogether

failed in his peace mission, The Confederate House of Representatives. has unanimously confirmed the resolution to issue an address to the Southern people announcing the determination of Congress to continue the war; and at Washington resolutions have been introduced into the Senate in favour of the continuance of the war until the South shall make an unconditional submission. So it is clear that "the end is not yet."

The Federal General' Terry had demanded the surrender of Wilmington, giving General Bragg until the 19th inst. to decide. Opinions differ as to whether the Confederates would surrender or defend the place. the mean time Admiral Porter had occupied all the forts and we abandoned by the enemy, and was feeling his way up the river.

A'Confederate squadron, composed of three ironclads and five gunboats, and said to have been commanded by Captain Smmes, descended the 'lames River during the night of the 23rd silt., with the supposed purpose of surprising the Federal flotilla end destroying General Grant's stores and transports at City Point. But the (ionfederate vessels failed to pass the obstructions laid by the Federals in the stream. One of them ran aground, and had to be destroyed; and the others were compelled to return without effecting anything.

General Sherman has received considerable reinforcements, but

nothing definite is known as to his movements.

In the West there have been several movements of detach--,d expeditions.

'The city of New York was to furnish 20,000 recruits under

President Lincoln's last levy; and the Government had refused toreduce the quota.

 President Davis has signed the Congressional resolutions creating the office of general-inchief. He has also sent a letter to the Confederate Congress stating that, when General Lee took the command of the army of Virginia, he was commanding all the armies of the Confederate States, but was relieved of the latter command at his own request. Whenever General Lee finds it practicable to assume the chief command without withdrawing from the direct obinmancl of the army of Virginia, Mr. Davis will deem it conducive to the public interest to place hint in that position.. General Johnston has been reinstated, and appointed, it is said, to the command of the Confederate army in the West.

President Davis has written along letter in which he argues against

separate State action, and also agaanst the project of a convention of all the States of the Confederacy and of the Union.

The New York oil "diggings" promise to become as remunerative

as those of Pennsylvania or West Virginia, and Oattaa'ongus County is fast becoming the Mecca of those who hasten to he rich.

The Senate has ratified the treaties with the north-western bands of

Shoshoonce Indians establishing peace and friendship, the srveral

bands stipulating that hostilities and all depredations upon the emigrant-trains, the mail and telegraph lines, and upon citizens of the United States within,their country, shall cease. The boundaries of their country, as claimed and occupied by them1 are thus given by the New Yin-k Tribune :-On the north, by the middle of the Great Desert; on the west, by Steptne Valley- on the south, by Toedon or Green Mountains; and on the east, by the Great Salt Lake, Tuilla, and Rush Valleys. The Indians agree to remove to the reservations whenever the President shall deem it expedient for them to do so, and become herdsmen or agriculturists, the Government paying them certain annuities in money, provisions, and goods. The Indians also agree that the Paeificjtailroad shall not be molested; that military posts, ike., may be constructed, the gold and silver mines worked, and mining and agricultural settlements formed, and rancheros established Wherever they may be required.

BIUTIH NORTH AMERICA.

The Canadian Government and Parliament are taking high ground

in the matter of the St. Albans outrages. Judge Coureol has been suspended, and a bill introduced to make good the fifty thousand dollars which were returned to the raiders on their release. In the opening debate in Parliament the Government was sustained by a large majority, and the conduct of the Southern refugees in Canada strongly denounced. A determination was expressed to stop the abuse of asyinm. The Government is carrying out a general draaght n order to be prepared for the worst, but the speeches in Parliament
