<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TEI.2>
   <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated London News
Perspective</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Compiled and edited by</resp>
               <name>Sandra Still</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent/>         
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Emory University</pubPlace>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine>
            </address>
            <availability>
               <p>1996 Emory University.
Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce,
distribute or display the contributions to the work claimed by Emory
University for non-profit educational purposes, provided this header
is included in its entirety.  For inquiries about commercial uses,
contact the Lewis H. Beck Center, Woodruff Library, Emory University,
Atlanta, Georgia 30322</p>
            </availability>
            <date>2004</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated
London News Perspective</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Illustrated London News</title>
               <biblScope type="volume">Volume 41</biblScope> 
               <date>JULY to DEC<hi rend="smallcaps">R</hi> 1862</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p/>
         </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text> 
      <front/>
      <body>
         <div1 id="iln41.001" n="Illustrated London News: Volume 41" type="Volume">
            <head>Illustrated London News: Volume 41</head>
            <docDate>July to Dec 1862</docDate>

<div2 id="iln41.1152.001" n="Foreign and Colonial News"
      type="article">
<head>Foreign and Colonial News</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1152</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.2</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-05">July 5, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>

<p>By the arrival of the steamer St. George we have telegrams from New
York via Cape Race to the evening of the 23rd ult.</p>

<p rend="center"> BELLIGERENT OPERATIONS.</p>

<p>The Confederates made  a bold dash on the 14th ult., with a force of
calvary and artillery, in the rear of General M'Cllellan's army. They
passed  round his right flank, cut the telegraph wires, and injured
the railway from West Point. They also destroyed forage and tents. took many prisoners, and retreated safely.</p>
<p>General M'Clellan army before Richmond had been reinforced by the
corps under General M'Dowell. The weather was fine and the reads firm.</p>

<p>The Confederates opened fire upon the Federal fleet at City Point, on James River, but the batteries were silenced by the Federals.</p>

<p>General Jackson's forces are concentrated at Harrisonburg and Fort

Republic, in the valley of the Shenandoah. He has been reinforced. General Fremont was falling back on Mount Jackson.</p>

<p>General Morgan, of the Federal army, reports, under date of the 18th, that he that day marched upon and occupied Cumberland gap, which the enemy evacuated for hours before his arrival. This gap is a pass in the Cumberland mountains, at a point where the boundary lines of the States of Virginia, Kentucky, and Tennessee converge.</p>

<p>A meagre telegram from Cape Race announces that a bloody battle was
fought near Charleston on the 16th, with heavy loss on both sides. The
latest issue of the<hi rend="italic"> Charleston Mercury</hi> expresses appre-hension for the safety of the city.</p>

<p>The Confederates, 65,000 strong, were reported to be concentrated at Grenada, Mississippi. Some fighting had taken place in the neigh- bourhood of B&#x00e2;ton Rouge, but the result was unknown. General Pope had discontinued his pursuit of Beauregard, who was last heard of at Montgomery, on his way to Richmond.</p>

<p>Vicksburg on the Mississippi, still held out against the Federal flotilla, which is about to be reinforced  by the mortar fleet from New Orleans.</p>

<p>It is confirmed that the British prize-ship Circassian had been con-demned at Key West.</p>

<p>At New Orleans one man had been hanged for hauling down the

Federal flag from the Mint. At Memphis the Federal sentinels had received orders to shoot any person attempting to lower the Federal flag or to molest Union citizens.</p>

<p rend="center">WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>On the 17th the bill for the abolition of slavery in the territories of the United States finally passed Congress. It is as follows:--</p>

<q>To the end that freedom may to and remain for ever the fundamental law

of the land in all places whatoesver so far as it lies within the power or

depends upon the action of the Government of the United States to make
it so, therefore be it enacted, h&#x0026;c., that from end after the
pessege of this Act there shall be neither slavery nor involuntary
servitude in any of the territories of the United States now existing, or which may at any time hereafter be formed or acquired by the United States, otherwise than in punishment of crimes,

whereof the party shall have been duly convicted.</q>

<p>A bill to free from servitude the slaves of certain "rebel" leaders was passed in the House by a vote of 82 against 54.</p>

<p>Secretary Chase has announced that the Mississippi and its tribu-taries are open for legitimate traffic as far as Memphis.</p>

<p>Prior to the departure of Lord Lyons from Washington he presented Mr. Stewart, First Secretary of the Legation, to the State Department, where he won duly recognised as Charg&#x00e9; d'Affaires during his Lordship's absence.</p>

<p rend="center">MISCELLANEOUS.</p>

<p>M. Pierre Soul&#x00e9; had arrived in New York, and was, incarcerated in

Fort Lafayette.</p>

<p>Mr. Appleton Oaksmith, after a trial of five days, had been found guilty by a New York jury of participating in the slave trade. The punishment for the crime is five years' confinement in the State prison and a fine of 5000 dollars, or in default of payment one year's additional imprisonment for each 1000 dollars.</p>

<p>The export of specie to Europe continues, the steamer City of

Washington alone having taken 2,400,000 dollars.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1152.002" n="American News is Full of Incident"
      type="article">
<head>[American News Is Full of Incident]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1152</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.7</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-05">July 5, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>American news is full of incident, though the results of recent
operations do not seem to be important. General Jackson defeated
General Shields, the Federal, on the 9th of June, with much loss on
both sides; but Jackson's man&#x0153;uvres were masterly, and he
joined his chief near Richmond. From that quarter there had been a
dash of Confederates, who had skir-mished with the Unionists, and had
taken a more menacing attitude. The Confederates also made a brilliant
razzia on the 13th, turned the right flank of the Federals, cut up the
waggontrains, killed the persons in charge, and made many
prisoners. Some bombardment, apparently of no great importance, is
reported, and we hear of a battery on White River. Beauregard was
entirely ruined, and his army scattered and demoralised  at the last
mail but one; but at the last mail of all he was at Okalona with
80,000 men, a "resuscitation" more wonderful than that which is
drawing all the town to Drury Lane. General Butler adheres to his
rufflanly New Orleans proclamation against the women, and a reign of
terrorism seems to be established both there and at Memphis. The house
of Representatives has passed a bill for confiscating the slaves of
rebels, a step which must involve very, important considerations. To
whom do the slaves belong, or are they freed? If not, Uncle Sam
himself becomes their owners, and places himself where the great
serfowner in Russia, the Emperor, has refused to believe it safe to
remain. If they are to be freed, the General who sought to disarm
rebellion by a recent proclamation of a similar effect may complain of
rather harsh treatment in having been so severely censured for
"atrocious injustice." We may add that what are called the horrors of
war are now beginning to be understood by those whose churches are
converted into hospitals, and whose friends return, when they return
at all, fearfully mutilated by the newer and deadlier engines of
war.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1152.003" n="House of Lords.--Monday." type="article">
<head>HOUSE OF LORDS.--M<hi rend="smallcaps">ONDAY</hi></head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1152</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.10</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-05">July 5, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>T<hi rend="smallcaps">HE CIVIL WAR IN AMERICA</hi>--Lord B<hi
rend="smallcaps">ROUGHAM</hi> offered  a few remarks, on the American
War. He felt it was impossible for her Majesty's Government to
interfere, but expressed earnest hope that the Americans themselves
would recognise the suicidal character of the conflict and come to
some arrangement before they entirely alienated from themselves the
respec and afection of civilised Europe.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1152.004" n="House of Commons.--Monday."
      type="article">
<head>HOUSE OF COMMONS.--M<hi rend="smallcaps">ONDAY.</hi></head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1152</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.10</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-05">July 5, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>T<hi rend="smallcaps">HE CIVIL WAR IN AMERICA</hi>--Lord P<hi
rend="smallcaps">ALMERSTON</hi> (in reply to a question by
Mr. Hopwood, "Whether, on various considerations Government intend to
take any steps to endeavour to put an end to the civil war in
America?"), paid a warm tribute  to the heroic patience with which the
operatives of the cotton-manufacturing districts had borne their
privations, but submitted that any interference on our part between
the Northern and Southern States might produce no other effect than an
aggravation of their sufferings. The Govern-ments of England and
France would be delighted to offer their mediationif they saw any
prospect that such a step would be welcomed on the other side of the
Atlantic; but, for the present, he could only say that, if at any
future time there should be a fair opening for friendly counsel, it
would be the duty of the Government, as well as a great pleasure, to
take advantage of it.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1152.005" n="The Queeen has approved of Mr. Conyers"
      type="article">
<head>[The Queen has approved of Mr. Conyers]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1152</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.23</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-05">July 5, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>The Queen has approved of Mr. Conyers. O. Leach as Consul as
St. John's, Newfoundland; and of Mr. Alled Francis as Consul at
Victoria, Vancouver Island, for the United States of
America.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1152.051" n="Refugees from Southern Cities Flocking
      for Protection to the Federal Transports on their Advance down
      the River.--From a Sketch by Our Special Artist" type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1152</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.24</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-05">July 5, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v41p24">
<head>Refugees from Southern Cities Flocking
      for Protection to the Federal Transports on their Advance down
      the River.--From a Sketch by Our Special Artist.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>
<div2 id="iln41.1152.006" n="Illustration of the War in America"
      type="article">
<head>ILLUSTRATION OF THE WAR IN AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1152</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.24</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-05">July 5, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>O<hi rend="smallcaps">UR</hi> Special Artist and Correspondent, in
his last letter from the Mississippi Flotilla, writes as follows
respecting the subject of the accompanying Engraving:-"I take it that
the opening the Mississippi is not the least important among the many
movements of the Federal forces; indeed, it appears to me that Peace and Commerce, hand in hand, will float down its broad bosom in the wake of the flotilla, restoring confidence on their way by

recalling the suffering disaffected to their former avocations: Already

numbers of refugees from the Confederate strongholds below us have
penetrated through the submerged forests in 'dug outs,' and have
requested to be allowed to take the oath of allegiance to the old
Government. Their description of the condition of the Southern cities
would scarcely indicate that the population is over sanguine as to the
result of the struggle pro-gressing  or that its confidence is great
in the ultimate success of Confederacy. They say that the more quiet
and law-abiding portion of the people are crushed and held in
subjection by the military authorities, and that hundreds would
welcome the appearance of the Federal fleet and the restoration of
their former condition of order and prosperity. No doubt the
destruction of property will be great on the approach of the flotilla,
but this will be simply because the citizens are powerless to prevent
it; and I am strengthened in this opinion from a conversation I have
had with a Memphis merchant who is on the same boat as
myself. Possibly, however, these fugitives may wish to represent
matters to the Federal commander in a<hi rend="italic"> couleur de
rose</hi> tint, and therefore their statements should perhaps be
accepted with considerable reservation; yet I cannot conceive they
would fly from their bones and seek the protection of Uncle Sam had not, their convictions
undergone a change, and their confidence in Jeff Davis and his power to
sustain his Government been greatly diminished."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1153.001" n="Foreign and Colonial News"
      type="article">
<head><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1153</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.26</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-12">July 12, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>

<p>By the arrival of the Etna and Nova Scotian we  have news till the 1st inst.</p>

<p rend="center">INTELLIGENT OPERATIONS.</p>

<p>The Confederates had made another onslaught on the right wing of the Federal army before Richmond. On the 26th uit.[sic], the Confede-rates having been reinforced by General Stonewall Jackson, attacked the Federals with heavy force. After two days' hard fighting General

M'Clellan found it necessary to withdraw his forces across the
Chicka-hominy, evacuating White House, but saving all the<orig reg="material"> materiel</orig> stored there. His army is now massed between the James and Chickahominy Rivers, with the former as a base of operations.</p>

<p>The forces of Generals Fremont, Banks, and M'Dowell have been consolidated into one army, and General Pope has been assigned to the chief command. General Fremont asked to be relieved from his command because of this arrangement, President Lincoln acceded to his request, and appointed General Rufus Ring in his place.</p>

<p>The Southern account of the sharply-contested battle before Charleston has been received. The Confederates claim the victory. Their account is as follows:--</p>

<q> A severe battle took place on the 16th on James Island, four miles from this city (Charleston). Five regiments, of Federals, with artillery, attacked our

batteries at Secessionville. Colonel Lamar commanded the Confederates, and

with a few hundred men repulsed the enemy three times with great slaughter. The enemy fought bravely, but were defeated. Our victory was complete. The enemy's loss is supposed to be about 400, including forty prisoners. Our loss was 40 killed and 100 wounded, including one Colonel. We buried on the field 100 Federals.</q>

 <p>The Federal accounts admit the defeat and acknowledge a loss of 660 killed, wounded, and missing. The Federals were obliged to retreat under cover of their gun-boats. It is stated that General Benham will be court-marshalled for disobeying orders in attacking the batteries before Charleston.</p>

<p>It is reported from New Orleans that Fort Morgan, at the entrance to Mobile Bay, had capitulated to Commodore Porter.</p>

<p>On White River, in Arkansas, four gun-boats and a transport, having on board one regiment, engaged and captured two batteries, with a loss of 150 men scalded or drowned by the blowing up of a gun-boat. The Confederate loss was about the same. The White

River is now open to commerce.</p>

<p rend="center">WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>President Lincoln had sent to the Senate a treaty made by Mr. Corwin, the American Minister in Mexico, loaning to the Government of Juarez 11 000,000 dols.</p>

<p>The War Department in order to stimulate recruiting, had offered 2 dols. premium and one month's pay in advance to all recruits.</p>

<p>The Post-office Department has concluded an arrangement with the Hamburg, Bremen, and Liverpool lines of steamers by which the fastest steamers of each of those lines are accepted for the United States' mail service throughout the year, thus securing a fast steamer for the conveyance of the mails, on Saturdays from New York, and on Wednesdays from Southampton or Liverpool. This arrangement had long been pressed on the department by the commercial interests.</p>

<p>In the House of Representatives, the bill for the further issue of
150,000,000 dols, in Treasury notes was passed by 76 against 46. The
Senate's amendments to the Pacific Railroad Bill were concurred
in. The House also concurred in the Senate's amendments to the bill
prohibiting polygamy in the territories. The offence is punishable by
a fine not exceeding 500 dols., and imprisonment for five years. A bill "increasing temporarily the duties on imports" has been reported by the Committee of Ways and Means: it largely increases the duties on iron, ironware, coal, drugs, dry goods of all kinds, fancy goods, and miscellaneous articles generally.</p>

<p>The provisions of the Confiscation Act are very sweeping. They confiscate the slaves of all persons engaged in the military or civil service of the Confederate or separate State Governments of the Seceding States.</p>

<p rend="center">NEW ORLEANS.</p>

<p>General Butler is still carrying things with a high hand in this city. Four men have been hung for falsely representing themselves as Federal officials, and in this character searching houses and stealing articles therefrom.></p>

<p>The controversies with the foreign Consuls continue. General Butler lays down the law that no foreigner has a right to buy sugar of "rebel" owners and pay for it by bills drawn on England. General Butler desires that the Consuls should not unite to present joint and argumentative protests to him. The Consuls have unanimously protested against the oath demanded by General Butler of foreigners. General Butler defends the course he has taken, and politely suggests that if foreign residents do not like the treatment they receive they can leave the country, which they were never in-vited

to visit.</p>

<p rend="center">MISCELLANEOUS.</p>

<p>The judgment against the British steamer Circassian declares that
papers were found on board giving conclusive proof of an intention to
run the blockade.</p>

<p>As the municipality of Norfolk still refused to take the oath

of allegiance to the Federal Government martial law had been

proclaimed.</p>

<p>The people of Illinois, by direct popular vote, have adopted
amendments to their Constitution which prevent negroes and<orig reg="mulattoes"> mulattos</orig> front settling in that State.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1153.002" n="Fort Pillow" type="article">
<head>FORT PILLOW.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1153</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.27</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-12">July 12, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>W<hi rend="smallcaps">E</hi> give, at page 37, two Illustrations by
our Special Artist of this important stronghold--by some esteemed the
strongest position on the Mississippi--which the Confederates
abandoned on the 5th ult. Some particulars of the strength and
position of Pillow are given by the correspondent of the <hi
rend="italic">New York Tribune.</hi> "The Bohemians," he says, "were
early on the ground, and began rambling up and down the Bluff, through
ravines and over hills, examining the batteries, the deserted camps,
and the ruined barracks, sketching the situation, enter-ing magazines,
and doing all the necessary but disagreeable duties that appertain to
their avocation. The situation of the Mississippi at Pillow is most
favourable for defence. The river at Craighead Point makes a very
sudden bend, running nearly north and south, and narrowing so
remarkably that at the lower end of the works it is not more than half
a mile wide, and at their first batteries is about three-quarters of a
mile; bringing all boats within easy range of their guns, and
ren-dering their escape almost an impossibility. Below the point there
are two large sandbars which render navigation quite difficult. The
fort, by which I mean the series of fortifications, is on the first
Chickasaw Bluff is composed of nine different works, extending about
half a mile. The bluff is some 80ft. high, very precipitous and
rugged, furnishing an excellent location for<orig reg="defense">
defence</orig>. The works erected at the base of the bluff and on the bank, at some distance from the river, are very well and carefully built for about fifty guns. The country about the fort is exceedingly uneven and rough, and presents the most for-midable obstacles to pedestrians everywhere. There are deep ravines, steep ascents, wild gorges, sudden and unexpected declivities on every hand; while in the rear of the fort there is an unbroken line of heavy and carefully-built breastworks, some seven miles in length, to resist any and all attacks by land. These breastworks are far superior, considering their length, to any others which I have seen during the war. Usually they are merely thrown-up embankments of earth; but these

are regularly and scientifically made, with broad parapets, heavy

escarpments, and counterscarps neatly lined with timber and firmly

secured by deeply-driven posts."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1153.031" n="Portion of the Water Batteries at Fort
      Pillow, On the Mississippi, After the Evacuation--Looking Up The
      River.--From a Sketch By Our Special Artist." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1153</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.37</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-12">July 12, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v41p37a">
<head>Portion of the Water Batteries at Fort
      Pillow, On the Mississippi, After the Evacuation--Looking Up The
      River.--From a Sketch By Our Special Artist.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1153.032" n="Main Battery at Fort Pillow, On the
      Mississippi, Evacuated by the Confederates on the 5th of
      June.--From a Sketch by Our Special Artist."
      type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1153</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.37</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-12">July 12, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v41p37b">
<head>Main Battery at Fort Pillow, On the
      Mississippi, Evacuated by the Confederates on the 5th of
      June.--From a Sketch by Our Special Artist.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>


<div2 id="iln41.1153.003" n="The Illustrated London News."
      type="article">
<head>THE ILLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1153</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.30</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-12">July 12, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">LONDON: SATURDAY, JULY</hi> 12, 1862.</p>

<p>T<hi rend="smallcaps">HERE</hi> has been fighting about five miles
from Charleston, but the affair, although of course dignified into "a
battle," and sensationised with a very strong adjective, was not
important, nor was there much slaughter. Some gun-boat business is
loosely reported, and we are told of one really fearful catastrophe-a
Confederate shot having shattered the steam-drum of a Federal vessel,
and nearly all who were on board having perished, either by scalding
or drowning. Of other operations the news is too vague to be worth
transcription. The Federal army before Richmond was said to he
suffering most severely from fever, and it was even rumoured that
General M'Clellan himself had been seized by it. The Legislature had,
however, performed a far more important act than had been achieved by
the Generals; for the new tariff, which is almost prohibitory of
foreign importations, is a measure which will array all the mercantile
interests of England and France against the Union. Should this new enactment upon further examination sustain the character at present attributed to it the French and English

Governments will find it difficult to abstain from a recognition  of
the South. We have to add that General Butler, whose ruffianly
proclamation against the ladies of New Orleans is defended by some of
the New York journals, is embroiling himself with foreign Consuls
there in a way that may make it necessary to interfere somewhat
promptly with proceedings conceived in the united spirit of a low
attorney and a brutal cateran.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1153.004" n="House of Lords.--Tuesday."
      type="article">
<head>HOUSE OF LORDS.--T<hi rend="smallcaps">UESDAY.</hi></head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1153</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.34</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-12">July 12, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>S<hi rend="smallcaps">LAVE TRADE</hi>--Earl R<hi
rend="smallcaps">USSELL</hi> moved the second reading of the African
Slave Trade Treaty Bill, saying a few words in commendation of the
conduct of the American Government in entering into the convention
which the bill<orig reg="legalized"> legalised.</orig>--The Earl of
D<hi rend="smallcaps">ERBY</hi> also eulogised the conduct pursued by
the Unites States Executive.--The bill was read a second
time.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1153.005" n="The Textile Manufactures in the
      International Exhibition--British and Foreign" type="article">
<head>THE TEXTILE MANUFACTURES IN THE INTERNATIONAL EXHIBITION -- BRITISH AND FOREIGN.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1153</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.47</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-12">July 12, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Have we not seen how the very anticipation of even a short supply
of one of these materials--cotton alone--has agitated the lending nations of Europe?--how the immense monopoly which one portion--of the earth has been permitted to enjoy in the production of this
new indispensable material has led to an arrogant assumption of a
right to defy the laws of a great federation and trample on the
freedom of a suction of mankind unrestrained and unchecked? Such is
the importance to which the great development of one portion of the
textile industry of Great Britain has attained in our day that it was
supposed that Englishmen would become accomplices in a great crime
rather than allow the possibility of any limitation to its
progress.</p>

<p>A few earnest men, such as Mr. Thomas Bazley, M.P. and Mr. Henry
Ashworth, have not been idle during the decade in endeavouring to draw public attention to the question of a supply of cotton from some

source over which we have more control than that of the Southern
States of America, but with what a poor result until the calamity of a
dearth was upon us! The other day Mr. Bazley called the attention of
an influential audience at the Royal Institution to the subject,
especially pointing out the Island of Jamaica as a source whence we
might expect a good supply of cotton of a suitable staple; it may,
therefore, not be without interest to see what we said in these pagee
on this very subject when considering the cotton exhibits in the Great
Exhibition. The views then expressed (May 31, 1851) were:-"That the
Southern States of America cannot continue to supply our wants, as
hitherto with any degree of certainty, seems a settled question with
those who best understand the peculiar position of the United States,
and at the same time take into consideration the requirements of our
manufacturers; apart from the fact that it would be unwise to continue
to suffer the immense population of our cotton manufacturing districts
to depend upon an institution so uncertain in its character as slavery
certainly is, for any movement which might take place in the Slave
States of the American Union, by which its present servile population
should temporarily suspend their industrial pursuits as cultivators of
cotton, would inevitably tell with frightful effect upon the industry
of the north of England and of Scotland in the suspension of trade for
the want of raw material. This question, therefore, of the source
whence our future cotton supply is to come is of infinitely more
importance in a, national and social point of view than at first sight
appears; for it is a fact which cannot be too often brought forward
for the consideration of 'the powers that be,' both home and colonial,
that the great staple trade of probably one-third of the population of
England and Scotland is mainly dependent, at the present time, for
employment and almost for existence upon the worst institution of
modern times, the slavery of the Southern States of America; and,
without seeking to become alarmists, it would be a dereliction of duty
not to take an opportunity like the present to endeavour to bring this
fact more prominently forward than hitherto. With our East India
possessions, with Natal, and many of our colonies, particularly some
of the West India Islands, where cotton is indigenous to the soil, but
where it has been neglected for far less profitable and important
matters, we may, if those who guide our affairs think of it, do great things towards supplying our own wants ; and, whilst contriving to keep up our trade with the United States, to be less dependent upon them, and induce them to supply even their own wants in a more satisfactory way then at present."</p>

<p> The writer subsequently visited the United States in a capacity

which enabled him to examine thoroughly into the industrial pursuits
of the people. His impressions as to the danger of  the British cotton
manu-facture continuing, for all practical purposes, solely dependent
upon the Slave Slates of America for the supply of raw material were
confirmed, and to-day we see the very calamity foreshadowed in the
passage of the quotation from these pages of eleven years ago, a stern
reality; nor did it require the gift of prophecy to see this. Had our
rulers been statesman for the present and future, instead of followers
of a dead pact in routine and precedent, or had our Manchester friends
shown a little more logical foresight at all parallel to that
shrewdness and intelligence which they display in every-day matters,
they must have soon the error, to see a familiar illustration, of
"placing all their eggs in one basket," apart altogether from their
unintentional complicity with a system which it is rovolting to
contemplate, and which has borne, and will continue to bear, its own
bitter fruits. The taunt which Englishmen had to put up with when
visiting the United States, that "cotton ruled England, and the
Southern States ruled cotton," is now a thing of the past. We must
proceed at once to help ourselves; for we venture to predict, and with
the certainty of a realisation quite as full as that which has
followed the warning of 1851, that whenever England gets cotton again
from the Southern States of America it will be the result of a
cultivation of the soil by <hi rend="italic">free</hi> men and women, unstained by the brand of slavery. Half a generation, which is quite as short a period as we can expect, may elapse before this change can be affected, but it is as inevitable as Truth and as inexorable as Justice.</p></div2>
<div2 id="iln41.1153.006" n="The Case of the Emily St. Pierre"
      type="article">
<head>THE CASE OF THE EMILY ST. PIERRE.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1153</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.58</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-12">July 12, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>The official correspondence respecting the above vessel has been published.
On the 24th of April Mr. Adams wrote to Earl Russell on the subject, and transmitted certain depositions relating to her seizure. Mr. Adam's contended that the act committed by Captain Wilson, the master of the neutral vessel entailed her confiscation and that of the cargo, and asked that directionsmight be given for their restoration.</p>

<p>On the 7th of May Earl Russell replied that, having taken the opinion of the law officers, the Government were unable to comply, inasmuch as acts of forcible resistance to the rights of belligerents on the high seas were not cog-nisable by the municipal law of England, however punishable as offences against international law in the prize courts of the captor administering such law.</p>

<p>Mr. Adams replied by quoting the language of Lord Stowell, by which
he considered the restoration of the vessel to called for, and by
pointing to the language of her Majesty's proclamation, which, he
thinks, was intended to apply to precisely such mess as this.</p>

<p>The Foreign Minister rejoined that Lord Stowell's language was limited to the action of a prize court of the captor; and does not extend to the municipal law of a neutral country. - Chancellor Kent is quoted at some length by the noble Lord, who concludes by saying that the meaning of the pro-
clamation was that any breach of the statute would be punished under
the statute by the same national authority by which the statute was enacted.</p>

<p>In a despatch which occupies three pages and a half of the printed return Mr. Adams reviews the arguments of the noble Lord and what he considers the recognised doctrines of international law, coming to the conclusion that the claim for the restoration of the ship rests on the soundest principles of equity and law. The restitution, he says, of Messrs. Mason and Slidell was not required by any portion of the municipal law of the United States, and the United States' Government restored them simply because the seizure seemed to have been wrongful as construed by the law of nations. If the Royal proclamation is to be made so null and void, foreign nations must, he says, adopt more stringent measures of repression, "in order to bring down with real effect upon her subjects the just consequences of her Majesty's displeasure for their violation of her will." The Government and people of the United States had expected some mark of indignation on the part of her Majesty's Govern-ment. "The decision has been otherwise. Made wiser by the result, they will take the necessary precautions in like cases that may happen hereafter to protect themselves."</p>

<p> Writing on the 12th ult., the Foreign Minister endeavours to
convince Mr. Adams that it is a general principle that each nation
deals only with offences committed against its own laws, and is not
called upon to carry into effect, or to aid in carrying into effect,
the laws of foreign nations against persons who may have violated them
and who may be found within its territory. "Not only in the case of
neutrals in war, but in all cases falling within the same general
principle, the nation to whom the parties complained of belong leaves
to other nations who may suffer by the acts of such parties the
penalty. It may happen that the nation receiving the injury may have
an opportunity of resenting it should it perchance catch the offenders
within its jurisdiction. Had the Emily St. Pierre fallen a second time
into the hands of a United States' cruiser, a prize court of the
United States would in all probability have condemned the ship and
cargo. Nor would her Majesty's Government have com-plained of a
condemnation judicially pronounced in accordance with the law of
nations. Her Majesty's Government, adhering to this line of conduct,
are, therefore, acting in accordance with reason, policy, and the
common and universal usage of nations in like cases. You speak of the
rescue of the Emily St. Pierre as being a fraud by the law of nations. But whether the act of rescue be viewed as one of fraud or of force, or as partaking of both characters, the act was done only against the rights accruing to a belligerent under the law of nations relating to war, and in violation of the law of war, which, whilst it permits the bellige-rent to exercise and enforce such rights against neutrals by the peculiar and exceptional right of capture, at the same time leaves to the bel-ligerent alone the duty, and confers upon him the power, of vindicating each rights and of enforcing such law. The same law not only does not require, but does not even permit, neutral nations to carry out belligerent rights. You allude to the conduct of the United States' Government in the case of the Trent; but the flagrant wrong done in that case was done by a naval officer in the service of the United States; the prisoners whose release was demanded were in the direct custody and keeping of the executive Government; and the Government of the United States had actually the power to deliver them up, and did deliver them up, to the British Government. But the Emily St. Flora is not in the power of the executive Government of this country, and the laws of England, as well as the law of nations, forbid the executive Government from taking away that ship from its legal owners."</p>

<p>Mr. Adams's reply, on the following day, is a simple acknowledgment of the above note, with the remark, "As I do not perceive that its contents mate-rially change the nature of the issue that had been already made up, I shall content myself with the transmission of a copy, to complete the correspondence on the subject, to the Government of the United States.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1153.007" n="A letter from Jerusalem" type="article">
<head>[A Letter from Jerusalem]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1153</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.63</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-12">July 12, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A letter from Jerusalem states that a young American gentle-man,
named Carter, a divinity student, ws lately drowned in the Jordan. the
young man, when bathing, was carried away by the rapid current, and,
after sinking tow or three times, disappeared.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1155.001" n="Northern Reverses" type="article">
<head>NORTHERN REVERSES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.66</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>T<hi rend="smallcaps">HROUGH</hi> the base of the telegrams brought
to this country by the China and the preceding packets from New York
and Quebec, dimly outlining such information from the principal seats
of war as the Government at Washington thought fit to give to the
American public, looms the fact that the Federal arms have sustained a
succession of serious reverses. The Confederate General. "Stonewall"
Jackson, suddenly quitting the valley of the Shenandoah and crossing
the mountainous district lying between it and Richmond, fell upon
General M'Clellan's right wing, and succeeded, after three days'
sanguinary conflicts, in driving it back behind his centre and left
wing, on the other side of the Chickahominy River. Another battle,
fought on Sunday, June 29, probably resulted in a still more important
defeat of M'Clellan's forces (subsequently confirmed by the news
brought by the Jura), since the Secretary of War forbad the Northern
press to publish any detailed news. It is clear, however; that things
have gone unfortunately with the Federals, or President Lincoln would
hardly have issued a proclamation calling fop 300,000 additional
troops, much less would a cry have been raised for a conscription, if
necessary. But ground has been lost elsewhere than before
Richmond. James Island, lying in close contiguity to Charleston, his
been evacuated by the troops under General Hunter, and the campaign
against that city has been inde-finitely suspended. The position of
General Curtis in Arkansas had become so precarious that he is
reported to have retired into Missouri. Vicksburg, on the Mississippi,
still remains in possession of the Confederates, although the latest
news states that its bombardment by twenty Federal vessels had
com-menced. Altogether, Northern prospects have become gloomy; the
idea of mediation appears to be entertained-with some show of favour;
and the night before the China steamer sailed from New York an
enthusiastic public meeting in favour of peace was held in that
city. If these latter statements can be safely taken as indicating a
turn in the current of public sentiment, we might almost indulge the
hope that the conclusion of this most disastrous war cannot be very
far off.</p>

<p> Summer heat has now entered upon its allotted term on the American
continent, and what that means in the Southern States the shiploads of
sick men sent back to New York may faithfully, but only faintly, make
manifest. A tropical sun acting upon an immense extent of unreclaimed
forest and swamp fearfully tries the rigour of even an<orig
reg="acclimatized"> acclimatised</orig> con-stitution. When associated
with the toils and hardships, the broken rest, add the coarse and
irregular fare of camp life, it becomes a more merciless foe than men,
however infuriated and in whatever force, can prove themselves. Its
power is unseen and intangible, and therefore irresistible. It is at
work along the whole line night and day. No resolution, no discipline,
no bravery, can fight it off. The havoc it has already played with
M'Clellan's army far exceeds that inflicted by the arms of his
adversaries, and as yet the unhealthy season has but initiated its
rule. For several weeks previously the commander had reiterated the
most urgent demand for reinforcements, and it was only just before the
late reverses that General M'Dowell had' succeeded in joining him with
his division. The telegram tells us that in the collision before
Richmond, M'Clellan was driven from his position on the Pamunkey River
and the White House "with great loss," and that "there was fearful
carnage on both aides." Quite irrespectively, therefore, of his
strategical loss; which, by changing his position, has increased his
disadvantages, if not involved his army in danger,it seems evident
that he will be unable to resume the offensive, even if he succeeds in
holding his ground, until after the solstitial months. Protracted
inaction during the coming three months, at least in Virginia, would
appear to be the best prospect which the case of the Northern army
will now admit of, and there is a possibility that it may have to face
a far more gloomy one. The 300,000 additional men called for by the
President will not be available for the purposes of the closing campaign, and Northern patience and persistence are doomed to undergo a further and much severer test than it has yet sustained.</p>

<p>We record these Federal reverses with unfeigned regret. We are
conscious of no inclination to allow the unreasonable petulance into
which the based hopes of a young and self-confident community have
temporarily betrayed it to alienate our sympathies from the principles
with which, whether it means so or not, its conduct in this struggle
is inseparably identified. We cannot find pleasure in its humiliation,
nor gratify our own violated self-respect by taunting it with the
collapse of its vainglorious boasts. But it would be childish to
attempt to pass any delusion upon ourselves as to the stern
significance of the facts before us. We see in them, indeed no proof
that the North is essentially inferior to the South in military
qualities. We do not trace them to lack either of courage, of
discipline, or of generalship. But we do ascribe them to the nature of
the enterprise upon which the North saw fit, although under great
provocation, to embark. All sub-sidiary chances are against them, for
the simple reason that they are invaders of the soil of a hostile
people. They can command no accurate information because the
inhabitants of the Southern States regard them with fiercest
hate--they are not familiar with the regions into which they seek to
penetrate. They cannot choose their own ground, nor determine where or
when battle shall be given them. Political reasons, if not strategical
exigencies, have compelled them to distribute their forces over a vast
surface, and ever imporant place that they take must be held by
garrisons detached from the main army. Their antagonists, on the
contrary, move about amid a sympathising population, know every
move-ment of every part of the invading force, are free to select the
positions they will abandon or hold, and by surrender-ing minor
advantages, can concentrate nearly thier whole military power at will
upon any one point. It will require immense superiority in men and means to balance these
advantages, and it is no discredit to the military character of the
North that it has not succeeded where European arms would have
certainly failed. Its miscarriage is almost inevitable; for, although
it may tear out the word "impossibility" from its dictionary, the
stubborn impracticability of geographical facts and of physical and
moral laws will successfully defy it. Its only chance was bound up
with the hope that the rebellion was the work of a dominant faction
rather, than the deliberate resolve of a whole population. When that hope was shattered every likelihood of ultimate success was shattered with it.</p>

<p>The question now presents itself whether, during the coming three months of compulsory inaction, the North will hang on to its determination to reinstate the South in the Union with the same desperate tenacity of purpose it has hitherto exhibited. Already a peace party makes itself heard, and the alternative of mediation begins to be discussed. With the evidence before us of the singular want of correspondence, from the very beginning of this war, between European predictions and American events, we will not be rash enough to forecast the probabilities of the future. But we may venture to say that such moral certainties as are within view do not favour a belief that another campaign must precede the termination of hostilities. That, no doubt, is at the present moment the fixed intention of the Government at Washington; perhaps, also, it is the preponderant resolution of a majority of the people. But there is no saying how long it will remain so. In the first place, all the sober-minded and well-informed classes of society must have become sceptical, to say the least, of the feasibility of the enterprise upon which they started, and of its desirability even if it is considered feasible. The temper of the Southern people can no longer be mistaken. Their attachment to the cause of Secession has been tried by the severest vicissitudes, but has never wavered even for a moment. No compromise will entice them back--no offer to concede their largest claims. This fact has become undeniable, and a protraction of the war can hardly be persisted in with the expectation of practically disproving it. The main object for which the North so enthusiastically welcomed privation, suffering, debt, taxation, and even death, may be said to have disappeared. Will not this fact take the heart out of resolution? Immense losses have been incurred--immense sacrifices are further required; and there is no reason-able hope that either the one or the other will be of ultimate avail. For several weeks to come there will probably be no tidings calculated to excite or feed national ambition. Swollen sick-lists, commercial disquietude, the rapid exportation of bullion, high prices, and the first call of the tax-gatherer, are not very well adapted to shore up a bulging and undermined determination to persevere. Should the North give way to inevitable necessity, or, as Napoleon III. describes it, to "the inexorable logic of facts," before the middle of October next, and should it invite mediation in place of rushing into a new campaign, it will be only yielding to the force of motives which all the world over are powerful to influence reasonable minds.</p>

<p>That the statesmen and people of Federal America may feel their way to a settlement of this terrible quarrel before the close of the summer heats will be, we are sure, the most earnest desire of Englishmen of all political parties. They are convinced that free institutions are never in greater peril than during the convulsions of civil strife. They can discover no possible compensation in the future either of Europe or of America for such a miserable waste of life and resources as another campaign would entail. Perhaps they are not wholly disinterested in their desire for the restoration of peace. But, whether their own industry would be profited or otherwise by the sheathing of the sword, it is certain that the dictates of humanity alone would suffice to make them hail with delight any probable prospect of witnessing the end of a contest which, in political and moral as well as in social and commercial respects, has proved the most calamitous event of modern times.</p>

<p>According to the last advices three ships had arrived at San

Francisco, from Hong-Kong, with 1000 Chinamen on  board.</p>

<p>Colonel Colt, the inventor of the revolver, died worth about

&#x00a3;300,000. His manufactory at Hartford, United States, employs 1100 hands, and the wages paid there amount to &#x00a3;10,000 per month.</p></div2>
<div2 id="iln41.1155.002" n="America" type="article">
<head>AMERICA</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.67</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>By the Jura we are in possession of telegrams from New York to the evening of the 7th inst.</p>

<p rend="center">BELLIGERENT OPERATIONS.</p>

<p>There has been a succession of conflicts between the Confederate army, commanded by General Jackson, and the right wing of the Federal forces. The Federal account of the result is that it was part

of M'Clellan's plan to withdraw his forces from across the Chicka-hominy and concentrate them on the James River, along which they / might advance on Richmond in company with the gun-boats, seven-teen of which are at hand. This movement, which leaves the left wing of the old position in the situation of the right wing of the new, was interrupted by repeated attacks from the Confederates. The Federals affirm that they were net beaten in any of these conflicts, and that, though suffering severely themselves, they always inflicted heavier losses on the assailants. No guns were lost since the 27th ult., when General M'Call's division was at first overwhelmed and twenty-five pieces fell into the hands of the enemy. On the other hand, the Confederate General Magruder has been captured. The evacuation of the several places was effected without any loss of stores or baggage. The position now occupied by the Federals near Turkey Bend, on the James River, is much healthier than that in the swamp country bordering on the Chickahominy.</p>

<p>The Confederates claim to have captured 12,000 prisoners, all

M'Clellan's siege guns, and supplies sufficient to last the Confederate army for three months. Richmond, accordingly, has been illuminated.</p>

 <p>As no details have yet been allowed to appear, it is impossible to
 estimate the losses on either side, The Richmond <hi
 rend="italic">Examiner</hi> confesses that one division, which went
 into the fight on Friday, the 27th, 14,000 strong, could only muster
 6000 for duty on the following Tuesday and that the sacrifice of life
 exceeds that of any battle yet fought, MClellan's head-quarters were
 established on Malvern Hills, one mile back of Turkey Bend.</p>

<p>The Federals had captured the Confederate gun-beat Teaser in

James River.</p>

<p>General M'Clellan had issued an address to the army declaring that the Federals shall enter Richmond, and that the Union shall be preserved, no matter what the cost of time, treasure, and blood.</p>

<p>The Federals had evacuated James Island, near Charleston, and

retooned to Hilton Head. The summer campaign against Charleston had
been suspended. Since the evacuation of James Island the Confederates
have been threatening Fort Royal, in the same State. General Hunter,
commanding in this deportment, acknowledges, in reply to an inquiry
from Congress, that, in default of reinforcements from New York, he
had drilled and armed fugitive negro, and that by the end of the autumn he would present to the Government from 48,000 to 50,000 "of these hardy and devoted soldiers."</p>

<p>Vicksburg continued to hold out against the Federal fleet. The

Federal Commander was employing his troops to cut a canal across

the land opposite the city, so as to change the course of the Missis-sippi and render Vicksburg an inland town.</p>

<p>The Federal General Curtis was in a perilous condition in Arkansas. He was unable to procure supplies, and his army had been reduced to half rations for a week. The enemy under Pike, 6000 strong, were moving from Fort Smith to take him in the rear.</p>

 <p>The first train from Memphis to Corinth was attacked by the Con-federate cavalry and capted twelve miles from Memphis. It contained eighty mule-teams with provender-waggons, and a company of an Ohio regiment, besides several officers and railway officials, who were all captured.</p>

<p rend="center">THE CONFEDERATE STATES.</p>

<p>President Davis had informed the Governor of Georgia that the nonscription was necessary to ensuring the success of the Confederacy.</p>

<p>General Beauregard had published a letter in the Mobile <hi
rend="italic">News</hi> denying the capture by General Pope of 10,000
prisoners, as telegraphed by General Halleck. He says that 100 or 200 stragglers would cover all the prisoners he took, and about 500 damaged muskets to boot. All that the Confederates lost during the retreat would not amount, he says, to one day's expenses of the enemy's army.</p>

<p>All the clergymen of Nashville had refused to take the oath of allegiance to the Federal Government. Most of them had been confined in the Penitentiary.</p>

<p>General Butler had issued a new form of oath for foreigners at New
Orleans. Instructions had been sent to him from Washington to cease
all further correspondence with the foreign diplomatic agents and to
leave such matters to the Department of State.</p>

<p rend="center">WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>President Lincoln, urged by a petition signed by eighteen Governors

of loyal States, had called for a levy of 300,000 additional troops.</p>

<p>The House of Representatives had passed the Tariff Bill.</p>

<p>A meeting of the Conservative members of Congress had been held in the Capitol.</p>

<p rend="center">PERSONAL</p>

<p>The Comte de Paris and the Duc de Chartres  have quitted the Federal army and returned to Europe.</p>

<p>General "Stonewall" Jackson, the hero of the recent rencontres with the Federals, is a native of Virginia, where he was born in 1825. He graduated at West Point in the same class with M'Clellan in 1846. He fought through the Mexican War, which he entered as s Second Lieutenant and quitted as a Major. A description of him in a New York paper is to this effect:--</p>

<p>As for his outer man, he looks at least seven years older then he
is--his height about five feet ten inches; his figure thick-set,
square-shouldered, and decidedly clumsy ; his gait very awkward,
stooping, and with long strides. He often walks with his head somewhat
on one side, and his eyes fixed upon the ground, imparting to his
whole appearance that abstracted quality which young ladles describe
as absent-minded. A lady who has known him long and well has told me
that she never saw him on horseback without laughing-short stirrups,
knees cramped up, heels stuck out behind, and chin on his breast--a
most unmilitary phenomenon. In society he is quiet but cheerful, not loquacious, but intelligent  and  shrewd; in religion the bluest kind of a Presbyterian, and extremely strict in his church observances. In Winchester he took a very active part in revivals, and habitually led the Union prayer meetings.</p>

<p rend="center">MISCELLANEOUS</p>

<p>A large anti-abolition meeting had been held in and around the Cooper Institute, New York.</p>

<p>Gold had advanced to 10 per cent premium, and the exchange

on London had reeahed a higher quotation than at any period since
1837. American stocks and bonds were being sent over for sale in large
quantities by European holders.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1155.003" n="The Illustrated London News"
      type="article">
<head>THE ILLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.70</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">LONDON, SATURDAY, JULY</hi> 19, 1862</p>

<p>We are menaced  with a prolongation of the Parliamentary

Session on the ground that it has become necessary to provide

by legislative action for the relief of the thousands who have been
reduced to distress by the American fratricidal war. We arc unaware of
any valid reason for the expectation that the Session would terminate
much earlier than usual, and we are equally unable to see why a
measure upon the justice and humanity of which all must agree need
occupy many nights in discussion. We perceive, however, that, in
anticipation of the bill, the Manchester organs are calling upon the
landowners of the distressed district to lay down vast sums as
contri-butions to the relief fund for those whom the manufacturing
interest has congregated in such dense swarms around its factories,
and, it is not impossible that ungracefnl demonstrations may be made
on both sides.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1155.004" n="House of Commons.--Tuesday."
      type="article">
<head>House of Commons.--Tuesday.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.74</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>T<hi rend="smallcaps">HE CIVIL WAR IN AMERICA</hi>--AT THE EVENING
SITTING  MR. W. E. F<HI REND="SMALLCAPS">ORSTER</HI>gave notice that,
in the event of Mr. Lindsay's motionin favour of acknow-ledging the
independence of the Confederate States becoming a substantive motion,
he should propose, as an amendment, that the House would cordially
support her Majesty's Government in the policy of non-intervention in
the civil war now being waged in America.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1155.041" n="Federal Gun-Boat.--See Supplement, Page
      84." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.77</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v41p77">
<head>Federal Gun-Boat.--See Supplement, Page
      84.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>
<div2 id="iln41.1155.005" n="The Civil War in America" type="article">
<head>THE CIVIL WAR IN AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.84</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">(From our Special Artist and Correspondent.)</hi></p>
<p rend="right">The Gayoso House, Memphis, Tennessee,</p>
<p rend="right">June 10</p>
<p>A<hi rend="smallcaps">FTER</hi>six weeks of cramped existence on a
Mississippi transport, I again find myself enjoying some of the
comforts of <orig reg="civilization">civilisation</orig>. The limited
area of a state-room of the smallest dimensions has changed to an
apartment of such proportions that I am almost tempted to write a new
version of "Une Voyage autour de ma Chambre." But either to write or draw with the thermometer at 100 deg. in the shade is a task so laborious, and one's energies become so lymphatic under the moistening influences of heat, that I must content me with relating facts and eschew the realms of fancy.</p>

<p>Memphis, the hotbed of Secession, has fallen. The proud city that

would never surrender to the Northern vandal is now garrisoned by Federal soldiers; the blackened, smoking ruins that were to have greeted the advent of the invader was an empty boast; the streets

bathed in blood" but a figurative piece of bombast, for which the
editor of<hi rend="italic"> The Appeal</hi> is responsible. Commodore Davis, who commends the national flotilla, need scarcely have wasted words in writing his despatch. "I came, I saw, I conquered," would have expressed everything. Never was a success so complete and so cheaply purchased by the victors; never an enemy so humiliated. The "stars and bars" have been trailed in the dust; the flag of the Union waves from the principal buildings in the fallen city. Verily, the Memphians have eaten dirt.</p>

<p>On the evening of the 4th inst. a lurid glare rising above the woods

 that separated us from Fort Pillow betokened the evacuation and

destruction of the last but one of the defences of the Confederates on
the banks of the Mississippi. Captain Phelps, commending the flag-ship
of the flotilla, immediately started on a reconnaissance round
Craighead Point whence an uninterrupted view of the works could be
obtained, and found the flames to pmaeed from the burning of
gun-carriages, cotton embrasures, and barrack-sheds. Beauregard's
retreat from Corinth had induced the abandonment of Fort Pillow; and,
to make its occupation as profitless as possible to the Federals, the
torch had been applied to what remained. Nothing could be seen of the
Confederate fleet; and the presumption was they had fallen back to
Memphis, seventy-five miles below, the result proving this surmise to
be correct. As it would have been extremely unwise to land a force
with the risk of magazines exploding, it was determined to delay the
occupation till the following morning and accordingly at daylight on
the 6th the flotilla weighed anchor, and steamed down to the still
smoking line of earthworks. The position of Fort Pillow struck me as
being remarkably strong both naturally and artificially. Situated on a
bold rise known as the First Chickasaw Bluff, it commanded the bend in
the river, which here has its channel immediately under the cliff, and
within a hundred yards of the guns most of which would direct a
plunging fire on passing vessels; he works were in three tiers, and
composed of a water battery over a quarter of a mile in length, a
sense of strong redoubts midway up the face of the bluff, and an upper
series partially hidden by dense foliage. A semicircular line of
rifle-pits, running three miles back in the country, protected the
garrison from attack in the rear. The Confederates had evidently been
engaged for some time removing their guns, as we found only twelve
remaining when we landed. A portion of these had been spiked, some had
been burst, and others had been dismounted; but some half dozen might prove serviceable to the Federalists. There is no doubt the Southerners had had at least fifty guns in position; but, finding they would sooner or later have to evacuate, they had gradually removed the greater number of their pieces to strengthen the batteries being constructed at Vicksburg, the last barrier closing the Mississippi to the Federalists. By the time this letter appears in print the "Father of Waters" will

pursue his course uninterrupted by cannon from his source to the Gulf of Mexico, and Vicksburg, the final stand-point of the Confederates, will have been wrenched from them by Davis and Farragut.</p>

<p>Remaining at Fort Pillow but time enough to make arrangements

for holding it, the flotilla, consisting of five gun-boats, accompanied

by the transports, steamed down the river for Memphis. Now I

realised to the fullest extent the barbarous and wanton destruction of

property of which the Secessionists are guilty. Whenever we approached
a plantation on either the Tenneeese or the Arkansas shore we were
certain to see a column of smoke rising in the neighbourhood
indicating the burning of cotton or also the water would be covered by
floating masses cast from the bank into the stream. Passing within
hailing distance of one of these plantations, and noticing some men
engaged in efforts to save a quantity that had become entangled with
some drifting timber, I called and asked then by whose orders their
property had been destroyed. Their reply was, "They say it's by order
of the Government, but there<orig reg="ain't"> aint</orig> been no
each thing in this <hi rend="italic">dog-goned</hi> country for over a
year." I then asked if they were glad to see the stars and stripes back again, and the answer was, "We guess we are, mighty so;" and, in token of this feelinp being pretty general, numbers came down through the woods and cheered us as we passed along. We learned that the Southern fleet had preceded us but a few hours, and that their crews had landed and searched every plantation they came to for cotton, which they either burnt or threw into the river, despite the protestations of the owners. One of their transports we overtook and captured while engaged in this vandalism, but the more responsible of those who were on board landed and escaped across the country before we took possession of her. That night, at ten o'clock, we anchored three miles above Memphis, concealed from the town by a duster of islands brown to Mississippi boatmen as "Paddy's Hen and Chickens." The next day, June 6, was to decide the fate of the city, perhaps of the Federal flotilla, for, undoubtedly there would be a great passage of arms between the rival fleets, the crews of one fighting beneath the eyes of their Southern hellos and inspired to deeds of valour by their presence. An hour after the flotilla had come to its moorings a dead silence reigned on every vessel: many that night said "God save us!" and others cried "Amen!"</p>

<p> At five a.m. on the morrow the signal was flying from the Benton
(flag-ship)to cast off, and at half-past five we rounded the point
that separated us from Memphis, and came in full view of the city and
the Confederate fleet, eight in number, drawn up in line across the
river to dispute our progress. Nothing daunted, the five national
gun-boats steadily pressed forward; and as we drew nearer we saw that
the bluff in front of the town was covered by a dense crowd assembled
to witness the gladiatorial display. The glorious sun of June rose
resplendent, shedding its golden rays on spire and roof, and bathing
the brown old Mississippi in a flood of light that made its opaque
waters fairly sparkle. The parti-coloured masses on the cliff dressed
in their gay summer clothing gave to the scene a festive appearance
strangely at variance with the stern reality of war about to be
enacted in their presence. But I was soon called from the
con-templation of the spectators in the amphitheatre tiers to the
arena itself, in which I was somewhat of an actor, for the first note
of defiance had been reared from the throat of a 64-pounder, and the
shot scattered the water up all round. In a few minutes all the
vessels on each side were engaged, and the firing became general, the
Southern boats slowly falling back while we continued advancing. Two
vessels under a full head of steam came from our rear and passed
swiftly through our line, each seeking an antagonist in the
Confederate fleet. They mounted no guns, and had but a crew of twelve
riflemen stationed behind a massive loopholed bulkhead. A few weeks
since they were ordinary river steamers, but, having been thoroughly
strengthened and protected by massive timbers and a solid iron-tipped
prow placed on each, it was determined to try them as rams. On they
sped un-harmed by the storm of shot and shell which was rained upon
them. The first, the Queen of the West, made for the Beauregard, and,
as the latter sheared off to avoid the blow, she ran foul of the
General Price, one of her consorts, completely tearing the starboard
wheel off the latter and compelling her to run to the Arkansas shore
in a sink-ing condition, where she was abandoned by her crew. The
General Bragg now came up to the assistance of the Beauregard and
struck the Queen of the West on her port paddle-box, crushing it in,
but in turn got a huge rent in her port bow. In the mean time the
other Federal ram, the Monarch, bore down towards the General Lovell,
and, striking her amidships, cut her down to the water's edge, and in
three minutes afterwards she sunk in one hundred feat of water, taking
with her most of her crew. Thus two of the Confederate boats were dis-posed of, six only being left for the free national vessels to contend with the rams retiring from the fight. A shot from the Banton fired

by Captain Phelps, struck the Beauregerd in her boilers, and she went down, giving Commodore Davis, who made the most humane efforts, barely time to save those on board her. The Jeff Thompson was set on fire by a shell from a Federal boat, and, being run ashore, blew up shortly after she was abandoned; the General Bragg also was struck by a shell and her cotton bulkheads ignited, but the crew of the Sentou, who boarded her, succeeded in extinguishing the fire. To sum up the whole affair, one Confederate vessel alone escaped-the General Van Dorn; three were destroyed, and four were captured after a running fight of one hour and a half.</p>

<p>Next mail will bring you an account of the occupation of Memphis, the
feeling of the people, and their conduct under Federal rule. At
present I can do no more than send you this brief letter, as my time
has been taken up with sketching.</p>
<p rend="right">F. V.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1155.051" n="The Civil War in America: Destruction of
      the Confederate Flotilla Off Memphis.--From a Sketch By Our
      Special Artist.--See Page 84.">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.92</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v41p92">
<head>The Civil War in America: Destruction of
      the Confederate Flotilla Off Memphis.--From a Sketch By Our
      Special Artist.--See Page 84.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>
<div2 id="iln41.1155.006" n="Cotton Statistics" type="article">
<head>COTTON STATISTICS</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.85</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Cotton Statistics</hi>--In five months ending
the 31st of May the total receipts from the United States were only
30,396 bales, against 494,662 bales in the corresponding period of
last yar, and 538,413 bales in the corresponding period of 1860. The
aggregate importations from all countries wre 126,788 bales, which is
equalonly to 23 per cent of the total receipts of the first five
months of last year. India has contributed 73,403 bales, Egypt 30,872
bales, and Brazil 7513 bales, and these quantities are about double
those that were furnished from the same countries in the like period
of last year. Our miscellaneous receipts from various places not
specially distinguished have reached 11,959 bales, against 27,996
bales in 1861.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1155.007" n="American Ladies" type="article">
<head>AMERICAN LADIES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.89</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">American Ladies</hi>-- I confess that in the States I have

sometimes been driven to think that chivalry has been carried too
far--that there is an attempt to make women think more of the rights
of their womanhood than is needful. There are ladies' doors at hotels,
and ladies' drawing-rooms, ladies' aides on the ferry-boats, and
ladies' windows at the post-office for the delivery of letters (which,
by-the-by, is an atrocious institution, as anybody may learn who will
look at the advertisements called personal in some of the New York
papers). Why should not young ladies have their letters sent to their
houses instead of getting them at a private window? The post-office
clerks can tell stories about these ladies' windows. But at every turn
it is necessary to melee separate provision for ladies. From all this
it comes to pass that the baker's daughter looks down from a great
height on her papa, and by no means thinks her brother good enough for
her associate. Nature, the great restorer, comes in and teaches her to
fall in love with the butcher's son. Thus the evil is mitigated; but I
cannot but wish that the young woman, should not see herself
denominated a lady so often and should receive fewer lessons as to the
extent of her privileges. I would save her, if I could, from working
at the oven; I would give to her bread and meat earned by her father's
care and her brother's sweat; but, when she has received these good
things, I would have her proud of the one and by no means ashamed of
the other.--<hi rend="italic">Trollope</hi></p></div2>.

<div2 id="iln41.1155.008" n="The Prospects of California"
      type="article">
<head>[THE PROSPECTS OF CALIFORNIA]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.89</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>The Californians are anticipating the time when they shall be
compelled to turn their attention to other pursuits than gold
digging. Placer mining in some parts of California has already ceased
to be profitable for white men. In 1852 gold diggers earned 10 dollars
per day, and in 1862 they are obliged to be contented with 2&#x00bd;
dollars. It is estimated that if the fruitfulness of the gold mines
continues to decrease in the same ratio as it has done for the last
ten years, in 1872 no white men will be found at work in the gold
mines. American writers express an opinion that in a few years
California will get rich by carrying timber to China. The 

latter country, having been densely populated for ages, is bare of
timber and the monster forests of California could furnish that
product for centuries to come, and also supply the fleets of which
will be required for the Chinese rivers.

"The Chinese," says a Californian paper, "are alive to the benefits of river

steamers, and to the advantages which shipments on European vessels give in

safety and certainty of insurance. Before the pirates made the voyages
of the junks almost impossible the Chinese merchant calculated to lose
one venture in three. He now avoids the risk by freighting in foreign bottoms. The

opening of the rivers will call for the construction of a fleet of light-draught

steamers, which California can supply. We have faith that the trade
may be ours; if efforts be made to secure it; and that as our mills
increase and labour diminishes in value we may make steady shipments
of lumber in China's great valley, and, if we will, that the return
vessels may be loaded with a product which will give employment to
Californian looms and spindles. Our northern forests will resound with
cheerful industry and our shipyards give forth the productions of
ingenious laboor. Youthful California and Oregon will spare to aged
China the surplus of their forests for the produce of her plains, made
bare of wood by the wants of centuries of a dense
population."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1155.009" n="American Silence" type="article">
<head>AMERICAN SILENCE</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.91</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A<hi rend="smallcaps">MERICAN SILENCE</hi>-I found no aptitude, no wish for

conversation; nay, even a disinclination to converse. In the Western
States I do not think that I was ever addressed first by an American
sitting next to me at table. Indeed, I never held any conversation at
a public table in the West. I have sat in the same room with men for
hours and have not had a word spoken in me. I have done my very best
to break through this ice, and have always failed. A West American man
is not a talking man. He will sit for hours over a stove with a cigar
in his month, and his hat over his eyes chewing the end of
reflection. A dozen will sit together in the same way, and there shall
not be a dozen words spoken  between them in an hour. With the

women one's chance at conversation is still worse. It seemed as though
the cares of the world had been too much for them, and that all
talking, except business (demands, for instance, on the servants for
pickles for their children), had gone by the board. They were
generally hard, dry, and melancholy. I am speaking, of course, of aged
females from five-and-twenty perhaps to thirty, and who had long since
given up the amusements and levities of life. I very soon abandoned
any attempt at drawing a word from these ancient mothers of families;
but not the less did I ponder in my mind over the circumstances of
their lives.--<hi rend="italic">North America. By Anthony
Trollope.</hi></p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1155.010" n="A Large Lump of Gold has been dug out"
      type="article">
<head>[A Large Lump of Coal Has Been Dug Out]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.91</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>A large lump of gold has been dug out in the Siskiyon region, near
the border line between Oregon and California. It weighs 190 oz. It is
not quite pure, and is worth about &#x00a3;600.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1155.011" n="There are no Hungarians in the
      Confederate Army" type="article">
<head>[There are no Hungarians in the Confederate Army]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1155</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.91</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-19">July 19, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>There are no Hungarians in the Confederate army, while the number
in the Union service is large. It is said that General Fremont, while
at the West sent his secret dispatches to Washington in Magyar, which
was as good as cipher, since no person in the Confederate service
knows the tongue.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1156.001" n="Foreign and Colonial News"
      type="article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1156</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.94</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-26">July 26, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>By the arrival of the Montreal Company's steamer Anglo-Saxon we have newspapers to the 11th and telegrams vi&#x00e0; Cape Race to the 14th instant.</p>

<p>BELLIGERENT OPERATIONS.</p>


<p>The grand army on the James River, reinforced by the corps-d'arm&#x00e9;e

under General Burnside, is safely intrenched around Harrison's

Landing, about twenty-seven miles from Richmond. Beyond a slight skirmish on the 3rd, there had been no fighting since the 1st instant. It is admitted that all idea of immediate advance upon the Confederate capital is abandoned.</p>

<p>President Lincoln had paid a visit to the army, in order to see for
himself if any changes were needed in the command of the army. He held
a private conference with General M'Clellan for half an hour, and then
proceeded to visit the line of intrenchments. He was welcomed with great enthusiasm by the troops. He addressed to them some encouraging words, denying that they had been beaten, and expressing his confidence that they would not give up without going into Richmond. He declared his confidence in the army and its commanders.</p>

<p>The special correspondents of the journals acknowledge that the
retreat of the army was attended with the greatest port, and that
nothing but the superiority of the Federals in artillery saved
them. The Confederates marched up to the mouth of the guns with utter
recklessness of life. Had they placed 30,000 men south of White Oak
Swamp they could have divided the Federals into two parts, and
annihilated them. The Confederate journals complain that they were
outgeneralled at this point. The Federal loss in killed, wounded, and
missing is set down at 30,000. It is probable that the Confede-rates
suffered as severely. The report that their General Magruder, was
captured, and General Jackson killed, was unfounded.</p>

 <p>A Federal transport conveying supplies up the James River was fixed into by the Confederate batteries below Harrison's Landing, and was obliged to run "ashore to escape being sunk. Captain Wilkes, late of the San Jacinto, had been appointed to the command of the James River flotilla.</p>

<p>The British steamer Modern Greece, whilst attempting to run the
blockade at Wilmington, North Carolina, was run aground by the
blockading fleet, who hauled off on the opening of the fort on
them. She had 100 tons of powder on board, but the fort succeeded in
sinking her so as to wet the powder and prevent her explosion by the
Federal shells. Her passengers and crew were saved. It was believed that a large portion of her cargo would also be saved.</p>

<p>Vicksburg still held out against the Federals, although the city

had suffered a ten-days' bombardment, and been on fire several times.</p>

<p>The army of occupation in the Valley of the Mississippi has met with two reverses. A large body of Confederates has captured Murfreesborough, a town thirty-two miles south of Nashville, and taken one Federal regiment prisoners. Despatches from Mobile say that Baton Rouge, the capital of Louisiana, had been recaptured, and 1500 Federal prisoners had been taken.</p>

<p rend="center">THE CONFEDERATE STATES</p>

<p>In consequence of the late battles, Confederate stock rose from 93 to 97. The wheat and oat crop in these States is a failure.</p>

<p rend="center">WASHINGTON</p>

<p>General Scott had been summoned to Washington and had quarters assigned him at the War Department.</p>

<p>The Treasury Note Bill as finally passed, allows the issue of
150,000,000 dols., of which 50,000,000 dols. are reserved as a banking fund to secure the payment of temporary deposits, leaving 100,000,000 dols. for circulation. Of these 35,000,000 dols. may be issued in small notes of one, two, and three dollars denomination.</p>

<p>Congress is debating the propriety of employing negroes in the military service of the nation, and has passed a bill authorising the President to make arrangements with foreign Governments, especially with Denmark, for the colonisation, of captured negroes.</p>

<p>A meeting of the members of Congress for the Border States had been
held to consider the President's emancipation scheme. The <hi rend="italic">New York Post</hi>  says that the majority oppose the scheme and will decline to accept the proposal.</p>

<p rend="center">THE NORTHERN STATES</p>


<p>The great question of the hour is the means of teasing the 300,000
men called for by the President at the instance of eighteen
Governors. Great efforts were being made by public meetings, patriotic
addresses, gubernatorial proclamations, &#x0026;c., to promote
volunteering. The Common Council of Buffalo had appropriated 80,000
dollars to raise a new regiment in that city, giving 75 dollars bounty
to each recruit in addition the 40 dollars granted by the Federal
Government. Other cities had adored 100 dols. The Mayor of New York in
has proclama-tion urges the people to enlist, not only to put down the
rebellion but to repel with becoming spirit the first approach of
foreign intervention.</p>

<p>The eighty-sixth aniversary of the Independence of the nation was
celebrated with less &#x00e9;clat and with greater gloom and
depression of spirits than in any previous year during the course of
their history.</p><pb n="95"/>

<p>Gold has varied from 15 to 17 per cent premium. Silver commands 8
per cent premium; and even copper cents are 2 to 3 per cent above
par. The greatest inconvenience existed among retail dealers for small
change, and "shinplasters" were freely used. Some journals advocated
the use of postage-stamps for small change.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1156.002" n="Letters from Nassau" type="article">
<head>[Letters from Nassau]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1156</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.95</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-26">July 26, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>Letters from Nassau say that the captain of the British steamer
Greyhound had seized  the Confederate steamer Ovieto. The cause is
said to be an attachment of the vessel for wages due to the crew.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1156.003" n="The Illustrated London News"
      type="article">
<head>THE ILLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1156</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.98</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-26">July 26, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">LONDON, SATURDAY, JULY</hi> 1862.</p>

<p>F<hi rend="smallcaps">OR</hi> the time, at all events, the tide
seems to have turned. Details of the six day of fighting near Richmond
have arrived, and it will need something more than a speech from
Mr. Lincoln to convince the world that the Federals were ,not, in his
delightful language, "whipped." The whipping was certainly
administered with immense vigour and disastrous effect. That General
M'Clellan is now safe, under the protection of the gun-boats, which
have again proved of the utmost value in the strangest campaign on
record, is probably true; but the contrast between-the vauntful
promises and the almost piteous reference to the last date at which
guns were lost is very significant. The largest statements were set
flying, to the effect that it least five armies, numbering 130,000
men, were all marching on Richmond; but we have heard all this kind of
thing before. The best thing that can be said is that, apart from the
bombast necessary for civil consumption, General M'Clellan has a right
to take credit for having got a portion of his army well out, of a
terrible scrape,;'- but it is insulting common sense to talk of a
rapid flight over seventeen miles, the loss of a very large number of
guns, and the abandoning dead and wounded, as anything but a defeat of
the most signal character; and it is not a healthy sign that a
Government is afraid to trust a people with the truth, and compels a
brave soldier to frame addresses in the style of Napoleon at Astleys
Amphitheatre. The slaughter of those days should have made men grave
and truthful; it is almost impossible to realise the fact that some
five and twenty thousand men were either killed or <hi
rend="italic">hors de combat</hi> but so the estimates, now permitted
to ooze out, represent the case to be. A new success gained by the
Confederates in the South is reported, and we learn that Baton Rouge
has fallen into their hands, with 1500 prisoners. The ruffian Butler
may  begin to tremble in New Orleans. A battle with Halleck was
thought to be impending. Finally, all reports certify that "an uneasy
feeling as to both military and political matters prevails," and this
is a vague formula, yet one which has often preceded news of strange disruptions in the Old World.</p>

<p>In our own Parliament silence has been at last broken upon the
American question, and in a, debate, raised by Mr. Lindsay, the House
was asked to consider whether England ought to interfere. But we are
glad to say that the Commons preserved the self-control which has so
creditably characterised their pro-ceedings in reference to
America. No speaker of first-class position took part in the debate
except Lord Palmerston, who spoke only to deprecate discussion and to
urge that so difficult and important a subject should be left to the
Government. There was little that fell from any of the debaters that
should annoy either Northerns or Southrons, at least such among them
as are aware that Mr. Whiteside is rather liked for a vitupe-ration
which disturbs the dullness of the House, but is nobody, when heads
are counted. The other speakers displayed the most laudable moderation
of language.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1156.004" n="Richmond Virginia" type="article">
<head>RICHMOND, VIRGINIA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1156</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.100</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-26">July 26, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>We give below a View (from a by sketch

Eyre Crowe) of the High-street, Richmond

towards which city public attention is now

naturally directed. This street straggles pic-turesquely down one side
of a hill and another. The stores are of a strictly utilitarian
character, with nothing pretentious about them. The poles which
extend. through-out the breadth of the flagway are intended during the
summer heats, to protect the lounger from the blistering sun. By far
the greatest object of curiosity to European visitors in Richmond is
the little street running at right angles with High-street, and on the
left-hand side. It is called Wall-street: in it the sales of negroes
take place. From this narrow little passage have issued entire armies
of "likely hands" after being sold, so they have gone southwards to
the plantations. Thousands, however, are fixtures in Richmond
itself. They throng the streets carting away large tobacco<orig
reg="barrells"> barrels</orig>; or else grin good-humouredly at the
door of the American Hotel, the principal one of the town, which is
also in the High-street. As in every town in America, the telegraphic
wires festoon the street, and send sensation headings to the

<hi rend="italic">Richmond Times</hi> or the<hi rend="italic"> Richmond Enquirer.</hi>

Doubtless they have ere this flashed to these

offices news of more than ordinary import, and

the High-street is thronged with soldiery seldom seen there in more
peaceful times.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1156.005" n="House of Commons.--Monday."
      type="article">
<head>HOUSE OF COMMONS.--MONDAY.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1156</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.102</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-26">July 26, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>B<hi rend="smallcaps">HITISH INTERESTS AT NEW
ORLEANS.</hi>--Mr. S. F<hi rend="smallcaps">ITZGERALD</hi> complained
that, while France, Spain, and every other maritime power were
represented at New Orleans by ships of war, no similar protection had
been afforded to British subjects in that city. The subject was one of
grave interest, and the proceedings of General Butler, as well as the
possibility of differences between England and America rendered it
important that her Majesty's Government should give their serious
attention to the matter.--Sir J. F<hi rend="smallcaps">ERGUSON</hi>
having expressed his concurrence in the remarks of the member for
Horsham, Mr. L<hi rend="smallcaps">AYARD</hi> insisted that the
Government had not neglected British Interests at New Orleans. A ship
of war had been ordered to that city, but the order was subsequently
countermanded, as it was felt to be desirable to avoid any
manifestation of power. He added that our Vice-Consul been recognised
by the Federal Government.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1156.051" n="Position of the Federal Flotilla on the
      Mississippi, Off Fort Pillow, Shortly Before Its Evacuation"
      type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1156</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.105</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-26">July 26, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v41p105a">
<head>Position of the Federal Flotilla on the
      Mississippi, Off Fort Pillow, Shortly Before Its
Evacuation.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1156.052" n="Colonel Fitch and the 46th Indiana
      Volunteers Taking at the Point of the Bayonet the Confederate
      Battery of Fort St. Charles, On the White River, Arkansas. See
      Supplement, Page 111." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1156</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.105</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-26">July 26, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>
<figure entity="v41p105b">
<head>Colonel Fitch and the 46th Indiana
      Volunteers Taking at the Point of the Bayonet the Confederate
      Battery of Fort St. Charles, On the White River, Arkansas. See
      Supplement, Page 111.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1156.006" n="The Civil War in America" type="article">
<head>THE CIVIL WAR IN AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1156</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.111</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-26">July 26, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">(From our Special Artist and Correspondent.)</hi></p>

<p rend="right">Washington, July 4.</p>

<p>T<hi rend="smallcaps">HE</hi> thunder of the cannon before Richmond
reached me in ominous echoes down the valley of the Mississippi. It
was whispered the roar of the Confederate guns rose more defiant than
that of the Federal. Rumours of great battles on the Chickahominy came
hourly to Memphis through Southern sources, and, though nothing was
reliable, yet it was evident the fight for the championship had
commenced. I had always felt that my place was before Richmond, and
your readers are aware of the cause of my absence from that central
point of interest. What I proposed, Mr. Stanton was not disposed
should be. However, the manifold blunders and petty jealousies of this
official are now producing such grievous results that his downfall is
almost certain, and if his removal in disgrace from a position which
he has proved himself totally unfit for be considered a satisfaction
to those he has injured, why then I, among others, am morally assured
of that amount of vengeance, at least. With the probability that his
succesor may be more liberal towards English correspondents, and less
narrow-minded generally, I have hastened back from the West and await
the change in the Administration, which may, perhaps, enable me at the
eleventh hour to avail myself of General M'Clellan's invitation to
join his headquarters on the James River.</p>

<p>I want your readers to understand one thing, and that is, that I
write my impressions from day to day, and if I am misled at the time
it is by force of circumstances for which I can scarcely be held
responsible; but I can clear up and correct afterwards when I find I
have been deceived. In a former letter I mentioned that crowds of
refugees from Memphis sought the protection of the Federal gun-boats
as they lay off Fort Pillow, and that I learnt from many of them that
there was a strong Union element in that city which only awaited the
appearance of the flotilla to declare itself. I have since found this
not to be the case, and I may say positively that there is more
bitterness of feeling evinced towards the North by the Memphians than
I ever saw displayed by the Italians to the Austrians. If the entire
South is actuated by the same sentiments breathed by the people of
South-western Tennessee and Mississippi; why, then I declare the
reconstruction of the Union impossible; and, though the North by
superior power and resources may eventually conquer the South, she can
never hold her in any other way than that which binds Venetia to the
Tedeschi. Your readers must understand that I never saw anything of
Southern people until I landed at Memphis. A "peculiar institution" of
theirs had prejudiced me somewhat against them, and I believed from
all I heard that the Secession movement was but skin deep after all,
and that the people would willingly return to their allegiance to the
Government of the United States if the old flag were carried to their
midst and the leaders of the rebellion removed from among them, I have
been astounded at the unanimity displayed by all on the one subject of
separation. If there be a dissentient here and there, he is a man who
has Northern interests, and most frequently he is a German, a
sojourner among a strange people. If the South had not been unanimous,
how could the movements of their Generals have been kept so secret,
and yet all transpiring within the Federal camps be known in the ranks
of the Secessionists? If they had had traitors to their cause in their
midst, would Corinth have been evacuated in the face
of Halleck's immense army without that General being made aware of
what was transpiring within three miles of him? Would "Stonewall"
Jackson have been allowed to perform that brilliant movement which
enabled him to attack M'Clellan's right and form a junction with Lee,
while the Federal commanders, over a hundred miles away in the
Shenandoah Valley were trembling in their jackboots at the idea of
his momentarily attacking them? I say again, I believe the South to
be unanimous, and with this belief my ideas have notably changed as
to the future. In Memphis and its immediate neighbourhood I made it
my business to mix with all classes and test their loyalty or
disloyalty, and, though the stars and stripes floated from the public
buildings, and the supremacy of the Federal Government had been
asserted by the Federal arms, yet I found but one minute drop of
Union oil to pour upon the troubled ocean of Secession : all were
<orig reg="clamoring">clamouring</orig> for separation. If, then,
such are the sentiments of the entire South, and defeat does not
bring them nearer to the Union, what is to be the result of all this
bloodshed? A conquered people, writhing in the chains that bind them
to their conquerors seeking every fresh opportunity for outbreak. The
civilised world will shortly demand that this wholesale massacre shall
cease, and that the temperate counsels of European Governments shall
take the place of unskilful Generals, who, while sacrificing the lives
of thousands of brave men and deluging this vast continent with their
blood, approach no nearer to a solution, but widen the gulf which
separates the combatants and embitter the hatred which is daily
growing fiercer.</p>


<p>As I have stated at the opening of this letter, my purpose in return-
ing Washington is, it possible, to reach the army on the James
River. Very bad news for the Federalists will reach you by this mail,
already, I suppose, anticipated by telegraph, and, though it is
evidently the wish to make the best of it, I must caution you against
believing in a victory where there was a defeat. At present I know but
little about what has latterly transpired in front of Richmond, at
least I am scarcely sufficiently posted to go into the matter, and
must refer you to the general news. Of one thing there is no doubt,
that M'Clellan has been forced to retreat seventeen miles with
frightful loss, and yet hypocritical journalists here chant a "Te
Deum," and pronounce the movement to have been a masterly piece of
strategy. I have still one or two more Mississippi Sketches to send
you, and with them I will write more fully and from the best authority
as to the actual condition of matters with the army of the Potomac. I
have hopes of getting on the spot myself, and shall leave no effort
untried to reach the James River, but how am I to achieve my purpose unless the Minister of War relents, I scarcely know.  F. V.</p>

<p rend="center">OUR ILLUSTRATIONS.</p>

<p>Two Engravings in connection with the operations of the Federal
flotilla on the Mississippi, from Sketches by our Special Artist, forworded by the previous mail, are given in this week's Impression at page 105.</p>

<p>The first shows the position of the flotilla before Fort Pillow shortly before the evacuation of that fort by the Confederates. In a letter written in a transport off Fort Pillow, on the 31st of May last, our Special Artist writes as follows respecting the subject of this Illustration :&#x2014;" Our mortars have been pegging away at Fort Pillow for the last day or two without intermission, and we occasionally get a shell in return. Unfortunately, the Federalists cannot well ascertain the effect of their fire, as all, they can see of the fort or its
position is simply the rise of the bluff on which it is situated above the bend in the river. The Sketch I send will give a tolerable idea of

the relative positions. The national mortar-rafts are placed against the Arkansas shore, immediately under the bank, and half a mile of dense forest lies between them and the winding bed of the river which

flows by the fort. The shells are thrown over the trees, the range being calculated by a daily reconnaissance sent to observe the effect of

the bombardment; but this reconnaissance is not always successful, for
the woods are often filled by Confederate scouts, on which occasions a free fight takes place, knocking everything else on the head."</p>

<p>As regards the second Engraving, which shows Colonel Fitch and the
46th Indiana Volunteers taking at the point of the bayonet the battery
of Fort St. Charles, we have the following particulars:--On the 13th of June four of the gun-boats from the flotilla in front of Memphis

were dispatched to the White River, Arkansas, 185 miles below, to
clear out the cotton-burners and to endeavour to communicate with
Curtis. The expedition on its way up the White River, met with a battery mounted on a bluff, and the gun-boats immediately engaged,

the Mound City leading. Unfortunately, a 42-pound shot from the
breastwork entered the casemates of the Mound City and burst her
steam-drum, scalding 125 persons. The poor fellows, writhing with

agony, jumped through the ports into the river, and were there, while shrieking for help, shut down by the rebels. Colonel Fitch, who was on board one of the Union transports, immediately landed, and carried

the works at the point of the bayonet. The success of the Union forces was complete, and the Southern artillerymen were shot at their guns.</p>

<p>The <hi rend="italic">Cincinnati Daily Times</hi>, in its number for June 28, has

the following notice of the arrival in that city of our Special Artist:-"Among the recent arrivals at the Burnet House we are pleased to see the

name of Frank Viztelly, Esq., artist and correspondent of the I<hi
rend="smallcaps">LLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS</hi>. This paper, it will be remembered, is one of the few London journals that has token an unbiased view of our politicos troubles, and has

done not a little toward setting us right before the English people. The

numerous life-like sketches and graphic letters from the Army of the Potomac

and the Burnside expedition, which have appeared in the pages of the
I<hi rend="smallcaps">LLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS</hi> from week to week
during the past year; have been from Mr. Viztelly's pencil and pen. He
has just returned from Memphis, having been with the Mississippi
flotilla for two months, and purposes joining the army before Richmond
in a few days."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1156.007" n="The Queen has appointed Mr. Edgar Leopold
      Layard" type="article">
<head>[The Queen has appointed Mr. Edgar Leopold Layard]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1156</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.114</biblScope>
<date value="1862-07-26">July 26, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The Queen has appointed Mr. Edgar Leopold Layard, in the

room of Mr. Richard Surtees, to be Arbitrator to the Mixed British and

Portuguese Commission established at the Cape of Good Hope. The Queen has

approved of Mr. Arnold Otto Meyer as Consul at Singapore for the Free
Hanseatic city of Hamburg and for the Free Hanseatic city of
Bremen. Her Majesty has also approved of Mr. Theodore D. Edwards as
Consul at Demerara for the United States of America. The Queen has
appointed Frederick Seymour,Esq., Boil., late Superintendent of the
settlement of British Honduras, to be Lieutenant Governor of the
colony of British Honduras.</p></div2>


<div2 id="iln41.1157.001" n="America." type="article">
<head>AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1157</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.119</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-02">August 2, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>By the Canadian mail-steamer Hibernian we have telegrams vi&#x00e2; Cape Race to the 22nd ult.

<p rend="center">WAR NEWS.</p>

<p>The position of the army of the Potomac remained unchanged. It had been reinforced from General Hunter's command, now inactive on the coast of South Carolina. The Federal fleet in James River comprises an immense number of vessels. There are nearly 600 transports and war-steamers between Newport News and Harrison's Bar, besides almost innumerable small craft, among which are 100 to 200 canal-boats. The gun-boats number from 20 to 25. From Rich-mond we learn that the obstructions in the river had been considerably weakened by the recent freshets; that Fort Darling had been greatly strengthened and the batteries iron-clad; that, a division of the Con-federate army had crossed the river on a pontoon-bridge to assist in its defence against any land force. A gun-boat on the plan of the Merrimac was rapidly approaching completion at Richmond, though great difficulty was experienced in obtaining iron for her armour.</p>

<p>President Davis had issued an address to the army congratulating

them "on the series of brilliant victories" which they had lately

won which had forced the foe, "despite his reinforcements, to seek shelter under the cover of his gun-boats where he now lies cowering

before the army so lately divided and threatened with entire
subju-gation." General Lee also congratulates the army upon relieving Richmond from a state of siege, and claims to have captured fifty-three pieces of artillery in the late engagement.</p>

 <p>In the valley of the Shenandoah all is quiet. Labourers are wanted

to gather the bountiful harvests. General Pope had issued a general order that the army would subsist on the country in which he was about to carry on operations.</p>

<p>The West has been prolific of desultory contests. Murfreesborough
has been taken and evacuated. The Federal General Duffield was
mortally wounded, and the Confederate General Twiggs killed in the
affair. The south-west is overrun with guerrillas. The Confederates
have captured Cynthiana and Henderson, in Kentucky, and have even
crossed the Ohio River, for the first time since the war commenced, and seized the river town of Newbourg, in the free State of Indiana. In view of these events the Governor of Ohio had called out volunteers for thirty days, to resist incursions from Kentucky.</p>

<p>Vicksburg still holds out, and the canal which is to divert the

course of the river, and which is being dug by negroes in the Federal service, advances towards completion. A Confederate ram had arrived at Vicksburg, and, after inflicting considerable damage upon the Federal fleet, had anchored under cover of the Confederate batteries.</p>

<p>The story that B&#x00e2;ton Rouge had been recaptured by the Confede-rates is without foundation in fact.</p>

<p>General Curtis, by forced marches, had safely arrived at Helena, Arkanese. after worsting the Confederates in several small engage-ments. The Confederate General Price has crossed the Mississippi into Arkansas to co-operate against General Curtis.</p>

<p>The British steamer Ann was discovered by a United States' frigate

 and gun-boat under the guns of Fort Morgan, Mobile Bay, unloading
arms and gunpowder. The former engaged the fort, and the latter
succeeded in cutting the British vessel out. Her cargo consisted of
war material, tea, coffee, pepper, and the like.</p>

<p rend="center">WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>Congress adjourned on the 17th ult. During the Session it has appropriated 800,000,000 dols., including 560,000,000 dols. for the Army and 100 000,000 dols. for the Navy.</p>

<p>Congress has passed the Militia Bill, authorising the President to
employ negroes for camp service, or any military or, naval service for
which they are competent; also to accept 100,000 volunteers for nine
months, with the usual bounty.</p>

<p>President Lincoln had signed the Confiscation Bill, with amendments
that the provisions of the bill should not apply to acts of rebels
done previous to the passing of the bill, and that the confiscation
is to be only during the lifetime of offenders.</p>

<p>The President had signed an Act for issuing postage and other
stamps for currency, and forbidding banks or corporations to issue
bills for less than one dollar.</p>

<p>The House of Representatives had postponed the Senate Bill for the
admission of Western Virginia until the next Session of Congress by a
vote of 63 to 53.</p>

<p>In the Senate, Mr. Chandler denounced M'Clellan's tactics,
declaring that tens of thousands of men were killed in the swamps of
the Chickahominy, and that 158,000 men were sent to M'Clellan previous
to the battles before Richmond.</p>

<p>The Border States members had issued a majority report opposing
President Lincoln's emancipation scheme, and a minority report favouring the scheme.</p>

<p rend="center">THE NORTHERN SCHEME.</p>


<p>The press and public meetings continue to stir up popular
enthusiasm for the war. Nevertheless, the recruits do not come forward
in the large numbers needed by the Government. The State of Vermont
had been the first to raise a regiment under the new oak and dispatch
it to the seat of war.</p>

<p>The Great Eastern was anchored in Flushing Bay, on the northern
coast of Long Island, about eight miles east of New York City. The New
York <hi rend="italic">Tribune</hi> says, "The experiment of bringing
her through the Race and up Long Island Sound to her anchorage in
Flushing Bay was a complete success. She was brought to her ancherags
with as much ease and dispatch as any ordinary vessel would have
been." The passengers were conveyed to the city by steamers expressly
provided by the agents. Before leaving, the passengers presented a
Complimentary letter and resolutions to Captain Paton. She approached
New York by this route instead of by the Hudson River, because her
heavy cargo rendered her incapable of entering by the latter
inlet.</p>

<p>Gold has risen to twenty per cent, and silver to fifteen per cent
premium. The city of Newark, in order to meet the outcry for small
change, has issued corporation notes for small amounts varying from
ten cents. (5d.) to fifty. The strike of the grain shovellers of New
York against the floating grain e1evetor, is a serious check to the
most flourishing department of the export trade of the States.</p>

<p rend="center">CALIFORNIA.</p>

On the 10th ult. thcte was a grand torchlight procession in San
Francisco in honour of the passage of the Pacific Railroad Bill. Many
houses were illuminated.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1157.002" n="The American Patent Machine"
      type="article">
<head>[The American Patent Machine]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1157</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.119</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-02">August 2, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>The American Patent Machine for milking cows has been tested at the
exhibition with great success. It milked a cow in three
minutes.</p></div2>
<div2 id="iln41.1157.003" n="The Illustrated London News"
      type="article">
<head>THE ILLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1157</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.122</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-02">August 2, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>


<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">LONDON, SATURDAY, AUGUST</hi> 2, 1282.</p>

<p><hi rend="smallcaps">American</hi> news is more important than
exciting. In the midst of a mass of detail of a complex character
comes the announce-ment that Congress enables the President to employ
the Negro in any military or naval service for which he may be
qualified. If, therefore, a "contraband" of warlike genius should
arise, there should be nothing to prevent his becoming an officer of
the United States Army or Navy, and leading the Whites into
action. Surely Africa is winning in the great game, whatever may be
the ill fortune of Europe and America. We further learn that the
unwise act--to give it no harsher name--by which the breach between
North and South is rendered irreparable--the act of confiscation, and
imposition of the penalty of death, in the case of every Confederate
who shall be in arms after the middle of September--has not been
vetoed by the President, but has received his assent, with the
amendment that it shall not be an<hi rend="italic"> ex post facto</hi>
law. That Mr. Lincoln dared not repudiate a measure at which his
judg-ment revolted shows the greatly increasing power of the
Republican section in the North, as opposed to the Demoecats, and that
it is clear that the idea of reconstructing the Union has been
renounced by the former. The currency question exerts its fatal power
in the North, as elsewhere, and various shifts are being employed to
mitigate inconvenience, postage and other stamps being made legal
tender. Congress had adjourned, having during the Session appropriated
800,000,000 dollars. Thomas Moore wrote, in the Prince Regent's
days--</p>

<p rend="center">When mighty Beishazzar brims high in the hall</p>
 <p rend="center">His cup full of <hi rend="italic">go&#x00fb;t</hi>
to the Gaul's overthrow,</p>
<p rend="center">Lo, "Eight Hundred Millions" I write on the wall,</p>
<p rend="center"> And the cup falls to earth and the gout to his
toe.</p>
<p> We may believe that still more crippling results will he found to
have followed Jonathan's indulgence in the luxury of
extra-vagance. The military news represents the Confederates as having
gained a number of small but exhilarating successes, and of having
effected some movements of a really "strategic" kind, and which will
be found to have value in the later part of the campaign. M'Clellan
had been reinforced, and in one column of an American journal we read
"Enormous Enthusiasm for Little Mac," while in the report of the
proceedings in the Senate we find him denounced in no measured terms,
and charged with having lost men by tens of thousands in the
swamps. At last the North, which has had several pseudo-Napoleons, has
found one general capable of treading in the steps of Bonaparte. --
General Pope has proclaimed that "war is to support war," that the
Federal armies are to live upon the resources of the country in which
operations may be carried on. Every successive act of the Federals
further destroys the fiction that they are not dealing with
"belligerents." Re-cruiting is said to proceed very slowly, in spite
of the large sums offered by the Governments. The Confederate General
at Richmond congratulates the army there upon having delivered that
city from a state of siege, and states that fifty-three Federal guns
have been taken in the recent engagements. For what strategic purpose
it was desired that these should be in the hands of the enemy General
M'Clellan will explain at his leisure; the Duke of Wellington was
rather particular upon this subject, and we remember seeing him
touchingly earnest upon one occasion in explaining to the Lords that
in all affair to which reference had been made two or three guns were
supposed to have been lost, but he would not move until they had been
brought in. We are justified in bringing in the name of a single
Wellington where so many Napoleons are set up. Lastly, the prompt act
of the English authorities in seizing a Confederate vessel that had
violated the Queen's orders had received tolerably courteous
recognition at New York, and this is something in the present temper
of the North.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1157.004" n="The Wife of General Beauregard"
      type="article">
<head>[The Wife of General Beauregard]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1157</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.122</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-02">August 2, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The wife of General Beauregard has died at New Orleans.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1157.005" n="Plan of the Seat of War in Eastern
      Virginia" type="article">
<head>PLAN OF THE SEAT OF WAR IN EASTERN VIRGINIA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1157</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.128</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-02">August 2, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>T<hi rend="smallcaps">HE</hi> Plan which we present to our readers
on page 125 covers an area of about 20,000 square miles, and includes
a large portion of the country between the Blue Ridge on the west and
Chesapeake Bay on the east, between the Potomac on the north and James
River on the South, which has been the theatre of the best-contested
conflicts on land and sea between the Federals and Confederates. East
of the Chesapeake are the two peninsular counties of Virginia and a
portion of the "eastern shore" section of Maryland. West of it lies a
nobly-watered country, including portions of Maryland, the district of
Columbia, and the "tide-water" section of Virginia. The rivers falling
into the Chesapeake from the west are sucessively from north to south,
the Patuxent, Potomac, Rappahannock, York (formed by the confluence of
the Pamunkey and Maltapony), and, lastly, the James. In the north-west
corner of the plan are to be seen the cities of Washington,
Georgetown, and Alexandria. The country intersected by the York and
James Rivers abounds in points of interest. At the extremity of the
peninsula formed by those two rivers are Fort Monroe and
Hampton. Nearly opposite, on the Elizabeth River, are Norfolk and the
Gosport Navy-yard. On the York River, near its embouchure, is the
little port of Yorktown, famous for the surrender of Lord Conwallis to
the American forces in 1781. It<pb n="129"/> recently fell into the
hands of the Federals, when the Confederates fell back on
Richmond. Jamestown, a little village on the north bank of the James
River, thirty-two miles from its mouth, was the seat of the first
permanent English colony in America (in 1607). A few miles above
Jamestown the Chickahominy discharges itself into the James. About
halfway between Richmond and the mouth of the Chickahominy, lies the
hilly country, where M'Clellan's army is now stationed. Still higher
up, and only seven miles below Richmond, is Fort Darling, where the
course of the river is obstructed to prevent the passage of the
Federal gun-boats. Richmond itself is situated on the north bank of
the James, about 100 miles from its mouth. Directly oppoeite to
Richmond are its suburbs of Manchester and, Spring Hill, which are
connected with the city by three bridges. Five lines of railroad
radiate from the capital of Virginia. The Richmond and York River
Railroad, which in times of peace connected the city with the
aforesaid river, was the line by which M'Clellan supplied his army,
and on which his head-quarters at White House were situated until his
recent change of front and base of operations. His right wing at one
time was extended so far as to rest on the Virginia Central Railway, a
line running north from Richmond just north of the point where it
crosses the Chickahominy. This river and the White Oak Swamp, across
which his army retreated, lie between the Richmond and York River
Railway and the James River. On the south bank of this river, nearly
opposite to Turkey Bend, is City Point, where the Federal flotilla is
now anchored. This is also the point where the Appomattox flows into
the James.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1157.006" n="The Civil War in America: Scene of
      Operations in Eastern Virginia, Showing M'Clellan's Present
      Position.--See Page 128." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1157</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.125</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-02">August 2, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="v41p125">
<head>The Civil War in America: Scene of
      Operations in Eastern Virginia, Showing M'Clellan's Present
      Position.--See Page 128.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1157.007" n="Atrocious Act of Piracy" type="article">
<head>ATROCIOUS ACT OF PIRACY</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1157</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.138</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-02">August 2, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A<hi rend="smallcaps">TROCIOUS ACT OF PIRACY</hi>-The secretary at Lloyd's has
received from the Board of Trade a copy of a despatch from the British
Consul at Malaga relative to an atrocious act of piracy committed near
the Spanish coast. A short time ago the American barque Reindeer,
Captain J. N. Hewlett, master, received a cargo of salt at Cette, for
New York. At one o'clock on the morning of the 9th ult, she had
proceeded on her homeward voyage to a point about thirty miles to the
south-east of Malaga. There two Spanish seamen belonging to the crew
surprised and murdered the second mate, the carpenter, the cook, and
another seaman, wounded the master, the chief mate, and two
others. They plundered the ship of some 400 dols, in specie, and a
watch. They stove one of the boats, and absconded with the other one,
after setting fire to the vessel fore and aft. At eight am. the
American ship Minstrel, and the English brig Susannah hove in sight,
and Captain Hewlett and the survivors of his crew were transhipped on
board the Minstrel. At six p.m. they abandoned the Reindeer, and very
soon afterwards she became completely enveloped in flames. Two of the
victims were British subjects. The second mate, John H. Hanson, was a
native of Liverpool; and a seaman. Henry Frost Jones, was a native of
Cardiff. Both of them were murdered in their berths; the bodies were
left on board and went down with the burning ship. The boat in which
the pirates quitted the Reindeer has been found on the beach a few
miles to the eastward of Malaga.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1157.008" n="Textile Manufactures in the International
      Exhibition. Cotton--Foreign Division." type="article">
<head>Textile Manufactures in the International Exhibition</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1157</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.142</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-02">August 2, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">COTTON--FOREIGN DIVISION.</p>

<p rend="center">U<hi rend="smallcaps">NITED STATES</hi>.</p>

<p>The only exhibitors of cotton goods from the United States are
Messrs.  Gardner, Brewer, and Co., of Boston, Massachusetts (96). The
goods shown are a very superior quality of fine shirtings, which were
certainly not produced a few years ago in any part of the
States. These goods arrived very late, and have not been included in
the awards of the jury, which they certainly ought to have been if in
time for examination.</p>

<p>Having noticed, as far as the space at our disposal will admit, all
the countries which exhibit cotton goods worthy of special
examination, we must conclude with simply recording the interesting
fact that the jury of class 18 has awarded three prize medals to
exhibitors of raw cotton grown in New South Wales, and the same number
to exhibitors of the same material grown in Queensland. One exhibitor
in each colony is distinguished in the awards-Mr. J. B. Nowlan (41),
New South Wales, and Mr. W. Cairncross (18),Queensland-as exhibiting
"splendid cotton," and the others as being of "good and useful
qualities." This is a distinct proof that the British colonies of the
Southern Hemisphere can produce raw cotton which will satisfy the
fastidious taste of an international jury of cotton manufacturers, and
this is saying a great deal, when the prejudice in favour of American
cotton, and, unfortunately, nothing but American cotton is taken into
account.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1158.001" n="The Cotton of Various Climes"
      type="article">
<head>THE COTTON OF VARIOUS CLIMES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1158</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.149</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-09">August 9, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p><hi rend="smallcaps">If</hi> the shade of one of those vigorous
Englishmen who laid the foundations of our manufacturing prosperity--a
Watt or an Arkwright, for instance--could just now revisit the scenes
he so dearly loved, how inexplicable would seem to him the distress of
our artisans&#x0021; How difficult it would be to explain to him why
such a calamity should have happened, or, if it had happened, why it
was not speedily put an end to. Let us but review in thought the kind
of questions and answers that would have to be exchanged. "Has the
cotton crop suddenly failed through a universal blight?" No; but we
can't get our usual supply on account of a civil war in
America."--What, then, are you dependent mainly upon that one source?"
"Yes &#x0021;"-"And were the merchants and manufacturers never warned
of the danger of thus relying &#x003f;" "Often; but the warnings were
never heeded."-" Then, of course, there was no special cause of fear
inherent in the nature of the case?" "Indeed but there was; all the
cotton from the Southern States of America was slave-grown, and there
were probably few Englishmen who did not believe that some day or
other the system must come to the ground with a crash."</p>

<p>And; if such a glimpse of the causes of our trouble would seem
necessarily surprising to the shade of a truehearted and strong-souled
Englishman of no earlier era, how would he look on the present aspect
of affairs, and on the future prospects of remedy they open? Suppose
we pursue a little further our imaginary dialogue, which, as will be
seen, deals with no imaginary facts:<hi rend="italic"> they</hi>,
unhappily, are but too real. "How long may it be since this war broke
out?" "It is now in its second year."--"And what has been done by you
all in England to put an end to so terrible a state of things?" "By
us? 0, we have read, the papers daily, to see how the war was going
on, and to judge how it was likely to end."-"And now?" "Why, now we
incline to think that it grows more intense than ever, and that its
termination is more hopelessly distant."--"And you really mean to say
that neither your Parliament, nor your manufacturers, nor your cotton
operatives have done or are doing anything effectual to ensure the
reopening of all these deserted or half-deserted mills, and the relief
of millions of your people from so unnatural a suffering &#x003f;""
Why, you see, the difficulties of action great."--" You mean that
cotton grows but in few places, and is not of easy culture?" "No; next
to corn there is no product at once so valuable and so widely
dispersed over the globe as cotton, or that grows so spontaneously
where it grows at all. The hand of Providence seems to be everywhere
raising up for the human family in boundless profusion the corn
wherewith to make the bread we eat, and the cotton wherewith to make
the clothes we wear."--" Perhaps, then, it is England's peculiar
misfortune to be shut out from the cotton-fields of the world?" "On
the contrary, she has, in no less than four out of five of the great
divisions of the world--Asia, Africa, America, and
Australia-cotton-fields of almost limitless extent."--" Well, I can
but venture on two or three questions more (so strangely confusing
does the whole business appear). Has England any high motives of state
for not encouraging the growth of this all-important plant in her own
dominions &#x003f;"" She has every conceivable motive and temptation
for doing the very reverse. To take a single instance. We now hold
India by the tenure of a European force seventy thousand strong; if we
could but substitute for that tenure the right of taking from her
three millions of cotton-bales for English use, and of repaying her by
an equal amount of manufactured goods for the use of the people of
India, we might at once recall half our soldiery: these delicate
cotton filaments would doubtless prove -of greater tenacity for
holding nation to nation than the strongest sword ever forged."-"
Well, but England is, perhaps, very poor just now, unable to do more
than take care of these her half-famished children who have been so
suddenly stricken down?" "Excuse my smile in answer; we are so troubled with a plethora of gold
that the Bank of England discounts at two and a half per cent; and
capital, not knowing what else to do with itself, is flowing away,
first to Turkey, then to Morocco, next to Egypt, then to Italy, then
to Portugal, and seems, indeed; piteously begging foreign countries of
all kinds to take pity on its destitute state."-" One guess more, and
I have done. Has there fallen upon the world an evil period when
industrial skill and energy are paralysed, and no one has the heart to
move in an unaccustomed way?"" Come and look at our International
Exhibition, and there you will have your answer! You will see that
never before in all human history were the elements of industrial
prosperity and material grandeur so rife as now."</p>

<p>We will not any longer trespass upon the reader's indulgence by
taking an indirect mode of trying to bring home to him the very
peculiar position in which we now as a nation stand; but we should
like to take such a reader with us to the building just mentioned,
that we might pursue with him the interesting question that forms our
theme to-day. We should like him to see with his own eyes the samples
of cotton that are there being exhibited, to study their quality, and
to mark how wide are the geographical boundaries of the world's
cotton-field. We should desire him to dwell especially on the samples
from India, and to note from how many different parts of that splendid
country ye can reckon supplies. No less than sixteen prize medals have
been awarded for Indian cotton, and the value thus suggested is still
more directly confirmed by the market prices that have been affixed to
them by the commissioners. The lowest price is 11d. per lb. ; the
highest (from Penang), 2s.; and the average 12&#x00bd;d. We would ask
him to remember that India has already, in a single year (1861), sent
us very nearly a bird of the three million bales that we require; that
the most popular of all the South American kinds, the New Orleans,
rows perfectly in India from American seed; and that the best judges
calculate that, even at present, the annual growth of the country
amounts to something like six million bales, or twice the entire
amount of our demand. Of course, India needs cotton for herself; and
cannot under any circumstances, be expected without preparation to
spare very largely from he ordinary stock; but still she can spare, no
doubt, far more thn we seem likely to get from her under existing
arrangements.</p>

 <p>From the study of the Indian cotton samples we would have the
 visitor go to that of the samples from Jamaica, which prove that our
 West Indian colonies can grow as good cotton, and as cheaply, by free
 negro labour, as it has been grown in America by slaves. He will find
 among them samples of almost fabulous value, varying from 2s. 8d. to
 3s.6d. per lb. And it is estimated that Jamaica alone could furnish
 half a million bales yearly. So again we shall find in the exhibition
 Barbadoes cotton, worth 2s. 10d, a pound; Bermuda, worth
 ll&#x00bd;d. ; Ceylon, worth from l0d; to 1s. 9d.; and Trinidad,
 worth 2s. 11d. Or yet again to pass to the samples from quite other
 parts of the world, but still keeping within our own dominions (where
 it is our fellow-subjects who ask us to trade with them by exchanging
 cotton for manufactures), there is Natal, which sends us samples
 ranging in value from l2&#x00bd;d to 2s., and reminds us of the
 inexhaustible cotton-fields of Africa on which Dr. Livingstone has
 been so wisely eloquent. The plant is indigenous there, and grows to
 wondrous profusion. What a blessing alike to us and to the benighted
 Africans would it not be if we could teach their chiefs to employ
 their spare population in growing cotton at home as free men instead
 of selling them away to foreign lands to be there similarly engaged
 as slaves&#x0021; And then, too, there is that recent but most
 wonderful development of British blood and enterprise, the Australian
 community, which promises to be able before long to give us all the
 wool and all the cotton that even our two colossal manufactures
 demand. Take Queensland for instance, where the best South American
 cotton-seed flourishes in perfection, both the Sea Island kind, and
 the less valuable short staples. The local Government of the colony
 appears to be quite aware of thre value of the prospect. It has
 offered a bonus of ten acres of land for every bale of a certain size
 of Sea Island cotton grown in the colony. Here then, is a field from
 which, if no other existed in the world, all our necessities might be
 supplied in a few years. And as to the value of the cotton it
 produces, let us look to the practical opinions of the commissioners,
 who have affixed the almost incredible price of 3s. 6d. per pound to
 Mr. Rode's sample; and there are other samples similarly
 distinguished by the very high price of 3s. 3d.</p>

 <p>Not one bale of cotton, therefore, do we need that cannot be well
 and wisely grown--that is to say, economically--in our own
 colonies. But it is quite certain that we shall not be allowed to
 depend upon them exclusively. Here is Brazil with its samples of
 equal but moderate excellence, averaging in value about 1s., sending
 us already--in 1861--nearly 100,000 bales. Here is Egypt, with its
 Pacha claiming and obtaining a prize for his cotton, valued at
 1s. 8d., and telling us, through the lips of its excellent Viceroy,
 that whereas last year it sent us about the same quantity as Brazil,
 we may expect next year at least one-half as much more. Syria is
 trying, and with success, both Egyptian and American seed. France,
 too, is joining in the struggle, as the possessor of Algeria; where
 the very finest possible kinds of cotton are being grown, and of a
 commercial value that the exhibition commissioners mark by numerous
 prizes (eighteen) for samples varying in worth from 2s. 6d. to
 3s. 6d. per lb. Turkey, too, claims to be able to grow and sell
 cotton of a useful kind; so does Russia, her old antagonist ; so does
 Portugal; and so do most of the South American Republics. But there
 is one nation that we should have hardly expected to find thinking of
 cotton just now, when arms appear to be so much more attractive to
 it, and possibly in its view so necessary-that is Italy. It is said,
 and apparently with truth, that else could give us next year 100,000
 bales by merely devoting to the culture some of those southern
 districts that are now lying waste and breeding miasma instead of
 expanding their surplus heat and moisture in cotton. The prize
 samples of Italian cotton in the exhibition are valued generally at
 about 1s. 1&#x00bd;d, per lb.</p>

<p>Why, then, are we in our present difficulty, and how are we to get
out of it? These are this questions we ought to ask, and not rest till
a clear and sufficing answer has been given to them. Looking
practically at the position, we shall find that we must distinguish
between the countries that cannot immediately give us, an increased
supply and those that can; and the part of true wisdom surely must be
to take immediate help from the one class while urging this other on
to give us permanent relief. It is probable that India is this only
country that can be relied on to mitigate our present strait. And why
do we not seek the co-operation of that country? The answer must be,
because Indian views of political-which means national economy do not
agree with the views of English manufacturers. The latter appear to
think it very good economy to say to time millions of Hindostan. " Be
you quite ready to 'supply,' but don't rely upon as to 'demand.' No
wonder the people of India decline the flattering invitation."</p>

<p>"Last May," says Mr. Saunders, the commissioner appointed by the
late Lord Canning to inquire into the growth of cotton in India, " I
was in the cotton districts ; and, as the period for sewing cotton was
approaching, I asked some of the growers if they intruded to increase
the cultivation of cotton, as the price had risen so high in England?
They replied, 'Sahib, we hear of high prices, but there are no buyers
or contractors here. When the Sahibs want indigos or sugar, or
oilseeds, they come among its and build kothees (factories), make
advances and contracts; but in the case of cotton, which is said to be
so much wanted, there is not a single Sahib buyer or contractor. No;
there is something wrong. We won't grow more than we want for
ourselves or our native merchants.' The manufacturer steadily declines
to send out his agent; the Indian landholder as steadily declines to
increase his cotton cultivation. The latter is no sufferer, for he
continues to grow his indigo, sugar, cereals&#x0026;c.; and will grow
cotton when a local demand arises for it, and is quite indifferent
whether that demand comes in one year, or in ten years, or at all. And
what is the position of the former? A ruined trade and a starving
population around him. One-tenth of the funds required to support that
population during the cessation of the cotton manufacture would
suffice to establish agencies in Berar and the North-West Provinces :
that would increase in one season the present production by a million
of bales, and, in process of time, would produce sufficient cotton to
supply all the wants of England."</p>

 <p>Here is the whole problem for us in a nutshell. We must send out
 agents with the money in their hands to buy, for we shall not get
 Indian cotton sent here on speculation to sell. The Hindoos know as
 well as we do the possible contingency of a sudden influx of American
 cotton, and they are determined that if it does take place it shall
 not be at their cost. And however we may turn or twist the matter
 about, whether we say it is or is not in accordance with the
 teachings of economical science, we shall have to come back to the
 same original starting-point, Do we need cotton from India? then we
 must fetch it at our own risk. We can get it at a very moderate
 price; but we must pay that price, not ask the Indians to speculate
 on getting probably a much larger, possibly a much smaller, one. Many
 modes of action have been proposed, such as a differen-tial duty for
 a time (say three years) in favour of free-grown cotton, which would
 cause American slave-grown cotton to be taxed if it came into
 competition during the three years. It has also been suggested that
 Government may itself buy the cotton required for a brief period,
 taking precautions against anything beyond a temporary interference;
 or it may guarantee a five per cent dividend to cotton companies for
 a similarly sort period while they undertake the work and risk. Or,
 lastly, our manufacturers themselves might do all that is requisite
 by a combination amongst their own members to buy or bargain for all
 the cotton they require for a year or two, and so share the gain or
 the loss that might accrue from their cotton-buying speculation. If
 any of these modes are adopted, the end of view can clearly be
 obtained; and it would be desirable to adopt the one that best
 harmonises with the ordinary course business and with teachings of
 economists. But if all of them are refused or neglected, we must make
 up our minds to continue to suffer with constantly-increasing
 severity for an indefinite term ; with all the risks of political
 agitation ; while no longer able to attribute our distress to a
 sudden and unforeseen cause, and still less to any lack of the
 Divine bounty.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1158.002" n="Illustration of the War in America"
      type="article">
<head>ILLUSTRATION OF THE WAR IN AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1158</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.150</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-09">August 9, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center">COTTONBURNERS SURPRISED BY FEDERAL SCOUTS.</p>

<p>0<hi rend="smallcaps">UR</hi> Special Artist writes from Memphis as
follows rsepesting the Illustration on the preceding page :-" The only
excitement now in the immediate neighbourhood of Memphis and in
Southwestern Tennessee generally is an occasional collision between
scouting parties of Indiana cavalry and the guerrilla bands of
cottonburners. I send you a Sketch, the result of one of my scouts
with a troop of horse, in which we came upon a party of Southerners
one plantation destroying every bale they could lay, their hands
on. In the foreground an officer is "hurrying up" the business; one
man applies the torch to a pile of loose cotton; others are ripping
open and rolling up the bales; while a group of frightened whites and
negroes are assembled under the perch of the house, We took two or
three of the guerrilla band; the rest scattered and made for the
surrounding timber."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1158.003" n="Foreign and Colonial News" type="article">
<head>AMERICA</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1158</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.151</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-09">August 9, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>By the arrival of the Montreal Company's steamer Norwegian we have
telegrams, vi&#x00e2; Cape Race, until the 28th ult.</p>

<p>WAR NEWS.</p>

<p>General Halleck, late Commander of the forces in the Department of
the Mississippi valley, has been officially appointed General-in-Chief
to command all the land forces of the United States. The appointment
has been favourably received by the Northern public, who have lost
their former faith in General M'Clellan.</p>

<p>The President had issued a proclamation<orig reg="authorizing">
authorising</orig> the military, commanders to seize and use for the
Federal army all property, real and personal, in the rebel States
which might be necessary for military and purposes. The military and
naval officers are ordered to employ as many negroes for labourers as
can be advantageously used for military and naval purposes, and pay
them wages.</p>

<p>General Pope had issued orders to the army under his command to
seize all houses, mules, and stores in their vicinity not absolutely
needed by the inhabitants of the surrounding country. All the
inhabitants must take the oath of allegiance or be driven south. The
inhabitants who break the oath will be shot.</p>

<p>The same General reports that a calvary expedition had, at this
directions, made a descent upon the Virginia Central Railroad at
Beaver Dam Creek, thirty-five miles from Richmond. They destroyed the
railroad and telegraph lines for several miles, burned up the
d&#x00e9;p&#x00f4;t, which contained 40,000 rounds of musket
ammunition, 100 barrels of flour, and other valuable property. The
Confederate General Jackson was in or near Gordonsville, and a
collision between his army and that of General Pope was daily
expected.</p>

<p>From the army of the Potomac, we learn nothing beyond that the
health of the army is improving, and that General M'Clellan has
expelled all civilians, including newspaper correspondents, from the
camp.</p>

<p>General Dix has been appointed commissioner to negotiate with the
Confederates for a general exchange of prisoners. Thus the full
belligerent rights of the Confederates are at length conceded.</p>

<p>It is officially reported that the Federal loss in the recent
battles before Richmond was 16,000 men.</p>

<p>The Confederate General Johnston's report of the battle of Seven
Pines has appeared. He mentions his own weak state from wounds
received. He charges upon General Huger's delay the escape from
destruction of on entire Federal corps. He claims to have captured on
that occasion ten pieces of artillery, 6000 muskets, one garrison
flag, and four regimental colours, besides a large quantity of tents
and camp equipage. The Confederate loss was 4283.</p>

<p>In Kentucky, Tennessee, and Missouri, the activity of the guerilla
bands increases. A plot to rise and seize the city had been discovered
in St. Louis. The loyal Governor had called out the State militia and
forbidden the sale of arms. Many of the British subjects in St. Louis
had thronged the Consul's office in that city, to get certificates of
nationality, protecting them from the conscription. Here they had been
attacked by a mob. A detachment of the provost guard was ordered out
and the outbreak suppressed.</p>

<p>The Federal Commander Farragut had abandoned the siege of
Vicksburg, and left, with his flotilla, for New Orleans.</p>

<p>In view of General Butler's proceedings at New Orleans, the
President had issued an order, prohibiting military commanders from
exacting an oath of allegiance from aliens, and absolving such aliens
as had taken such an oath from its obligations. In all cases where an
alien is deprived of his liberty, a full account of the Circumstances
must be sent to the War Department, for the consideration of the
Department of the State.</p>

<p>At the request of the British Ambassador, conveyed by the
Commander of her Majesty's sloop-of-war Rinaldo, General Butler had
consented to recognise Mr. George Coppell as Acting British Consul,
upon the latter's apologising for an offensive expression which he had
made use of respecting General Butler's orders.</p>

<p>The British steamer Adela had been captured by a Federal vessel off
Abaco, one of the Bahamas. The British steamer Tubal Cain had been
captured off Charleston. The British schooner Star of the East had
been seized by the Custom House officials in New York, and the case
referred to the Secretary of the Treasury. She took out a clearance
for Long Cay, in the Bahamas, and it was asserted her cargo consisted
of goods well adapted for the use of the Confederates.</p>

<p>Recruiting for the Federal army still languished. The
municipalities and the State Legislatures continued to offer very high
bounties, but the attractions of the harvest-field seemed greater than
those of the battle-field to the mass of the labouring
classes. General Meagher had addressed the Irish of New York with the
view of stimulating them to enlist. The Governor of Ohio had announced
that if the quota of that State was not ready in forty days he should
resort to draughting.</p>

 <p rend="center">THE EMANCIPATION QUESTION.</p>

 <p>President Lincoln's appeal to the Border State members is very
 urgent in recommending them to accept his proposals. He says, that
 "if the war continues long the institution in your States will be
 extinguished by mere friction and abrasion--by the mere incidents of
 war." In repudiating General Hunter's proclamation, he says, I gave
 dissatisfaction, if not offence, to many whose support I cannot
 afford to lose. And this is not the end of it. The pressure in this
 direction is still upon me, and is increasing."</p>

<p>Twenty of the Border State members have replied that Congress had
not voted any sum for remuneration, and that they could not consider
the proposition in its impalpable form. When a formal proposition was
made, backed by the necessary appropriations, they might submit it to
their states, but the debt it would involve appalled them by its
magnitude. They had contributed their full share to the support of the
war, and they did not see why they should be called upon to make
sacrifices greater than the people of other States, who were not more
loyal. They would under no circumstances consent to the dissolution of
the Union, neither would they ever consent to join the Southern
Confederacy, as they could not place their security in the the custody
of an association which had incorporated in its organic law the seeds
of its own destruction. They deny that their refusal to adopt
emancipation had prolonged the war. They would not, under any
circumstances, become parties to General Hunter's policy of letting
loose the slaves on the Southern people.</p>

<p>The minority of the Border State members, eight in number, respond favourably:--</p>

 <q>We are the more emboldened to assume this position from the
 fat,now become history, that the leaders of the Southern rebellion
 have offere to abolish slavery among them as a condition to foreing
 intervention in favour of their independence as a nation. f they can
 give up slavery to destroy the Union, we can surely ask our people to
 consider the question of emancipation to save the Union.</q>

<p>Several committees, composed of the Mayor and many of the leading
merchants and lawyers of New York, have passed resolutions declaring
that no qualified unionism should be longer permitted, and that it is
far better every rebel should perish than that one more loyal man
should die. The committee therefore earnestly call upon the President
immediately to issue an emancipation proclamation, "This," they say,
"will diminish the rebel army by calling many rebel officers and men
to the defense of their homes. The Free States and the whole, <orig
reg="civilized">civilised</orig> world will applaud the emancipation
proclamation."</p>

<p rend="center">MISCELLANEOUS.</p>
<p> The crops are generally good throughout the North, but there is a
scarcity of labourers. One railroad company advertised in New York for
fifty labourers and did not receive any applications. This is
attributable to the drain caused by the war.</p>

<p>The Danish Government had agreed to take as apprentices all negroes
captured on board slave vessels by the Federal cruisers.</p>

<p>It is reported from Key West that a Federal gun-boat had captured a
large barque on the Coast of Cuba, just as she was unloading her last
boat of slaves. She was at Key West under charge of a prize crew. One
hundred thousand dollars were found on board.</p>

<p>Gold had fallen; but still commanded 17 per cent premium.</p>

<p rend="center">OBITUARY</p>

<p>Ex-President Van Buren died an his estate at Kinderbrook, in the
State of New York, on the 24th ult., at the advanced age of
seventy-eight. He was President of the United States from March 4,
1837, to March 4, 1841, being the successor of General Jackson and the
predecessor of General Harrison and Mr. Tyler, the last of whom died
lately at Richmond. It was during his presidency that the Canadian
rebellion took place. He was elected to his office by the Democratic
party, which, however, failed to re-elect him in 1840, when he was
defeated by the Whig candidate, General Harrison. In 1848 he was the
candidate of the Free-soil Democrats. To this schism in the Democratic
camp General Cass, the regular Democratic nominee, owed his defeat,
and General Taylor, the Whig candidate, his election. Since then the
deceased took no active part in American politics. His death leaves
but three surviving ex-Presidents of the United States--viz.,
Messrs. Fillmore, Pierce, said Buchanan.</p></div2> 

<div2 id="iln41.1158.001" n="The Queen's Speech." type="article">
<head>THE QUEEN'S SPEECH.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1158</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.154</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-09">August 9, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic"><hi rend="smallcap">London,
Saturday, August 9, 1862.</hi></hi></p>

<p rend="center">----</p>

<p rend="center">THE QUEEN'S SPEECH.</p>

<p><hi rend="smallcap">On</hi> Thursday afternoon the Commissioners
appointed by her Majesty to prorogue parliament took their seats
shortly before two o'clock. The Commons having been summoned, the
Speaker, with a few members, appeared at the bar ; and, the Royal assent
having been given to some public and private bills, the Lord
Chancellor read her Majesty's Speech, which was as follows :--....</p>

<p>The civil war which has for some time been raging among the States
of the North American Union has unfortunately continued in unabated
intensity ; and the evils with which it has been attended have not been
confined to the American continent. But her Majesty, having from the
outset determined to take no part in the contest, has seen no reason
to depart from the neutrality to which she has steadily adhered....</p>

<p>Her Majesty has given her ready assent to an Act for carrying into
effect the treaty which her Majesty has concluded with the President
of the United States for the suppression of the slave trade and her
Majesty trusts that the co-operation of the United States' navy with
her own may go far to extinguish the desolating crime against which
that treaty is directed.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1158.002" n="'Great Expectations' are the burden of
      the American telegrams." type="article">
<head>'GREAT EXPECTATIONS' ARE THE BURDEN OF THE AMERICAN TELEGRAMS.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1158</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.154</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-09">August 9, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p><hi rend="smallcap">"Great</hi> expectations" are the burden of the
American telegrams. We are also told of much "uneasiness," a word of
significance in troubled times, and one which implies an unhealthy
state of feeling as regards the authorities. It would seem that the
reluctance of the people to enlist in the armies, while the Generals
appeared to be objectless and the incidents of the war were so
disastrous, was represented as being unabated ; and the President's
proclamation calling on the South to take notice of the new law which
made them liable to the penalties of treason was regarded as <hi
rend="italic">brutum fulmen</hi>. The intention of employing the negro
in military and naval work was very unfavourably commented upon by
many who grudge the "contraband" any of the gain of the war, but was
approved by his friends as a new recognition of his status as a man
and a brother. In spite of meetings, which are variously described as
glorious demonstrations and as utter failures, and at which
excessively tall talk had been emitted, and the most portentous
declarations had been made to the effect that it was better that
every "rebel" should perish rather than that the Union should be
broken, it appears to be sullenly admitted that the mode in which a
compromise could be brought about was really the subject for the
consideration of sensible citizens. The President was asked to
proclaim emancipation everywhere, and amiable philanthropists were
complacently viewing the possibility of adding the horrors
of servile war to those of a fratricidal contest ; but we are not
informed that the President or Mr. Seward was lending a favourable
ear to the project, whatever admiration it might excite among the
Abolitionists. Assuredly, should the course in question be adopted,
its results might precipitate an interference, in the interests of
humanity, by all rulers whose subjects are sojourners in a country
which it is proposed to give up to new horrors. In presence of a
negro rising, who, for instance, could blame the Emperor of the
French for taking measures for the protection of the thousands of
Frenchmen and Frenchwomen in the South? The President was still
trying to negotiate with the Border States ; but it may be that they
not only know their value, but the singular difficulty of their
position, and have no desire to be</p>
<p><q rend="center">Feathered 'twixt castle wall</q></p>
<p><q rend="center">And heavy brunt of cannon ball.</q></p>

<p>We are informed that the losses of the Federals during the week of
slaughter near Richmond are estimated at 16,000. The ecstatic
admiration of the Southern organs for their generals is tremendous ;
and Austerlitz, with its trio of Emperors on the field and its
awful carnage, is considered a small matter compared to the recent
engagements. The latest mail tells us to expect early news of new
battles of the utmost importance.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1158.003" n="Imperial Parliament" type="article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1158</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.158</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-09">August 9, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF LORDS.--MONDAY.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcap">The Confederate States.</hi></p>

<p>An important discussion in reference to the recognition of the
Southern States was raised by a motion of Lord Stratheden for the
correspondence which had passed between Mr. Mason, the Confederate
commissioner, and the Foreign Office. The noble Lord urged strongly
that the time had come for intervention.</p>

<p>Earl <hi rend="smallcap">Russell</hi> declined to give the papers
asked for. No representative of the Southern States had been received
officially, and therefore all the correspondence which had taken place
was of an unofficial character. There was, however, a despatch which
had passed between the Government and its representative in America
which might he published hereafter. It contained a statement of the
views of the Government on the American question, and nothing had
occurred to alter their intentions since it was written. If in the
course of the recess the Government thought it desirable to take any
step, be should communicate with the great maritime Powers of Europe
before doing so. He had had no communication from any foreign Power
stating a wish for recognition of the Southern States.</p>

<p>The Earl of <hi rend="smallcap">Malmesbury</hi>, while believing
that the question of our interference was only one of time, to be
decided by the Government, hoped that when the step was taken this
country would be backed by France, Russia, and the other great
Powers. He also expressed a hope that Lord Lyons would speedily
return to Washington.</p>

<p>Earl <hi rend="smallcap">Russell</hi> said there was the most
perfect understanding with France, and he had no doubt that in any
step which might be taken Russia and the other Powers would
agree.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1159.001" n="Imperial Parliament" type="article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1158</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.158</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-09">August 9, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF COMMONS.--<hi rend="smallcap">Thursday.</hi></p>

<p><hi rend="smallcap">England and America</hi>.--Some questions on
important matters having been put and answered, Mr. <hi
rend="smallcap">Seymour</hi> called attention to the conduct of the
United States in the immediate neighbourhood of Nassau, and hoped the
Government would direct vigorous remonstrances to the United States on
that subject. He also called attention to the the bonds required by
the United States from British merchants that they would not send
their goods to the Confederate States.--Lord <hi
rend="smallcap">Palmerston</hi> said that, with regard to then first
question, the House must be aware that there was no country more
interested than Great Britain in the maintenance of belligerent rights
at sea. It was the undoubted right of belligerants to search nerchant
vessels at sea if they had reasonable ground to suppose that they were
carrying contraband of war to an enemy. It was for the owner of the
ship taken, when brought for adjudication, to urge in defence
circumstances to show that the capture was illegal. Heer Majesty's
Government were, of course, not disposed to interfere with the proper
exercise of belligerent rights by the United States; but if there
should be any abuse of those rights, that being properly shown, her
Majesty's Government would take proper steps. With regard to the
second question, it was true that bonds had been demanded from British
merchants not to send their goods to the Confederate States. Her
Majesty's Government, believing such bonds to be illegal, had made
representations on the subject.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1159.001" n="Foreign Intelligence: America" type="article">
<head>FOREIGN INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1159</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.174</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-16">August 16, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>

<p>By the arrival of the City of Washington, from New York, and the
North American, from Quebec, we have received telegrams vi Cape Race
to the 5th inst.</p>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcap">WAR NEWS.</hi></p>

<p>The situation in General M'Clellan's camp remains the same. His
army is suffering from scurvy and receives few reinforcements. The
movements of the enemy are kept secret from the Federals, except when
they reveal themselves on the south bank of the James River by opening
fire on the Federal shipping.</p>

<p>Seven vessels of Porter's mortar-fleet had arrived at Hampton
Roads, and five more were expected. It is supposed they will be
employed to reduce Fort Darling.</p>

<p>A new Merrimac and another ram, built at Richmond, had appeared in
the James River as far down as Turkey Bend. The Federal gunboats took
upan position in line of battle, but no engagement ensued.</p>

<p>General Pope, who is said to have 60,000 men under his command, has
been more active. He had crossed the Rapidan and captured Orange
Court-house, driving out two regiments of Confederate cavalry. His
troops continue to forage upon the farms in the Shenandoah Valley,
where the people refuse to take the oath of allegiance.</p>

<p>Guerrilla bands are active in several of the Border States. A
masked battery, planted by one of these bands on the banks of the
Mississippi 150 miles above Vicksburg, had destroyed a Federal
despatch-boat and killed several hands on another Federal river
steamer.</p>

<p>In Southern Tennessee the Federals had evacuated Grand Junction,
which had been occupied by the Confederates together with the larger
portion of the Memphis and Charleston Railroad between Memphis and
Corinth.</p>

<p>Much Sickness prevailed on board the Federal fleet before
Vicksburg. More than half the crews were unfit for duty. An
unsucessful attempt had been made to capture the Confederate gun-boat
Arkansas, in which the Federal gun-boats Queen and Essex were
damaged. The Confederates have several rams and steamers up the Yazoo
River, near the mouth of which Vicksburg is situated.</p>

<p>Volunteers not having presented themselves in sufficient numbers,
notwithstanding the tempting pecuniary inducements held out by the
Federal State and City governments, and by private subscriptions, the
President has found it necessary to announce that if the 300,000
volunteers were not ready by the 15th of August immediate resort would
be had to draughting from the militia. The term of service is fixed at
nine months. The President declines to accept the negro regiments as
soldiers, but will avail himself of them as labourers.</p>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcap">MISCELLANEOUS.</hi></p>
<p>The Governor of Kentucky, hitherto a staunch Union man, had
convened the Legislature to consider the late action of Congress
touching slavery, and to provide for the safety of the domestic
institution ice Kentucky. This proclamation is considered treasonable
irs the North. It receives additional importance from the fact that
the Governor has lately made a speech denouncing the confiscation and
emancipation policy, and declaring that to save the Union it was
necessary to throw over the Abolitionists.</p>

<p>Congress in the Session just closed appropriated the enormous sum
of 913,000,000 dols., which, with the sum appropriated at the summer 
Session last ycar--265,000,000 dols.--amounts to 1,178,000,000 dols.
since the commencement of the war.</p>

<p>Several persons had been arrested in the streets of New York for
speaking unfavourably of the war and declaring that they could not
suffer draughting.</p>

<p>The loyal Irish Americans of St. Louis had met and drawn up
resolutions denouncing the conduct of those of their countrymen who
had appealed to British protection against the threatened
conscription.</p>

<p>Isabella Susini (ne Hinckley), the American prima donna, had died
after her accouchement.</p>

<p>The premium on gold had fallen to 14 1/2 per cent. The exports of
grain to Europe were very heavy, and the cereal crops of the present
year were superabundant.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln41.1159.001" n="Despatches which had passed" type="article">
<head>[DESPATCHES WHICH HAD PASSED]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.41</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1159</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p.174</biblScope>
<date value="1862-08-16">August 16, 1862</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>Despatches which had passed between the Government of this country
and that of the United States have just been published. In a despatch
to Mr. Adams, dated May 28, Mr. Seward urges the reasons why this
counry should not interfere in the war in the States, and sketches
tersely and vigorously the position of affairs. This despatch was
answered, after a considerable lapse of time, by Earl Russell, who
announced that England would still preserve an impartial neutrality,
while heartily wishing for a speedy conclusion to the "unnecessary and injurious civil war."</p></div2>

Aepr- 7"
TEE ILLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS. LOS'S 07: ,envany, AUGUST 10, 1862.

Loon PALMDIOTFOIe 110(1 scarcely ahaken hands with the Speaker, in congratulation upon the end of a dolt Session, when the Premier was hurrying Yorkehicewarcis to shako hands with Sheffield. An enthusiastic assemblage gathered to banquet in the Patter's Hall there, and to welcome tl1s veteran champion of English independence. The guests were the notables of the district, but the waroa feeling in favour of Lord Palmcratcn was shined by all classes, and stalwart workmen pressed round him to greet him with a hearty "God bless thee, led I" The members for Sheffield were present, and Mr. P,oabork availed himself of the opportunity of making 'a sensation speech," in which he vehemently adjured Lard ralmerston to recognise the Southern Confederacy, and said that the severance of the Union world be far the benefit of England. "No doubt of it," said no leas a personage then the Mayor of Manchester, amid loud plaudit. Sheffield moot prepare itself to receive a broadside of the hea%iort abuse which the Federal prints and orators can pour in; hot it will possibly be as harmless an the united fire from fifteen ships and seven rains that was poured upon the Arkansas when she made her destroying way through the Northern first at Viokaberg. The point will be that such a speech was made, unchallenged, in the presence of the Premier

of England, and that it was approved by the representative

of the great beast of Liberalism. In the absence of other

American noses of interest, we hors amid fl-1, ,.-. -

eating intrrlereoce, and that the Earl cmsntismnly woitad, not seeing any oseeconity for prompt roply, and, when hr did answer, simply pointed omit that svomtto were indecisive-that, despite all the provmmnatinmsn given by the North, we had remnaiisrd tmnpartial, and that we intended to remain so. The Hurts despatch in cairo and terse, but it eoudcmssro the situation with too much felicity to nsakn it eaaetly plcosart rea'1in in the

North. The Binbop of Oxford's reromnmnemrdotian that con-gregations should engage iii "shunt prayer" for the rostoratiun of peace in America ltns oerasimctod some remark; but a clergy. moon named Jordan, who cnntencl.m that the clergy ought to be allowed to oiler op what public prayers they please, door not materially support his own cage by intimating that he should pray for the suppression of the "rebellion "-a enorsa which, in this present divided state of feeling in this country, might induce a moiety of his dock to discontinue attendance on his ministry. -
AIIFSICA.

By the arrival of the Etna from New York we have telegraene from Cape Race to the evening of the 12th inst.

will NEWS.

A reconnaissance in force was made from General b['(Jinflan'S army to Malvern Rill and Newmarket, within ten miles of Richmond At the former place two Confederate regiments and a battery were. encountered, but they tied after a alight engagement leaving 100 erieeners. At Newmarket the Federals retired before two Gonfederate trigadea. ThO next day the Confederates moved down in force upon l,felvern Hill, end the Federal. retired on their old positions. Fifteen hundred Federals have been thrown across the James River, preparatory, it is conjectured, to an attack upon Fart Darling.

General Burnside'e whole command has been transferred from

Fortress Monroe to the Potomac, where it landed at Acqu.ia Creek,. and had advanced, by last accounts, to Frederiolcabung.

Severe fighting had taken place in the Virginia Valley-. General

Jackson, having crossed the .linpidon, was met by General Povo. & conflict ensued about a nails and a half from Cedar Mountain, It lasted from three o'clock till dark, with what result is not clear from. the telegrams, which give two opposite versions of it. Both accounts. agree that the Federale loot one gun, and thatboth parties fell back from the battle-field, General Jackson having recroased the Bapadan under cover of, the night,

General Pope's troops were committing great havoc in the Virginia Volley. President Dims had issued a proclamation, thasgi9 hen with changing war "into indiscriminate robbery and murder.' He therefore orders, that if Pope or any commissioned officer of his command be captured, they shall not be treated as prisoners of war, but be held in close confinement. In the event of the mu.rd.er iii an unarmed citizen of the Confederate States reprisals will be taken on a commissioned emcee of Pope's command. The above rogulatione are epplieablo only to the commissioned officers of Pope, e oons-tnend.

 From the West there is a tedious recital of guerrilla attacks and movements of small bodies of regulars. The guerilla heave made. their appearance so for north as Missouri. The Federal General MeCook had been shot by guerrillas in Alabama while tra'jofling in an

ambulance. The Federals devastated the neighbourhood and hanged

several of the inhabitants in retaliation for the murder of their General.

The Confederate ram Arkansas has been blown up on the .wtissieeeppl,. bet whether by her owners, by accident, or byher asasilants is as Yet uncertain.

Pestilence was reported as raging in Richmond, where hundreds. were dying daily. Yellow favor was active among the Federals at. Key West, in Florida, A vessel had arrived at lics:oa with thirlr

patisuteenboard. A new outrage on the British .fiag had been committed by an officer of the Federal Navy. The British steamer Herald issued from the hcrbeur of Charleston with a cargo of cotton. She was chased by the Federal steamer Aduundac to within two miles of the harbour of, Nassau, New Providence, shot and shell being thrown at her all the. way. The Herald entered Nassau in safety. The captain of tho. Bcitieh steamer Greyhound had an interview with the Federal captain, end protested against the act. The matter is referred to the Govemsuents on either side.

The conscription causes much excitement. In Indiana. a secret. society, numbering several thousands of adherents, has been discovered. It aims at pceuynting enlistments and resisting taxation. The consulates in the lstge cities are crowded with applicants for exemption-papers. The rash of Irishmen at the British consulate m New York was so great that the police had to dear the office. The Secretary of War had issued an order that no citizen liable to be draughted into the militia shell be allowed to go to a foreign, country. The Federal officials at the ports, seaboard and frontiers, will arrest. such persons, who will be talcente the nearest militarypoet and placed on military duty for the termof drau'tt, The wnt of habeas corpus is suspended as to all such. On the etL many passengers were arrested by the police on beard of the European steamers. Some were disguised as sailors and stoutly resisted. The Government telegraphed. that these who had purchased tickets previous to the issue of the order might proceed on their voyage. The same system of police visits has been pm sued on beard the Californian steamers. Persons liable to militia duty can only emigrate to California by giving bonds for 1009 dollars to pro-vide a substitute, if draughted.

 iexscanraisnous.

A large war meeting had been held at Washington, at winch the. President made a speech. He denial that there was any wxarrsl between General M'CleGan and Secretary Stantan. He indorsdd the character of Mr. Stanten for bravery and ability, and he came forward to take upon himself the odium of, the charges made against. him. At this meeting ax-Governor Bontwell, of Massachusetts, made

an abolition speech.

The anniversary of the emancipation of the nsgree in the Beitiela West Indies was celebrated by the coloured people throughout the Northern States with the usual festivities. The Irish in the large cities have of late conducted themselves riotously towards the free negreee. They have resisted their employment as stevedores. and ice factories. A very aggravated outrage occurred in Brooklyn, where a tobacco factory, filled with coloured women and children chiefly,. was

attacked and set on fire. But for the exertions of the police in extin-guishing the flames, made while the mob were pelting them with

missiles, all the factory hands would have perished.

The Ma York limes, apropos of Lord Palmereten'e speech on Mr.

Lmdeay'e motion, is candid enough to tell its readers that "the. British Government deserves the praise of having held to the obligations of neutrality under conditions such as never before urged a people to their violation."

The steamer Golden Gate, which left San Franciaco m the 2Iet salt.

for Panama, was burnt to the water's edge on the 27th nit., o

Mecsaanilla, When the fire was discovered she was only three anal and a half from the shore. The steamer struck the beach soon af(Lec the upper deck fell, and the passengers and crew jumped overboar

to swim aahore. Out of 310 persons about 100 were saved. The specie

lest in her amounted to over 1,000,000 dote.
THE ILLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS.

-  LONDON: SATURDAY, Lire 052' 23, 1902.

RECENT movements of the American armies do not appear to have been of an important clonraoter, but the movements of American citizens and others, in ordor to escape being sent to the Federal armies, have been very prompt and decided. The conscription has fairly terrified the population of the North, and if. Mr. Lincoln makes up anything like the force which he demands it will be by recourse to measures which the most despotic soldier of the Old World has never employed, except in the ektremest used. When France was struggling against the combined exertions of indignant Europe she raised soldiers by the means which the Federal Government uses against a revolt at borne, a revolt which was to have been put down in a given number. of days. Americans, Irish, and Germane were hnrrying to the British frontier or getting on board English ships in the hope of avoiding- the "prose-gang.' Government, on the other band, was establishing a real blockade to keep its subjects at home, and the sternest edicts were isaaod for preventing this unpatriotic exodus. Such an illustration of the popularity of the war furnishes its own comment. In Missouri the citizens and the troops have come into actual echelon on the enrolment question, and lives have been lost on both aides ; and in Indiana a .secret confederation has been discovered-if anything oan be called secret in which 15,000 men joinfor preventing enlistment and taxation, and for enpporting the South. Persons are arrested on board the steamers for California, and permitted to depart only on giving a thousand-dollar security, in order to provide enbatitutea ; and in New York a provost-marshal and a military guard are doing the work of recruiting. There has been fighting in iheVirghoiaYalley, andthe Federals have been beaten, with mach slaughter, and bave lost guns. The Confederate President has met General Pope's marauding proclamation by an intimation that be should net treat Pope's officers as prisoners of war, end that, if unarmed Confederates are murdered, he will make immediate reprisals. Pestilence is said to be ravagiag Richmond; but there is no authentic information as to the movements of the defending army. M'Cleilau is reported as ,iss state quo. Taken as a whole, the latest budget of American newsiadnguiarly nufavourable to the North
THE SITUATION IN AMERICA.

Tus time seems to have come at last when the Federal Government, slow to believe and slow to act, is prepared to recognise the stupendous nature of the work it has commenced in combating by force of arms the determination of the Southern States to maintain their independence. The Northern people, impelled by passion and not by reason-for reason would have allowed the South to go in peace as soon as it became evident that their Southern fellow-citizens were earnest and unanimous in their desire to secede-have hitherto been unable to see what Englishmen, Frenchmen, Canadians, and indecd the whole world except themselves, have perceived from the beginning-that they must either overrun the South by fire

and sword, massacre or banish the white population and give up the plantations to the negroes and the Northern soldiers, or consent to the separation. Mr. Lincoln, his Cabinet, the press, ths New England population, and all the large class of contractors, antlers, and others, who are making rapid and scandalous fortunes out of the war, have decided within the last few weeks that the fight has not hitherto been fought as if the whole heart and purpose of the people and the Government were in it, and that it is necessary to carry on hostilities against their countrymen in as vigorous and unmerciful a spirit as if they were foreign foes leagued for the invasion of their soil and the destruction of their liberties. And clearly, if there is to be a war at all, this

is the only spirit by which to invoke and command But is it in the power of the Federal Goverumeat partisans in the press and in the pulpit, in the army a counting-house, to arouse such a feeling in the mm Northern people? We doubt it. The voluntary en] entreated by the President, and sought to be by bribes of bounty-money from the Federal so from the State Governments, from the municipalities cities, and from the liberality of contractors growing plunder of the army, have lamentably failed. The: asked for three hundred thousand men, and in five v than thirty thousand offered themselves, This fact mid in Washington that the war could not be carried on
firmly-united and desperate People oy the more especially as the mercenaries only provided one m51 where ton were demanded. Consequently, the President, whose original idea was that seventy-five thousand men would be ant

cient to conquer the South and to gather up and cement the broken fragments of the Union, awoke to the conviction that six hundred thousand men, in addition to the armies in the eld, would be no more than adequate to the mighty work which it is his ill-fortune to conduct. If such vast forces can be collected by the conscription which he has ordereda new thing among a free people, end never befote resorted to in any self-governed nation except to repel the invasion of a forcimi foe-the aggregate armies of the North levied since the assault upon Fort Snmter until the present day will roach the frightful number of one in ill hoe three hundred thousand men. Of the first lovias, composed wholly of volunteers, at least four hundred thousand have either perished on the battle-field or in the pestilential swamps of the South and South-West, been disabled by wounds and disease, or have ingloriously deserted and slunk sway, no more to be heard of. And it is net too much to say, if the conduct of the war for the future be neither more vigorous nor mere successful than it has been in the past, that a similar doom will await the stow levy of six hundred thousand men.

But will the six hundred thousand be raised 1 That is the vital question of the day in America, as well as in Europe, which looks on wondering at the suicidal conflict. It is 'is yet impossible to answer the question. The response lies in a dim but not reunite future, of which no one can lift the veil. Yet one corner of it can be partially drawn aside, and through that corner all who choose may see one thing very distinctly which is. that the new army, if raised at all, will be tempered mainly of Americans. and that the Irish anti Germans who, up to the recent battles on the fltickabominy and the Panumbey, formed so large a portion of the Federal strength, have lost their relish for. and their hope in, the struggle, and will persistently refuse to shed their blood in its support. Nothing else is clear in the haze of American politics but that one peat fact and it is ,me winch can afford no cucouragomeet to the Northern leaders, whether they be civil or military.

 Perhaps, however, there is another fact ahnost enally ominous of the li,sal issue of the strife-a fact which the Americas;.,: refuse to admit. hat which is noise the less palpable on that account. In fact, much as the North hates disunion, it hales negro esncncipallon cliii more. New England lucy Cell laetily for the abolition of negro slavery and the elevation of the negro race to the political status of white 115011 ; but the Northern, the Middle, and the great Western States repudiate the political pnrtnership, would fight to the death against the social equality, and would rather expel the negroes from American soil than consent to amannnmission of slaves which would bring black Ini osirers from the Southern rice and cotton fields to the fanas and cities of the celder North, to reduce the wages of white lai.onr. Between the white population and the negroes there is an amount of repulsion and antipathy which noise hot those who have lived in or studied America can understand; so that the more loudly the bitter philanthropists of New England insist upon converting the war into one of abolition, the inure inclined are the messes of the North who live by their labour to look upon the war as a lamentable mistake.

At this point at the present moment things appear to stand. The South gets heated as the North grows cool. Jefferson Davis takes bean as Abraham Linoola loses it, The North hears the President's call for six hundred thousand inen, and obeys unwillingly, While public opinionwhen bold enough to express itself-declares that one million will not suffice for the I conquest, much less the retention, of the Sooth. We in England, looking upon the matter dispassionately, bystanders that survey the game from a vantage-ground denied to either of the players, see that one section of the late ill-assorted Uision is still united as one man in favour of independence wider a separate form of goveromeat; while the other section, the only one as yet acknowledged as a de forts Government by the European Powers, is divided into a dozen warring carts and factions, and redividee and subdivides itself as the war proceeds. In tlse South the North has no friends. In the North the South has many warm adherents. Democrats and Republicans, professing both of them to love the Union above all things, hate each other with an amosmt of animosity unknown to the political struggles of the Old World, and only equalled by the antipathies of the Gironda and the Mountain in the amity days of the French Revolution.

How long this useless war will continue to devastate the fairest portions of the North American continent it is impossible to forecast; hot it is easy enough to sac, from the

'desperation of the South, and the mingled pride anti hesitation of the North, that the issues are not in American but in El

are

penn hands. As one of the asoat influential and rcvpectabte of the a Northern journals, the Ma' Tacit Pleats, declares, with a strong hiss against the South, "the age of long wars has passed. The industry, the commerce, the eiviieatioo of the world cannot

,tnntt till fnvrn-,,,5,mu, o-, 1 --------------- C
she was attacked by a fleet of Federal gnn4oate from below: Aftera stern resistance she was abandoned apd blown up, The ofiloers and crew reached the shore in safety.

The accounts from Tennessee and ;Xantuoky report a continuation

of operadic guerrilla warfare. A Confederate General Casweli by name, has been assassinated at his residence near Knoxville, by a Union Tenneesreon. Three tundred houses in Memphis have been seized by the Federals under the O'onileoation Act. The Confederate General Morgan, who claim to have taken 20 towns, 1200 prisoners, and destroyed 2,000,000 dollars' worth of property, spealcs in high teems of the -velour of Colonel George St. Lager Gronf oil, late of the British, now of the Confederate, Army.

The Federal General Phelps had resigned his position at New

Crlcaee, because General Butler refused to supply arms for equipping his negro regiments. General Butler orders them to be employed in throwing up entrepohments, and refuses to acceptGeneral Phelps's resignation.

General Butler has ordered a forced contribution of 330,000 dole. from the basics, cotton brokers, and merchants of Now Orleans for the support of the poor. The assessments are made in proportion to the sum subscribed by the merchants for the defence of New Orleans against the Federal Government. The forced contributions from each firm varies from 86,000 dole, to 6 dole. Nearly two hundred firms are rssoseed.

In scene of the Northern States volunteering is progressing favourably, Maine and Michigan have already contributed bionic quota, end there will be no need to resort to droughtinginthooc States. The large States of New York and Ohio ask for more time, which has been granted by the War Deportment. The process of conscription has therofots been postponed until September 1, in order to give the Northern States an opportunity of filling up their quotas by voluntary enlistments. Foreigner's who have declared their intention to become citizens are net allowed to leave the country. Numerous emigrants enlist on lending. The Governor of Massachusetts has ordered the onrolmeut of coloured citizens among those subject to the draught.

 A collision has occurred on the Potomac between two transports. Eighty sick soldiers were drowned.

o,necur,nAinooisa.

The Governor of Kontuok-y, in hie message to the Legislature,

recommends the adoption of the Crittondsn resolution as a standing proposition for peace and the settlement of the war.

Mr. Cassius M. Clay, late United States' Minister to Russia, has

made a speech at Washington devoted to abuse of the Iiinglieh Par-liament, press, and people, and laudatory of Francs and Russia. the municipality MEW York has appropriated 1,000,000 dole, for the defence of the harbour by gun-boats and rams.

A. letter from Richmond, dated the 3rd inst., says :--g There is a great deal of suffering hers. Coffee sails at Idols, per. lb. ; tea, Idols.; brown sugar, 75c. per lb.; eggs, per dozen; 1 dol. ; moth, 1 dol. per gallon calico, 750; per yard; linen, 2 dole. per yard; hate, 14 dole.; toots, 25 dole, to 40 dole. per pair; shoes, 16 fda. ; salt, tOe. psr lb.; flour, 13 dols. per lb.; butter, 1 dol. per lb.; writing-paper, 30 fda. per ream; potatoes, 6 dole, per bushel; any kind of ,coal, ,50 dole. to 75 dole.; pants, 25 dole." This seals of prices indicates not only a great scarcity, but a great deprsoiation in the paper money

of the Confederate States.

In the North the crops of grain are heavier than in any preteens year. In wheat alone the State of Ohio has an estimated. surplus for export of 17,000,000 bushels.

The heat was so intense in New York and Brooklyn on the 9th and 10th inst. that upwards of fifty deaths were reported in the journals of the two following days resulting from crap do soloil and cholera morhue, induced by exposure to the sun.

CANADA.

The Canadian Parliament has been unexpectedly sanrqoened to

meet on the 28th of this month.

It was expected that the war in the neighbouring roptabho would have largely increased the numbers of Europeans emigrating to Canada, This expectation has not been realised, the increase hemg this year only about six per cent compared with the season of 1861. The emigrants arriving at Quebec up to the 15th ult. ware 14,434 against 13,587 up to the same date in 1861. The immigration at the port of New York has fallen off in about the same proportion.

The immigration into Canada from the United States has, on the ether hand) exceeded anticipations. The Montreal .e.filocrt lacy says

"Canada is at present invaded by the Yankees; they are -aging the frontier in crowds-filling the railway oars, thronging the steamboats. A single train brought yesterday sixty young men from New York State. During the next ten days Canada well renews an addition of some thousands to her population. Many of the imincgrants are mechanics and workmen, and the majority are young men bat's'ren eighteen and thirty, and therefore liable to the first draught.

AMERICA,

By the snivel of the steamer Bohemian we have telegrams from Now York to the evening of the 16th inst.

WAR mows.

Details of the sanguinary battle at Cedar Mountain have bose poblishod. It scorns to have base one of the beet fought and at the simi time most fruitless engagements to which this war has given rise. The looses were heavy on both sides.

General Pope's official report of the battle atCadar Mountain states,

that the 10tH of the Poderals woe 1530 killed, wounded, and missing, 300 ci whom were taken prisoners. Federal General Prinec was

- _A 'itcam-iloat explosion has ocourrcd at Shanghot 'i'hc vessel which sustained the disaster is the Union Star, which had just arrived from Celifosnia, and was on a trial trip when the aaoidant happaasd. Upwards of a dozen lives were lost, one half of whom were Americans; in addition to which there were several persons injured.

A Now York paper states that a Brooklyn lady purchased as

snide in Polton-strcoo the other day, when she rocoivod thu following aS

ehoego for a one-dollar bill -Peory tickets, shinplaster, coouterf nit penny, o.u

ticket, milk ticket, butcher's JO U, grocer's 1 0 U, broad ticket, three ee's\

i)et-esgo-stamp, One cent psetego-otemp, and ioc-oresen ticket.
AMERICA.

By the arrival of the Jura end City of Baltimore we have journals of the 23rd and telegreaois of the 26th ult.

WAB NEWS.

The evacuation of Harrison's Landing by the army of General M'C:eilan was effected 'without bee or interruption. The bulk of his army has since been removed from the peninsula of Yorktown to Acqi. is. Creek on the Potomac, whence it effected a junction with the army cinder the command of General Pore.

The Confederates, on receiving information of M'Clellan'e movements, immediately marched out in full force from Richmond in order to fall upon general Pope before reinforcements could reach him. The latter forthwith retreated across the Rappahannook, the Confederates following close on his rear, Repeated skirmishing and artillery

engagements took place. At Cnttls'e Station the Confederates cap-tured a staff officer and General Pope's personal luggage, maps, official despatches, end valuable papers relating to the campaign. The Federals occupied Wsrrenton after a slight engegement. By last accounts the Oonfedatee held the south bank of Ioe Rappahaonoclc with a line of batteries extending fifteen miles. They had attacked the Federals and endeavoured to cross the river several times, but had been repulsed by General Pope.

General Halisok had issued orders that officers and men will be held accountable for all property taken from the enemy. Officers and ansn taking private property without authority would be shot.

The Confederates had retreated from Lexington, Missouri, had been defeated in Arkansas, and repulsed in an attack on Edgelield, Ten. nsesee; bnt had captured Clarkevalle, in the, same State, and wore advancing on Fort Dennelson. They had also invaded Kentucky and captured several towns.

 The Negro Brigade formed by General Hunter in South Carolina lead been disbanded, in tensequence of its being discountenanced by the Administration.

'iha Federal commissioner sent to New Orleans to examine into same of General Butler's proceedings there has reported, and recommends the return to the Dutch said French Consuls of the specie seized by that General, and also that a large amount of sugar and ether merchandise should be relinquished to British, Greek, and other foreign msrcban in New Orleans,

Mrsortn.tosaous.

Mr. Seward has officially announced that persons who have msrcly declared their intention to become citizens, without taking the subaequeot steps necessary to-complete the presess of naturalisation, are not liable to be th'aughted. He had also issued orders to grant passports to persons liable to be draughtcd who desire to go abroad, on their executing a bond to the United Statoa conditional to porform military duty or furnish a substitute,

President Lincoln had addressed a deputation of coloured men verging them to ce-opcrato with ham in colonising their race in Central America, inasmuch as there was no chance of their attaining to a position of civil end social equality with white men owing to the antipathy of the latter to people of their race and complexion.

An enthusiastic reception had been accorded to the released General (late Colonel) Corcoran, of the 69th (Irish) Regiment, captured at the battle of Bull Run, in Baltimore, Philadelphia, and New York. He everywhere stimulated his countrymen to enlist, holding out to them the inducement that the cause of Irish independence would- be benefited by the military training they would receive under the American flag.

General Meagher and Archbishop Hughes having spoken in the same sense, enlistments have been more numerous of late, both among the Irish end native elements of the population.

The new smell-nets and postogo-atamp Federal currency was issued on the 21st nit. Gold was at lO premium.

The Indians in the north-west part of Minnesota, exasperated at the non-payment of the money due to them from the Federal Government, attacked the whites, and murdered men, women, and children, burning all the dwelling-houses they could find. Several hundreds are said to have been lulled. A body of forty-five volunteers was cat to pieces. The Governor of the State has ordered out the militia with Iscrrss to the scene of action.

PRESIDENT n&vas's acssssos.

The Confederate Congress assembled at Richmond on the 18th nit. The message of lafr. Davis admits "the suffering endured by some portions of the people." The prowess of the army is spoken of as assuring the triumph of "constitutional liberty" in the pending struggle logainet "despotic usurpation." He charges the Peolerals with disregarding the laws of civilised warfare :

Stem ccocniplery punishment mont lc mated o,st to the ,n,cnlarers au,l felons 'who, flrgr,'clcg the prcfraiso of anal,, eerie to ,cake public war the occa-sion for the cocs,ci'elen of the enact ,necc'trmci, crimes. Do ply as we regret the rOse-crier of the cceltect into which we are about to be forced, we coast accept it as eli olter,,cclve wl,irlc recent manifestations glee sic little hop3 call he avoided. The exeeperaciecs of failure has sareccscd the worst passions of our cosmic,. A large portion of their people, even at their clergymen, now engage in urging an excited populace to the extreme of ferocity.

He recommends the extension of the conscription law so as to include all citizens between thirtyfive and forty-five years of age. Bills embodying his suggestions had already been introduced into Congress-in particular, one providing that a Federal army, composed incongruously of whites and blacks, shall not be entitled to the privileges of war. All Degrees belonging to such an army who may be captured will be sold end theft commanders hang or shot.

ti A ti A fl a
NEW ORLEANS S HUNDRED YEARS Am.-The River

Mtooisoippi (says the Pool Boy of June 4, 1761) is now near 1503 cellos navigable, and has several rivers canoeing into it both from the east and west, some of winch are one, two, and some above three, hundred mi1ei navigable. The land is so rich end the soil so deep, especially he the south parts of it, that in mercy places one may run a soldier's pike op to the hoed without meeting with a rock or stone. Its south ports are so warm, and the land so rich, that the French who live steer the city of New Orleans, which is lIt miles op from the month of that liver, have planted and merle good anger these live years last past. What act immense end extensive trade will that city have which is tIes seaport (as New Orleans now is) to all this extensive country, which is capable of producing everything-sugar, esioto, &c.-if civiltsed, coltivated, and peopled, on it way probably be in a few centuries. The Clown of England has a right by eliseevery and taking possession of oil this country ; and ICing Charles IL granted it to the ancestors of the late Dr. (lox, but they serglerted en settle and people it; And Sir Francis Drake took possession on the scoot side f it, as far north as let. 41, and a great way south of that, far Queen Bhixaberle

but the English neglected to settle it. The Trends Caine and built the city of

New Orleans fifty leagues op the river, and a fort or two about sixty cities below the city. The city aced the forts might have been easily behest lbs last evinter-the beet time to take it in, it being so svorsn there. If we ha-1 sent 1000 or 3000 men down the River Ohio into the Mississippi, end thither, on large heats, os there is timber enough on its banks to build them with, the Eesghlsh might here been in posseooioo of all North America (except LiIsc Florida sod the north part of Mexico, which belong to Opals) ; and our King would then have been to possession of both the north end south passages to all that fine country and to Coestla also, and no way left DO the French to cease at either of them, The French there now ore, acid ever will be, enemiesto the English, end have lately stirred op the Cherokees and other Indian nations to

II espsn the evosrito weston parts of Virginia, tiorohisa, awl Georgia, and

ro it so molly barbarous murders on the English oanlrclo as they hare lately doze there.
THE ILLUSTRATED LONDON NEWS.

- .&OXl.JON, 'SAO'UIWAY, SEPTEMBER 5, 1550.

We have another State paper from America, in the form of a message from President Davis. It is a temperate document, designed to encourage the South, and to promote among strangers the belief that the Confederate interest is consolidating and that it Comprehends administrative duties. It wars not to be expected, however, that such an address shonl,l be entirely devoid of hard words; and the most is made of the conduct of Pope and Butler, and of the atrocities hoputod to the Fedemis. We also learn that the South will not tolerate the employment of negro areas in the quarrel, but intimates that all black prisoners will be sold for what they will bring and that all white prisoners who have commanded them shall he treated as felons, which, under the circumstances, may be held to mean that they are to be hanged. The enormous prices offcrsd!or recruits for the North, and the consideration that it is batter to be paid for soldiering than to be pressed and taken gratis, have had their effect upon the new levy.and the materials for a fresh army are coining in. Perhaps General MOldllan may be intrustcd with the work of manipnlathsg these materials-a duty for which the most malicious of his enemies, even Mr. Stasaton, cannot deny Millellan's fitness. The system of espionage and arrest continued in fell force, and a handsome batch of disaffected parsons were daily sent off to prison, though a nserc instalment of those who will be incarcerated, should it be true that Botlsr is to be placed as military Governor at New York. We have no valuable information as to any other military movement than the retreat of General M'ClslJan, who is credited with having taken a leaf from the hock of the Southern leaders, and having shown himself a master of escape. Rumours of battles are rife, and it is now clear that the last Confederate exploit was a real success, but we ore uninformed as to the fact of there having bson an important conflict. All the avenues of intelligence from the Federal camps are carefully closed, all reporters are soot an-ay, and the mnmnrfactore of guesswork- correspondence, though not suppressed, is conducted under rather disagroeable coaditiona Except that some of the Roman Catholics and some of the Irish ore very loud in their appeals to the North to go on vigorously with the war, that the leading Abolitionists arm talking unpunished treason while unijaflucntinl man are dragged off to gaol, and That the New York press is exhausting every form of bluster in regard to the grand preparations that are being made, and the necessity of nttsrlyassnihiloting the South, and rceolonising it, if necessary, we have no news of interest from the Wcsteris scene of war.
00 The (Jimnntln papers say that an extensive fair tratit will

centre tMe fall in Montreal in conseiluence of the troubles in the United States preventing traders from going to New York and Boston. The mason's supply of robes from the Hudson's Bay Company will, it is expected, be over 12,000.

--- ----------------

The Pea cc Society lips issued an address to the people of th'

United states. It rnye -"Is the time not come, we repeat, friends as fellew-Chrjstieflo. when an attempt should be made to arrest this destreccfr' cc elhct? We deprecate utterly all nomad intervention at all, bat such a a you yeseiselves would willingly s'lniit an the part of England or any aino peon rower, in your allaire, l3ut sorely the idea of a friendly medlatte s may l,e entertained without any derogation at your national dignity. Wa b-e.eh you to collect that, sooner or later, some method of peaceful adieisli' sit must be edepteel. There are only two alternative insues of eitw the utter oateiiuuiattoi'. of one party, or some form of accommodation and' 'omproinlie between the contending sides. None 0f you can wish the former And is it 4'ot totter at once to have recourse to the latter before further) i is shed end the feelings an both sides shall become hopelessly inflnuvsl with animosity and vengeance?"
