<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI.2//EN" "iln.dtd"
[<!ENTITY % iln-entities SYSTEM
"/Beck-files/ILN/ILNCVS/ilnxml/iln_entities">
 %iln-entities; ]>

<TEI.2>
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated London News
Perspective</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Compiled and edited by</resp>
               <name>Sandra Still</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent/>         
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Emory University</pubPlace>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine>
            </address>
            <availability>
               <p>2005 Emory University.
Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce,
distribute or display the contributions to the work claimed by Emory
University for non-profit educational purposes, provided this header
is included in its entirety.  For inquiries about commercial uses,
contact the Lewis H. Beck Center, Woodruff Library, Emory University,
Atlanta, Georgia 30322</p>
            </availability>
            <date>2005</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated
London News Perspective</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Illustrated London News</title>
               <biblScope type="volume">Volume 44</biblScope> 
               <date>Jan to June 1864</date>
</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p/>
         </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	<change><date>September 2005</date>
          <respStmt><name>Robin Conner, </name><resp>Beck Center Staff.</resp></respStmt>
          <item>Encoded text according to TEI guidelines.</item>
	</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div1 id="iln42.001" n="Illustrated London News: Volume 44" type="Volume"> 
            <head>Illustrated London News: Volume 44</head>
            <docDate>Jan to June 1864</docDate>

<div2 id="iln44.1238.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1238</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 3</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-02">January 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">War Intelligence.</hi></p>
<p>We have news from New York to the morning of the 19th ult. The
information respecting the war movements may be briefy summarised.</p>
<p>General Langstreet, who does not appear to have been retreating
with any hot haste from Knoxville, turned upon the pursuing Federals
on the 14th and drove them back some distance with considerable
loss. The latest accounts were to the effect that fighting was still
going on at a point described as Blair's crossroads.</p>
<p>The Federals are said to have abandoned Lookout Mountain
Missionary Ridge, and other points, from which General Grant recently
drove the Confederates.</p>
<p>Hardee's army is estimated at 35,000 strong, and is at Dalton, with
pickets extending to the tunnel. Wheeler is reorganising cavalry at
Dalton for an active winter campaign. Grant and Sherman have left
Chattanooga for Bridgenorth.</p>
<p>The famous Confederate guerilla leader, Morgan, who recently made
his escape from a Federal prison, had, it is said, succeeded in
getting across the Tennessee, but not, it would seem, without
considerable difficulty and risk, as it is affirmed that sixteen of
his escort were captured.</p>
<p>There is no news of importance from the army of the
Potomac. Mosby's and White's guerillas are very troublesome and
numerous, continually harassing the outposts. On the 13th 700 of them
made a dash at the bridge across Cedar Run, near Catlett's station,
but were driven back by the force guarding the bridge. The line of the
railroad from the front to Alexandria is hereafter to be well
protected by both cavalry and infantry. Short leaves of absence are
freely granted to officers and men. There is nothing further in relation to the removal of General Meade. It is reported that he has
demanded a court of inquiry into the conduct of the late campaign.</p>
<p>General Stuart, at the head of a force of Confederate cavalry, had
made a raid upon the Orange and Alexandria Railroad, near Fairfax,
and, besides capturing a number of prisoners, he destroyed about two
miles of the line of railway.</p>
<p>A despatch from General Butler at Fortress Monroe announces that a
portion of his force, under General Wistar, had succeeded in capturing
the Confederate garrison at Charles City crossroads on the James
River. Eight officers and over eighty Confederate soldiers were
taken. The Federal forces, to accomplish this, had marched seventy-two
miles in fifty-four hours, mostly in a severe storm.</p>
<p>A brigade of coloured troops under General Wild occupied Elizabeth
City, North Carolina, on the 10th of of December. The inhabitants were
entirely taken by surprise, and offered no resistance. Twenty
waggon-loads of contraband goods were sent back to Portsmouth by
General Wild. It is said that Elizabeth City is to be made the base
of important operations.</p>
<p>The Federals were throwing a large number of shells into
Charleston, replied to by the Confederate batteries. An accidental
fire had occured in Fort Sumter, killing ten and injuring thirty
men. a storm had so seriously injured the obstructions to the harbour
that it was thought the Federal fleet would be able to make its way
through them.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">the Ironclads.</hi></p>
<p>The official reports of the commanders of the monitors engaged in
Dupont's attack on Charleston express disappointment at their capacity
to overcome strong forts, and state that if the attack had been
prolonged the monitors would all have been disabled. One commander
says he was disappointed beyond measure at the experiment of monitors
overcoming strong forts, and considers it was a fair
trial.</p><p>Captain Drayton, of the Passive, says:--</p>
<q><p>I was struck in quick succession in the lower part of the
turret by two heavy shots, which bulged	in its plates and beams, and
forcing together the rails on which the carriage of the 11-inch gun
worked, rendered it wholly useless for the remainder of the action. A
little after a very heavy rifle-shot struck the upper edge of the
turret, broke all its eleven heavy plates, and then, glancing upwards,
struck the pilot-house with such force as to send it over, open the
plates, and squeeze out the top, exposing the inside of the
pilot-house, and rendering it extremely likely that the next shot
would take of the top entirely.</p></q>
<p>Captain Rodgers, of the Weehawken, reports:--</p>
<q><p>Two or three heavy shots struck the side armour near the same
place. They so broke the iron that it only remained in splintered
fragments, much of which could be picked of by hand, and the wood was
exposed. the deck was pierced so as to make a hole, through which
water ran into the vessel; thirty-six bolts were broken in the turret,
and a great many in the pilot-house. To the Patapsco, on damage was
done which disabled her, although injuries which she received, if
multiplied, would do so. Forty bolts in the funnel were broken. After
the third shot from the 15-inch gun of the Nantuck a port-stopper
became jammed, several shots striking very near the port and driving
in the plating. It was not used again. A number of these same plates
were started so much that another shot in their vicinity would have
knocked them off. The deck plates were cut in twelve places; one shot
cut through the iron and about two inches into the beam, starting the
plates, several bolts, and the planking, for some feet below. The
plates pm the side armour of the Nahant were badly broken in several
places, and one, where struck by two shots in close proximity, partly
stripped from the wood, and the wood backing broken in, with edging of
back plates started up and rolled back in places. The deck was struck
twice damagingly, one shot near the propeller-wheel quite shattering
and tearing the plate in its passage, and starting up twenty-five
bolts in the turret. There were marks of nine shots; fifty-six of the
bolts were broken perceptibly, the heads flying off inside the turret,
and the bolts starting almost their length outside, some of them
flying out completely, and being found at a considerable distance from
the turret, on the deck. One shot struck the upper part of the turret,
breaking through every plate. The pilot-house was much damaged and
wrecked, and four more such shots as it received would have demolished
it. One shot at the base broke every plate through, and evidently
nearly penetrated it.</p></q>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">Miscellaneous.</hi></p>
<p>The Federal House of Representatives has passed a resolution, by 93
to 64, that the war should be prosecuted so long as the rebels are
found in arms. A motion, submitted by the Hon. Fernando Wood,
requesting the President to appoint two commissioners to negotiate
with the authorities at Richmond with the view of terminating the war
and restoring the Union upon the terms of equity, fraternity, and
equality under the Constitution, was tabled--i.e., thrown aside--by a
vote of 98 against 59. All the Democratic members except five voted
for its adoption, and the large minority in its favour has created
some sensation.</p>
<p>Resolutions have been introduced for a new reciprocity treaty with
Canada; also to inquire into the expediency of putting coloured
soldiers on the same footing as white men as regards pay, and of
abolishing the 300 dols. draught commutation.</p>
<p>A bill has been introduced in the the Senate prohibiting the sale
of gold, silver, or exchange through brokers unless the whole of the
purchase-money be paid down, under the penalty of a heavy fine and
imprisonment.</p>
<p>A banquet to both Houeoe of Congress has been given on board the
Russian fleet at Washington. The Russian Minister and the Speaker of
the House of Representatives made speeches.</p>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">New York Herald</hi> has nominated General
Grant as candidate for the next presidency, and has put forward an
electioneering cry that he would demand from England an	indemnity for
the depredations of privateers, and would expel the French from
Mexico.</p>
<p>An "Evening Exchange" has been opened in the heart of the
handsomest quarter of New York, to which, after a hastily-snatched
dinner, crowds of brokers and speculators eagerly hurry, there to resume the transactions of the day and to anticipate those of the
morrow.</p>
<p>There have been several rumours of peace proposals coming from the
South lately, but nothing of the kind has appeared as yet.</p>
<p>The Confederate Senate has, in conformity with the recommendation
of President Davis, passed a bill prohibiting the employment of
substitutes in the Confederate army.</p>
<p>Mr. Foote, from Tennessee, of the Confederate House of Representatives, in a speech of the 11th ult., casts the whole blame of the
 fall of Vicksburg and the Confederate reverses in East Tennessee upon
President Davis for retaining Generals Pemberton and Bragg in
command.</p>
<p>The Richmond press denounces President Lincoln's amnesty
proclamation as an infamous document, which will but arouse the
Southern people to new zeal and new efforts.</p>
<p>The Federal steamer Ella Annie has recaptured the Chesapeake, with
three of her crew, in Sambro Harbour, Nova Scotia. The Chesapeake was
taken to Halifax for judicial decision. No resistance was offered by
the crew, all of whom, except three, escaped to the shore. The English
authorities in Nova Scotia had forbidden the furnishing of coals to
the Chesapeake by the people of that province; they had ordered her
detention wherever she appeared, and gave the information to the
Federals which led to her capture. It is also alleged that they have
ordered the arrest of the men who seized her while going in her as
passengers, holding them to have been guilty of piracy. Mr. Seward has
had a friendly interview with Lord Lyons on the subject.</p>
<p>The Federal brig Perry has been captured near Charleston. The
steamer Ceres was destroyed off Beaufort.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1238.002" n= "The Pampero." type="Article">
<head>THE PAMPERO.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1238</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 12</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-02">January 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE PAMPERO.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">This</hi> vessel, launched a short time ago
from the building-yard of Messrs. J. G. Thomson, Glasgow, has created
a good deal of interest, owing to a suspicion being pretty generally
entertained that it was intended to make her a consort to the Alabama,
Georgia, and Florida. Shortly after being launched, the Emancipation
Society at Glasgow addressed a memorial to Earl Russell, stating that
they had reasons for supposing her to be for that service, and praying
for an investigation into the matter. To this Earl Russell replied
that the attention of her Majesty's Government had already been
directed to this vessel. No interference with the vessel took place
beyond posting customs officers near her berth and moving from
Greenock the gun-boat Goldfinch, one of the tenders to her Majesty's
ship Hogue, stationed there, and placing her on the opposite side of
the harbour to the Pampero. Recently the Lord Advocate of Scotland
instructed the customs authorities to detain her, and she is now in
charge of a gang of bluejackets. The Pampero is a handsome steamer of
1000 tons, builder's measurement; length, 230 ft.; beam, 32 ft.;
depth, 20 ft.; with direct-acting engines of 200-horse power. She is
finely sparred, and her	main and foremasts, of iron, are capable of
spreading a large area of canvas. Her funnel is telescopic. She has
lifting screw, and patent reefing topsails. Our Engraving of the
Pampero is from a sketch by Mr. Hugh Aird, of Glasgow.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1238.003" n="The Suspected Confederate Cruiser Pampero
      Seized at Glasgow." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1238</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 12</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-02">January 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv44p12">
<head>THE SUSPECTED CONFEDERATE CRUISER PAMPERO
      SEIZED AT GLASGOW.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1238.004" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1238</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 18</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-02">January 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....Englishmen must be wicked in the American eye, and there can be
no peace for them or with them. Unhappily, the latest aggravation
given comes from our own Government. It is the case of the Victor,  an
Admiralty ship of six guns, which was sold to some private individual,
fitted out by Chatham Dockyard workmen, and finally got clear off, as
the Rappahannock, Confederate States' cruiser. Anything more unhappy,
more ludicrous, cannot be conceived. Of course, it was never intended,
but it looks very much as if our great men were so tired after the
labour of delaying the steam-rams in the Mersey that there was no more
energy amongst then to look after Victors and Rappahannocks. Within a
fortnight there will be another supply of the choicest Sewardian
scolding, and passionate threats from certain New York organs. And
then there will be Lord Russell's reply, and promises, already once
broken, never to do the like again. And all this in face of General
Grant's standing for the presidency, with a popular "platform," or
"ticket," of sworn warfare with England unless reparation be made for
fifty thousand incomprehensible things. The workmen, said to have been
officially employed,  are all to be dismissed, nominally for being
absent without leave: but, in reality, for having been as careless as
Government itself in breaking international laws.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1238.005" n= "Burning of the American River-Steamer
      Isaac Newton." type="Article">
<head>BURNING OF THE AMERICAN RIVER-STEAMER ISAAC NEWTON.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1238</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 20</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-02">January 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">BURNING OF THE AMERICAN RIVER-STEAMER</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">ISAAC NEWTON.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> Isaac Newton, one of the most elegant
of the many floating palaces on the Hudson River, while on her way
from New York to Albany, caught fire near Fort Washington, from the
bursting of one of her boilers, on Saturday, the 5th ult., and was
burnt to the water's edge. All attempts to extinguish the flames
proved unavailing. It was impossible, owing to the dense smoke and
steam on the lower deck, to get at the hose, and the heat drove the
engineer from his post. The Isaac Newton had on board, at the time of
the accident, about 130 passengers. A tug and a propeller hastened to
the relief of those on board, who were speedily removed from the
burning wreck. Fourteen persons were, however, badly scalded by the
steam, and of these six died. Our Engraving is from a sketch taken by
Mr. Edward L. Henry, of Tenth-street, New York.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1238.006" n="Burning of the American River-Steamer
      Isaac Newton on her Way from New York to Albany." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1238</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 20</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-02">January 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv44p20">
<head>BURNING OF THE AMERICAN RIVER-STEAMER
      ISAAC NEWTON ON HER WAY FROM NEW YORK TO ALBANY.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1239.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1239</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 26</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-09">January 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">War Intelligence.</hi></p>
<p>We have news from New York to December 26. Everything was quiet to
that date in the army of the Potomac. The troops were settling down
into comfortable winter quarters. Nothing of importance was known to
have occured recently in General Lee's army. A slight skirmish took
place on the 20th ult. between a small body of guerrillas and some of
Gregg's cavalry, near Morgansburg. The Confederates retreated after a
few shots were exchanged.</p>
<p>General Longstreet had inflicted a check on a body of Federals at
Bear Station, and was reported to be contemplating fresh operations;
but it was said that his railway communication with Richmond had been
more or less obstructed by a successful "raid" made on the Virginia
and Tennessee Railway by the Federal General Averill.</p>
<p>General Joe Johnston	was moving to reinforce Hardee, and was, it is
said, to take the command of the Southern army in Georgia.</p>
<p>The Confederates in Arkansas were reported to be about to attack
Little Rock, but they had sustained a repulse in an attempt on the
outposts of Fort Gibson.</p>
<p>General Rosecranz is to supersede General Schofield in
Missouri.</p>
<p>The bombardment of Charleston continued. It had been reported that
several monitors and the iron-clad frigate Ironsides had become
entangled in the obstructions placed in Charleston Harbour, and were
in a very dangerous position; but it had susequently been declared
that there was no foundation for the report.</p>
<p>There was a rumour at New Orleans that a mutiny had broken out
among the coloured troops in Fort Jackson. The Federals had abandoned
the Teche country.</p>
<p>There is no news of importance from Texas. Generals Banks and Kirby
Smith were exchanging prisoners.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">Miscellaneous.</hi></p>
<p>The Federal Congress have voted 20,000,000 dols. for bounties and
advance pay to volunteers, and passed a vote against submitting the
legality of the Conscription Act to the Supreme Court.</p><pb n="27"/>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">New York Herald</hi> has commenced a
systematic attack upon President Lincoln, saying that his fatuity and
imbecility, where his personal partialities are concerned, pass all
belief, and that he is an amiable sort of man, but his works are too
costly.</p>
<p>Mr. Secretary Stanton states in his report to President Lincoln,
that up to midsummer last there had been issued to the Federal troops
by the War Department since the present war began, 1,550,576 muskets
and rifles for foot soldiers, 327,170 carbines and pistols for mounted
troops, 271,817 sabres, 1,745,586 cannon balls and shells, 50,045,515
lb. of lead and lead bullets, 2,274,490 cartridges for artillery,
378,584,104 cartridges for small arms, 715,036,470 percussion-caps,
6,082,505 friction primers, 13,071,073 lb. of gunpowder, 1,680,220
sets of accoutrements for infantry, and 196,298 for cavalry.</p>
<p>General M'Clellan was adopted as a candidate at the next
presidential election by a meeting of the Conservative Union National
Committee, held at Philadelphia on the 23rd ult. Judge Campbell was
nominated for the vice-presidency.</p>
<p>General Burnside is in New York, receiving much public
attention.</p>
<p>General Corcoran has been killed by a fall from his
horse.</p>
<p>The passport system for passengers leaving by American vessels has
been revived.</p>
<p>Federal war-vessels have been stationed off the Narrows to overhaul
vessels leaving New York.</p>
<p>The English barque Circassian has been seized at New York by the
Provost Marshal, and many arrests, both male and female, have been
made on board.</p>
<p>Advices from fortress Monroe state that General Butler has issued
an order for enrolling all ablebodied citizens, white and coloured,
between the ages of eighteen and forty-five in his department.</p>
<p>At the ceremony of turning the first sod of the Atlantic and
Pacific Railway, in Nebraska, Mr. Poppleton, of Omaha, citizen and
promoter of the railway, thus addressed the
assembly:--"Fellow-citizens of Omaha and Council Bluffs,--On the 13th
day of October, 1854, about seven o'clock in the evening, I was set
down by the Western Stage Company at yonder city of Council Bluffs. At
the rising of the sun on the following morning I climbed to the summit
of one of the bluffs which overlook that prosperous and enterprising
town, and took one long and lingering look across the Missouri at the
beautiful site on which now sits, in the full vigour of business,
social and religious life, the youthful but thriving, and this day
jubilant, city of Omaha. Early in the day I crossed the river, and
along a narrow path, cut by some stalwart man through the tall, rank,
prairie grass, I wended my way in search of the post-office. At length
I found an old pioneer seated, apparently in solitary rumination, upon
a piece of hewn timber, and inquired of him for the post-office. He
replied that he was the postmaster, and would examine the office for
my letters, Thereupon he removed from his head a hat, to say the least
of it, somewhat veteran in appearance, and drew from its cavernous
depths the coveted letters. On that day the wolves and the Omahas were
the almost undisputed lords of the soil, and the entire postal system
of the city was conducted in the crown of this venerable hat! To-day,
at least 4000 radiant faces gladden our streets, and the postal
service, sheltered by a costly edifice, strikes its Briarien arms
towards the north, the south, the east, and the west, penetrating
regions then unexplored and unknown, and bearing the symbols of values
then hidden in the mountains and beneath the streams of which the
world in its wildest vagaries had never dreamed."--Mr. Train took a
prominent part in the celebration, making a speech in which he was
unsparing in his abuse of England. The <hi
rend="italic">Republican</hi>, speaking of Mr. Train's appearance,
says, "By special request of the ladies, Mr. T. mounted a buggy, threw
off his overcoat, laid down his hat, rolled up his sleeves, and in
another moment the steam was on, and he was under full headway."</p>
<p>The Governor of Texas had issued a message declaring that there can
be no peace until the Southern Confederacy shall have been
recognised.</p>
<p>A correspondence between Jefferson Davis and the Pope has been
published. The two eminent personages are charmingly courteous to each
other. Mr. Davis informs the Pope that the laws of the Southern
Confederacy ensure to every one the enjoyment of his temporal rights
and the free exercise of his religion. He presumes, no doubt, that the
Pope has never heard of the negro population. Mr. Davis finally prays
that Heaven may prolong the Pope's days, The Pope, in return, prays
that the God of pity may shed upon Davis the light of His grace.</p>
<p>It is stated in the <hi rend="italic">Richmond Enquirer</hi> that
Jefferson Davis will soon make a decided change in the whole
Government, and also in the army.</p>
<p>The substitute system has been abrogated in the Confederate
Congress.</p>
<p>The steamer Vanderbilt has captured the barque Saxon off Cape Town,
and the Angela Pequina on the West Coast of Africa. The schooner
J. L. Gerity, which left Matamoras on Nov. 16 with a cargo of cotton
and six passengers, was captured at sea by the passengers, who
overpowered the captain and crew and set them adrift in an open
boat. After two days they landed at Sisal.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1239.002" n= "According to the Returns" type="Article">
<head>[ACCORDING TO THE RETURNS]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1239</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 27</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-09">January 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>According to the returns of the Government emigration officers at
Liverpool, for 1863, the emigration from that port, when compared with
1862, is greatly on the increase. The total number of steerage
passengers sailling "under the Act" was 119,772, and of cabin
passengers 3765; making a total of 123,537. Added to this there are
the passengers carried out in the short ships, which number 14,445;
making a grand total of 137,982. When compared with last year, there
is an increase of 76,668. The tide of emigration is principally
accelerated by the enormous Irish emigration to America, which appears
to increase daily. It is also a fact that the Irish emigrants are much
better clothed than those whose homes have been in England or
Scotland. This is attributed to the high pay now being given to
labourers in the United States.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1239.003" n="The War in America: The Confederates
      Quitting Brownsville, Texas, on Hearing of the Approach of
      Federal Transports.--See Next Page." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1239</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 29</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-09">January 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv44p29">
<head>THE WAR IN AMERICA: THE CONFEDERATES
      QUITTING BROWNSVILLE, TEXAS, ON HEARING OF THE APPROACH OF
      FEDERAL TRANSPORTS.--SEE NEXT PAGE.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1239.004" n= "The Confederates Quitting Brownsville, Texas." type="Article">
<head>THE CONFEDERATES QUITTING BROWNSVILLE, TEXAS.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1239</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 30</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-09">January 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE CONFEDERATES QUITTING BROWNSVILLE,</p>
<p rend="center">TEXAS.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> town of Brownsville lies on the Texan
bank of the Rio Grand (or Rio Bravo) del Norte, about two miles from
Matamoros, a town of some note in Mexico, on the south side of the
river. Although built almost entirely of wood, Brownsville has a neat
and bright appearance. There was a considerable Confederate garrison
at this place; but the inhabitants, having, on Monday, Nov. 2, 1863,
received information of the arrival of a fleet of Federal transports
off Brazos, Santiago, began immediately to evacuate the town; and for
two days every means of transit across the Rio Grande was crowded to
excess with goods, furniture, cotton, and baggage; while upon both
banks were piled in confused heaps bedding, cotton bales, luggage,
vehicles, and merchandise of every description. About three o'clock
p.m. on Tuesday, the 3rd ult., the military authorities retreated,
after burning the garrison buildings, the cotton, and all public
stores they were not able to remove. On the 6th ult. the Federals,
under command of General Banks, took quiet possession of the
place.</p>
<p>Our Engraving on the preceding page is from a photograph by
Mr. A. G. Wedge, of Matamoras.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1239.005" n="The War In America: The Federal Steamer
      Chesapeake, Seized By Confederates, Landing Crew and Passengers
      off Musquash Harbour, Bay of Pundy.--See Next Page." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1239</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 33</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-09">January 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv44p33">
<head>THE WAR IN AMERICA: THE FEDERAL STEAMER
      CHESAPEAKE, SEIZED BY CONFEDERATES, LANDING CREW AND PASSENGERS
      OFF MUSQUASH HARBOUR, BAY OF PUNDY.--SEE NEXT PAGE.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1239.006" n= "Capture and Recapture of the Chesapeake." type="Article">
<head>CAPTURE AND RECAPTURE OF THE CHESAPEAKE.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1239</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 34</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-09">January 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">CAPTURE AND RECAPTURE OF THE CHESAPEAKE.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> Chesapeake, Captain Willet,
screw-steamer, of 460 tons, one of a line of freight and passenger
steamers sailing between New York and Portland, Maine, left New York
on the 5th ult., on her regular trip to Portland. At one o'clock
a.m. on the 6th ult., when about twenty miles N.N.E. of Cape Cod, she
was seized by a party of Confederates, who had taken passage on her
for Portland. The second engineer, who was in charge of the engine at
the time, was shot dead and his body thrown overboard. The first
engineer was wounded by a ball in the chin, and was kept on board to
work the engine. The first mate was also wounded, but not dangerously;
and although several shots were fired at the captain he was fortunate
enough to escape without even getting a wound. After the crew had been
overpowered, the vessel was taken charge of by the Confederates; the
captain, officers, and crew were placed in irons, and the passengers,
some six or eight in number, on promising not to interfere, were
allowed their liberty. The Confederates numbered sixteen persons, and
were commanded by a Lieutenant Braine, reputed to hold a commission in
the Confederate service. Among the passengers was a man belonging to
St. John, N.B., who, on its being ascertained that he was acquainted
with the navigation of the Bay of Fundy, was forced by Braine to act
as pilot. On the night of the 8th ult. the Chesapeake arrived off
Musquash Harbour, where she was boarded by a person, said to be a
Confederate officer, who assumed the command of the steamer. A passing
pilot-boat, "The Simonds," was hailed, the pilot was compelled to come
on board, and the boat was taken in tow. The passengers, captain,
officers, and crew of the Chesapeake were landed at this place, and
arrived at St. John, New Brunswick, on the morning of the 9th
ult. This incident forms the subject of our Illustration on the
preceding page, from a sketch by Mr. Charles C. Ward, of St. John. The
Chesapeake then steamed up to Partridge Island, at the mouth of the
Harbour of St. John, where the man who had acted as pilot was landed,
and the vessel sailed away.</p>
<p>The Chesapeake has been subsequently recaptured by the Federal
steamer Ella Annie, in Sambro Harbour, Nova Scotia. The Chesapeake was
taken to Halifax for judicial decision. No resistance was offered by
the crew, all of whom, except three, escaped to the shore. The English
authorities in Nova Scotia had forbidden the furnishing of coals to
the Chesapeake by the people of that province; they had ordered her
detention wherever she appeared, and gave the information to the
Federals which led to her capture. It is also alleged that they have
ordered the arrest of the men who seized her while going in her as
passengers, holding them to have been guilty of piracy.</p>
<p>We learn by the last mail that the three pirates captured on board
the Chesapeake were taken from the authorities by the mob whilst being
landed at Halifax, and set free.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1239.007" n= "A Great Waterfall." type="Article">
<head>A GREAT WATERFALL.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1239</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 35</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-09">January 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">A Great Waterfall</hi>.--A detachment of
troops recently scouting in the valley of the Snake or Lewis fork of
the Columbia discovered a waterfall which, it is said, is entitled to
the distinction of being called the greatest in the world. The entire
volume of Snake River pours over a sheer precipice 198 ft. high, 38
ft. higher than Niagara. Snake River is fully as large as the Niagara,
and the cascade is one solid sheet or body. The locality of this
immense waterfall is near the point heretofore designated as the Great
Shoshone or Salmon Falls of that river, but they have always been
enveloped in mystery. Almost a dozen years ago the writer passed along
the Snake River road. For two days we heard the roaring of these
falls, but learned no more respecting them than if they had been in
the moon. It was said that there were a series of falls and rapids,
making a descent of 700 ft. in seven miles, and the sound gave colour
to the report. For hundreds of miles across the great plain Snake
River flows through a canon, with vertical walls hundreds of feet
high. It is only at long intervals that salient points are found by
which the river can be reached. The road crosses from point to point
of the bends, only approaching close to the river where there is a
chance to descend for water. From these facts very few, if any, of the
tens of thousands of adventurers that have crossed the plains have
ever looked upon the great falls. The late discoverers report, beside
the main cataract, many others of less height, varying from 20 ft. to
50 ft. each, near by. Some day they will be visited by the tourist and
pleasure-seeker, and looked upon as frequently and familiarly as
Niagara is today; and it will be admitted that, with the stupendous
grandeur of their surroundings, they are as far beyond Niagara as
Niagara now excels the balance of the world.--<hi rend="italic">New
York World</hi>.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1239.008" n= "The Massachusetts Volunteers" type="Article">
<head>[THE MASSACHUSETTS VOLUNTEERS]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1239</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 46</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-09">January 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>The Massachusetts volunteers, under the Bounty Act just published
by the General Court, will be the best paid troops in the world. The
amount of bounty and pay to be received for three years' service, by a
soldier who has previously been in the army nine months or more, if he
has a family of not less than three persons dependent on his labour
for support, is as follows:--United States' bounty, 402 dols.; the
Commonwealth's bounty, 325 dols.; pay, 468 dols.; rations, 324 dols.;
clothing, 126 dols.; aid to family, 432 dols.--total, 2077 dols. If,
instead of 325 dols. in hand from the State, he accepts the offer of
20 dols. per month increase, he will receive 445 dols. of pay more
than the sum above.--<hi rend="italic">New York Paper.</hi></p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1239.009" n= "Column for the Curious." type="Article">
<head>COLUMN FOR THE CURIOUS.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1239</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 47</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-09">January 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">COLUMN FOR THE CURIOUS.</hi></p>
<p>The History of Steam Navigation is yet to be written. New facts, or
novel versions of old facts, are repeatedly turning up, so as to
affect claims of priority. Last year three papers were read to the
Manchester Literary and Philosophical Society--1, " On the
Introduction of Steam Navigation;" 2 and 3, "Note on Two Events in the
History," &#x0026;c.; and there cropped up the following paragraph:--
<q><p><hi rend="smallcaps">A Steam-Boat in 1788</hi>.--In a letter
from Dr. Franklin to Dr. Ingenhauz, dated Philadelphia, Oct. 24, 1788,
the Doctor remarks:--We have no philosophical news here at present,
except that a boat moved by a steam-engine rows itself against tide in
our river, and it is apprehended the construction may be so simplified
and improved as to become generally useful."</p></q>
In going over the ground of the history, even practised writers are
continually stumbling. The other day a reviewer, in the <hi
rend="italic">Times</hi>, referred to a statement that, "three
centuries ago, Blasco de Garay attempted to propel a boat by steam in
the harbour of Barcelona." To this a Correspondent has replied as
follows:--
<q><p>The evidence cited by the Spaniards for this assertion, often
repeated, is a letter from Blasco himself, written in A.D. 1543.</p>
<p>By permission of the Queen of Spain, but after much hindrance, I
was enabled to inspect this letter, now preserved with the Archives at
Simancas, near Valladolid, and there is not one word about steam in
the document. Blasco describes minutely a vessel propelled by paddles
worked by 200 men.</p>
<p>The first well authenticated instance of a steam-boat actually used
is found in the manuscript correspondence between Leibnitz and Papin,
in the Royal Library at Hanover, where Papin relates his experiments
with a model steam-boat on the River Fulda in the year 1707. Next, in
1783, De Jouffroy in France and Fitch in America used steam-boats
experimentally. The first practically successful steam-boat was worked
in 1787 by Mr. Miller, of Dalswinton, in
Scotland....</p></q></p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1240.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1240</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 50</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-16">January 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>No movement has been made by any of the armies in Virginia or the
south-west, but the Confederate guerrillas were still
active. Longstreet had removed to a position which he can fortify
while he retains convenient means of retreat. The effect of this
movement will be, it is said, to necessitate the keeping of a large
Federal army in East Tennessee.</p>
<p>It is said that the Confederate General Rossee had accomplished the
ominous feat of making a complete circuit of General Meade's army.</p>
<p>General Grant is reported to have drawn up a new plan for the next
campaign, and to have submitted it to the Government at
Washington.</p>
<p>The bombardment of Charleston continued, with little result.</p>
<p>The Confederates had refused to negotiate with General Butler for
an exchange of prisoners, on the ground that he had been "outlawed" by
President Davis.</p>
<p>The Free States men have held a convention in New Orleans, in which
negroes were admitted to seats and the convention was opened by a
prayer from a coloured preacher.</p>
<p>The Federal Government have officially denied that they would never
tolerate or recognise the Mexican monarchy.</p>
<p>The draught has been postponed till the middle of January.</p>
<p>The Governor of New York has removed the New York Police
Commissioners, on the ground that their reports of the New York riots
were sectarian and partisan.</p>
<p>Several more merchants of New York have been arrested for carrying
on a contraband trade with the South.</p>
<p>The Most Rev. Dr. Hughes, the Roman Catholic Archbishop of New
York, is dead.</p>
<p>The ironclad Dictator has been successfully launched at New
York. Two of the men implicated in the seizure of the Chesapeake had
been arrested at St. John, New Brunswick, and had been brought before
the police magistrate.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1240.002" n= "News comes from Batavia" type="Article">
<head>[NEWS COMES FROM BATAVIA]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1240</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 51</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-16">January 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>News comes from Batavia of the ubiquitous Alabama. On Nov. 6 this
daring cruiser, last from Cape Town, fell in with the Amanda, an
American ship laden with sugar and hemp, took her, and burnt her. On
the 10th she captured and burnt another American ship, the clipper
Winged Racer, also laden with hemp and sugar.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1241.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1241</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 70</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-23">January 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>By the arrival of the North American we have news from New York to
the afternoon of Jan. 9.</p>
<p>There had been some skirmishes and minor engagements in Western
Virginia and in the neighbourhood of Winchester, and their result
seems to have been generally advantageous to the Confederates. At
Chattanooga all was quiet, and General Joseph Johnstone was understood
to be actively reorganising the Confederate army in the neighbourhood
of Dalton. An expedition sailed from New Orleans on the 30th ult., and
although its destination was not positively known, it was supposed
that the forces would at first proceed to Pensacola, and would
ultimately operate against Mobile. On Christmas Day the Federals
bombarded Charleston with great effect. The Confederates erected a
battery on Stono River, and did considerable damage to the gun-boat
Marble Head. Two other gun-boats went to her assistance, drove the
enemy from the battery, and captured it.</p>
<p>Everything shows the determination of the North to prosecute the
war to the utmost. President Lincoln and his Cabinet recommended
Congress to offer liberal bounties to volunteers up to the end of
February, as the suspension of bounties had almost stopped
recruiting. Mr. Wilson has consequently introduced a bill, offering
bounties of 400 dols. to re-enlisting volunteers, 300 dols. to new
volunteers, and 100 dols. to negro recruits. A resolution to the
effect that 1,000,000 volunteers should be called out for ninety days,
and should be placed under General Grant's command, had been referred
for consideration to the Senate's Military Committee. The House of
Representatives had passed a resolution declaring that any proposal
for negotiation with the "rebels" should be immediately and
unhesitatingly rejected. Mr. Lincoln has been nominated for
re-election as President, and his reappointment has been urged in the
House of Representatives. The ground alleged in the latter case was
that his election would ensure emancipation throughout the Union. In
the same connection, the Governor of Maryland, in his message to the
State Legislature, has urged that steps should be taken to push
forward gradual emancipation in the State. A delegation of citizens
had left Arkansas for Washington to arrange for their State
re-entering the Union.</p>
<p>Governor Seymour, in his message to the New York Legislature, had
recommended measures for the protection of the State banks against the
new national banks, had denounced the draught as a failure, and had
declared that President Lincoln had assumed powers which subordinated
the laws to military authority. The Governor declares that the country
can only be saved from ruin by the Administration adhering to its
pledge to restore constitutional union. The Republican press are
incensed against the message. The <hi rend="italic">New York
Times</hi> declares that Governor Seymour's sympathies are with
rebellion. The <hi rend="italic">New York Tribune</hi> denounces him
as a traitorous and malignant enemy of his country.</p>
<p>Extensive shipments from New York to the South have come to light,
and more arrests have been made.</p>
<p>A letter recently intercepted by the War Department disclosed the
fact that W. E. Hilton, a printer in New York, was engaged, under
contract with the Southern Confederate Secretary of the Treasury, in
furnishing notes, bonds, &#x0026;c., to the South, and that he was
about to proceed to Richmond to superintend a printing and engraving
establishment. Hilton was arrested and consigned to Fort Lafayette. In
his possession were found six million dollars in Confederate bonds
ready for signature.</p>
<p>Archbishop Hughes was buried in New York with great ceremony on the
7th inst. An immense concourse of people was present. The law courts
and numerous places of business were closed.</p>
<p>Four negroes called at the Executive mansion, Washington, on
New-Year's Day, and were presented to Mr. Lincoln. This is the first
occurrence of the kind.</p>
<p>Signal stations, occupied by a small garrison, are to be
established along the Mississippi for the protection of the
navigation, in accordance with a recommendation from President Lincoln
and the Secretary for War.</p>
<p>The Federals have constructed upwards of 5000 miles of military
telegraph, and the Secretary for War states that in the course of last
year at least 1,200,000 telegrams were sent along these lines--about
3300 a day.</p>
<p>The City of Baltimore was intercepted off Cape Race on the 2nd.</p>
<p>The Nova Scotia Government has placed the steamer Chesapeake in the
Admiralty Court.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1241.002" n= "A contract for the construction of a tunnel" type="Article">
<head>[A CONTRACT FOR THE CONSTRUCTION OF A TUNNEL]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1241</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 70</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-23">January 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A contract for the construction of a tunnel, extending two miles
under Lake Michigan, at Chicago, for the purpose of supplying the city
with pure water, has been awarded; the lowest bid for completing the
tunnel being 315,130 dollars. The contract is for a tunnel of five
feet internal diameter, lined with brick. The tunnel is to be
excavated thirty-five feet below the bed of the lake, and to have four
feet of dip landwards. Strainers will be fixed over the outlet to keep
out the fish. The total area of the tunnel will be nearly twenty
square feet, an area amply large enough to furnish water continuously
to a city five or six times the size of Chicago in the present
day.</p>
<p>The Confederate cruiser Florida is said to have completed her
repairs and alterations at Brest, and to be ready to put to sea. Her
recent trial-trip was most satisfactory, and she is reported to be in
a high state of efficiency. Captain Maurice Richard, her new
commander, has waited on the Vice-Admiral of the port and other local
authorities to take official leave of them, and no doubt the Florida
will sail shortly. The Kearsage, Federal frigate, still mounts guard
outside the port of Brest, and a fight is looked forward to with
considerable certainty. Captain Richard expresses himself confident of
being able to give a good account of himself and his ship, and has, it
is stated, written to the Federal commander that he is prepared to
accept a combat with him outside the limits of French
waters.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1241.003" n= "An Irish American, named Feeney" type="Article">
<head>[AN IRISH AMERICAN, NAMED FEENEY]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1241</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 71</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-23">January 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>An Irish American, named Feeny, is actively engaged in Galway in
getting labourers for a railroad in the Federal States. He offers
eight shillings a day and other advantages to his recruits on arriving
at their "destination;" but where that may be is not very clear. He
has had great success, and in two or three days enrolled five hundred
men. He has been arrested under the Foreign Enlistment Act, in
Loughrea, on suspicion of enlisting for the Federal army, but, as no
proof could be had, he was acquitted.</p>
<p>Mr. Thomas Highat, a member of the firm of Messrs. Jones and Co.,
ship-chandlers, Liverpool, was charged before the stipendiary
magistrate of that borough, yesterday week, with an offence against
the Foreign Enlistment Act. The specific charge against Mr. Highat was
that he had been concerned in the enlistment of men for service on
board the Confederate cruiser Georgia. The witnesses for the
prosecution were four men who served for a short time on board that
ship, but who are now employed at a weekly salary by a private
detective, who seems to be one of the Attach&#x00E9;s of the United
States Consulate at Liverpool. Mr. Highat was bound over in his own
recognizances and two sureties to appear to answer any charge which
may be preferred against him at the next Assizes.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1241.004" n= "Illustration of the War in America." type="Article">
<head>ILLUSTRATION OF THE WAR IN AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1241</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 76</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-23">January 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ILLUSTRATION OF THE WAR IN<lb/>
AMERICA.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Our</hi> Special Artist in the South writes as
follows concerning the accompanying Illustration:--"Herewith I send
you a sketch of Fort Fisher, commanding the approach to Cape Fear
River, the entrance to Wilmington, North Carolina. I was down there
one night, and, as it is twenty-five miles from the town, it was
impossible to get back that night, so I had to rough it in a casemate
till morning. As luck would have it, we discovered a blockade-running
steamer, the Hansa, under our guns at dawn, and at the same time the
Yankee blockaders also became aware of her presence and opened fire,
thinking, as she had already got inside the bar (the line of white
breakers just seaward of her), they would destroy her before she made
the inlet. To get within range they had to expose themselves to the
metal of the fort, which soon drove them off, leaving the Hansa at
liberty to make her way safely into the river. The distant point of
land is Cape Fear. Fort Fisher is one of the strongest coast defences
I have seen, not excepting any of those at Charleston, that have
hitherto held an entire iron-clad fleet at bay."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1241.005" n="The War In America: Fort Fisher,
      Commanding The New Inlet Entrance To Cape Fear River.--The
      British Steamer Hansa Running The Blockade Under The Guns Of The
      Fort.--From A Sketch By Our Special Artist." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1241</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 76</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-23">January 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv44p76">
<head>THE WAR IN AMERICA: FORT FISHER,
      COMMANDING THE NEW INLET ENTRANCE TO CAPE FEAR RIVER.--THE
      BRITISH STEAMER HANSA RUNNING THE BLOCKADE UNDER THE GUNS OF THE
      FORT.--FROM A SKETCH BY OUR SPECIAL ARTIST.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1241.006" n= "Last year there were exported to Europe" type="Article">
<head>[LAST YEAR THERE WERE EXPORTED TO EUROPE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1241</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 91</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-23">January 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Last year there were exported to Europe from all parts of the
United States, except California, 1,705,882 barrels of flour,
16,150,811 bushels of wheat, 7,106,482 bushels of corn, and 383,316
bushels of rye. In 1862 the exports were 2,376,954 barrels of flour,
29,300,084 bushels of wheat, 12,301,205 bushels of corn, and 910,746
bushels of rye.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1242.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1242</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 94</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-30">January 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p>AMERICA.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">War Intelligence.</hi></p>
<p>There is nothing important in the latest news from New
York. Generals Lee, Johnston, and Longstreet were assiduously engaged
in recruiting and reorganising the Confederate armies under their
respective commands; and General Longstreet was said to occupy a
position within twenty miles of Knoxville. General Meade, in a speech
which he had made in Philadelphia, had declared that active operations
would be recommenced in Virginia as soon as the weather and the season
permitted.</p>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">Times'</hi> correspondent adds to the above
intelligence that General Stuart, with 5000 Confederate cavalry, had
again passed round General Meade on the night of the 14th inst. The
object of this movement is believed to be to sever either the
Alexandria and Orange or the Baltimore and Ohio Railways. The Federal
authorities are said to be fully prepared to prevent material damage
to either.</p>
<p>General Lee, under date of the 8th, announces the capture, in Hardy
County, Virginia, of 300 Federals, 125 mules, and 123 cattle.</p>
<p>Telegrams from Fortress Monroe of the 13th reported the Federal
gun-boat Iron Age aground, and under the fire of Confederate
batteries, at the entrance of Wilmington Harbour, on the 11th. Her
destruction on that day, by being blown up, is subsequently announced
by Confederate despatches to General Cooper. Twenty-four of her crew
were captured.</p>
<p>Two blocks of buildings and several large warehouses are reported
to have been destroyed in Charleston on the 20th by Gillmore's
shells. The city was almost deserted by the military. The
correspondent of the <hi rend="italic">New York Tribune</hi> states
that three new Confederate iron-clad vessels are visible in Charleston
Harbour in a forward state of construction. It is expected that these
and other Confederate ironclads will shortly make a sortie against the
Federal squadron.</p>
<p>The Confederate General Magruder was reported to be concentrating a
corps of 20,000 men in Central Texas, with the purpose of attacking
and overwhelming the Federal troops lately landed on the bank of the
Rio Grande and the neighbouring coast.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">Miscellaneous.</hi></p>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">New York Times</hi> has come out for the
re-nomination of Mr. Lincoln to the presidency.</p>
<p>A memorandum on the plan and conduct of the war, dated Aug. 4,
1861, prepared, at the request of Mr. Lincoln, by General M'Clellan,
has just been published. The predictions of the General in that
document, which is evidently published at this time for electioneering
purposes by the General's friends, seem to have been verified by
subsequent events.</p>
<p>Smallpox is becoming so prevalent in Washington that the House of
Representatives have adopted a resolution recommending the municipal
authorities of that city and Georgetown to take measures to ensure the
vaccination of the citizens, to prevent the further spread of the
disease.</p>
<p>Governor Parker, in his message to the New Jersey Legislature,
delivered on the 12th inst., advocates the adoption of a conciliatory
policy towards the South and the reconstruction of the Union upon its
original basis. He asserts that the emancipation proclamation is the
chief obstacle to the termination of the war and the return of the
seceded States to the Union, and condemns the amnesty manifesto; but
believes that these, together with many other of Mr. Lincoln's
unconstitutional acts, will be annulled upon the change of
Administration.</p>
<p>The Democratic members of Congress, in a meeting held at
Washington, had resolved that President Lincoln's amnesty proclamation
was unconstitutional, and that the army and navy ought to be paid in
specie or its equivalent.</p>
<p>Extensive frauds in the Custom House of New York, the Treasury
Department of Washington, the Navy Yard, Brooklyn, and the public
offices continue to be discovered. Mr. Fernando Wood proposed to
appoint a Congressional Committee to investigate the administration of
affairs in all the departments, as well as the charges against General
Butler at New Orleans. The proposition was rejected by a vote of 76 to
63. A resolution to inquire into the frauds in the Custom House was,
however, adopted.</p><pb n="95"/>
<p>The New York Legislature has passed a bill to enable soldiers in
the field to vote.</p>
<p>A municipal report on the condition of the barracks on Broadway,
near Astor House, has created much indignation. Sixty men, arrested
for various military offences, were found confined in a room fifteen
by twenty feet square. Many had been there for months, with no
accommodation for sitting or lying down. The report states that they
were covered with filth and treated worse than wild beasts, and that
the existence of such a place was an outrage on humanity, bringing
disgrace to a nation.</p>
<p>The Maryland Legislature have voted in favour of calling a
convention to carry out emancipation.</p>
<p>The Judge of the Admiralty Court at Halifax had expressed an
opinion that the capture of the Chesapeake was a piratical seizure,
but had not delivered any judgment, nor ordered the restoration of the
vessel to her owners.</p>
<p>The pirate passengers who lately captured the schooner Gerety, from
Matamoras, for Havannah, took her into Honduras, and, after selling a
portion of her cargo, escaped.</p>
<p>The American corvette St. Louis sailed from Lisbon on Monday to
intercept an English barque with guns and stores for the Confederate
cruiser Rappahannock.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1242.002" n= "According to the last advices from New York" type="Article">
<head>[ACCORDING TO THE LAST ADVICES FROM NEW YORK]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1242</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 110</biblScope>
<date value="1864-01-30">January 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>According to the last advices from New York, the report of the
Commission appointed by the Nary Department, consisting of three
chief engineers, who have made careful experiments for five months,
showing the practicability of using petroleum or hydro-carbon oils for
the purpose of generating steam, has been issued, and proves
satisfactory. It is alleged that its use will produce a great saving,
not only for merchant steamers, but that a naval steamer can keep the
sea under steam three times as long with less labour and greater
economy as compared with an equal weight of coal.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1243.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1243</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 118</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-06">February 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>There is not any intelligence of military interest from
America. The main bodies of the respective armies were motionless, and
the only activity displayed was by the raids of light cavalry. The
weather was so severe that no important movement was likely for the
present, but both sides were making the most extensive preparations
for operations in the spring. It is said that the Federals intend to
make a double movement on Richmond. The Federals bombarded Charleston
for four days, from the 10th to the 14th ult., and the firing was
going on when the last reports left. Much mischief to property had
resulted, but no injury to life or person. The Federals were preparing
to meet the anticipated attack by the Confederate ironclads. On the
coast of Texas there has been a little fighting, to the advantage of
the Confederates, who are believed to be well fortified and in strong
force there. The Federals are reported to have landed at Morehead
city, North Carolina. The journals of that State continue to urge
peace with the North, and there is, beyond doubt, a strong Union
feeling existing.</p>
<p>A volume of diplomatic correspondence has been laid before
Congress, containing 700 pages of communications between the British
and the Federal Governments. In one letter Secretary Seward declared
that the Federal Cabinet must persist in maintaining that England is
responsible for the losses sustained by American citizens from the
Alabama's depredations and in urging consequent claims for
compensation. In complaining of the outfit of iron-clad rams in
British harbours, he said that those rams must be expected to assail
some of the great American ports, and that the Navy Department had not
a sufficient number of disposable vessels to protect all. In the event
of such an attack a retaliatory war would be inevitable. After Earl
Russell's intimation that orders had been given for the seizure of the
rams at Liverpool, Secretary Seward directed Mr. Adams to inform the
English Cabinet that the Federal Government would, hereafter hold
itself obliged, with even more cause than heretofore, to endeaour to
conduct its intercourse with England so that the civil war, when
terminated, will leave to neither nation any permanent cause for
discontent.</p>
<p>Further correspondence between the British and the American
Governments the main subject of which is the Alexandra and her sister
ships, has been published. Mr. Seward complains of Chief Baron
Pollock's decision in the Alexandra case, and intimates that if that
be English Law, not only does it require amendment, but America will
have to take unusual steps to protect herself against it. The American
Secretary continues, that America is sufficiently chastened by the
civil war to make any concession compatible with the interests of the
national life and honour, but she cannot stand the fitting-out of
Alabamas and Alexandras, and the responsibility for the consequences
will not be left with President Lincoln. The negotiation of a
Confederate loan in this country, Mr. Seward says, puts an end to all
concessions for mitigating the rigour of the<pb n="119"/> blockade in
regard to the shipment of tobacco and cotton. To a complaint of the
enlistment of British subjects in the Confederate service, Earl
Russell requests that it should not be repeated unless all British
subjects are discharged from the Federal service, and orders given not
to enlist any more. In respect to compensation for the depredations of
the Alabama, the noble Earl says they cannot be recognised by the
British Government, as they are not founded on grounds of law and
justice.</p>
<p>With regard to France, M. Drouyn de Lhuys had urged the recognition
of Mexico as a monarchy by the Washington Government. Mr. Seward had
firmly declined; and, while avowing that the United States would
adhere to a policy of non-intervention, he expresses a belief that the
establishment of a monarchical Government will be found neither
desirable nor easy.</p>
<p>The House of Representatives has passed a bill imposing a duty of
two cents on cotton and an additional duty of 40 cents per gallon on
imported spirits.</p>
<p>General Rosecranz has been appointed to command the district of
Missouri.</p>
<p>General Banks had issued a proclamation declaring that more than
one tenth of the population of Louisiana desired to return to the
Union, abrogating the State laws concerning slavery, and ordering that
a convention shall revise the State Constitution, and that members of
Congress shall be elected.</p>
<p>Thomas Francis Meagher has delivered a panegyric on General
Corcoran before a large Irish audience at the Cooper Institute, New
York. His numerous references to the Fenian Brotherhood were loudly
cheered.</p>
<p>The Confederate Congress have resolved that persons who furnished
substitutes will not be exempt from military service. It also passed a
resolution pledging the Confederates to perpetual resistance.</p>
<p>It was asserted that some Confederates had assembled at Point
Pel&#x00E9;e, in Canada, for the purpose of rescuing the Confederate
prisoners confined on Johnson's Island, in Lake Erie, and that a
detachment of British troops had been sent to watch their
movements.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1244.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1244</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 143</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-13">February 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>The Columbia brings news from New York to the evening of
Jan. 29.</p>
<p>The most important fact mentioned is the near approach of General
Longetreet, reinforced by 20,000 men, to Knoxville. Skirmishing
between his cavalry and the Federal outposts had commenced, and the
latest accounts state that great anxiety, amounting to a panic,
prevailed in the city.</p>
<p>The Confederates had made two separate attacks on Athens and
Florence, in Alabama, in both of which they are said to have
failed.</p>
<p>Despatches from Chattanooga report that the Confederate General
Johnston had fallen back forty miles south of Dalton.</p>
<p>The Federal batteries continued to throw shells into Charleston;
and it was reported that half the city had been abandoned by the
inhabitants.</p>
<p>General Butler reports that he had sent three transports and a
competent force up the James River, which landed seven miles below
Fort Powhattan and captured twenty Confederates, seven of whom
belonged to the signal corps, and brought away ninety negroes, besides
destroying large stores.</p>
<p>Re-enlistments in the Federal army are very numerous. Throughout
the West several entire corps have re-enlisted.</p>
<p>The trade of the Mississippi is still interrupted--indeed, almost
suspended--by the Confederate batteries.</p>
<p>Mr. Lincoln has been nominated by the Republican members of the New
Jersey Legislature for the presidency.</p>
<p>The delegates to the State Convention held at Little Rock,
Arkansas, have adopted a resolution prohibiting slavery.</p>
<p>In Congress the Senate has passed a resolution requiring members to
take the oath. Senator Bayard took the oath, and announced his
intention of retiring into private life. The Judiciary Committee of
the Senate has discharged from consideration the resolution to expel
Mr. Davis, of Kentucky, from the Senate. Senator Hale urges the
appointment of a committee to investigate the affairs of the Navy
Department, and proved statistically that the United States were
called upon to spend this year for the navy more than the combined
annual naval expenses of all the European Powers, excluding Denmark
and Italy, and forty millions more than the naval expenses of France
and England during the three years and five months of the Crimean
War.</p>
<p>Mr. Fernando Wood has spoken strongly in the House of
Representatives in favour of peace, declaring that the Administration
opposed the restoration of the Union and favoured the continuance of
the war for partisan advantage. He said that the most damnable deeds
were perpetrated under the plea of patriotism.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1244.002" n= "The English Government and Confederate Cruisers." type="Article">
<head>.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1244</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 143</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-13">February 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center">THE ENGLISH GOVERNMENT AND CONFEDERATE<lb/>
CRUISERS.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">On</hi> Tuesday was issued a batch of
correspondence with the United States' Government in continuation of
the despatches presented to Parliament last March. The new documents
consist of affidavits and memorials relating to the depredations of
the Alabama and the Florida; despatches from Mr. Adams to Earl
Russell, quoting each of these as claims for indemnity and adding them
"to others of the same kind which it has been my painful duty to
present to your Lordship heretofore;" and of replies from Earl Russell
disclaiming all responsibility in regard to the proceedings of the
Alabama or of any other Confederate cruiser.</p>
<p>In the course of a despatch dated March 27 last year Earl Russell,
describing to Lord Lyons an interview with Mr. Adams, after stating
that the American Ambassador had observed that the President might
probably find no better resource than the issue of letters of marque,
proceeds:--</p>
<p>"I said I would at once suggest a better measure. Mr. Seward had
said to Lord Lyons that the crews of privateers had this
advantage--that they reaped the whole benefit of the prizes they took,
whereas the crews of men-of-war were entitled to only half the value
of the prizes they took. Let the President, I said, offer a higher
reward for the capture of the Alabama and Oreto to the crews of
men-of-war than even the entire value of those vessels. Let him offer
double their value as a gratuity, and thus confine his action to
officers and men of the United States navy over whom he could keep a
control and who were amenable to the laws which govern an honourable
profession. But what could Mr. Adams ask of the British Government?
What was his proposal? Mr. Adams said there was one thing which might
be easily done. It was supposed the British Government were
indifferent to these notorious violations of their own laws. Let them
declare their condemnation of all such infractions of law. With
respect to the law itself, Mr. Adams said either it was sufficient for
the purposes of neutrality, and then, let the British Government
enforce it; or it was insufficient, and then let the British
Government apply to Parliament to amend it. I said that the Cabinet
were of opinion that the law was sufficient, but that legal evidence
could not always be procured. That the British Government had done
everything in its power to execute the law; but I admitted that the
cases of the Alabama and Oreto were a scandal, and, in some degree, a
reproach, to our laws. Still, I said, it was my belief that if all the
assistance given to the Federals by British subjects and British
munitions of war were weighed against similar aid given to the
Confederates, the balance would be greatly in favour of the
Federals. Mr. Adams totally denied this proposition. But, above all,
he said, there is a manifest conspiracy in this country--of which the
Confederate loan is an additional proof--to produce a state of
exasperation in America, and thus bring on a war with Great Britain
with a view to aid the Confederate cause and secure a monopoly of the
trade of the Southern States, whose independence these conspirators
hope to establish by those illegal and unjust measures. He had worked
to the best of his power for peace, but it had become a most difficult
task. Mr. Adams fully deserves the character of having always laboured
for peace between our two nations nor, I trust, will his efforts and
those of the two Governments fail of success."</p>
<p>In a letter to Mr. Adams, dated the 28th of October last, Earl
Russell says:--</p>
<p>"I have had the honour to receive your letter of the 28th inst. In
that letter you inform me that you are instructed to say that the
Government of the United States must continue to insist that Great
Britain has made itself responsible for the damages which the citizens
of the United States sustain by the depredations of the vessel called
the Alabama. But towards the conclusion of your letter you state that
the Government of the United States are not disposed to act
dogmatically or in a spirit of litigation; that they desire to
maintain amity as well as peace; that they fully comprehend how
unavoidably reciprocal grievances must spring up from the divergence
of the policy of the two countries in regard to the present
insurrection. You add further on, that the United States frankly
confess themselves unwilling to regard the present hour as the most
favourable to a calm and candid examination by either party of the
facts or the principles involved in cases like the one now in
question. With this declaration her Majesty's Government may well be
content to wait the time when a calm and candid examination of the
facts and principles involved in the case of the Alabama may, in the
opinion of the Government of the United States, usefully be
undertaken. In the mean time, I must request you to believe that the
principle contended for by Her Majesty's Government is not that of
commissioning, equipping, and manning vessels in our ports to cruise
against either of the belligerent parties, a principle which was so
justly and unequivocally condemned by the President of the United
States in 1793, as recorded by Mr. Jefferson in his letter to
Mr. Hammond on the 18th of May of that year. But the British
Government must decline to be responsible for the acts of parties who
fit out a seeming merchant-ship, send her to a port or to waters far
from the jurisdiction of British Courts, and there commission, equip,
and man her as a vessel of war. Her Majesty's Government fear that if
an admitted principle were thus made elastic to suit a particular
case, the trade of shipbuilding, in which our people excel, and which
is to great numbers of them a source of honest livelihood, would be
seriously embarassed and impeded. I may add that it appears strange
that, notwithstanding the large and powerful naval force possessed by
the Government of the United States, no efficient measures have been
taken by that Government to capture the Alabama. On our part, I must
declare that to perform the duties of neutrality fairly and
impartially, and at the same time to maintain the spirit of British
law and protect the lawful industry of the Queen's subjects, is the
object of her Majesty's Government; and they trust that the Government
of the United States will recognise their earnest desire to preserve,
in the difficult circumstances of the present time, the relations of
amity between the two nations."</p>
<p>On the 29th of the same month Lord Russell informed Mr. Adams that
the proceedings of the Alabama at the Cape had been under the
consideration of the Government, and the following conclusions had
been adopted by them:--</p>
<p>"1. That her Majesty's Government are satisfied by the concurrent
testimony of the colonial and naval authorities at the Cape that at
the time of capture the Sea Bride was considerably more than three
miles distant from the nearest land. 2. That as regards the character
of the Alabama, that vessel is entitled to be treated as a ship of war
belonging to a belligerent Power, and that neither the Governor nor
any other British authority at the Cape was entitled to exercise any
jurisdiction over her. 3. That as regards the Tuscaloosa, although her
Majesty's Government would have approved the British authorities at
the Cape if they had adopted towards that vessel a course different
from that which was adopted, yet the question as to the manner in
which a vessal under such circumstances should, according to the
tenour of her Majesty's orders, be dealt with, was one not altogether
free from uncertainty. Nevertheless, instructions will be sent to the
British authorities at the Cape for their guidance in the event of a
similar case occurring hereafter, and her Majesty's Government hope
that under those instructions nothing will for the future happen to
admit of a question being raised as to her Majesty's orders having
been strictly carried out."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1244.003" n= "We consider ourselves fortunate" type="Article">
<head>[WE CONSIDER OURSELVES FORTUNATE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1244</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 146</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-13">February 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps"><hi rend="italic">London:
Saturday, February</hi> 13, 1864.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">We</hi> consider ourselves fortunate in being
but rarely compelled to address the public upon matters affecting the
interests of this Journal, or in defence of any portion of its
conduct; but some expressions which were used by Mr. Layard in the
debate on Tuesday night, upon the subject of the burning of Kagosima,
demand a few words from the conductors of the <hi
rend="smallcaps">Illustrated London News</hi>. In Mr. Buxton's speech
in support of his resolution condemnatory of the destruction of
Kagosima, the honourable member for Maidstone read an extract from an
article accompanying a Sketch of the bombardment of that city
transmitted to us by our Special Artist in Japan. The object of the
reference and of the quotation was to show the great amount of ruin
that had been effected by the British squadron. In his reply, on
behalf of the Government, the Under-Secretary of State for Foreign
Affairs "did not wish to say anything against that admirable and
useful publication the <hi rend="smallcaps">Illustrated London
News</hi>; but those who were in the secret knew how drawings were
made of places at the other end of the world, and he doubted whether
any person connected with the News was at Kagosima when the engagement
took place. It was not impossible, indeed, that a picture of a town in
South America had been furbished up to represent a town in Japan."</p>
<p>Whatever pictorial value may attach to the Engravings of distant
scenery and events which appear in this Journal, their greatest value
is, undoubtedly, in their genuineness and authenticity. To secure
these qualities, the Conductors spare no cost or exertion; and
incessant tributes from all parts of the world to the fidelity of the
representations which we offer give us the amplest assurance that we
are well served by the gentlemen who undertake the troublesome, and
often dangerous, mission of sketching for us. Remarks, therefore, like
those which escaped Mr. Layard in the heat of a debate, would scarcely
have required notice from us had they proceeded from a less
distinguished man than the accomplished Under-Secretary of State for
Foreign Affairs. We felt it due to him, no less than to ourselves, to
convince him that the evidence brought forward by Mr. Buxton from our
pages was of the highest order, and we had the satisfaction of showing
Mr. Layard, not only the original sketch, transmitted by Mr. Charles
Wirgman, our Artist in Japan, but some evidence in unintended but
complete corroboration of the accuracy of Mr. Wirgman's
drawing. Mr. Layard's frankness and courtesy are proverbial, and we
have no reason to doubt that he will be glad, upon fitting occasion,
to do us the justice which we were denied amid the excitement of an
energetic debate. We also thought it our duty to place the sketches
and papers in the hands of the honourable member for Maidstone, that
he might be satisfied of the truthfulness of the extract he had quoted
from this journal.</p>
<p>Whilst adverting to the subject, it seems scarcely out of place to
mention, lest any similar misconception should arise in regard to
other Engravings which are just now sought after with the utmost
interest, that in Schleswig-Holstein Mr. Landells is present on the
scene of the strife there raging, entirely engaged with his pencil and
pen in our service; and that Mr. F. Vizetelly is in Richmond, as we
learned not an hour ago from one of high authority just returned to
England from the Southern States vi&#x00E2; the "underground."
Sketches from the latter gentleman have to make their way through the
blockade, and such as escape the hands of the Federals appear at once
in this Paper. To this system of procuring, under great risks and at
almost any cost, faithful representations of the scenes we propose to
depict, is due the greater part of the favour by which the <hi
rend="smallcaps">Illustrated London News</hi> is received by the
public.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1244.004" n= "Imperial Parliament." type="Article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1244</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 150</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-13">February 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">(<hi rend="italic">Continued from page</hi> 159).</p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF LORDS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Thursday.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The Confederate Rams At Liverpool.</hi>--Earl
<hi rend="smallcaps">Derby</hi> again asked the noble Earl (Earl
Russell) a question that he had asked on Tuesday with reference to the
Confederate rams now lying in the Mersey. The noble Earl had stated
that he could not lay any papers upon the table of the House in
reference to the rams, as the question had been taken into the courts
of law. He understood that the rams had been seized in September last,
and that from that time until this no step has been taken to bring the
cause to an issue, except that on Saturday last the information was
filed. This the noble Earl humbly conceived might have been done in
the month of October or November. The question was whether the
Government were prepared to lay upon the table the correspondence
which had taken place upon the remonstrance made with respect to
injuries sustained by American commerce in consequence of certain
vessels having sailed from British ports. He wished for this
correspondence as well as that relating to the Alabama, and any
correspondence containing representations on the part of her Majesty's
Government against the apparent violation of the law by American
cruisers in enforcing their rights. He also asked whether the noble
Earl would lay before the House any correspondence that might have
taken place on the report of some very curious decisions which had
been come to in the prize courts of the United States. Under the
circumstances the noble Earl could not see that the publication of
these despatches would in any way clash with the cases now before the
courts of law. The correspondence had been published in America; the
noble Earl wished to have the English version of that
correspondence. What course the Government had taken in vindication of
international law in respect to the differences that had arisen
between this country and America was a question that Parliament was
bound to consider. He urged the noble Earl (Earl Russell) to
reconsider his reply of Tuesday, and lay this correspondence before
their Lordships.--Earl <hi rend="smallcaps">Russell</hi> said that
when the attention of her Majesty's Government was first brought to
these vessels the answer they received to inquiries that they made was
that they were intended for the French; but the French Minister for
Foreign Affairs denied this. The ships were evidently intended for
warlike purposes, and Mr. Adams was told that her Majesty's Government
was looking out for evidence as to the persons for whom the vessels
were really destined. Another story afterwards became current that the
vessels were intended for the Viceroy of Egypt. This was also found to
be without foundation. With regard to the general question, the noble
Earl thought that Mr. Adams was not far wrong in saying that vessels
were fitted out here to be used for warlike purposes against a State
that was at peace with her Majesty. This was undoubtedly a gross
insult to her Majesty. But the law officers of the Crown, who have
been consulted on the question, consider that her Majesty's Government
must suffer from having their case only partially stated, so they
would suffer, from having the case in the courts of law forestalled;
therefore their request was that the Government should not produce
those papers. The noble Earl felt he should be doing an injustice to
the law officers of the Crown and thwarting the fair hearing of the
case if he produced the correspondence. With respect to the question
of the conduct of the prize courts of America, the noble Earl was far
from thinking that they had in every case done England justice. The
noble Earl concluded by saying that he would look over the papers and
see what he could produce without detriment to the public service, and
should the noble Earl require any particular document, he would either
produce it or give valid reasons for withholding it.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1244.005" n= "The Confederate cruiser Florida" type="Article">
<head>[THE CONFEDERATE CRUISER FLORIDA]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1244</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 150</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-13">February 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>The Confederate cruiser Florida, under the command of Captain
Maffitt, left Brest on Tuesday night, in the midst of a dense fog, on
a cruise. The United States' war-steamer Kearsage, on being apprised
of the Florida's sailing, stood out to sea the same night.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1244.006" n= "Imperial Parliament." type="Article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1244</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 159</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-13">February 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF LORDS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Tuesday.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The Alabama.</hi>--In answer to a question
from Lord Derby, Earl <hi rend="smallcaps">russell</hi> stated he had
ascertained that Mr. Seward had written to Mr. Adams the despatch
referring to the demand of indemnification for the losses sustained by
the commerce of the North from the captures made by the
Alabama. Mr. Adams had received that despatch, but had not
communicated it.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1244.007" n= "A new steam-whistle" type="Article">
<head>[A NEW STEAM-WHISTLE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1244</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 171</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-13">February 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A new steam-whistle (to arouse the workmen), six feet high and
fifteen inches in diameter, has been erected on Colt's revolver
factory, in Hartford, Connecticut.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1244.008" n= "Telegraphic facilities" type="Article">
<head>[TELEGRAPHIC FACILITIES]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1244</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 171</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-13">February 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Telegraphic facilities are rapidly increasing along the Pacific
slope. A line is now being constructed frcm San Francisco to Portland,
Oregon. Workmen are now at work extending the wires from Sacremento
along the line of the Pacific Railroad, across the Sierra Nevada,
making it, when completed, the third line belonging to this company
crossing those mountains. Men are also at work in Carson Valley
extending the line westward from this side to meet it.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1245.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1245</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 175</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-20">February 20, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>The Confederates appear to have made a general aggressive
movement.  General Longstreet has, it is stated, driven the Federals
into Knoxville and got possession of the French Bread River, whence
large supplies of forage can be drawn. In North Carolina they had
driven in the Federal outposts, and in Western Virginia had captured
some Federal detachments and stores; but, on pressing their
advantages, they were repulsed in both instances.</p>
<p>The Federals have recommenced shelling Fort Sumter, having
discovered that the Confederates had remounted five guns on the
fort.</p>
<p>There was a renewed report of General Meade being superseded by
General Thomas.</p>
<p>Another land and naval expedition was being fitted out at New
Orleans; its destination was not known, but was supposed to be
Mobile.</p>
<p>The Southern army is said to be in the best spirits, and the
soldiers were re-enlisting by brigades and regiments. General Lee
issued an order on the 22nd ult. stating that the temporary reduction
of rations was caused by circumstances beyond the control of those
charged with the support of the army; but it was hoped this would be
of short duration. The army has proved that the country could require
no sacrifice too great for its patriotism.</p>
<p>President Lincoln has ordered a forced levy of 500,000 men. The
levy is to be made on the 10th of March next, and all volunteers who
may be raised before that date will be deducted from it. The 300,000
men summoned in October last are to be included in the 500,000
required by the present call, which is therefore an order for an
additional levy of 200,000 men.</p>
<p>A bill has been reported in the House of Representatives
appropriating 529,000,000 dols. for the army expenses in the year
ending June, 1865.</p>
<p>The New York Legislature has resolved to add 2,000 000 dols. to
the recruiting fund, and to increase the State bounty to 300 dols.</p>
<p>A New York letter states that since the outbreak of the civil war
President Lincoln has called out about 2,000,000 men for service in
the Federal army, and 500,000 for service in the Federal navy.</p>
<p>Quite an excitement exists in relation to the next
presidency. Mr. Lincoln has been nominated by the several State
Legislatures and conventions, and it is believed that he will get the
regular Republican nomination, although Mr. Chase's friends are
advancing his claims with great energy. It is also said that Fremont
will be a candidate. The nomination of General Grant has been strongly
advocated by the <hi rend="italic">New York Herald</hi> and several
other papers; but M'Clellan, thus far, seems to be the probable
candidate of the Democratic party.</p>
<p>Colonel Colt's pistol factory at Hartford, Connecticut, has been
destroyed by fire: 1700 workmen were thrown out of employment, and the
loss was computed at over 2,000,000 dollars. The new buildings in
which mini&#x00E9; rifles are made were saved.</p>
<p>The Cabinet of Washington has ordered a Court of Inquiry to
investigate the circumstances under which an officer of the Federal
steamer Vanderbilt shot Mr. Gray, the mate of the British barque
Saxon, which was captured by the Vanderbilt at Angra Pequena, and
which is alleged to have been taken in British waters. According to
the published accounts of the occurrence and the statements of the
English crew, an unprovoked murder was committed by Doniphan, the
Federal officer; but the <hi rend="italic">Boston Advertiser</hi>
states that Doniphan declares the fatal shot was fired accidentally by
him.</p>
<p>The Judge of the Admiralty Court at Halifax has decided to restore
the Chesapeake and cargo to the owners, subject to conditions
respecting the payment of such expenses as the Attorney-General may
exact. The Attorney-General demands a surety against latent claims,
but the owners of the Chesapeake demur to this.</p>
<p>The hearing of the case of the men implicated in the seizure of
the Chesapeake was still going on at St. John, New
Brunswick. Testimony was given to the effect that ten of the men who
seized the ship were commissioned Confederate officers.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1245.002" n= "A Telegram from Bombay" type="Article">
<head>[A TELEGRAM FROM BOMBAY]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1245</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 179</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-20">February 20, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A telegram from Bombay states that the Alabama was off the west
coast of India, and that she had burnt the ship Emma, of New
York.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1245.003" n= "The Prince of Wales has sent to the laboratory" type="Article">
<head>[THE PRINCE OF WALES HAS SENT TO THE LABORATORY]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1245</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 182</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-20">February 20, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The Prince of Wales has sent to the laboratory at Cambridge
University, Massachusetts, a copy of the photographs of the Samaritan
Pentateuch taken during the visit of his Royal Highness to
Nablous. In presenting this gift the private secretary of his Royal
Highness writes:--"The Prince of Wales desires me to add that he will
always be glad of any opportunity which may enable him to evince, in
however slight a manner, the lively sense which he entertains of the
kindness and hospitality he received during his visit to the United
States; and that, with these recollections, he cannot fail cordially
to reciprocate the wish to which you have given expression, that
nothing may occur to interrupt the friendship which ought ever to
subsist between the old country and the new."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1245.003" n= "Imperial Parliament." type="Article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1245</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 182</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-20">February 20, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF LORDS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Monday.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The British and United States
Governments.</hi>--Earl <hi rend="smallcaps">Russell</hi>, adverting
to some observations made by the Earl of Derby in a former
discussion, read extracts from the correspondence with Mr. Adams;
and, by a comparison of dates, proved that the decision of the
Government as to detaining the iron-clad rams could not have been
influenced by any representations of Mr. Adams. He thought that the
Earl of Derby ought to have quoted the correspondence more
completely.--The Earl of <hi rend="smallcaps">Derby</hi> denied that
he had suppressed anything. He had seen the volume of correspondence
laid before Congress, and therefore knew it was in this country, but
he had not read it. The passages he quoted were taken from a
newspaper.--Earl <hi rend="smallcaps">Russell</hi>, having heard the
noble Lord refer to the official publication laid before Congress,
had concluded too hastily he had read the volume.</p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF LORDS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Tuesday.</hi></p>
<p>The Lord Chancellor laid on the table a return showing the working
of the Augmentation of Benefices Act, under which it appeared that
sixty-seven livings had been sold, thirty-seven of which fetched
&#x00A3;65,300, and negotiations were in progress for the sale of
fifty-three more.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">British And American Claims.</hi>--The Earl of
<hi rend="smallcaps">Carnarvon</hi> moved for a return of claims made
by British subjects upon the United States' Government, sustained
either in person or property since the secession of the Southern
States, specifying how and the grounds on which such claims have been
disposed of; and to ask for any further information as to claims made
by the United States' Government upon her Majesty's Government for
damages alleged to be done to American ships by the Alabama and other
Confederate cruisers. He pointed out that many vessels engaged in
legitimate trade had unwarrantably been seized, and he alluded to the
case of the Saxon, and that of the Tuscaloosa, which had been seized
at the Cape, a matter which required explanation. He stated that the
claims of British subjects for compensation for illegal seizure of
vessels amounted to no less than two millions.--Earl <hi
rend="smallcaps">Russell</hi> said that personally, he had no
objection to the granting of the return; but it would be<pb n="183"/>
very voluminous, and its publication would tend to prejudice the
claims to which it would refer. He justified the proceedings of the
American prize courts, while as regarded the Saxon ample apology had
been made by the Captain of the American cruiser for what had
occurred; and as to the murder of the mate, all that could be asked
was that the offender be put on his trial. The Tuscaloosa was seized
under the advice of the law of officers of the Crown. He repudiated
now, as he had always done, any claims arising out of the depredations
of the Alabama.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1246.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1246</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 199</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-27">February 27, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>We have news from New York to the 13th ult. Of war movements we
learn, among other matters, that General Meade made a reconnaisance on
the 5th, on the south side of the Rapidan, where he found Lee in
force, and, after a brief engagement, retired; that 4000 Confederates
made a demonstration against Cumberland Gap on the 29th ult., but,
after heavy skirmishing, were driven back; that General Sherman's
whole force has crossed the Black River, with a view to a junction
with a cavalry and infantry force--it is supposed to flank Johnston
and Hardee in Alabama and Georgia; that Admiral Porter is fitting out
a formidable fleet on the Mississippi; and that, the siege of
Chmieston having proved a failure, General Gilmore and Admiral
Dahlgren had dispatched a land and naval expedition to Florida, and,
having made a landing at Jacksonville, the expedition was supposed to
be advancing on Tallahassee.</p>
<p>On the night of the 2nd a large steamer entered Charleston Harbour,
unobserved by the Federal fleet, and was not discovered until the
morning of the 3rd, when she had run aground and was landing her cargo
under the guns of Fort Moultrie. The Federal batteries opened on her,
and shortly afterwards she sank.</p>
<p>The British gun-boat Petrel arrived at Charleston on the 5th,
wishing to caniniunicate with the British Consul at Savannah. Admiral
Dahlgren refused permission, and the Petrel put to sea.</p>
<p>A considerable force, sent by General Butler towards Richmond for
the purpose of surprising the Confederates and releasing the Federal
prisoners, was discovered when within twelve miles of the city, and
obliged to return. The <hi rend="italic">Richmond Examiner</hi>
mentions the arrest of a German as the ringleader of a plot for the
release of the prisoners and the assassination of Jefferson Davis.</p>
<p>General Meade made a speech at Philadelphia, stating that since
March, 1861, 100,000 men of the Potomac army have been killed and
wounded.</p>
<p>The Conscription Bill has passed Congress. Slaves between the ages
of fourteen and forty-five are liable to be draughted, loyal owners to
be compensated.</p>
<p>The Judiciary Committee in Congress has reported adversely to
Mr. Sumner's amendment to the Constitution, abolishing slavery, but
reported favourably on the resolution declaring that Congress shall
have power to legislate that slavery shall not exist within the United
States.</p>
<p>The German Republicans of New Jersey declare in favour of Butler,
Fremont, or any other Radical candidate for the presidency who will
guarantee an emancipation and confiscation policy.</p>
<p>An express-train has been captured eight miles from Harper's
Ferry, and the passengers have been robbed. It is not known whether
the attack was made by the Confederates or by gangs of Federal
deserters.</p>
<p>The Halifax Admiralty Court has restored the Chesapeake and her
cargo to the owners on the payment of legal expenses.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1246.002" n= "The Times of India says" type="Article">
<head>[THE TIMES OF INDIA SAYS]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1246</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 202</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-27">February 27, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">Times of India</hi> says, in its impression
of Jan. 29:--"The Confederate privateer Alabama is on our coast. She
captured and burnt the American ship Emma Jane off Trevandrum on the
14th inst., and landed the captain and crew at Anjengo on the 17th
inst. The Emma Jane sailed from Bombay on the 5th inst., bound to
Amherst. The Alabama is now reported to be cruising off Bombay
harbour, lying in wait for the American ice-ship now due, and for
several American ships in this port under charter to sea within a few
days. It is expected that she may come into port for the purpose of
coaling."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1246.003" n= "Imperial Parliament." type="Article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1246</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 206</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-27">February 27, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF COMMONS.--<hi rend="smallcaps">Friday,
Fed. 19.</hi></p>
<p>Mr. Haliburton asked whether the Government had heard of the
capture of a veecel bearing the Confederate flag by a Federal cruiser
in the harbour of Pankbar, Nova Scotia, and under the guns of the
fort; and whether her Majesty's Government had entered into a
correspondence with the United States on the subject of this
outrage.--Mr. Layard said the subject was still under inquiry, and
therefore he could not give any definite reply to the question. He
might say, however, that the facts had been brought under the notice
of the American Government, and Mr. Seward had made an ample
apology.</p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF LORDS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Monday.</hi></p>
<p>Earl De Grey and Ripon, in answer to Lord Stratheden, stated that
it was not intended to send military commissioners to report on the
operations of the Federal or Confederate armies; but an engineer, an
artillery and a naval officer, had been sent to report on improvements
in artillery and iron-clad ships in the Federal States, but not to the
Confederate States.</p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF COMMONS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Tuesday.</hi></p>
<p>Mr. Layard, in reply to Sir R. Clifton, said the Government had
given its consent to the removal from Richmond of tobacco purchased by
France and Austria, provided such a course was not taken as a
precedent. Cotton was in another category. It belonged to private
individuals, while the tobacco was the property of the two Governments
he had named.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">The Steam-Rams In The
Mersey.</hi></p>
<p>Mr. S. <hi rend="smallcaps">Fitzgerald</hi> moved for papers
relating to the seizure of the steam rams at Liverpool. He did not
want those relating to the judicial proceedings as to the rams, but
only those before the seizure. Reviewing the documents which had been
laid before Congress on the subject, he said it seemed to him that the
Government had no good grounds for the seizure; and he asked for the
papers in order that the House might see whether the law had or had
not been overstepped by the Executive.</p>
<p>The <hi rend="smallcaps">Attorney-General</hi> said the papers
asked for were only a fragmentary part of the case, and would not give
to the House the means of forming a correct opinion on the subject. He
vindicated the conduct of the Government, and said they had made
inquiries which proved that the vessels were not, as had been
represented, for Egypt or France. That they were intended for the
Confederates was shown by a paragraph which he quoted from the report
of the Secretary of the Confederate Navy. The trial as to the vessels
would take place in May next. The Government had only vindicated the
law, and done what they would expect other countries under similar
circumstances to do.</p>
<p>Mr. <hi rend="smallcaps">Horsfall</hi> declared the proceedings of
the Government in the case of the Alexandra, and against
Messrs. Laird, to be cruelly unjust, and a profligate expenditure of
public money.</p>
<p>Lord <hi rend="smallcaps">R. Cecil</hi> also attacked the
Government for its conduct in the matter.</p>
<p>Mr. <hi rend="smallcaps">W. E. Forster</hi> supported them, and
argued that English interests were sustained by the course which had
been pursued in the seizure of the vessels.</p>
<p>Sir <hi rend="smallcaps">H. Cairns</hi> at great length criticised
the proceedings in respect to the steam-rams, and strongly condemned
them.</p>
<p>The <hi rend="smallcaps">Solicitor-General</hi> replied to him;
and, after some observations from Mr. Walpole and Mr. T. Baring, the
House divided, and rejected Mr. Fitzgerald's motion by 178 votes to
153.</p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF LORDS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Thursday.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The Steam-Rams In The Mersey.</hi>--The Earl
of <hi rend="smallcaps">Derby</hi> again referred to the question he
had asked Earl Russell on two occasions before--whether her Majesty's
Government would give to Parliament copies of the correspondence that
had taken place with reference to the detention of the rams in the
Mersey? In doing so the noble Earl referred to the reply he last
received and to the discussion that had taken place upon the question
in the House of Commons.--Earl <hi rend="smallcaps">Russell</hi> said
the noble Earl had somewhat misrepresented his reply. The answer he
had given was, that the law officers of the Crown considered the
production of these papers would result in an incomplete discussion of
the legal point at issue in the Houses of Parliament, and so prejudice
the result of the cause now being discussed in the courts of law. With
regard to the other papers for which the noble Earl asked, he had
replied that he would look over the correspondence that had taken
place, and produce any further papers to the production of which there
could be no objection. The noble Earl then laid such papers upon the
table.--After some further discussion, which was joined in by Earl
Russell, the Earl of Derby, Lord Granvllle, Lord Chelmsford, and the
Earl of Carnarvon, the subject dropped.</p><pb n="207"/>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF COMMONS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Thursday.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The Tuscaloosa.</hi>--Lord <hi
rend="smallcaps">Palmerston</hi>, in reply to Mr. Peacocke, said the
Tuscaloosa had been seized by orders sent out to the Cape. The
Government, however, had ascertained that there was no sufficient
reason for the seizure, and had ordered her release.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1246.004" n= "The New York Herald states" type="Article">
<head>[THE NEW YORK HERALD STATES]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1246</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 218</biblScope>
<date value="1864-02-27">February 27, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">New Yord Herald</hi> states that the
estimated cost of the ship canal around Niagara Falls is five millions
and a half. It is proposed to build it from the Head Water to
Lewiston, with locks 300 ft. long, 50 ft, wide, and 10 ft. deep. In
addition to this, three millions and a half will be asked for the
enlargement of the Oswego and Erie canals, and four millions for a
canal from the St. Lawrence over to Albany, vi&#x00E2; Lake Champlain;
and thirteen millions for an enlargement of the Illinois Canal, from
Keokuk to Chicago, so that vessels of 600 tons burden can
pass.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1247.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1247</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 223</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-05">March 5, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>News from New York extends to the 19th ult. General Meade left
Washington on the 15th to resume the permanent command of the army of
the Potomac. The Federal General Sherman occupied Jackson,
Mississippi, on the 5th ult., and had advanced to Brandon. A portion
of his troops occupied Yazoo city on the same day. General Thomas is
reported to have moved towards Dalton. These advances are considered
to be the opening of the spring campaign in the southwest, which
appears likely to comprehend a combined movement against Mobile,
Savannah, and the Confederate armies and strongholds in Georgia. Naval
and military expeditions now preparing at New Orleans are to
co-operate. It is anticipated that the Confederates willopen the
spring campaign by a formidable raid into Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>President Davis has issued an address to the army thanking the
troops for their alacrity. He says that "the spring campaign opens
under auspices well calculated to sustain their hopes. Assured success
awaits their struggle for liberty and independence."</p>
<p>President Davis has signed a bill prohibiting the exportation of
tobacco, rice, sugar, and molasses, except by special permit; also a
bill prohibiting the importation of luxuries after March next, and
fixing the maximum price at which articles of silk, wool, flax, and
cotton may be imported.</p>
<p>A despatch received at Washington from General Butler announces
that Colonel Straight and about 100 Federal prisoners escaped from
Richmond by tunnelling under the walls of the gaol. The Colonel and
twenty other officers had arrived at Williamsburg. Butler had sent out
cavalry as far as the Chickahominy to assist the flight of the escaped
prisoners. Twenty-two officers had been recaptured by the Confederates
and more were expected to be brought in. The guards of the prisoners
were placed under arrest, charged with aiding the prisoners to
escape.</p>
<p>General Banks had issued orders restoring compulsory labour in
Louisiana under certain conditions, and declaring that it was the duty
of the people to re-establish the civil Government, and that
"indifference would be treated as a crime."</p>
<p>The Supreme Court has decided against Mr. Vallandigham's
application to annul the sentence passed upon him by the military
court.</p>
<p>The House of Representatives, by a majority of twenty-one, have
passed a resolution in favour of an amendment to the Constitution
abolishing slavery.</p>
<p>Details are given of a wholesale destruction of
blockade-runners. The Wild Dayrell was run ashore near Stump Inlet,
and was completely destroyed by her captors. The estimated value of
ship and cargo was 200,000 dols. The steamer Nutfield, an iron
paddle-steamer, whioh sailed from London in December last, and was
bound from Bermuda to Wilmington, was run ashore to escape pursuit
near New River Inlet. She also was fired and destroyed. Her cargo
consisted of arms and ammunition, including a battery of eight
Whitworth guns. Some of her crew were drowned in endeavouring to reach
the shore in a boat. The steamer Dee, a new double-screw iron steamer,
recently from London, was run ashore and burnt off Masonboro'. She was
loaded with lead, coffee, and bacon. Seven of her crew were taken
prisoners. The side-wheel steamer Fanny and Jennie was run ashore and
destroyed in close proximity to the Dee. Twenty-five of her crew were
taken prisoners. The capture of the Emily, a new steamer, from
London, and of the steamer Cumberland are also reported. The latter
was taken while on the passage from Havannah to Mobile, and was laden
with arms and ammunition.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1247.002" n= "Imperial Parliament." type="Article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1247</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 230</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-05">March 5, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF COMMONS.--<hi rend="smallcaps">Friday,
Feb. 26.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The Slave Trade.</hi>--Mr. <hi
rend="smallcaps">Cave</hi> asked the First Lord of the Treasury
whether her Majesty's Government intended to carry into execution the
provisions of the treaty with the United States for the suppression of
the slave trede by stationing cruisers off the coast of Cuba.--Lord
<hi rend="smallcaps">Palmerston</hi> said that no doubt the provisions
of the document alluded to had been colourably evaded so far as
related to the French interest in the matter, but really he thought it
was without design in that quarter. Great progress had been made in
the suppression of the traffic, and it might be depended upon that no
inactivity would be exhibited therein.</p>

<p rend="center">HOUSE OF LORDS.--<hi rend="smallcaps">Tuesday.</hi></p>/
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">Alleged Federal Recruiting In
Ireland.</hi></p>
<p>The Marquis of <hi rend="smallcaps">Clanricarde</hi>, in moving for
copies of any papers that might have been received by the Government
relative to recruiting in Ireland for the army of the Federal States,
inquired whether any remonstrance against such a proceeding had been
addressed to the authorities at Washington. It was, he said, notorious
that American agents had been enlisting recruits in the sister island,
and, as it was in violation of the principle of neutrality and a
breach of international law, he urged that it was the duty of the
Government to put a stop to it.</p>
<p>Earl <hi rend="smallcaps">Russell</hi> said he had no doubt that
any attempt on the part of the Federals to enlist recruits for their
army in Ireland would be a breach of the principle of neutrality, and
that it was an offence against our own municipal laws, which, if
detected, would subject the offender to punishment, and justify strong
complaints to the Government of the United States. On more than one
occasion he had already complained that such practices as the noble
Marqusi had adverted to were going on on behalf of the Federal
Government in Ireland, and he had opened a correspondence with
Mr. Adams on the subject. That gentleman had, however, indignantly
denied the truth of such allegations; and, having received that
denial, he (Earl Russell) felt obliged to wait until some case had
occurred in which proof was forthcoming.</p>
<p>The Earl of <hi rend="smallcaps">Donoughmore</hi> observed that the
conduct of the Foreign Office in the particular case which had been
made the subject of inquiry contrasted most unfavourably with the
course they had adopted in reference to the steam rams.</p>
<p>The Earl of <hi rend="smallcaps">Derby</hi> inquired whether the
Government had received any information from the authorities at Cork
and Dublin to the effect that persons were in the habit of assembling
in these places for the purpose of going through military drill and
exercise, and, if so, whether they had taken any measures to put down
such illegal proceedings.</p>
<p>Earl <hi rend="smallcaps">Granville</hi> replied that the Dublin
authorities had directed the attention of the police to the
proceediegs of the Fenian Brotherhood, and there was reason to believe
that it was a perfectly contemptible organisation.</p>
<p>The motion for papers was then withdrawn.</p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF COMMONS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Thursday.</hi></p>
<p>Mr. Long gave notice that on Monday he would ask Lord Palmerston
whether the ships of war of the Confederate States were allowed the
same rights end privileges of searching and seizing contraband of war
on the high seas, &#x0026;c.; and, if not, whether he thought it was
extending to them the same principle of impartiality as was shown to
the Federal States.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1247.003" n= "A Post Office notice" type="Article">
<head>[A POST OFFICE NOTICE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1247</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 231</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-05">March 5, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A Post Office notice states that there will be no dispatch of
American mails this week vi&#x00E2; Galway, as the company have again
failed to provide a steamer. The <hi rend="italic">Galway Gazette</hi>
says:--"The directors of the Atlantic Company have applied to the Post
Office authorities for permission to discontinue the mail service
between Galway and America until June next. They have also intimated
their intention of entering into negotiations with another company for
the use of steamers to commence the service at that time, as the ships
of the company will not be in readiness to sail even then. The
directors are reported to be of opinion that they can never carry out
the contract with the ships at present in their possession, and will,
in all probability, endeavour to effect a sale of their interest in
the project, with a transfer of the mail subsidy to some existing
company more capable of carrying out the project. Two or three
companies are said to be in negotiation with the Atlantic Company on
the subject at present."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1247.004" n= "Current Literature." type="Article">
<head>CURRENT LITERATURE.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1247</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 239</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-05">March 5, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">CURRENT LITERATURE.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Soundings from the Atlantic.</hi> By
O. W. Holmes. (1 vol. Sampson Low, Son, and Marston.) The "Autocrat of
the Breakfast Table" needs introduction to (we should hope) very few
English readers; and a fresh volume from his pen will, no doubt, find
a cordial welcome. The nine essays and one oration now offered in a
compact form for public perusal combine, after the author's fashion,
fun and serious reflections, and are written in a style which makes
them more than commonly readable. The awful war now raging amongst our
Transatlantic kinsmen naturally forms one of the topics which
Mr. Holmes undertakes to handle; and in the oration appended to his
other compositions, with the title of "The Inevitable Trial," he
discusses at some length the origin, the progress, and the probable
result of the great struggle. This is not the place to follow him step
by step, but it is compatible with our province to announce that he
does not despair of the Republic.</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Dan to Beersheba.</hi> (1 vol. Chapman and Hall.)
A supplementary or, more correctly speaking, an explanatory title is
given to this singular book--the alias is "Northern and Southern
Friends." We began to read with an impression that the American civil
war would furnish the groundwork of the story; but it was not so. Nor
is there any satisfactory explanation given of the scriptural title;
so that, as we failed to find either Dan or Beersheba upon the only
map of America we happen to possess, we were constrained to guess from
the hints furnished by the narrative that Dan is, being interpreted,
Boston, and Beersheba, Charleston; for Northern friends from the
capital of Massachusetts go upon a visit to Southern friends in the
capital of the Palmetto State, and there are no other fixed points
which the most elastic imagination could comfortably fasten upon as
corresponding in position with Dan and Beersheba. The writer's object,
we apprehend, is to sketch the habits and manners of both Northern and
Southern Americans; and the conclusion we arrived at from the
specimens given was that both are almost equally objectionable. There
is no attempt at plot. Flirtations, and arguments, and dances, and
revels, and slave crimes, and slave-hunts and their attendant horrors
(including anti-slavery meetings and speeches, and pro-slavery
brutality) follow one another with true American independence; and the
ultimate bliss even of the hero and heroine (to strain the
time-honoured terms) is left to mere conjecture. On the whole, the
writer, though distributing ugly features with tolerable impartiality,
seems to incline just a little to the Northern side, for which the
tendency of Southern ladies (according to the author's representation)
to treat lovers slightingly and to sing improper songs, and of
Southern gentlemen to propose to ladies under extraordinary
circumstances and in Bedlamite language, is sufficient to account.</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">My Days and Nights on the Battle-field.</hi> By
Carleton. (1 vol. Sampson Low, Son, and Marston.) This is a little
work, intended chiefly for boys, giving some account (accompanied by
diagrams) of several of the more important engagements between
Federals and Confederates in the earlier part of the present war. A
sketch of later battles is conditionally promised. The style is
somewhat bombastic and the spirit is intensely Union.</p></div2>


<div2 id="iln44.1247.005" n= "Captain Cutting" type="Article">
<head>[CAPTAIN CUTTING]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1247</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 242</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-05">March 5, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Captain Cutting, of the American ship Adelaide, has been presented
by the Board of Trade with a valuable binocular telescope for saving
the captain and crew of the ship Polynesia, of Liverpool, in December
last. When Captain Cutting sighted the ship she was waterlogged, and
the crew were reduced to the last extremity, having nothing but a few
biscuits to eat and a little rain water to drink.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1248.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1248</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 246</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-12">March 12, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>We have news from New York to Feb. 24. It consists mainly of
conflicting rumours. First, we are informed that Sherman had reached
Quitman, on the Mobile and Ohio Railroad, with a force estimated at
between 25,000 and 30,000 men; that he had defeated Polk, near
Brandon, and captured 12,000 prisoners; and that Admiral Farragut was
preparing to attack the Confederates at Grant's Pass. A different
statement, however, is made in the Richmond papers. Those papers
assert that the Federals have been repulsed with great loss at Grant's
Pass, and that the Federal force at Quitman consisted of about 1000
men employed in tearing up the railroad. Nothing is said, however,
about the alleged defeat of Polk. General Longstreet was rumoured to
have retired from the neighbourhood of Knoxville, and to have
retreated beyond the French Broad River. General Gilmore had returned
from Florida to Port Royal, and reported that his expedition had been
successful. The Confederates have been twice repulsed in an attack
upon the Federals opposite Natchez, Mississippi. General Meade will
retain the command of the army of the Potomac during the next
campaign.</p>
<p>The Committee of Ways and Means reported back the bill authorising
the Secretary of the Treasury to sell the surplus gold, with a
recommendation that it be not passed, and that no further action be
taken.</p>
<p>The National Executive Committee had nominated Mr. Chase for the
presidency, while the Maryland State Union Convention had named
Mr. Lincoln.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1248.002" n= "Imperial Parliament." type="Article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1248</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 254</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-12">March 12, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF COMMONS.--<hi rend="smallcaps">Friday,
</hi>March 4.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Confederate War Vessels In British
Ports.</hi>--Mr. <hi rend="smallcaps">J. G. Shaw Lefevre</hi> called
attention to the course pursued by the agents of the Confederate
States of America in fitting out vessels of war and enlisting seaman
in the ports of this country in violation of the laws of
neutrality.--The <hi rend="smallcaps">Solicitor-General</hi> said the
Government was first of all blamed for siding with the North, and now
they were charged with partiality towards the South. He thought he had
better let those two accusations answer each other. The hon. and
learned gentleman then proceeded to defend the Government, and to show
that they had done all in their power to act with impartiality and to
maintain a strict neutrality.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1248.003" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1248</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 262</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-12">March 12, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....The Fenians, who have given rise to one or two Thackerayian
imitations of Irish ballads, have called forth "Mister Smith O'Brine,
who once raged like a line (lion)" on the "Shannon shore," but who now
tends the soundest advice in the most cogent of reasoning to his
Fenian or Finian friends. "Don't," says he in effect, "don't, my
friends, enlist, for the Northern States; it is a roundabout way to
free Ireland by getting kilt in America. The Federals only use you,
and crush you, and put you to the fore to be slain." Much more to this
tune, says O'Brien the King; and he calculates that upwards of 200,000
Irish have been cruelly "used up" on American soil. That this advice
will affect Yankee recruiting, we have no doubt; that like words have
done so is apparent from the fact that the recruiting-sergeants have
been shipping loads of Germans from Liverpool to fill the jaws of the
Yankee war. Is it not a pity that the German and the Celt did not
study Emerson, who so candidly explains that the coarse bodies of the
German and Irish are made purposely to manure the soil for the sweet
efflorescence of the superior Yankee?</p>
<p>And how "do you keep your health?" as Mrs. Lincoln said to
Mr. Sala, but which question we would apply to the American Bird o'
Freedom itself. Really, Sir, not very well. The South is <hi
rend="italic">not</hi> in a state of disintegration, but adheres more
strongly than over to its purpose. Charleslon is <hi
rend="italic">not</hi> taken, and, indeed, not one firm step forward
has been made by the North. Moreover, one of the Southern
commissioners is here back in London debating, or, rather, ready to
debate, with Lord Palmerston and Louis Napoleon the expediency of
recognition. Surely the heads of the Northern people must be alive now
to the hopelessness of their dream of reunion. Surely enough blood has
been spilt, and enough groans and tears have been vented and shed. In
the mean time, too, the deterioration of American society must have
been going on--luxury on one hand, license and corruption on the
other; sudden fortunes by illicit dealings, shoddy princes, springing
up like mushrooms, and firm and stalwart merchants of the old and
honourable school falling quickly to decay; these are not sights which
exalt a nation. Will not the Yankees at this last hour let their
"wayward sisters go in peace," or will they persist to the "bitter
end," an end no less bitter assuredly to themselves than to their
opponents, who are already growing better under the "sweet uses of
adversity"? By-the-way, one ought to notice the clear photographic
minuteness and evident truth of Mr. Sala's pen-pictures of "America in
a state of war." Nothing has ever been better done in that way. Many
object that he says little about the war, and for two very good
reasons, let us add. In the first place, his letters are not about the
war, but concerning the people during its progression; and, in the
second, it is absolutely at a stand-still, as we may gather from the
letters of Dr. Mackay in the <hi rend="italic">Times</hi>, which
specifically concern it....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1248.004" n= "It is reported" type="Article">
<head>[IT IS REPORTED]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1248</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 267</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-12">March 12, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>It is reported that the Confederate General Morgan has attached to
each regiment of his new command a negro barber, for the purpose of
shaving the heads of all Federal officers whom he may capture, in
retaliation for a similar indignity practised upon him in
Ohio.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1249.001" n= "During the first eleven months of 1863" type="Article">
<head>[DURING THE FIRST ELEVEN MONTHS OF 1863]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1249</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 270</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-19">March 19, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>During the first eleven months of 1863 there arrived emigrants at
New York:--From Ireland, 86,691; Germany, 32,801; England, 16,893;
Denmark, 1567; Switzerland, 1058; France, 1195; Wales, 1083; Scotland,
1664; Sweden, 1359; Italy, 405; Holland, 379; Belgium, 456; West
Indies, 242; Spain, 152; various others, 574; total,
146,519.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1249.002" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1249</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 270</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-19">March 19, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>As far as can be gathered from the latest accounts from New York,
the Federal movements in Virginia and the south-west have been
failures. General Sherman had been obliged to return to Vicksburg
without effecting the object of his advance into Alabama, and General
Thomas's advance upon Dalton and Atlanta had been checked by General
Joseph Johnston. General Kilpatrick, who had been engaged in a cavalry
raid in the rear of Lee's army, had found it impossible to reach
Richmond, and had returned into the Federal lines. A forward movement
had been made by General Meade, to divert attention from Kilpatrick's
movements; but, by the latest accounts, the army of the Potomac was at
its old position at Brandy Station. General Meade has again been
summoned to Washington to consult with Lincoln and the War
Department. The Federals have been seriously repulsed in Florida. In
an engagement beyond Jacksonville, on the 20th ult., they were
defeated with a loss of 1000 men and several guns. At Charleston the
Federal sloop of war Housatonic was destroyed on the 18th ult. by a
Confederate torpedo. The Northern crew, with the exception of two
officers and three men, were rescued by boats from other blockading
vessels. The Confederate guerrilla, Colonel Richardson, has been
captured by Federal cavalry.</p>
<p>President Lincoln sent to the Senate the nomination of
Major-General Grant to be Lieutenant-General, in accordance with the
provisions of the new law reviving that rank in the army; and the
appointment has been confirmed.</p>
<p>On the 1st inst. the Senate passed the House bill providing for
the issue of 200,000,000 dols. in forty-five bonds; and also a joint
resolulution of thanks to re-enlisted veterans.</p>
<p>In the House of Representatives, on the 29th ult., the bill to
authorise the transfer of 200,000,000 dols. from the 900,000,000
dols. ten-forty loan into a five-forty loan was passed. The bill also
authorises the issue of 11,000,000 dols. additional five-twenties to
supply the overplus of subscriptions on the day the loan was
exhausted.</p>
<p>The draught in New York has been postponed. Bounties will be
continued till the 1st of April.</p>
<p>The Confederate Congress has adjourned, after having issued
addresses declaring that the South will make no overtures for peace
until the Federal Cabinet shall announce them to be acceptable, and
that the Southern Confederacy would submit to a European protectorate
rather than to Yankee domination.</p>
<p>A bill has passed the Confederate Senate to establish a volunteer
navy. It authorises the Secretary of the Navy to commission vessels
either in or out of the waters of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>General Bragg has been appointed General-in-Chief of the
Confederate armies.</p>
<p>Richmond papers contain the following address of General Beauregard
to his troops:--
<q><p>Soldiers!--The term of service of some of you is about to
expire. You must have seen from the newspapers that your brothers in
arms of the veteran armies of Northern Virginia and Tennessee have
re-enrolled, as was to be expected of such men, by entire companies,
battalions, regiments, and brigades, proudly retaining the
organisation intact under which they won renown. Will the men who have
defended Sumter and Moultrie fail to follow these examples of
soldierly patriotism?</p></q></p>
<p>The population of Wisconsin appears to be of a polyglot character,
as the Governor's message is to be printed, by order, in the German,
Norwegian, Irish, Welsh, Dutch, and French languages.</p>
<p>The Chicago correspondent of the <hi rend="italic">New York
Times</hi> writes, under date of the 15th ult.:--"A gentleman arrived
in this city from Idaho last week says that, when he left, it was
estimated that there was 15,000,000 dols. in gold in the hands of the
miners, awaiting the means of transportation to the
States."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1249.003" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1249</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 275</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-19">March 19, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....Amongst other curions items of news only to be found in the
writings of the eccentric Manhattan we gather that Mr. George
Thompson, a foremost workman once in the corn-law agitation, but now
neglected by his party, has arrived in New York, and has been
presented to the sovereign people as "the representative of Liberal
democracy in England, and the true friend of America." Mr. Thompson
did his best to praise America at the expense of John Bull, and said
that millions of hearts in England worshipped Fremont! Surely, this is
a poor <hi rend="italic">m&#x00E9;tier</hi> for a man to take up in
his old age who has done good service in his youth. Pleasant it is
also to be told that we hear that for the sake of "making the
President popular" we are to have hostility displayed towards
England. Candidates for the presidency are cropping up like
mushrooms. There is not a negro barber in New York, we are told with
pardonable exaggeration, who is not an aspirant for the presidency,
and who does not think he has a good chance. If a railsplitter is
elected, why not a barber? "I do not believe," writes Manhattan, "In
any mulattos, quarteroons, or <hi rend="italic">eighteroons</hi>; give
us a pure, unadulterated negro, and I will vote for
him...."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1249.005" n= "Imperial Parliament." type="Article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1249</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 278</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-19">March 19, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF COMMONS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Monday.</hi></p>
<p>Mr. Roebuck made an angry attack on the general policy of Lord
Russell as Foreign Minister, and, adverting especially to the
intention of the Government to remonstrate with President Davis on the
employment of Confederate agents in this country, he wished to know
whether representations would be made to the Government of Washington
with reference to the enlistment of recruits in Ireland for the
Federal service.--Lord Palmerston defended the policy of the
Government with regard to the American war, and stated that there was
no evidence to show that the Federals were recruiting in
Ireland. After some discussion the subject dropped.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1249.006" n= "We are indebted to Mr. Bateman Smith" type="Article">
<head>[WE ARE INDEBTED TO MR. BATEMAN SMITH]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1249</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 285</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-19">March 19, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">We</hi> are indebted to Mr. Bateman Smith, one
of the cabin passengers who escaped from the wreck of the Bohemian,
for a sketch of that vessel upon the rocks near Portland Harbour, on
the coast of Maine, U.S., where she got aground on the 22nd of last
month. The steamer, carrying nineteen cabin passengers and 199
steerage, besides the mails and cargo, with a crew of about one
hundred men, left Liverpool on the 4th of February, and had been some
days overdue at Portland when she met with this disaster. She was just
rounding Cape Elizabeth, to enter the harbour from Casco Bay, when she
struck upon a ledge called St. Alden's Rock, about three miles from
land. It was about eight o'clock in the evening; the night was foggy,
and the speed of the vessel was not more than two or two miles and a
half an hour. It appears that the master, Captain Borland, had
misjudged the distance of the lights visible on Cape Elizabeth. The
vessel, having struck and passed over<pb n="286"/> the rocks, found a
large hole in her bottom, and began to fill rapidly. She was then
turned towards the shore, with the intention of beaching her; but,
when she got very near the land, her engine fires were put out, and
she sunk in four fathoms of water, in an almost upright position, as
shown in the Engraving. This was about an hour and a quarter after she
struck. The weather was mild and calm, and there was no sea but the
usual groundswell. The deck, after the ship had settled down, was a
foot or two above water at low tide, and not more than an eighth of a
mile from the shore. Most of the passengers, however, had already left
the ship, the first boat taking eighty of them in one trip and seventy
in the next trip all safe to land. The second boat was, unfortunately,
swamped, and nineteen or twenty lives were thus lost, all Irish
steerage passengers, including five or six women and one or two
children. The other boats, with the remainder of the passengers, had
no difficulty in getting to shore. Captain Borland, with some of the
officers and crew, remained on board until next day, and managed to
save the mails. By the verdict of the Coroner's jury, at the inquest
held upon those drowned, it is declared that, "after the vessel
struck, her officers and men worked with energy and good judgment,
rarely equalled and never surpassed, to avoid the loss of life." The
citizens of Portland, and especially those dwelling near Cape
Elizabeth, are much commended for their humane efforts to relieve and
provide for the destitute passengers and to help them to their
destinations. There are still hopes of raising the vessel, which rests
with her centre upon a rock, but with her bow and stern in deep
water.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1249.007" n="The Wreck Of The Bohemian, Montreal Ocean
      Company's Steam-Packet, off the Coast of Maine." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1249</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 285</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-19">March 19, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv44p285">
<head>THE WRECK OF THE BOHEMIAN, MONTREAL OCEAN
      COMPANY'S STEAM-PACKET, OFF THE COAST OF MAINE.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1249.008" n= "The Confederate steamer Florida" type="Article">
<head>[THE CONFEDERATE STEAMER FLORIDA]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1249</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 287</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-19">March 19, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The Confederate steamer Florida and the Federal sloop-of-war
St. Louis were lying in Funchal Bay when the mail-steamer left
Madeira.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1249.009" n= "George Armstrong" type="Article">
<head>[GEORGE ARMSTRONG]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1249</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 291</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-19">March 19, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>George Armstrong, a private of the 39th British Regiment, stationed
in Canada, who took advantage of his leave of absence to cross to the
American side, enlist there, receive the bounty, and then return to
his regiment boasting of his rascality, has been tried by
court-martial and sentenced to be drummed out of the service, and
afterwards imprisoned for two years.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1250.001" n= "Foreign And Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1250</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 294</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-26">March 26, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>President Lincoln has presented General Grant with the commission
of Lieutenant-General in presence of the whole Cabinet. Grant, after
visiting the army of the Potomac, returned, with Meade, to Washington,
and left immediately for the west. The <hi rend="italic">New York
World</hi> asserts that Grant has recommended the concentration of
forces for the capture of Richmond.</p>
<p>Rumours of General Meade's removal from command are current at
Washington. It appears that Generals Sickles and Doubleday assert that
Meade issued an order for a retreat after the first day's fight at
Gettysburg. This, however, Meade denies point blank in a letter to
Reverdy Johnson, admitting, however, that he had arranged before the
battle to take a safer position, and one where he could more
advantageously accept battle, and dwelling with particular tenacity
upon the point that that could not be a retreat which was to take
place without a fight.</p>
<p>There is no news of importance from the army of the Potomac. A
reconnaissance on the 5th to Ely's Ford discovered very few
Confederates to the north of the Rapidan.</p>
<p>Suffolk, in Virginia, has been occupied by Butler's forces.</p>
<p>The Confederates continue to make demonstrations against Suffolk
and Portsmouth, and have driven in the Federal cavalry and two
coloured regiments.</p>
<p>General Sherman's return to Vicksburg is confirmed. He penetrated
thirty-five miles beyond Meridian, destroying all railroads. His loss
is stated to have been only 500 men.</p>
<p>General Johnston was pressing the Federal lines in Tennessee. The
Federals have withdrawn from Tunnel Hill to Ringold. Longatreet's
cavalry hold Bull's Gap, fifty-six miles from Knoxvlle. His army is at
Greenville.</p>
<p>The Federals occupy Morristown, forty-two miles from Knoxville.</p>
<p>The failure of Kilpatrick's cavalry raid on Richmond was
complete. Upon the person of Colonel Dahlgren, who was cut off and
killed, papers were found informing the troops that their mission was
to burn Richmond and release the Federal prisoners, and not to allow
Jefferson Davis to escape. The Richmond press is strongly incensed,
and urges that the severest treatment should be exercised towards the
prisoners of Kilpatrick's command. The Northern press declares that
the orders said to have been found on Dalhgren were forgeries.</p>
<p>Admiral Farragut has been bombarding Fort Powell, one of the
defences of Mobile.</p>
<p>It is reported that 20,000 Confederates are advancing from Texas
towards Western Louisiana. Active dispositions are being made by the
Federals to check this movement. The Federals are also sending
reinforcements to hold Jacksonville, Florida, but have abandoned
further expeditions into the interior.</p>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">New York Tribune's</hi> correspondent reports
that the blockade-running at Charleston has been resumed, two or three
steamers entering weekly.</p>
<p>Charges and specifications have been filed by Secretary Welles
against Admiral Wilkes for disobedience of orders in taking and
keeping the Vanderbilt far his flag-ship, when he knew that she was
ordered on special service in South America; in refusing to send the
Oneida and and Cuyler to Farragut; for insubordination in going off
with the Vanderbilt to Laguayra when he should have remained about the
Bahamas, cruising for rebel privateers; for disrespectful language to
his superior officer in writing an insubordinate and saucy letter to
Secretary Welles; for disobedience of the naval regulations forbidding
publication of official communications in giving a New York paper a
copy of the above letter, and procuring it to be published therein;
and conduct unbecoming an officer in refusing to tell the Department
how old he was.</p>
<p>The House of Representatives has passed the bill authorising
Mr. Chase to anticipate the payment of interest on the public debt,
but not to sell gold.</p>
<p>The President had signed the whisky bill. It imposes a tax of sixty
cents per gallon on all domestic-manufactured liquors from the passing
of the Act, and forty cents on imported spirits on hand.</p>
<p>A bill had been introduced in the House of Representatives to
secure to persons in the military or naval services of the United
States homesteads on confiscated or forfeited estates in
insurrectionary districts. It proposes to give to all persons who have
been discharged therefrom by reason of wounds received or disease
contracted therein eighty acres or a less quantity of the
unappropriated lands, in conformity with the provisions of the
Homestead Act. The bill was ordered to be printed.</p>
<p>In Congress Senator Pomeroy has advocated the claims of Secretary
Chase for presidential nomination, stating his platform to be
emancipation, confiscation, and the maintenance of the Monroe
doctrine.</p>
<p>Secretary Chase has written a letter urging that his name should
not be considered in connection with the presidency.</p>
<p>Fremont's friends are more active in advocating his claims for the
presidency.</p>
<p>The Republican ticket has been elected by a large majority in New
Hampshire.</p>
<p>The majority in New York have voted in favour of permitting
soldiers and sailors to vote.</p>
<p>The Republicans have carried their elections in New Hampshire,
re-electing the present Governor, Joseph A. Gilmore by a majority of
about 5000.</p>
<p>A severe earthquake was experienced at San Francisco on the morning
of the 5th inst.</p>
<p>The gold diggings in Colorada and Idaho territories are proving to
be very rich, and bid far to outrival California. In both territories
an immense amount of gold has accumulated in the hands of miners and
others, but the insecurity of communication with States prevents its
shipment. A great deal is, however, sent vi&#x00E2; Salt Lake City to
California.</p>
<p>The Southern Confederacy has dispatched an envoy for the purpose of
negotiating a treaty of mutual amity and recognition with the new
Mexican empire.</p>
<p>It is stated that some ladies in the Southern Confederacy are
sending their plate to the Treasury as a free offering to the Treasury
"to relieve the pressure on the currency."</p>
<p>The Confederates have captured two Federal transports in the
Chesapeake Bay.</p>
<p>The Bohemian has broken up, and is a total loss.</p>
<p>The City of New York, Nova Scotian, and Bavaria have arrived out.</p>
<p>The Judge of the Court of Appeal, at St. John, has delivered
judgment releasing the Chesapeake pirates.</p>
<p>The steamer Donegal has arrived at Havannah with 1000 bales of
cotton.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln44.1250.002" n= "At this period of the year" type="Article">
<head>[AT THIS PERIOD OF THE YEAR]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 44</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1250</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 298</biblScope>
<date value="1864-03-26">March 26, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps"><hi rend="italic">London:
Saturday, March</hi> 26, 1864.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">At</hi> this period of the year, when, after
befitting attention to the most serious of all concerns, the mind of
our people turns upon social and lawful enjoyment, it is impossible
not to think (with deep regret for those who are differently engaged)
upon the unhappy condition of our American brethren. A few words in
explanation of the present state of the war may not be inappropriate,
now that the war itself appears to have reached a point of temporary
stoppage.</p>
<p>The new campaign opened with a series of boldly-conceived but
badly-executed movements on the part of the Federals. General Sherman
set out from Vicksburg for a rush eastward, and Admiral Farragut made
an assault of some kind at the entrance of the bay of Mobile, in the
extreme south, in order to distract the attention of the
Confederates. Both efforts appear to have signally failed. The sea
attack was useless, and has given new courage to the South; and
Sherman, who certainty dashed with great courage into a terrible
danger, was not seconded by the assistance on which he seems to have
relied. Had he succeeded, a most important gain would have accrued to
the Federals, by the acquisition of a large portion of Alabama and of
Georgia, with the Confederate arsenals and stores. As it is, we are by
no means informed how far Sherman proceeded; but he was soon met by
the enemy, suffered at least two defeats, and retreated to
Vicksburg. Rumuour said that he had suffered most tremendous loss;
but, except that the absence of authorised contradiction, usually so
ready, gives us reason to believe that there may be foundation for
such reports, we cannot form an opinion upon this part of the
story. The Confederate cavalry had again shown its vigour and the
ability with which it is handled; and though, as one of our military
writers said years ago, "more men are killed in an hour of musquetry
than in a day of galloping and sabring," the carnage must, at some
points, have been frightful. Moreover, the other attempt which was
made against Lee has even more conspicuously failed, and the Federal
force had to make its escape as best it might, leaving large numbers
behind it, either killed or prisoners. Nothing, in fact, could well be
more disastrous than the way the Federals have opened the war this new
year.</p>
<p>Such is the state of military affairs in America while we English
are preparing for a national holiday. The condition of political
matters there affords also a great contrast to that of our own. We
have had party fights; but no principle is at stake, and the
confidence of the country is given generously and fully to the veteran
statesman at the head of the Government--a man whom the bitterest
enemies of the Cabinet do not venture to say they desire to
displace. Our Parliament has done nothing since its meeting, for the
best of all reasons--it has had little or nothing to do; and if it has
occupied itself with wrangles it is because men are impatient of
idleness and will combat on trifles rather than sit silent. Were the
honour of the country at stake, or were a domestic interest in
question, we should speedily see patriotism take the place of
petulance. But the northern part of America is simply given up to
electioneering intrigue, and to all its treacheries and evil
influences. That unhappy arrangement, by which it becomes impossible
for the Americans to elect one of their best and ablest men, and which
compels them to fix upon some person for Chief Magistrate whom chief
merit is that nobody knows much about him, is not to be laid to the
present generation as a fault, though none will deny that it is a
misfortune. There is not one of the reputed candidates for the
presidency who, by any stretch of words, can be called a first-rate
man. But America is evidently longing for a military dictator, one who
will place a strong foot upon the miserable intriguers who make her
success in peace or in war an impossibility, and one who with a strong
hand will force the revolted States into submission. The two favourite
names are those of M'Clellan and of Grant, and, though neither has met
with disasters enough to disqualify him from popularity, neither has
done anything to justify his being raised to the headship of a mighty
country. It seems probable, however, that a military ruler may be more easily obtained than a successful commander. Mr. Lincoln's friends are strong, and he has the advantage of possession, and it may be fairly said that his chances are at present the best. But all presents a sorry prospect for our American brethren, and both North and South have the sincerest sympathies of all who are sincere in their observance of the season which is now passing.</p></div2>
AMERICA.

The President, by an official, order promulgated on the 1lUi n1, assigned Lieutenant-G encral Grant to the command of all the armies of the United States. General Halleck, who is, at his own request, relieved fJQrn duty as General-in-Chief, is assigned to duty m Washington as Chief of Army Staff. Major-General W. T. $horxhau is assigned to the command of the military division of the Mississippi, embracing the departments of the Ohio, the Omnberinnd, the Tennessee, and the Arkansas. Major General MPherson is assigned to the command of the department and army of the Tennessee. In relieving General Hafleck from duty as General-in-Chief, the President expresses his thanks and approbation "for the able and zealous manner in which the arduous and responsible duties of that position have been performed."

There seems to be a strong impression on both sides that General Grant is about to inaugurate a vigorous campaign in Virginia; and the Confederates are said to be concentrating an army of observation in North Carolina to watch the southern part of .Tames River, in which direction they anticipate the Northern legions will appear,

The Federals are concerting expeditions against bhreveport, Louisiana, and the transMississippi region,

General Sherman, who had gone to New Orleans to consult with General Banks, has arrived at Nashville to assume his new command. General Sherman was said to have done immense damao to (Jonfederate property in his late raid-to have destroyed 10 miles of railway, and to have brought 10,000 negroes with him to Vicksburg; but we are not told anything respecting the losses sustained by him.

Firing is still kept up against Charleston, but no more casualties are reported.

President Lincoln has called for 200,000 more men, to be raised by the 15th inst.

Both Houses of Congress have passed the bill authorising the sale of the surplus gold in the Treasury.

General M'Oleflan and General Fremont had both been nominated for the presidency by meetings held in New York.

Arkansas has elected an anti-slavery Legislature.

The Free-State Government has been publicly inaugurated at New Orleans with imposing ceremonies. The wife of General Beauregard has died in that city. At the funeral a great public demonslratiou of sympathy Was made.
President Davis, the Times' lew York correspondent telegraphs,

Las appointed the 8th inst. as a day of fasting and prayer.

A conspiracy has been discovered in Kentucky, having for its object

the annexation of that State to the Southern Confederacy.

The Federal Judge has decided that the English barque Saxon was illegally seized at Angra Pequena, on the South African coast; but we ha,e yet to learn the result of the inquiry into the homicide of her mate by one of the Vanderbilt's officers.

The steamer Mary Ann was captured by the Grand Gulf, off Wilmington, on the 6th nit. The sloop Two Brothers was captured on Feb. 25, off Indiana Inlet. On the 27th of February the sloop Mina was captured; on the 29th the schooner Rebel, and on the 4th nit. the schooner Lametta.

The Navy Department of the United States have advertised for tenders for raising the line-ofbattle ships Pennsylvania, Delaware, and Columbus, the frigates Cumberland, Congress, Merrimac, Rantaii, and Columbia, and the steamer Whitehall, which have been sunk during the conflict.

A treaty has been concluded between the United States and Great Britain for the sttlexnent of the claims of the Hudson's Bay and Pu get sound Agricultural Companies, under the Treaty of 1846.

TAnALT -
THE WINTER QUARTERS OF THE CONFEDERATE

ARMY ZN YIRGThTIA.

(From our Special Artist and CorrWndent.)

Iwo months ago I rode through the log and canvas city illustrated

the Engraving on the preceding page and as I left it I lingered for a few minutes to make a farewell sketci. There was much of sorrow in the feelings that governed me at that moment. I was looking, perhaps for the last time, on the camp that sheltered men who had been my companions for nearly two years. What thoughts crowded on me then-what a kaleidoscope of great events whirled through my recollection I Many a gallant deed and many a well-fought field that I had witnessed with my Southern friends were reviewed rapidly as I rose in my saddle and waved a trembling adieu. There curled the blue smoke from the tent of Robert E. Lee, whose hand I had just shaken, and whose friendship I am proud to own; there were the quarters of the gallant Stuart, whose guest I had been for the past few days, and whose hospitality in the field I had enjoyed for many months. Yes; every soldier of the army of Northern Virginia was a comrade; we had marched many weary miles together, and I had shared in some of their dangers. This brought me nearer to them than years of ordinary contact could have done; and now, as I looked on their camp for perhaps the last time, I realised painfully and forcibly the many friends who were lying there, some of whom would breathe their last in the first glad sunshine of coming spring. Not only did I survey the camp of the living, but around me, on every side as far as the eye could reach, lay spread the battle-fields of Virginia; and in many a distant clump of pine wood slept their last sleep those whom I had known in life. Requiescant in pace. Far away in the background, tipped with snow, towered the mountains of the Blue Ridge, every pass of which bears the imprint of the dead hero, Stonewall Jackson, and of the gallant men who fought with him in the valley of the Shenandoah that lies beyond. Through these passes were made some of those wonderful flank movements which for celerity and success have challenged the admiration of the world. There, within the eye's glance, lay a classic ground, crima*erl with deeds that will make history for the future. The camp which now looked so calm and peaceful in the clear winter's sunshine, with naught to disturb the quiet but the stroke of the pioneer's axe cutting fuel for the bivouac fire, would in a few short weeks be broken up. Across the Ilapidan, which flows beyond the nearer crest of hills, lay the enemy, only waiting probably the first

 approach of spring to renew the awful drama that has spread desolation over many a once smiling acre of Virginian soil. As I grasped the hands of my friends at leavetaking, they knew that the present lull was but the forerunner of a coming storm; every man amongst them spoke hopefully and confidently of the future, and here, dispassionately, will 1 assert that, whatever be the result of the approaching campaign, I am confident that General Lee and his veterans will have done their duty. And now, while bidding farewell to an array with which I have been associated for a lengthened period, let me take an opportunity of thanking all those officers and soldiers whose guest I have been during my sojourn in the Confederacy. From the Ilappahannock to the banks of Yazoo in Mississippi, from the Tennessee to the Atlantic seaboard, every detachment, every Southern command, has received me with unvarying courtesy and wholesouled hospitality; what they have had has been cheerfully shared with your correspondent. To procure me facilities great warriors and 11 medicine men" have not hesitated to inconvenience themselves where necessary, and if your readers have not benefited as they might have done by my experiences, it is the fault of a rigorous blockade which has intercepted much destined for your pages.

[Our Special Artist is now in London. He has brought several Illustrations, which will appear from time to time in this Journal.]
r rrwn rtrqr 1Lr

U14R. CZ XJa-ZAAA:;. IN XWCL TL&T -

f* y (Me Afl LIL y M wbm an bM t i.

k* W" in am-AM d,niw b s*' fro=

y. th 4t t e1y thc . . c t to *4 'e

A74',40* b -$. z- rn IL, *t

- kr M

%d WON so= stwv ris f, r~tt d t

twas I _I?.

r. w e. v 7
Texan Sear. alias the Mnrt,ban, bound to Singapore with a rice cargo, was then lying in the position which our Engraving represents; her sails were dewed up, her anchor was down in about fifteen fathoms water, and the fire was breaking out at both ends. The crew having been removed, the Alabama cut the barqne's boat adrift and steamed away at full speed to the northwest until. midnight, when she was seen suddenly to alter her course towards Ittalacca, where it appears she lauded the captured crew. The Texan Star when last seen was one mass of flame fore and aft, her masts had

fallen by the board, and, while fast burning to the water's edge, she cast through the intense darkness of the night a brilliant gleam of light, at once a beacon to the navigator and a warning to all Federal ships in those waters.
AMERICA.

The Australasian, which arrived at Qneenstown last Saturday, brings New York advicea to the 23rd alt.

General lee is reported. to have broken, up his encampment on the Rapidan and to be moving on the Shenandoah Valley, and an early attack by the General on the army of the Potomac was apprehended.

General Stuart was concentrating his cavalry at Fredericksburg and Charlottesville preparatory to making a raid. But the military operations in Virginia were delayed by a terrific snowstorm.

The movements of General Longatreet at Bull's Gap rendered it doubtful whether he intended to enter Kentucky or to join Lee: the latter was considered most probable.

Porter's fleet and Sherman's forces had left Vicksburg for Red River.

The steamer Norman has been destroyed in Suwannee river.

President Lincoln has signed the Enabling Acts for Nevada, Colorado, and Nebraska, allowing them to form State constitutions and come into the Union.

The negro colonists who left the United States for Hayti have returned, unable to form a colony.

The decree of the United States District Court in the case of the Saxon not only orders the ship and cargo to be restored to the owners, but recommends that Lieutenant Donovan, who shot Mr. Grey, should

be tried by-court-martial fur the murder. The questions of com

pensation to the widow and to the owners of the vessel have been reserved.

l'W5 ( A 'DV (j' lvr Dfl1Th
LATEST NEWS FROM ABROAD.

The following ze]egrama have been rec'4ved through Mr. Rentals

cflce -

&uie&.-New York, Much 2 (Evening).-AdYke$ from

Cl erketc n to the 1th ir.M. state that the Confederates have mounted

six nd gum in caema on Fort Sumter, besrrng on the obann&

end they have completed another Ironclad in the harbour. Tim RcJi5 hgni* **rLs that General Beinre,gartl has been *pponed to the coutmand of the army of the South Vv eat. General I). L thU rueeeeds General Iieaurvga*1 at Charleston.

March 24, 11 am.-it repoited that the Confederates are preparing

far a combined hiamlon of Kentucky from variona pointa.
an pa .

FEDERAL BIcL1STMENT IN IRunAED.-The Earl of DOzeoGIurOBE referred to the case of the men who had been received Into the United Slates ship of war the anage at Cork, and urged that the statement of the captain, that he did not know of their being in the vessel, was contrary to the depo-sitions of the men themselves.-Enrl RUSSELL said that he had called the

attention of the American Minister to this case, and be was informed by him

that instructions had been Issued by his Government to the effect that any

officer in their seivice who infringed the Foreign Enlistment Act should b

dlieeed. Mr. Adams had also offered to refer the case of the eareage to the Executive at Washington, but he (Earl Russell) was not of opinion that either the American Consul or the captain of the earaage was blamable in this matter.-The Earl of DERBY said that it was clearly proved that the men in question were examined, attested, and ci thed In the American uniform on board the Kearage; and It was, therefore, not possible that any of the officers of the ship could be unaware of the olrctunstence.-The Marquis of InanrameitnE objected to allowing the Xearssga to be repaired in one of her ldajeety'e dockyarda under the circumstances.

aaarovan o BRITISH CoEsuns UT THE CONFEDERATE STATES. -The

linrquis of CLAlUtXOAilE moved for correspondence relating to the removal if British Consuls from the Confederate States of America, urged the iucon eoience of there being no accredited agents of this country in those States, nd that it was quite possible to keep up the system of Consuls without reoog. thing the Southern States.-After some explanation by Earl RUSSELL the notion oz agreed to, and their lordships adjourned at a quarter to seven

']Mr.'Iayi in ar to Colonel Sykes, said that by a judgment of an tniertcan prize court, the ship Saxon was to be given up to the owner, free of II charges. He believed that Lteutennt Donoghue was to be tried for the

fling of the mate of the Saxon.

LOCAL TAXATION.
in neam-ship City of New York, one of the ships belonging to the

New York, and Philadelphia Steam-ship Company, usually

J Thman line, remains still fixed upon Daunt's Rock, at the

entrance of Cork or Queenstown harbour, where she struck on the morning of Tuesday week. The first of the two Engravings. Irons skctches taken expressly for this Journal, shows the position of the

ship last Sattusisy. when she prrcented no external aftp#'annee o injury; the tn-boats were alossgs4e nrorinr her cargo, and there was another large Iteamer, wkch Is seen on the right hno I of ott
View-the City o Glasgow, just arrived from New York, and about to enter the harbour. The unfortunate City of New York, having a hole of ten feet by three in her bottom, and being submerged by high tides above her upper (leeks. soon became full of water; and our second Engraving represents the midship dining saloon and berths in this condition, with beds, hampers, barrels, and furniture all floating about. We are glad to learn, however, that there is still a chance of saving this fine ship.
CAMP OF FEDERAL PRISONERS ON BELLE ISLE, RICHMOND, VIRGINIA.

Tin late raid of General Kilpatriok and Colonel Dahigren in the neighbourhood of Richmond, which resulted in a disastrous check and the death of Colonel Dahlgren, is still fresh in the minds of our readers. It will also be remembered that one of the prime objects of the expedition was to effect the release of the Federal prisoners now held in the capital of the Southern Confederacy. The Engraving which we publish this week shows the camp in which these Federal prisoners are confined. Our Special Artist and Correspondent gives the following description of his Sketch :-" For some time the cartel regulating the exchange of prisoners between the North and South has been in abeyance, the Federal and Confederate commissioners being at issue on a point of objection raised by the Lincoln Administration. The result of this misunderstanding has been a large increase of the captives on each side, and in Richmond especially the prisons are full to overflowing. In fact, those buildings originally set aside for the accommodation of prisoners of war in t

Confederate capital have been found insufficient for the purpose, and the authorities, to provide a remedy, have established a camp of dfitenus on Belle Isle. This is the largest of the numerous islands that intersect the channel of the James River, in the immediate neighbourhood Of Richmond, end is well adapted for the purpose to which it has been destined. A swift and turbulent current separates at from either shore, end bold, indeed, would be the swimmer who would usk himself amidst the eddies that hiss and boil on their way to the deeps below. Besides, its position allows of a cordon of sentries around its entire circumference, end these are within challenging distance of each other, making it next to impossible to pass through them unperceived. In addition to this, the camp occupied by the prisoners is intreached, and there is an inner line of guards pacing around its outskirts, with imperative orders to shoot the first man who attempts to cross the embankment. On a commending eminence close at hand is a detachment of artillerymen, with a shotted gun frowning on the tents beneath, and at the first sign of an outbreak the iron messengers of death would plough their way though the confused mass of insubordinates Again, on each bank of the river, are other guns, placed in a position to enfilade the island, and they are kept in readiness for any emergency that may arise. When I visited Belle Isle, at the latter end of Jknturry, there were more than 7000 prisoners in the camp, all of whom were rank and file from the Federal armies of Virginia and Tennessee The officers are confined in the "Libby," a large and well-ventilated building formerly used as a tobacco warehouse-since it has been found politic to separate the private soldier from his commissioned superior. At the time I mention, the Northern journals wore filled with accounts of barbarities practised by the Confederates upon those whom the fate of war had placed in their hands, and I was anxious to judge for myself of the correctness of these statements. Let your readers determine from my statement whether the charge of cruelty can he established :-The rations which I saw distributed to the prisoners were in every respect the same as those issued to the Southern soldier; possibly the former may get more fresh meat, and that, I apprehend, is scarcely a ground for objection. They certainly do not get such luxuries as coffee or sugar, but then the Confederates themselves are no better off with respect to these condiments, which, indeed, are only to be procured in the Southern States at such ruinous blockade prices as to prevent their finding their way into the commissariat of the Southern army. The doctor's report, on the day I visited the island, will also serve to indicate' hat the treatment to which the prisoners are subjected is not such as to affect their health. I am convinced your readers will be astounded when I tell them that, out of 71 000 of these craeQy-used captives, the sick-list only gave thirteen in hospital. Why, I have known, in one morning's report, as many as seventy-five or a hundred to be returned as unfit for duty out of a skeleton brigade of fifteen hundrd, in Bragg's army. After six months' confinement of these Federal prisoners at Belle Isle, there were only seventy-five graves to indicate the number of those who had died under the privations to which they are said to have been subjected! Any AdjutantGeneral of a division of 5000 men in Lee's army could show a very different bill of mortality from sickness end hardship embracing a corresponding period. I think that these statemeets should go a great way to disprove the charges made by the Northern press. The Northern journals have undoubtedly been misinformed in this particular, and it is only an act of justice on my part to dispel from your readers' minds any wrong impressions they may have formed an to the treatment which the Federal prisoners meet with at the hands of the Confederates. The point from which my sketch is taken affords a capital view of Richmond; and this must be my excuse for almost repeating a drawing of the city which appeared in your Journal many months ago. The bridge that crosses the river just below Belle Isle is known as the Petersburg Bridge, and it connects the Southern Railroad with the metropolis of the Southern Confederacy."
-  AMERICA.

The Arabia has brought n.s New York athices of the 2nd inst.

President Lincoln, on the 26th nit., issued a proclamation defining

and restricting his previous amnesty proclamation.

An order from the War Department has been promulgated b General Meade, which consolidates the troops of the Potomac arjX!Y into three corps. There had been no important movement ill Virginia; but the Confederates were believed to be strengbhen1X5 their positions on the Rapdan, and General Grant was at Portr Monroe, where he was suppored to be consulting General But1C. respecting his plans for the campaign.

The expedition up the Red Riyer t 1att tht w. a snaking pQ
- a on the 16th ult. The Confederates

AkmmdriA Was occupied

v Of the river were concentrating at Shreves- 1

s Lr05 tie Buys accidentally blown , killing fir men.

,eventyflvO miles above Alexandria engaged the capturing 200 prisoners and four pieces of the Confederate General Forrest upon Union City, As AuWk On the 24th ult., resulted in this capture of the ]minediatelv afterwards, Forrest entered on the 25th occuided  aducab, on the Ohio River,

jjo be M=oved many valuable spoils. He also attacked the , want of heavy cannon was compelled to desist. Two #04 b=U from Cairo opened fire to diaodge his forces, rtion of the city was destroyed. Forrest thirty-five miles east of Paducah. b5Cfl Ue soldiers and civilians (or, as another Copperheads and Republicans) occurred j1L0n the 28th nIt., in which between twenty and were killed or wounded. The civilians (Copper. isei from the town, but have intrenched themselves outbreaks in other districts in Illinois are also Hemntzeimn',  commanding that department

a in, iF

*041 1" WO troops to suppress insurrection.

ATTgPALL&.
LI1' OF (OLOZL COLT'S FIREARMS IPAC~MRY AT HARMED. r1Tr TAT.

'Tr txt fny fl*i1d. cizt bzig t a

: r fcr the ramufAMUM of (O1i Count  z &*a

d cit&r. wbich Imim ob*z*d s. 3.w4 rep

-M r4iy d&OYtd by 6e ex the &h of F*uay aat 1t

C of the &6 ot i 4r  b. by ti .c aaa flL The he vale &

In

of thi be the cpaVkm of the OMPMAY are ifl

cr1ed o. Tbe b* e beIere, *4y rzI the

of Cot fizr  *ti, W* t"ame. are a

4 teeet i Aa1a at the pe'eat se. I  pusW

pe,. that

e be tr4 cf the x the llartfc %oy will b et4. We  t ergmvvd * boogrph of te rue.
NASSAU, NEW PROVIDENCE.

WITH reference to the annexed Engraving of the capital of the

Bahamas, our Special Artist and Correspondent writes as follows

"Nassau. at the present moment is a point of very great interest

indeed, being the head-quarters of the Anglo-Confederate blockaderunners; and at no time, I presume, has its harbour shown so much activity as now. The enterprise of British merchants has lined its quays with long light-coloured, rakish-looking steamers, discharging their rich freights of cotton that have run the gauntlet through the Federal cruisers off Wilmington. The voyage from the Confederate -States to Nassau averages about fifty hours; but then these fifty hours are fraught with an excitement that a voyage of fifty days would fail in producing. From the time of leaving Cape Pear River, Wilmington, to the time of sighting Nassau and getting into British waters, these adventurous craft are never safe from being overhauled by 9'e Northern man-of-war. Many a feat of heroism has been displayd by the plucky Englishmen who command them, and I have known instances of a vessel being chased and fired into for an entire day, and the only answer given in reply was to display the British onsign more proudly than ever. C)! course the owners of these ships are, strictly speaking, violating the neutrality which her Majesty's Government baa proclaimed; but, for all that, we EnglisHmen may well be proud of the spirit of enterprise shown by our countrymen, who set at defiance the guns of the Federalists, and turn a blockaded harbour into an open port. Nassau is the point whence most of the blockadere start with the cargoes destined for the Southern (Jonfederacy, and it is here that they return with their bales of Sea Island and Upland cotton which they have obtained in exchange for the rifles, blankets, and shoes so much needed by the Southern soldier. The climate of the Bahamas, of which New Providence is -one of the group, is almost tropical; and pleasant, indeed, to your Correspondent was the change from the wintry weather which he had experienced on the banks of the Rapidan. Oranges, shaddocka, bananas, cocoanuts, pineapples and many other varieties of fruit abound, and lovely to the eye is the diversity of foliage in which the charming bungalow residences are embedded. The people of the place, led by their popular Governor and his lady, are the most hospitable I have ever met; and the officers of the let West India Regiment, stationed at Nassau, are the beat set of men it has been my chance to fall in with on a foreign station,
Master Willie Pape, the celebrated young American pianist,

has been playing at Liverpool with extraordinary success. At a concert at St. George's Hall, on Saturday last, he performed, among other pieces, Thalberg's serenade from "Don Pasquale," Beethoven's sonata in E flat, and Thalberg's fautasias on "Lucia," and "litosb in Egitto," intermingling these classical compositions with curious and interesting specimens of American and negro music. "Master Pape," sa's a Liverpool journal, "has a touch of equal softness and brilliancy; his execution seems equal to any difficulty; his repertoire is varied and abundant; his style, though it has yet to reach the poetical maturity of one or two of our greatest masters of the piano, is characterised by intelligence, appreciation, and feeling, while it is wholly devoid of the tricksiness usually found with prodigies; and to all his other merits he udda a memory which enables him to dispense with his music throughout the whole of his wonderful programme."

Information has been received in London respecting an enormous theft of bar gold, worth 00,000, from the sunken steamer Golden Gate, near San Francisco. The Golden Gate was wrecked in July, 1862, having on board 400,000 worth of gold and specie. The underwriters by whom the vessel had been insured dispatched an agent to the scene of the wreck, and a party of men who recovered about 50,000 worth of bar gold decamped with it. It is believed that most of the booty has been forwarded to London. One of the suspected thieves has been taken into custody.
NEw YoEx, April 9, Morning.-A slight engagement, lasting three hours, occurred on the 28th tilt., thirty-five miles above Alexandria, Louisiana, between 8000 Federals and the Confederates, who were estimated 12,000 strong. The Federals are reported to have captured 500 prisoners, and then continued advancing, endeavouring to bring on a general engagement. The confederate ram Tennessee is reported to have sunk at Grant's Pass, Mobile, during a gale. The Senate has passed a resolution amending the Constitution so as to abolish slavery. The resolution has yet to pass the House of Representatives and the State Legislatures. In Louisiana the election for delegates to the State Constitutional Convention has resulted in the success of the Free State party. An enormous mass meeting of working men has been held at New. York protesting against legislative interference with strikes.

AMERICA.

The military news from America is of little interest. Heavy rains. had fallen, and neither of the belligerent armies in Virginia had made any movement; but General Grant had proceeded from Washington to the Federal head-quarters. The Confederate cavalry was still active in West Tennessee and Kentucky. The Federal expedition which ascended the Red River to Alexandria was continuing its advance towards Shreveport.

The Federal House of Representatives had passed resolutions deploring recent events in Mexico, and declaring that it can never accord with American interests to recognise a monarchy established on the ruins of an American republic under the auspices of a European State.

The great metropolitan fair at New York in aid of the United States Sanitary Commission was inaugurated on the 4th inst. The day was observed as a holiday in New York. Eight thousand soldiers took part in the ceremony, and the people turned out en niese.

The Republican ticket has been elected by a large malority in Connecticut.
The Am York World pnbiishez a long and minute account

o the secret police system uiar.ta1ned by the Federal Govnment in bM

eit. It emptoys 800 oceTh, bseides an Immense number o snbordlnate

apise, male and female, and, like the Iu3o, bee Its own rIeone where

victims are Incarcerated, tortured, and sometImea dIsaeer, leaving no trace. This system, worthy of the worst days of HOW and Zptee, costs the Gc-ycrnment O,000 dots, 3 mouth.
-  AMERICA.

General Grant has joined the army of the Potomac. He has issued orders to revoke all furloughs, to send baggage to the rear, and to direct antlers to leave the army, in view of the resumption of active operation. Continuous rains however, prevented any immediate movemerit. It was rlimoure that a threefold advance on Richmond-namely, by Grant across the Rapidan, Smith up the Peninsula, and Burnaide vi Goldsborougb, North Carolina-as been determined upon. The army of the Potomac, it is said, has been largely reinforced. General Meade has moved his headquarters to Cudpepper. On the 12th inst. the Confederates, under General Forrest, attacked Fort Pillow, a few miles higher up the Mississippi than Memphis; and, after some fhting, they compelled the garrison of 600 men to surrender. It was- said that they had massacred the garrison. No certain information had been received, however, relative to this latter part of the affair, The Confederates had also taken Paducah, but had been shelled out of it again. The Federal expedition up the Red River had defeated a body of Confederates near Cane River,

had taken about 600 prisoners. The Confederate General
BCOO men, had made 5 unsuccessful attack on )laws I eral Steele's division near the little Missouri River Fed expedition is advancing  towards Texas. It

had two  skirmishes.

N the ]morning of the 9th the Confederates made an attempt to

ag-ship Minnesota, off Newport. The Minnesota bntnot sunk.

bas passed a resolution in favour of such an

of the Federal Constitution as shall for ever abolish - nt the United States. tC0m1tte8 on Foreign Affairs, with the approval of

*e praddat and the Cabinet, had decided not to support the recent

;PWdea of the House of Representatives relative to French ape

ado, eM)g5occurred in the Federal Rouse of Representatives.

spoke in favour of peace, advocating the inune

of the Southern Confederacy. Next day Speaker!

the chair and moved Mr. Long's expulsion for Harr* of Maryland, defended Mr. Long, and prayed

- b

00000. 1 t never be conquered; whereupon Mr. Washburne, the expulsion of Mr. Harris. Eighty-one votes and fifty-eight apinst the latter motion; but, there ,f two thirds, the motion was lost. A vote of bows was immediately afterwards carried, on the 4sW ick, against a minority of nineteen. The

Medea of 0ffr.Lvng was still under discussion. Several Democratic at they indorsed Mr. Long's opinions.

cjiu1eeujalmost 5panic inthemoney market. Gold roseto

aftewards declined and closed at 176k.
The ice-crop gathered last winter in America is said o be

the largest ever stored.

Tbeape mall has arrived. The news is not generally im

portant. The notorious Alabama bed put Into Table Bay for coals and supplies. In her cruise in the Indian Seas she had captured and destroyed seven vessels.


