<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI.2//EN" "iln.dtd"
[<!ENTITY % iln-entities SYSTEM
"/Beck-files/ILN/ILNCVS/ilnxml/iln_entities">
 %iln-entities; ]>

<TEI.2>
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated London News
Perspective</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Compiled and edited by</resp>
               <name>Sandra Still</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent/>         
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Emory University</pubPlace>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine>
            </address>
            <availability>
               <p>2005 Emory University.
Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce,
distribute or display the contributions to the work claimed by Emory
University for non-profit educational purposes, provided this header
is included in its entirety.  For inquiries about commercial uses,
contact the Lewis H. Beck Center, Woodruff Library, Emory University,
Atlanta, Georgia 30322</p>
            </availability>
            <date>2005</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated
London News Perspective</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
               <biblScope type="volume">Volume 45</biblScope> 
               <date>July to December 1864</date>
</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p/>
         </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	<change><date>October 2005</date>
          <respStmt><name>Robin Conner, </name><resp>Beck Center Staff.</resp></respStmt>
          <item>Encoded text according to TEI guidelines.</item>
	</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div1 id="iln45.001" n="Illustrated London News: Volume 45" type="Volume"> 
            <head>Illustrated London News: Volume 45</head>
<docDate>July to December 1864</docDate>

<div2 id="iln44.1266.001" n="The Deerhound Rescuing a Portion of the
      Crew of the Alabama.--From a Sketch by Mr. Robert
      Lancaster.--See Next Page." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1266</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 1</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv45p1">
<head>THE DEERHOUND RESCUING A PORTION OF THE
      CREW OF THE ALABAMA.--FROM A SKETCH BY MR. ROBERT
      LANCASTER.--SEE NEXT PAGE.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1266.002" n= "The Fight Between the Alabama and the Kearsarge." type="Article">
<head>THE FIGHT BETWEEN THE ALABAMA AND THE KEARSARGE.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1266</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 2</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE FIGHT BETWEEN THE ALABAMA AND THE<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">Kearsarge.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">We</hi> published last week an Engraving from
the sketch which was sent us by Mr. James Bryant, owner of the yacht
Hornet, representing the final scene of the combat between the Alabama
and the Kearsarge, a few miles off Cherbourg, on the morning of
Sunday, the 19th ult. We are now enabled, by the courtesy of
Mr. Robert Lancaster, of Hindley Hall, Wigan, to present our readers
with another Illustration of the same subject, which appears on our
front page. Mr. Lancaster is the owner of the yacht Deerhound, which
was present during the whole of the battle, and which was happily
instrumental in saving the lives of Captain Semmes, thirteen officers,
and twenty-six men of the Alabama, when they had leaped into the water
as their ship went down. Whilst we may congratulate this gentleman
upon the service to humanity which he was thus enabled to perform, we
are bound no less to thank him for aiding us, by the work of his
pencil, in producing a graphic record of the extraordinary spectacle
that he witnessed. Mr. Lancaster says in his letter, which accompanied
this drawing:--</p>
<p>"I have endeavoured to take the sketch just at the moment the
Alabama was going down. We were then about one hundred yards from the
sinking vessel, and about twice that distance from the Federal ship,
and between the two. Our two boats were a little ahead of us and
pulling towards the wreck and the crew, most of whom had jumped
overboard and were floating about on loose spars and other things. One
of the Alabama's boats, after having taken the wounded on board the
Kearsarge, returned and picked up another boatfull, and then came
alongside the Deerhound, where, to prevent her falling into the hands
of the Federals, she was sunk by some of the Alabama's men. The sides
of the Kearsarge were very much cut up, nearly all the chain-plating
being exposed on the starboard side. Just as the Alabama went down,
the mainmast, which had been struck by a shot, fell. The Kearsarge's
boats were not lowered until after the Alabama had disappeared
altogether. I shall be most happy if this sketch will be of any use to
you. It is the most correct you will be able to get as to the position
of the vessels and boats."</p>
<p>We have also engraved on another page of this Number a drawing
which has been made from the plan and information which have been
supplied to our Artist by Mr. George T. Fullam, an officer of the
Alabama. It was he who conveyed the wounded from that vessel to the
Kearsarge, and then came on board the Deerhound, which brought him to
Southampton. He has remarked to our Artist that it is an incident
worth noting, with regard to the damage done to the spars of the
Alabama, that the throat-blocks of both the main and mizen gaffs were
shot away. As we published last week the official report of Captain
Semmes to the agent of the Confederate Government in London, we here
subjoin a letter from the Federal commander, Captain Winslow, who
writes from Cherbourg as follows:--</p>
<q><p>Sir,--There have been so many nonsensical publications on the
engagement which took place between the Alabama and the Kearsarge that
it is my wish that a correction should be made.</p>
<p>In the first place, no challenge was sent by Captain Winslow; to
have done so would have been to have violated the order of the Navy
Department. On the contrary, Captain Winslow received a request from
Captain Semmes not to leave, as he would fight the Kearsarge, and
would only occupy a day or two in his preparations. Five days,
however, elapsed before they were completed. The Kearsarge's battery
consists of seven guns, two 11-inch Dahlgren's, four 12-pounders, one
light rifle 28-pounder. The battery of the Alabama consisted of one
100-pounder rifle, one heavy 68 ditto, six 32-pounder's, that is, one
more gun than the Kearsarge. In the wake of the engines on the outside
the Kearsarge had stopped up and down her sheet chains. These were
stopped by marline to eye bolts, which extended some twenty feet, and
was done by the hands of the Kearsarge; the whole was covered by light
plank, to prevent dirt collecting. It was for the purpose of
protecting the engines when there was no coal in the upper part of the
bunkers, as was the case when the action took place. The Alabama had
her bunkers full, and was equally protected. The Kearsarge went into
action with a crew of 162 officers and men. The Alabama, by report of
the Deerhound's officers, had 150.</p>
<p>The Kearsarge steamed to sea in order that no questions of
neutrality jurisdiction should be raised; when far enough, she turned
short round and steered immediately for the Alabama for close
action. The Alabama fired, as she was coming down on her, two
broadsides and part of another; no one shot came on board of the
Kearsarge. The Kearsarge then sheered and opened on the Alabama,
trying to get nearer. The action lasted one hour and two minutes from
the first to the last shot. The Kearsarge received twenty-eight shots
above and below, thirteen about her hull; the best shots were abaft
the mainmast, two shots which cut the chain stops, the shell of which
broke the casing of wood covering. They were too high to have damaged
the boilers had they penetrated. The Kearsarge was only slightly
damaged, and I supposed the action for hot work had just commenced
when it ended. Such stuff as the Alabama firing when she was going
down, and all such talk, is twaddle. The Alabama towards the last
hoisted sail to get away, when the Kearsarge was laid across her bows,
and would have raked had she not surrendered, which she had done, and
was trying to get her flags down and showing a white flag over the
stern. The officers of the Alabama on board the Kearsarge say that she
was a complete slaughter-house, and was completely torn to
pieces. This is all I know of the Alabama. Yours, &#x0026;c.,</p>
<p rend="right"><hi rend="smallcaps">John A. Winslow</hi>,
Captain.</p></q>
<p>It may be observed that Captain Winslow does not mention the way in
which the officers and crew of the Alabama were saved upon the sinking
of their ship. It is clear, however, that he made no such attempt to
rescue them as a generous enemy would have done; but the log kept on
board the Deerhound records that, when the yacht was passing the
Kearsarge, it was "requested to assist in saving the Alabama's crew."
Both Captain Semmes and Mr. Lancaster have testified that the boats of
the Kearsarge were not sent for that purpose until after the Alabama
had disappeared, though the Alabama had not only surrendered but had
sent her wounded to be received on board the Kearsarge as prisoners of
war. It is therefore probable that, if it had not been for
Mr. Lancaster's prompt interference, Captain Semmes and his brave
comrades would have shared the fate of Mr. Herbert Llewellyn, the
surgeon (an Englishman, the son of a clergyman in Wiltshire), who
perished with their sinking vessel. The Deerhound has therefore
earned, in our opinion, the fairest honours of the day. She was the
object of much curiosity and admiration during her stay at
Southhampton from the Sunday to the Wednesday, when she left that port
for Hull. As we have given her a conspicuous place in the Engraving on
our front page, it may be stated that she is entered on the lists of
the Royal Yacht Squadron of Cowes, the Royal Mersey Yacht Club of
Liverpool, and the (Irish) Royal Western Yacht Club stationed at
Queenstown. She was built, as it happens, upon the same model as the
Alabama, in the same shipyard at Birkenhead, by Messrs. Laird and
Co. She is a three-masted vessel, built of steel, with a
screw-propeller, with a tonnage (builders' measurement) of about 190,
and engines of a nominal power of seventy horse. When in her usual
trim she steams twenty knots, being about two knots beyond the speed
of the Alabama. She carries a crew of thirteen men. The Deerhound now
proceeds from Hull to Norway. Mr. Lancaster and his captain
indignantly deny the statement that an arrangement was made with the
Deerhound by Captain Semmes, before the engagement, that the yacht
should hover about the combatants and render assistance to the
Alabama. They knew that Captain Semmes had determined to engage the
Kearsarge, but no arrangement of any kind was thought of.</p>
<p>The famous Alabama herself, which was originally called "No. 290,"
came from Messrs. Laird's building-yard in July, 1862, and received
her armament and crew at Terceira, in the Azores, whence she started
upon a career most destructive to the maritime commerce of the United
States. She is said to have captured and burnt, in less than two
years, one hundred American vessels. She was a barque-rigged wooden
propeller, of 1040 ton's register. Length of keel, 210 ft.; length
over all, 220 ft.; beam, 32 ft.; depth, 17 ft. Her engines, built by
the same firm, were two horizontal ones, each of 300-horse power, with
stowage for 350 tons of coals. Her sails, carried at all times, were
as follows:--Fore, fore topmast, staysail jib, two large trysails; the
usual square sails on fore and main, with the exception of the
mainsail, which was a flying one; spanker and gaff-topsails; all
standing rigging wire. Double wheel, with motto engraved thereon,
"Aide toi, et Dieu t'aidera," placed just before the mizenmast. Bridge
in the centre, just before the funnel. She carried five boats--viz.,
cutter and launch amidships, gig and whaleboat between the main and
mizen masts, and dingy astern. The main deck was pierced for twelve
gusts, elliptic stern, billet head, high bulwarks; cabin accommodation
first class; wardroom furnished with a handsome suite of state-rooms;
steerage--starboard for midshipmen, port for engineers; next came
engine-room, and coal-bunkers; then the berth deck, capable of
accommodating 120 men; under the wardroom were store-rooms; and under
the steerage were shell-rooms; just forward of the firearms came the
hold; next the magazines, and forward of all the boatswains' and
sailmakers' store-rooms; the hold being under the berth deck.</p>
<p>The Kearsarge, named after a range of hills in Vermont, is a recent
acquisition to the navy of the United States; in fact, she is one of
the nine gun-boats completed within three months from the date of the
order given. She is the sister ship of the Tuscarora, whose presence
in the Solent, during the visit of the Confederate cruiser Nashville
(since destroyed), occasioned considerable excitement some time
since.</p>
<p>A correspondence is published between Captain Winslow and
Mr. Bonfils, the French Confederate agent. Captain Winslow claims as
his prisoners those of the Alabama's crew rescued by pilot-boats, and
brought into Cherbourg. He allowed the pilot-boats to save the
prisoners, from motives of humanity, but if the prisoners endeavour to
free themselves from the obligation they must expect to meet no mercy
another time. Mr. Bonfils replies that there is nothing to hinder even
a surrendered prisoner from escaping if he can, and he declines to act
as a go-between between Captain Winslow and persons he does not even
name; nor can he understand how Captain Winslow can claim to hold
prisoners within the territory of the French empire.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1266.003" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1266</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 3</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>By the steamer Edinburgh we have intelligence from New York to the
morning of the 18th ult.</p>
<p>General Grant has performed an important operation--that of moving
his army to the right bank of the James River. After turning
Spottsylvania Courthouse and Sexton's Junction, he has now turned the
lines of the Chickahominy and the northern defences of Richmond
itself. It remains to be seen what he will benefit by the change. The
mode in which Grant accomplished the flank march will be read with
interest when the details arrive. So far as the telegrams furnish
information, he seems to have covered the embarkation of Smith's corps
at White House by a cavalry demonstration on the right; then to have
made a show of forcing Bottom's Bridge, while the bulk of the army
marched rapidly down the Chickahominy, crossed at Long Bridge, and,
moving east of White Oak Swamp, struck the James in two columns, one
opposite Fort Powhattan, the other at Hasall's Landing, opposite
Bermuda Hundred. While the army was marching to the James, General
Smith's corps, carried in steam-transports from White House, landed at
City Point, as may be inferred, and, moving up the right bank of the
Appomattox, attacked and carried the southern defences of
Petersburg. Hancock came up, it is said, and took post on Smith's
left, and rumour avers that Petersburg fell into the hands of the
Federals the next day. Sheridan's cavalry in the meantime had been
encountered and defeated by the Confederates, but where the telegram
does not say. There appears to have been fighting at Bottom's Bridge,
where Grant crossed the Chickahominy, but with what result is
unknown. The development of Hunter's advance in the higher valleys of
the Shenandoah must have seriously alarmed General Lee, if it be true
that he had sent off a whole corps to attack Hunter and two divisions
to defend Lynchburg. We are not informed at all of the movements of
Lee himself; but it may be inferred that he has moved through Richmond
and taken post on the south. Nor are we told how Hunter got throngh
the Blue Ridge to Lovingston and Amherst. Upon these points we must
wait for information. Richmond journals discuss the military situation
in a very defiant tone, and regard with derision the idea of their
capital being captured.</p>
<p>The latest Federal accounts of General Sherman's operations in
Georgia represented that, on the 12th ult., the Federal army was
within 500 yards of the Confederate position, which was said to extend
from Kenesaw to Lost Mountain. There had been no serious engagement,
and it was reported in New York that General Sherman's troops were
intrenching themselves. A body of 8000 Federals, under General
Sturgis, who had been dispatched from Memphis for the purpose of
frustrating any attempts to impede General Sherman's long line of
communications, had been attacked at Gun Town, in Tennessee, by 10,000
Confederates, under General Forrest, and had been completely
defeated. General Sturgis himself was killed, and all his guns and
stores were captured by the victors, who likewise took a large number
of prisoners.</p>
<p>General Morgan's Confederates had done much damage to the railways
in Kentucky, and had taken, on the 10th ult., the town of Cynthiana,
with two Federal regiments quartered there. On the 11th, however, they
were attacked and defeated by General Burbridge, who made 300 or 400
prisoners and recaptured a few of the Federals taken on the previous
day.</p>
<p>By a vote of eighty-four against fifty-eight the House of
Representatives had repealed the Fugitive Slave Law.</p>
<p>The Senate have rejected the President's amendment of the
Constitution abolishing slavery.</p>
<p>A joint resolution for a final adjournment of Congress on Thursday,
June 23, was adopted.</p>
<p>More than 10,000 emigrants arrived at the port of New York in the
week ending June 4.</p>
<p>There had been a fall in the price of gold. At last accounts it
was quoted at 95&#x00B7; per cent premium.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1266.004" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1266</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 7</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>....Our redoubtable "Manhattan," common-councilman of New York and
correspondent of the <hi rend="italic">Mroning Herald</hi>, has been
summoned before the Military Governor of New York and threatened with
arrest. Pointing to a file of that journal, General Dix told him "that
they had done more harm to the United States than all the New York
papers combined." Only imagine, if we can, the pride of the author
when he heard this! Harm, i'faith; why, Manhattan, sometimes north,
sometimes south, twists about like the revolving lights in a
lighthouse, and flashes now yellow, now rose colour, now blue, all
very pretty to look at, but utterly useless to read by. We knew,
certainly, that there were rocks ahead at New York, and that
Washington was an uncomfortable place to live in; but why imprison a
poor harum-scarum newspaper correspondent for that?....</p>
<p>One is glad to see that the past and present students of
Charing-cross Hospital are about to raise a memorial to the brave
surgeon of the Alabama, Mr. Llewellyn, who went down with that vessel
whilst nobly doing his duty. Both Northern and Southern can show their
sympathies with a brave non-combatant, and his fellow-countrymen may
do it in two places, by either subscribing to the memorial at
Charing-cross or to the one at the little church of his native place
which his fellow-townsmen are about to erect....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1266.005" n="Kerbstone Stockbrokers in New York.--See
      Page 11." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1266</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 8</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv45p8">
<head>KERBSTONE STOCKBROKERS IN NEW YORK.--SEE
      PAGE 11.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1266.006" n="The Fight Between the Alabama and the
      Kearsarge.--See Page 2." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1266</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 9</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv45p9">
<head>THE FIGHT BETWEEN THE ALABAMA AND THE
      KEARSARGE.--SEE PAGE 2.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1266.007" n= "Kerbstone Stockbrokers in New York." type="Article">
<head>KERBSTONE STOCKBROKERS IN NEW YORK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1266</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 11-12</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">KERBSTONE STOCKBROKERS IN NEW YORK.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> prevailing mania just now in the city
of New York is that of gambling in stocks. All classes of people are
naturally intent upon converting fictitious "greenbacks" into some
more substantial and enduring property. Hence the universal spirit of
speculation which drives to the stock market merchants and mechanics,
gamblers and gentlemen, politicians and parsons. Railway shares,
mining companies' stock, and everything else that can, by the greatest
stretch of imagination, be supposed to offer a chance of permanent
investment or rapid profit, will command prices far above par; but
more in request than all other marketable securities is the American
eagle impressed upon gold coin. The Federal Secretary of the Treasury
has so flooded the country with paper "promises to pay," that the
holders are extremely doubtful of their validity, and hasten to
transmute this dubious "Chase currency" into the precious
metal. William-street, in the lower part of New York, is the great
theatre of speculation. In this street and Exchange-place, from the
corner of which our sketch is taken, are innumerable stockbrokers'
offices. Every building on each side of the way contains, on every
floor, luxuriously furnished chambers, the occupants of which have
made, are making, or expect to make their millions out of the
fluctuations of the stock market. There are three distinct marts held
in William-street for the sale of speculative commodities:--First, the
"Regular Board of Brokers," an exclusive and aristocratic fraternity,
whose sessions are held in an ex-Masonic lodge-room, and whose
regulations demand a rigorous ballot and a large initiation fee as
qualifications for membership. This organisation comprises men of the
"first families" of America, persons in good society, and its rules
are supposed to exclude all of doubtful commercial integrity. Next in
order comes the "Public Stock Exchange," held in a building on the
east side of the street (to the left of our Engraving), nearly
opposite the "Regular Board." Here assemble those brokers who are
excluded from the orthodox association, whether by their rejection on
ballot, or by their inability or disinclination to comply with its
code, or because its limited number is filled. Notwithstanding that
the "Public Board" is less strict and less expensive than its
neighbour, there are many of its members who have become millionaires
within the past few months by the magnitude and success of their
transactions; they have built superb mansions and established gorgeous
equipages outvieing those of the richest member of the "Regular
Board." Thirdly, and lastly, there is the "Kerbstone" business--the
common whirlpool of all persons of speculative tendencies who have not
sufficient capital or character to obtain admission into either of the
recognised places of Stock Exchange operations. As the session of the
Public Board draws to its close (about two p.m.), an indiscriminate
throng of all varieties of character and grades of rank, from the
"Fifth <pb n="12"/>   </p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1266.008" n= "The American Mail Steamer at Roche's Point." type="Article">
<head>THE AMERICAN MAIL STEAMER AT ROCHE'S POINT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1266</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 12</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE AMERICAN MAIL STEAMER AT<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">Roche's Point.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Every</hi> reader of the London morning papers
is accustomed at the present time to look for some exciting news of
the American war in that column of large type and short paragraphs
which is headed "By Electric and International Telegraph, vi&#x00E2;
Roche's Point," with the name, perhaps, of one of the Cunard line of
steamers, which may be half way up St. George's Channel, on her way to
Liverpool, at the moment when this intelligence meets the reader's
eye. We have engraved a Sketch of the Scotia lying off Roche's Point
at the entrance of Queenstown Harbour, where she is met by one or two
small boats, to bring the telegraphic despatches to land, when not a
moment is lost in transmitting their message by the electric wire to
London, Liverpool, and every other place concerned in obtaining the
earliest American news. At the same time, a portion of the mails are
taken by the Jackal tender, which is also shown in our Engraving, and
conveyed up the harbour to be forwarded by railway from
Cork.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1266.009" n="The Jackal Tender and Boats Going to Meet
      the American Mail Steamer at Roche's Point, Near Queenstown." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1266</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 12</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-02">July 2, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv45p12">
<head>THE JACKAL TENDER AND BOATS GOING TO MEET
      THE AMERICAN MAIL STEAMER AT ROCHE'S POINT, NEAR QUEENSTOWN.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1267.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1267</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 26-27</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-09">July 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>We have intelligence from New York to the 25th ult. The reported
capture of Petersburg, referred to in our last Number and stated to
require confirmation, is so far from having been confirmed that (as we
were able to state by telegram last week) Grant has been driven from
it with terrible loss. What, doubtless, gave rise to the statement was
the capture by the Federals, under General Smith, of the outer line of
defences of Petersburg, which were then thought to be its main
line. This occurred on the 15th of June. On the 17th, General Grant's
whole army was before Petersburg, and on that day severe fighting was
reported; on the 18th a general assault on the town was three times
made and repulsed with a loss to the Federals estimated at not less
than from 6000 to 8000 men.</p>
<p>The Confederate works were arranged in a semicircle south of
Petersburg, the flanks resting on the Appomatox River. The Federal
army advanced against them on the 18th in three divisions, the Second
Army Corps on the right, the Ninth in the centre, the Fifth on the
left. Hancock, being wounded, was unable to lead his men, and General
Birney commanded the Federal right. The assault was directed towards
the line of the City Point Railroad. The men were led forward to the
certainty of defeat or death. After getting over a fence they had to
cross a wide field exposed to a cross fire from the Confederate
breastworks. As soon as they were seen they were met with deadly
volleys of musketry, grape, and canister from the Southern
defences. Hundreds fell, many were taken prisoners, the rest retreated
in disorder. Reinforcements having been obtained, the Second Corps
formed another storming party. They tried another point of the works
but it was worse than the other. Infantry and artillery met them with
a terrific fire, and the heads of the columns were "lost in clouds of
smoke." It was a forlorn hope. Those in front were mown down and
scattered; the remainder broke and fled. While this was the fate of
the Second Corps, the Fifth Corps, on the Federal left, fought with
equal obstinacy, but found the earthworks in front of it
impregnable. The ground over which these troops advanced had evidently
been long prepared, for it was strewed thickly with an abbattis of
felled timber. The Ninth Corps, in the centre, was utterly routed by a
fierce attack of the Confederates, who rushed into the camp through a
terrible artillery fire, fought the Michigan sharpshooters hand to
hand, and drove them from all their positions. The Southern troops
were again withdrawn during the night to their own impregnable
defences.</p>
<p>After these unsuccessful attempts to force the Confederate
position, Grant appears for some days to have done little or
nothing. With his right flank resting on the Appomattox River, and his
left on the plank-road connecting Petersburg with Graysville, he
seems to have<pb n="27"/> pushed forward his outposts as near as he
conceived prudent to the Confederate intrenchments. On the 19th and
20th there was some slight skirmishing, in which the pickets and their
supports were alone engaged; and it was not until the night of the
21st that Grant resumed active operations. Intending, apparently, to
seek a weaker point in the Confederate lines than that against which
the assaults of the 17th and 18th were directed, the two corps which
formed the right of the Federal army were moved on the night of the
21st across the front of the Federal left, in the direction of the
Petersburg and Norfolk Railway. The ostensible motive was to cover
this line of railway and more completely invest the city of
Petersburg, but the ultimate object was to enable the Federal army to
attack the Confederate position at a point almost due south of the
town of Petersburg. For this man&#x0153;uvre, however, the
Confederates were fully prepared. A strong force under Hill
intercepted the advancing columns of the Federal right wing and
repulsed them with heavy loss both of men and artillery. The following
day, inspirited by this success, General Hill again resumed the
offensive, and, having managed to separate the Second from the Sixth
Army Corps, attacked the former in the rear and drove it in confusion
to its intrenchments, with an estimated loss of three thousand men. On
the 23rd Grant drew up his entire army in order of battle, and on that
day a general engagement was expected. Heavy firing in the direction
of the position of the rival armies was heard at City Point on that
day, but the results of the battle are not known, or not
published.</p>
<p>President Lincoln visited Grant at City Point on the 21st ult.</p>
<p>General Hunter is said to have been repulsed in an attack upon
Lynchburg, but there is no very definite news respecting his
movements.</p>
<p>General Sheridan has been defeated during his raid with heavy
loss. He claims, however, to have seriously injured the Virginia
Central Railroad, south of Gordonsville, and to have defeated the
Confederates at Trevellion Station.</p>
<p>The attitude of General Sherman was not materially changed.</p>
<p>New Orleans advices say that the State of Arkansas is overrun with
guerrillas. The Federals, however, still hold Little Rock and Pine
Bluffs. General Banks was at New Orleans.</p>
<p>The Federal papers state that General Scott has just attained his
seventy-eighth year, and has also just completed the memoirs of his
life.</p>
<p>The bill repealing the Fugitive Slave Law was passed in the
Federal Senate by a vote of 24 against 7. This bill, having passed
both Houses, now simply awaits the President's signature.</p>
<p>In the House of Representatives the Loan Bill was passed. This
bill authorises Secretary Chase to borrow 400,000,000 dols. from time
to time upon six per cent bonds redeemable in five to forty years. The
interest payable in coin semi-annually.</p>
<p>A resolution had been offered in the Federal Senate requesting the
President to inform Congress whether the recruiting in Ireland and
Canada for the Federal army was authorised.</p>
<p>The Constitutional Convention of Maryland has abolished slavery in
that State by a large majority. The <hi rend="italic">New York
Tribune</hi> of June 25 announces the fact in the following
terms:--</p>
<q>Maryland has wheeled into line, and another undimmed star shines
out in the constellation of Free States. Her constitutional
Convention, in Session at Annapolis, passed yesterday the following
article of her Bill of Rights:--"Hereafter in this State there shall
be neither slavery nor involuntary servitude, except in punishment for
crime whereof the party shall have been duly convicted; and all
persons held to service or labour as slaves are hereby declared
free. In every church in the land there ought to-morrow to be offered
solemn prayers of thanksgiving to God that to the people of that
State He has given grace, at length, to obey His mandate to 'Let the
oppressed go free.' A new prosperity will, in due season, follow that
obedience, and her children rejoice that the curse that has rested so
long upon her labour and hindered her growth is removed for ever.</q>
<p>Since the passing of the Gold Bill gold had gone up to 230, but
had declined again to 210. It stood at 219&#x00B7; on the evening of
the 25th ult.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1267.002" n= "The American war-steamer Kearsarge" type="Article">
<head>[THE AMERICAN WAR-STEAMER KEARSARGE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1267</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 27</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-09">July 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The American war-steamer Kearsarge arrived in Dover Road on
Wednesday evening.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1267.003" n= "Messrs. Sampson Low, Son, and Co." type="Article">
<head>[MESSRS. SAMPSON LOW, SON, AND CO.]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1267</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 27</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-09">July 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Messrs. Sampson Low, Son, and Co., of Ludgate-hill, have on view a
fine impression of a steel engraving by T. Barlow, of London, from a
design by the American artist, F. O. C. Dailey, having for its subject
Washington Irving surrounded by his literary friends. The scene is
Irving's library at Sunnyside, and his assembled friends are Prescott,
Cooper, Bancroft, Longfellow, Emerson, Kennedy, Bryant, Paulding,
Hawthorne, Halleck, Holmes, Simms, Tuckerman, and Willis. The
engraving is in the style known as "the line and stipple."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1267.004" n= "The returns compiled by the emigration agent" type="Article">
<head>[THE RETURNS COMPILED BY THE EMIGRATION AGENT]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1267</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 27</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-09">July 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The returns compiled by the emigration agent at Liverpool for the
month of June last, shows the following result:--Vessels under the
Act--United States: Twenty-seven ships, carrying 10,462 passengers, of
which 379 were cabin; of these 2,174 were English, 319 Scotch, 6,399
Irish, and 1101 from other countries. Canada: Five ships, 1163
passengers, of whom 101 were cabin; 471 were English, 325 Irish, 207
other countries. Victoria: Two ships, 823 passengers, including
twenty-six in the cabin; of whom 261 were English, ninety-four Scotch,
412 Irish, and thirty from other countries. South America: One ship,
carrying sixty-three passengers, including two in the cabin, all of
whom were Irish. Total under the Act, 12,511. The returns of short
ships, or those not under the Act were--United States: Seven ships,
476 passengers. Canada: Two ships, thirty-five. South America: One
ship, four. West Indies: One ship, five. Mexico: Two ships,
nine. Africa: One ship, ten. British Columbia: One ship,
thirteen. Making a total of 555 passengers in short ships. Aggregate
for the month, 13,O63; being a decrease as compared with the
corresponding month of the previous year of 2292. The total emigration
from Liverpool for the quarter ending the 30th of June last was
53,586; for the corresponding quarter of 1863, 54,044.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1267.005" n= "The Surgeon of the Alabama." type="Article">
<head>THE SURGEON OF THE ALABAMA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1267</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 41</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-09">July 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE SURGEON OF THE<lb/> ALABAMA.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Mr.</hi> David Herbert Llewellyn, who was the
surgeon of the Confederate war-steamer Alabama during the two years of
her adventurous career, perished by drowning on Sunday, the 19th ult.,
sinking with his ship after her conflict with the Federal steamer
Kearsarge. He was the son of the Rev. David Llewellyn, Perpetual
Curate of Easton, near Pewsey, Wiltshire. He was educated at
Marlborough College, and studied for the medical profession, firstly
as an articled pupil of Dr. Hassall, at Richmond, and then, from 1856
to 1859, at Charing-cross Hospital, where he gained the silver medals
for surgery and chemistry. The last letter which Mr. Llewellyn ever
wrote was addressed to Mr. Travers, the resident medical officer of
Charing-cross Hospital, and is as follows:--" Cherbourg, June 14,
1864. Dear Travers,--Here we are. I send this by gentleman coming to
London. An enemy is outside. If she only stays long enough, we go out
and fight her. If I live, expect to see me in London shortly. If I
die, give my best love to all who know me. If M. A. de Caillet should
call on you, please show him every attention. I remain, dear Travers,
ever yours, <hi rend="smallcaps">D. H. Llewellyn.</hi>" Mr. Llewellyn
was much loved and respected by all on board. In the final struggle of
the Alabama, when the ship was sinking, the whale-boat and dingy, the
only two boats uninjured, were lowered, and the wounded placed in
them, Mr. Fullam being sent in charge of them to the Kearsarge. When
the boats were full, a man (unwounded) endeavoured to enter one, but
Mr. Llewellyn held him back. "See," said he, "I want to save my life
as much as you do; but let the wounded men be saved first." "Doctor,"
said the officer in the boat, "we can make room for you." "I will not
peril the wounded men," was his reply. He remained behind and sank
with the ship, an ever memorable instance of that chivalrous spirit
and devotion to duty which we are proud to believe characterise the
medical officers of the united services and the medical profession
generally in the United Kingdom. It is further gratifying to hear that
Llewellyn's fellow-students have appointed a committee to provide for
the erection of a tablet to his memory in Charing-cross Hospital,
where as a pupil he had so greatly distinguished himself, and that
another memorial is to be fixed in the church of Easton parish, where
he was born. The Portrait of him which we have engraved is from a
photograph taken at the Maison Rideau, Cherbourg, on the Thursday
before his death.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1267.006" n="The Late David Herbert Llewellyn, Surgeon
      Of The Alabama." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1267</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 41</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-09">July 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv45p41">
<head>THE LATE DAVID HERBERT LLEWELLYN, SURGEON
      OF THE ALABAMA.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1267.007" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1267</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 42</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-09">July 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....Another of England's many admirers, Mr. George Francis Train,
has turned up in New York lately from a visit to Abraham Lincoln, at
least so we construe the profanity "Fresh from Abraham's bosom." His
last resting-place has not allowed the effervescence of the London
champagne to subside; for the great author of "Spread Eagledom" is as
wild as ever. "England," he says, and his subject was chosen by his
audience, "is only a little province of France, and a revolution is
coming there. When the Fenian brotherhood rises and fires its guns on
the tops of the mountains," &#x0026;c. Silly brotherhood! why on the
tops of the mountains? Had they not better come down, and listen to
the good sense of Mr. Justice Keogh and those true friends who would
try to regenerate Ireland. The Roman Catholic clergy are beginning to
see that their interest lies also with the Government and the
prosperity of the people; and the best way of showing the true
character of the Fenians is to quote the approval of them by Mr. Train
and the Americans, who in their own battles invariably put the Irish
recruit "in the front...."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1267.008" n= "The Magazines." type="Article">
<head>THE MAGAZINES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1267</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 46</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-09">July 9, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE MAGAZINES.</p>
<p>....<hi rend="italic">Macmillan</hi> proffers a very good
number. The two most interesting contributions relate to America--one
a poem by Longfellow, full of melody and feeling; the other,
Mr. Dicey's slight memoir of his slight acquaintance with Nathaniel
Hawthorne. There is not much to communicate about this shyest of men,
yet Mr. Dicey has succeeded in touching the hermitage of the recluse
with a pencil of light which diminishes without dissipating its
natural obscurity. Hawthorne will never be thoroughly understood until
the American nation shall have had time to develop further examples of
a character not altogether new to it, though never before exhibited in
such completeness, or under circumstances of such interest. The
singular alliance of conscious superiority with morbid humility, of
strong common sense with absolute nulllity in public life, of
vacillation almost ludicrous with perseverance and strength of will,
is not unparalleled in the States, and may be referred to the
conflicting influences of race and institutions on the one hand, and
of physical conditions on the other. The very slightness and
evanescence of Mr. Dicey's reminiscences impart to them the charm of
perfect keeping with their subject. "The Hillyars and the Burtons" and
"A Son of the Soil" are continued in the usual style, and with no
decline in interest. Mr. Maurice contributes a high-minded paper on
bribery at elections. He appears to possess the faith that removes
mountains, at which we rejoice, as it is about the only weapon left to
combat an abuse that has defied every other. A kind and judicious
critique on Miss Lucy Fletcher's poems introduces us to several
compositions by a very young lady who seems to have intuitively
acquired the power of writing with more lucidity and finish than nine
tenths of her contemporaries. These little poems are equally admirable
in point of diction, melody, and sentiment. Sigismund Krasinski's
poem, "Resurrecturis," is, doubtless, very fine in the original but
the prose translation inevitably degenerates into mere rhetoric. We
rather doubt the translator's assertion that Byron was acquainted with
Mickiewicz, and are certain, at all events, that the finest poetry of
the Pole was not produced till after Byron's death, An excellent
number is concluded by a spirited narrative of the bombardment of
Sonderburg.</p>
<p>Like <hi rend="italic">Macmillan, Blackwood</hi> is indebted for
its chief attraction to America--at least we do not think we err in
attributing the two lovely poems on Leonardo da Vinci's "Last Supper,"
to William Washington Story. It is now about six years since the great
sculptor published a volume of poems so saturated with the spirit of
Robert Browning as to deserve no better character than that of a
servile imitation, and to beget a seasonable fear that he would prove
incapable of excellence in original literary composition. These new
poems, however, retain just enough of the mannerism of Browning to
render evident their great superiority in clearness and symmetry. In
pith and masculine force they certainly fall short of Browning, yet
are not unworthy of a disciple. The subject is one on which a man of
Mr. Story's especial gifts deserves to be heard with reverence, a
feeling fully justified by his glowing and prophet-like proclamation
of inspiration from a higher source as as the indispensable condition
of all success in art....</p></div2>


<div2 id="iln45.1268.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1268</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 50-51</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-16">July 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>There is no news of importance from Virginia. General Grant has
made no further attempt to turn the Confederate position at Petersburg
since his defeat on the 22nd ult.</p>
<p>Wilson's cavalry has destroyed twenty miles of the Danville
Railroad. On their return, on the night of the 27th ult., they were
intercepted by the Confederates at Beam's station, on the Weldon and
Petersburg Railroad. Wilson fought all night and the following
morning, but was unable to push his way through. Meade sent the sixth
corps, with a division of the second corps, to the assistance of
Wilson. On the 28th the Confederates were moving in the direction of
the rear of Grant's left.</p>
<p>A special despatch to the <hi rend="italic">New York Times</hi>,
dated Washington, June 29, says:--</p>
<q><p>Latest advices from General Grant's head-quarters report only
such occasional skirmishing and artillery practice as inevitably
result from close proximity of the two forces. The chief enemies our
soldiers have had lately to combat are the heat and dust, which have
even been of the most malignant character. For thirty days not a drop
of rain has fallen, making a drought of a duration unparalleled in
that region for many years. It is with the utmost difficulty, that men
and animals get even a scanty supply of water. General Palmer's raid
from Newbern, on the Wilmington and Weldon Railroad seems to supply a
perfect explanation of the recently-reported march of rebel troops
from Lee's army to North Carolina, on which such absurd speculations
have been based. General Hancock, yesterday morning, resumed command
of the Second Army Corps. On Friday last Acting Master Street, of the
flotilla, obtained information that there were a number of guerrillas
on the peninsula engaged in making torpedoes, and accordingly on that
night he landed with thirty men and proceeded over the country some
ten miles, capturing six persons, among whom was a Confederate captain
and physician, whom he brought off to his vessel.</p></q>
<p>A telegram dated head-quarters of the army of the Potomac, June 28,
five a.m., says:--</p>
<q><p>All remains quiet at the front. Our left wing swung round and
took possession of the Weldon Railroad, about four miles from the
city, without opposition. It is believed the enemy's lines have been
somewhat contracted since Friday last, and the opinion prevails that a
force has been sent to meet and drive back General Hunter.</p></q>
<p>Another despatch, dated the 28th of June, noon, says:--</p>
<q><p>A severe engagement took place on Saturday between our cavalry
and a force of the enemy, consisting of cavalry and mounted infantry,
at the Chickahominy river. The enemy had followed Sheridan from the
White House, in the expectation of being able to cut off part of his
waggon-train, which was very large, and it was here they made their
attack. Jorbet's division was detailed to protect the train, while
Gregg's division was placed in position to resist an attack from the
enemy on the roads which they were known to occupy. At an early hour
skirmishing commenced, and was kept up until noon, when the
Confederate infantry, which had been dismounted, made a desperate
charge on our lines; and although our men dismounted and fought them
gallantly for a time, they were finally compelled to retire, suffering
considerably. Our loss is supposed to be about 1500. Our men fell back
to their supports near the bridge, and the command, with the entire
train, subsequently got over it without further loss. The enemy made
no effort to follow us up, and it is thought they must have suffered
severely. The whole command has arrived at the James River, and will
be across by to-night. There are now about 5000 sick and wounded in
hospital at City Point, and they suffer much from the heat and from a
lack of good water. The members of the different aid societies are
fast giving out from exhaustion and fever, and many of them have been
forced to give up their labours and return home.</p></q>
<p>General Sherman has been repulsed in Georgia with heavy loss. He
reports that two columns of his army, under Macpherson and Thomas,
simultaneously attacked the Confederates at Kenesaw Mountains on the
27th, and were repulsed. He admits Thomas's loss at 2000 and
Macpherson's at 500, among whom were General Harker and four
Colonels. Confederate despatches state the Federal loss at
4500. Sherman believes the Confederate loss to have been light, they
being protected by breastworks. According to a late rumour, General
Sherman was retreating for want of supplies and forage. The
Confederate General Pillow had been operating on Sherman's rear, and
had attacked the town of Lafayette, but was defeated.</p>
<p>General Hunter has been obliged to retreat into Western
Virginia. Mr. Stanton announces that Hunter, finding his ammunition
running short, was retreating to Western Virginia, but reports the
complete success of his expedition to Lynchburg. According to
Hunter's report, he has destroyed much Confederate property and
supplies, and beat the enemy in every engagement. Confederate
despatches of the 25th ult., however state that the Confederates were
pursuing Hunter, and had attacked him several times, captured thirteen
of his cannon and inflicted heavy loss upon him in killed, wounded,
and prisoners.</p>
<p>Mr. Chase, Secretary of the Treasury, has resigned, and Mr. Lincoln
nominated as his successor ex-Governor Todd, of Ohio, who having
declined the appointment, Senator Fessenden, of Maine, was appointed,
and confirmed by the Senate.</p>
<p>President Lincoln, in reply to a resolution of the United States'
Senate, had sent in a communication from the Secretary of State, from
which it appears that no authority has been given by the Executive of
the Federal Government, or by any executive department, to anyone,
either in the United States or elsewhere, to obtain recruits either
in Ireland or Canada, or in any foreign country, for either the army
or the navy of the United States; and, on the contrary, that whenever
application for such authority has been made, it has been refused and
absolutely withheld.</p>
<p>The following is President Lincoln's letter accepting the
nomination for the Presidency:--</p>
<q><p rend="right">Executive Mansion, Washington, June 27, 1864.</p>
<p>Gentlemen,--Your letter of the 14th inst., formally notifying me
that I have been nominated by the Convention you represent for the
presidency of the United States for four years from the 4th of March
next has been received. The nomination is gratefully accepted, as the
resolutions of the Convention called the platform are heartily
approved. While the resolution in regard to the supplanting of
Republican government upon the western continent is fully concurred
in, there might be misunderstanding were I not to say that the
position of the Government in relation to the action of France in
Mexico, as assumed through the State Department and endorsed by the
Convention among the measures and acts of the Executive, will be
faithfully maintained so long as the state of facts shall leave that
position permanent and applicable. I am especially gratified that the
soldier and the seaman were not forgotten by the Convention, as they
for ever must and will be remembered by the grateful country for whose
salvation they devote their lives. Thanking you for the kind and the
complimentary terms in which you have communicated the nomination and
other proceedings of the Convention, I subscribe myself your obedient
servant, <hi rend="smallcaps">Abraham Lincoln</hi>.</p></q>
<p>Congress has repealed the Gold Bill.</p>
<p>In Congress, on the 29th ult., a joint resolution, on the motion of
Mr. Harlan, of Iowa, was adopted, that the President of the United
States be requested to appoint a day for humiliation and prayer by the
people of the United States, to confess and to repent of their
manifold sins, to implore the compassion and forgiveness of the
Almighty "that, if consistent with his will, the existing rebellion
may be speedily suppressed, and the supremacy of the Constitution and
laws of the United States established throughout all the States."</p>
<p>In the Senate, on the 25th ult., the report of the Conference
Committee, appointed to adjust the disagreements of the two Houses on
the Internal Revenue Bill, was submitted and adopted. As the report
was also concurred in by the House of Representatives, the bill now
only needs the President's signature to become law. As now finally
fixed upon, the tax on whisky will be one dollar and a half per
gallon after the 1st of July till the 1st of February next, after
which it will be two dollars per gallon. On incomes the tax is 5 per
cent on all over 600 dols. and not exceeding 5000 dols.; on incomes
from 5000 dols. to 10,000 dols., 7&#x00BD; per cent; exceeding 10,000
dollars, 10 per cent.</p>
<p>In the House of Representatives the session was an excited one. The
bill amendatory of the Enrolment Act was taken up. The principal point
at issue was the proposition to repeal the 300 dollars commutation
clause. The debate was a very animated one, and at times<pb n="51"/>
became very personal and bitter. Mr. Fernando Wood, of New York, made
a speech denouncing the war and insisting that it should be
immediately stopped. He became so violent in his remarks that he was
hissed by the members.</p>
<p>Gold opened at 250, rose to 282, but declined to 260 on
Mr. Fessenden's confirmation to the secretaryship of the Treasury, and
to 230 on the repeal of the Gold Bill by the Senate.</p>
<p>It appears that General Bishop Polk was killed in battle in Georgia
on the 14th ult. The Bishop graduated at the West Point military
seminary in 1827, but Bishop M'Ilvaine, who was then Chaplain at that
place, persuaded him to enter the Church, and he afterwards became
Bishop of Louisiana. He inherited a good estate, with many slaves, and
his ideas were always intensely Southern. When the present war broke
out he entered the Confederate army, and was made a
Brigadier-General. He never resigned his bishopric, probably intending
at the close of the war to resume his spiritual functions.</p>
<p>Mr. Joseph F. Scoville, the well-known correspondent ("Manhattan")
of the <hi rend="italic">Standard</hi> and <hi
rend="italic">Herald</hi>, died suddenly in New York on the morning of
the 25th ult. of inflammation of the lungs. He had been summoned
recently before General Dix to answer for some of his statements in
his letters, and received a warning. He was in the fiftieth year of
his age.</p>
<p>Three hundred Swedish and Norwegian emigrants arrived in Chicago on
Sunday morning by the Michigan Southern Railroad. One portion of them
will go into Missouri, the other portion left for Minnesota.</p>
<p>The heat in New York had been intense. On the afternoon of the 25th
ult. the mercury mounted to 97 deg. in the shade. Several cases of
sunstroke had occurred.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1268.002" n="'Our Special Artist,' On Board the
      Lilian, Running the Blockade into Wilmington Harbour, North
      Carolina.--See Page 70." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1268</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 60</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-16">July 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv45p60">
<head>'OUR SPECIAL ARTIST,' ON BOARD THE
      LILIAN, RUNNING THE BLOCKADE INTO WILMINGTON HARBOUR, NORTH
      CAROLINA.--SEE PAGE 70.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1268.003" n= "The steamer Wonder" type="Article">
<head>[THE STEAMER WONDER]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1268</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 62</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-16">July 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>The steamer Wonder, which arrived at Southampton, on Thursday from
the Channel Islands, reports that the Federal steamer Kearsarge and
the Confederate steamer Florida had an engagement off Jersey on
Wednesday, in which the Kearsarge was disabled and put into Gorey. The
Florida was brought up off Gorey, waiting to renew the
engagement.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1268.004" n= "A letter from Calais" type="Article">
<head>[A LETTER FROM CALAIS]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1268</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 62</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-16">July 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>A letter from Calais states that the Confederate vessel the
Rappahannock, at present in that port, lately had a judgment
pronounced against her by the Chamber of Commerce of Boulogne for
commercial debts of the captain. It appears that when the <hi
rend="italic">huissier</hi> charged to affix the notice of sale made
his appearance on board the vessel the captain warned him off without
delay, as no such errand should be performed there. The <hi
rend="italic">huissier</hi> had nothing else to do but retire and draw
up a <hi rend="italic">proces-verbal</hi>.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1268.005" n= "Running the Blockade into the Port of
      Wilmington, North Carolina." type="Article">
<head>RUNNING THE BLOCKADE INTO THE PORT OF WILMINTON, NORTH CAROLINA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1268</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 70</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-16">July 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">RUNNING THE BLOCKADE INTO THE PORT OF<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">WILMINGTON, NORTH CAROLINA.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">We</hi> have received from our Special Artist,
who, after a short interval of repose in England, has returned to the
seat of war in America and safely arrived at the camp of General Lee,
a Sketch of the scene on board the blockade-running steamer Lilian as
she entered the port of Wilmington, in the Confederate States, passing
unharmed the squadron of Federal cruisers, on the morning of June
4. The special correspondent of the <hi rend="italic">Times</hi>, who
was a passenger on board the same vessel, has contributed to that
journal a narrative of the run from Bermuda to Wilmington, which may
be quoted as a commentary on the Illustration we have engraved:--</p>
<p>"Upon the evening of Wednesday, the 1st of June, the Lilian and the
Florie, two of the fleetest and most beautiful of the blockade-defying
vessels, started simultaneously from Bermuda upon the first trip
inward which either had ever made. Both belong to the same company,
but there is an emulation between the two rival vessels which is not
satisfactorily allayed by their experiences hitherto, but which waits
the solution of further trial. The weather was lovely,the sea like a
milldam, and favourable beyond expression to light draught and
gossamer craft, such as are these blockade-runners, which lightly
scratch the surface instead of clutching the ribs of old ocean, and
which in summer seas have no more to fear from heavy seagoing craft,
like the Rhode Island or the Vanderbilt, than has the Irish
freight-express from the lumbering freight-train which leaves
Euston-square five minutes in its rear. Rarely have two more
attractive prizes slipped through the meshes of the blockade than the
two vessels of which I am writing. It is not alone that they would be
invaluable with a view to their conversion into Federal cruisers, or
that two of the most valuable cargoes which have yet reached
Wilmington await at this instant the disposal of the Confederate
Government, but that on board both vessels were Confederate
'malignants,' whose capture would have been a sweet morsel to many a
craving palate in Washington and Boston. To many an English reader the
name of Captain Maffit, lately in command of the Confederate cruiser
Florida, well known as having assisted Captain Semmes and the Alabama
demonstrate that two light, and, as regards equipment, comparatively
insignificant vessels of war would have little difficulty in driving
from the ocean a flag which, three years ago, might have been seen
upon every wave of every sea.</p>
<p>"My experience on board the Lilian leads me to anticipate for
Captain Maffit and his vessel--a credit to her builders,
Messrs. Thompson, of Glasgow--a long and prosperous career. An
incident which occurred 200 miles from Wilmington, in a portion of the
ocean which is constantly swept by Federal cruisers, seems worthy of
record. Upon our port bow was descried a sail enveloped in a dense
canopy of smoke. Time was ineffably precious--there was every reason
to suspect Yankee guile, which is said to be nowhere more fertilely
exhibited than in their conduct of the blockade; but is was deemed
possible, after careful scrutiny, that the vessel might be on
fire. Briefly remarking, 'The ship which leaves a companion at sea in
distress must be accursed,' Captain Maffit ordered our course to be
altered, and bore down upon the stranger. It soon became evident that
she was a Federal cruiser, making a dense white smoke with her
Cumberland coal, and beating rapidly eastward in apparent pursuit of
another delinquent. The helm was rapidly changed, and our course
resumed. Dark and inscrutable came on the noon, defying all
possibility of an observation. It was believed that ere the morrow's
dawn should break we might reach Wilmington, and onward we
pressed. The night wore rapidly away; two o'clock, three o'clock, half
past three o'clock in the morning came, but by no eye peering through
the thick gloom could the looked-for light at Fort Fisher be
discerned. Then, as the morning dawned, we prepared to lay-to for the
day, between the outer and inner cordon of the blockaders. It was
hardly to be expected that we should escape for sixteen hours
unobserved; but it was a signal instance of good luck that from four
in the morning till half-past one p. m., we were unmolested. Then the
tall masts of a large Federal cruiser, and her immense paddlewheels
and lofty black hull were visible, and for the first time, as our
antagonist approached us from the direction of Wilmington, the 'airy
fairy Lilian' prepared to give us assurance of that speed which we all
felt she possessed. Some slight delay there was before steam could be
fully got up, and for some twenty minutes our pursuer seemed to gain
upon us. But as the pressure of steam ascended from fifteen pounds to
twenty, from twenty to twenty-three, from twenty-three to twenty-six,
and as the revolutions of the paddle mounted from twenty-six to
twenty-eight, from twenty-eight to thirty-three per minute, the Lilian
flew out to sea swift as arrow from a bow. In little more than two
hours the hull of our pursuer was invisible, and her topgallant sails
a speck upon the distant horizon. But as she still lay between us and
Wilmington it became necessary to run round her. This also the
light-heeled Lilian had little difficulty in accomplishing; but as the
sun dropped into the sea, and our pursuer, although distant, still
hung upon our rear, we found that, reckoning little the speed of our
advance, we had sighted the inside blockade squadron before the close
of day. There was nothing for it but to persevere, and fortunately,
before we approached close to land, darkness had completely set
in. Silently and with bated breath we passed cruiser after cruiser,
distinctly visible to every eye, and suggesting the flashing out of a
blue or Drummond light, and the rush of grape-shot and shrapnel
through our rigging and bulwarks. But it was not destined that upon
this occasion the Lilian should receive her baptism of fire. Just as
we approach Fort Fisher a dark spot is seen on the bar. It is a
Federal launch, seen by us too late for Captain Maffit to indulge the
anxious wish of his heart and to run her down. We pass her within
twenty yards, and again the expected volley of musketry is
wanting. Another moment and we are under the mound upon which stands
the fort, and eagerly questioned for news. 'The news is good all
round.' 'Three times three for General Johnston;' 'six times six for
General Lee;' and in mirth and laughter and song the night wears
away. Three hours after us comes the Florie, and is heavily fired at
as she wears inwards. But morning finds both vessels and their cargoes
safe at their wharf in Wilmington, nor is it rash to predict for them
both the probability of many returns. At least it may safely be
augered that it will take no ordinary amount of speed and courage to
circumvent so fearless and experienced a sailor as Captain Maffitt,
and that in his new career his skill and success will be not inferior
to those which he exhibited in his old.</p>
<p>"As an illustration of the facility and certainty with which the
blockade is now defied, I will mention, in conclusion, a few
facts. Between the 1st of May and the 1st of June no less than
twenty-four vessels made the port of Wilmington safely, without
disaster befalling a single vessel. No wonder that piles upon piles of
Government goods are stored here, awaiting, when there is less strain
upon the railroads, transportation to Richmond and Atlanta. I am
informed by the Government agent here that in his whole experience he
has never lost a single outward-bound letter. A gentleman at Bermuda,
the agent of an eminent English firm, told me that during two years he
had sent an average of three mails per month from Bermuda and Nassau
into Secessia, and that in the whole time only two mails had been
lost."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1268.006" n= "The New York Sun States" type="Article">
<head>[THE NEW YORK SUN STATES]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1268</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 71</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-16">July 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The New York <hi rend="italic">Sun</hi> states that M. Gouraud,
Vice-Consul of France for Rhode Island, has made application for a
patent for his aerostatic railway, to be worked by atmospheric forces
upon inclined planes of wire suspended in the air. It is proposed to
apply it to street railways, for crowded thoroughfares in populous
cities.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1268.007" n= "Richmond." type="Article">
<head>RICHMOND.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1268</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 71</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-16">July 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">RICHMOND</hi>.--The city of Richmond, by the
last census, had a population of 38,000 souls, but the great influx of
civil and military officers ad refugees from other parts of the State
has probably raised it to a much higher figure. It is situated at the
head of tide-water, at the lower falls of James River, about 150 miles
from its mouth. The city occupies a most picturesque situation, being
built on Richmond and Shockhoe hills, which are separated by Shockhoe
Creek and surrounded by beautiful scenery. It is regularly laid out
and well built, the streets, which are lighted with gas, crossing each
other at right angles. On Shockhoe-hill are the State Capitol and
other public buildings. The Capitol is an imposing edifice, and
contains, in its central hall, Houden's celebrated statue of
Washington. On the east of the square is the Governor's
mansion. Jefferson Davis's residence is a private mansion, which was
purchased for him by the Confederate Government. The city has many
fine public buildings, six banks, thirteen newspapers, and
twenty-three churches. In one of the three Presbyterian churches
Jefferson Davis worships. The falls of James River afford immense
water-power, and there are very extensive factories, including four
cotton and about fifty tobacco factories, flour mills, rolling mills,
forges, furnaces, machine shops, &#x0026;c., the latter of which, and
particularly the Tredegar Ironworks, have been of immense service to
the rebels in turning out ordnance and material of war. The annual
exports of Richmond before the rebellion reached nearly 7,000,000
dols. and its imports 750,000 dols. But since it had the honour of
being the rebel capital its foreign commerce has been
extinguished. Vessels or gun-boats drawing ten feet can ascend to
within a mile of the city, at a place called the Rockets. Vessels of
fifteen feet draught ascend to Warwick, three miles below. A canal has
been built around the falls, and above them there is navigation for
200 miles. The James River and Kanawha Canal, intended to extend to
Covington, is completed for 200 miles. Richmond has very extensive
railroad communications, being the terminus of five roads, running to
Fredericksburg and the Potomac, to West Point and the York River,
Petersburg and Norfolk, to Danville, Virginia, to Jackson's River, by
the Central Railroad, and from these the connections lead all through
the Southern States. Opposite the city are the two towns of Spring
Hill and Manchester. Richmond was founded in 1742, became the capital
of the State of Virginia in 1779, and in June, 1861, it was made the
seat of Government of the "Confederate States of America," whose
Congress assembled there on July 20. Its history since then is only
too familiar to the country. Around the city are various hills,
extending a great distance, on the most important of which
fortifications were erected in the days of the "On to Richmond"
cry.--<hi rend="italic">New York Tribune.</hi></p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1268.008" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1268</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 74</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-16">July 16, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....In America, History notes not so much the failure of Grant's
expedition and the struggle for the presidency as the first
influential cry for further division of the once great
Republic. Colonel Anderson, brother to Major Anderson, who defended
Fort Sumter, writes a letter full of Americanisms and plain
sense. "Rampant war has yoked her red dragons to her iron car, and all
humamity is trampled under foot. Our generals blush behind the buckler
of Mars, and that she-devil Bellona lights us on. I am for peace; for
a total and immediate cessation of war. I am tired of Yankee
taskmasters; I hate their selfish meanness. Let us have a Western
Confederacy!" Elsewhere Colonel Anderson wishes to follow "the bright
sparkling waters of the Ohio, down to the father of the waters--down
to the ocean of peace;" adding, "The original Union is dissolved; no
man is fool enough to doubt it. The Union is dissolved," Now, although
this may remind one of Elijah Pegram, and the bright home of the
American eagle being in the settin' sun, still it is a great sign of
the times. Many men must think with this honest gentleman, and, if so,
the beginning of the end, although a long end, perhaps, of the
American war has commenced....</p>
<p>Two celebrated personages--one being an abstraction--may be placed
in the obituary. The abstraction is <hi rend="italic">The Owl</hi>,
which, after No. 1006 (it began at No. 1001), ceases to be. It
contained early information of marriages, and picked up the whispers
of the Foreign Office. The other is "Manhattan," the New York
correspondent of the <hi rend="italic">Standard</hi>, a writer who
always amused, but never instructed. He held a dashing pen, which many
will miss; he overthrew alike propriety and grammar; and his vivid
pictures were like those figures which pass before a concave
mirror--you saw them plainly enough, but the next moment forgot
them. Peace be to his ashes! A rabid Northerner at one time, he had
honestly thought himself round to General Scott's opinion, and wanted
to let the "wayward sisters go in peace...."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1270.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1270</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 82</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-23">July 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>The Confederates are not acting wholly on the defensive. An
advance--by some termed an invasion, by others a raid for horses,
forage, and other plunder, but at all events an advance--has been made
into Maryland by a Confederate force. Our information respecting this
movement is confused and conflicting; and all that can he safely said
is that a body of Southern troops, estimated by Mr. Lincoln at from
15,000 to 20,000 (according to other accounts 30,000) strong, and
represented to be led by General Ewell, had taken possession of
Harper's Ferry and Hagerstown in Maryland, throwing out in various
directions what are described as marauding parties. No opposition
appears to have been offered to the progress of the invading column,
which must have slipped quietly along the Shenandoah Valley until it
reached Martinsburg, which was occupied by General Siegel. At this
point some severe fighting took place, but the Federals were obliged
to fall back to Harper's Ferry, which they in turn evacuated,
apparently without striking a blow for its defence. General Siegel
retired to Maryland Heights, and the Confederate are reported to have
been preparing to attack that position. Our present advices throw as
little light upon the subject as upon the strength of this expedition;
but Mr. Lincoln had called upon the States of New York, Pennsylvania,
and Massachusetts to send about 30,000 militia into the field to meet
this unexpected movement on the part of the Confederates. General
Hunter is moving northwards to attack the invaders. Great alarm, it is
said, was felt along the Pennsylvanian border respecting the position
of General Hunter, to whose force the people of the North had been
looking for protection against the Confederate invasion. A New York
telegram of the 8th stated that Hunter had reached Parkersburg, and
that he was hurrying on to Maryland. A telegram dated the 9th affirms,
on the other hand, that the latest accounts from that officer's
command left him at Charlestown, with his army dispirited and weakened
by long marches. Governor Seymour is said to have instructed the
General commanding the militia of New York not to allow any of his men
to leave the State for Washington until further orders.</p>
<p>From the neighbourhood of Petersburg there is no news of
importance, although it was expected that General Grant was nearly
ready for another demonstration. General Smith on the 30th ult. made
an attempt on one of the Confederate works; but owing, it is stated to
a misunderstanding of his orders, the troops were so disposed that the
enemy's artillery cut them up and they were obliged to retire. Next
day the Confederates made an attack on a position where the Federals
were planning a new battery, but they were repulsed with great
loss. General Wilson had succeeded in rejoining the army of the
Potomac, but with the loss of a considerable number of men and twelve
pieces of artillery. He is said to have destroyed sixty miles of the
Danville Railway.</p>
<p>Turning to the campaign in Georgia, we find that General Johnston
evacuated Kenesaw Mountain and Marietta on the 3rd, and that General
Sherman was following him.</p>
<p>At New York the dispute between the Federal and the State
authorities was not closed. The President, it is said, had ordered
General Dix to disregard the civil actions against him in respect of
the seizure of the <hi rend="italic">New York World</hi> and the <hi
rend="italic">Journal of Commerce</hi>. Governor Seymour, on the other
hand, was reported to be resolved on enforcing the civil actions and
ordering General Dix's arrest. The Governor had called for 75,000
additional militia, probably to secure the State against any possible
attack of the Confederates.</p>
<p>President Lincoln has appointed the 8th of August for a day of
humiliation and prayer.</p>
<p>Martial law has been proclaimed and the Habeas Corpus Act suspended
in Kentucky.</p>
<p>On the 3rd inst. died, at the venerable age of ninety-three, the
Hon. Josiah Quincy, of Boston, Massachusetts, a distinguished
statesman, a true patriot, born a British subject, five years older
than the Declaration of Independence, which his countrymen celebrated
on the 4th inst. for the eighty-eighth time, and sixteen years older
than the Union and the Federal Constitution.</p>
<p>Mr. Fessenden has definitively accepted the secretaryship to the
Treasury at Washington.</p>
<p>At the last accounts gold was quoted at 275.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps">Latest From Richmond.</hi></p>
<p>An English gentleman who left Richmond on the 1st. inst., having
previously visited Petersburg, and who, passing uninterruptedly into
the Federal territory, accomplished the journey between Richmond and
Queenstown in the remarkably short time of sixteen days, gives the
following particulars of the military situation in and around the
Confederate capital:--</p>
<q><p>The troops detached by way of the Shenandoah Valley towards
Maryland consisted of the whole of Ewell's corps (late Stonewall
Jackson's) under the personal command of that General, and numbered
25,000 men.</p>
<p>It was believed that another smaller detachment, with heavy
artillery, would be or had already been directed towards Acquia Creek,
with a view of creating powerful batteries on the Potomac, blockading
that river, and thus interrupting the water communication with
Washington, at the same time that Ewell's corps would destroy the
Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, and thus cut the main line of
communication with the capital.</p>
<p>Ewell's force was considered amply strong enough to cope with any
troops which the North in its present denuded condition could oppose
to it, and it was believed that as soon as the offensive movement of
the Confederates became developed in its true proportions the Federal
Government would recal Grant's whole army. No corps of observation
which Grant might leave behind on embarking could hold its ground
against a combined land and naval attack from Richmond.</p>
<p>Nearly 3000 prisoners had been brought in from Wilson's corps, so
that his entire loss could not be less than between 4000 and 5000. He
had lost all his artillery trains and stores; in fact, only just
escaped total destruction. About twenty miles of the track of the
Danville Railroad was destroyed by him; but as there are no important
bridges on that portion of the track, the "Corps of Constructions"--a
corps of railway engineers and labourers specially formed for such
purposes--would be able to repair the damage in less than two
weeks.</p>
<p>The balance of prisoners in favour of the Confederates during the
Virginia campaign alone was estimated at no less than 10,000. A great
portion of the prisoners are stragglers, who voluntarily came into the
Confederate lines and surrendered themselves. They report that in
Grant's army so frequent had become the practice of self-mutilation,
generally by shooting or cutting off a finger, that an order has been
issued severely punishing the men as soon as their self-made wounds
are healed, and then sending them as labourers under guard into the
trenches. Besides malarious fevers, very malignant bowel complaints,
caused by the bad water and the pulverised sand, with which the
atmosphere is surcharged, had appeared, and threatened to become
epidemic in the Federal army.</p>
<p>Grant was leisurely shelling Petersburg at a distance of about two
miles, but doing little damage. Communications between that city and
Richmond were perfect and not in the least disturbed. No scarcity was
apprehended of provisions. The army was healthy and in excellent
spirits. At no time had the Confederates been more sanguine. It was
generally considered that General Lee was indisputably master of the
situation and that the war could not be prolonged much beyond the
present campaign.</p>
<p>There was no distress, but also no excitement, in Richmond. A
solemn earnestness and calm confidence pervaded all classes. The
theatres had been closed. The churches were constantly open for
prayer, and thronged day and night with soldiers and civilians. The
houses of the wealthier citizens were so many open private hospitals,
and the ladies unremitting in their care of the sick and
wounded. Mr. Davis's health was good. Foreign exchange had fallen to
1500, but was little in demand. The prices of most commodities had
declined, owing to the gradual absorption of the redundant currency by
taxes and the funding system.</p>
<p>The Confederate Congress, previous to its adjournment on the 14th
ult., had, in view of the contemplated offensive movements, issued a
manifesto, chiefly, though not in express terms, addressed to the
people of the North. In this the earnest desire of the Confederate
States for peace is set forth in eloquent language; the war is
declared to be one only of self-preservation, and all intentions of
conquest or of impeding the happiness and development of the Northern
States is most distinctly disclaimed.</p></q></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1270.002" n= "Newspaper Correspondents at the Seat of
      War." type="Article">
<head>NEWSPAPER CORRESPONDENTS AT THE SEAT OF WAR.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1270</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 83</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-23">July 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Newspaper Correspondents At The Seat Of
War.</hi>--I was writing in my tent yesterday when a Mini&#x00E9;
bullet came whizzing through the canvas, passing just by Captain
Bradly, Captain Zaft, and Lieutenant Dawkens, of General Wood's Staff,
who were sitting inside. It completely disturbed my reflective powers
for the time being. Another struck me lately in the breast, passing
through my coat and vest; but, fortunately for me, I had my portfolio
full of paper inside, through which it also passed, but did me no
serious injury. I intend carrying my life preserver home with
me. Mr. Bearrie, of the Cincinnati <hi rend="italic">Times</hi>, had
his portfolio shot through in his hand, and Mr. Furey, of the
Cincinnati <hi rend="italic">Gazette</hi>, was at supper, when an
unceremonious shell came and took away his candle, leaving him a dark
subject. Here we get accustomed to such things.--<hi rend="italic">New
York Paper.</hi></p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1270.003" n= "A Baltimore paper says" type="Article">
<head>[A BALTIMORE PAPER SAYS]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1270</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 90</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-23">July 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A Baltimore paper says:--"Our harbour has been on fire for the last
twenty-four hours: literally on fire. The surface of the water for
thousands of square yards has been a perfect flame, caused by the
destruction of the Italian ship Juliana, which took fire whilst lying
at the wharf and loading with petroleum. She had on board 1800
barrels, and had to be towed over to the opposite side of the basin to
save the surrounding property. As the barrels burst, the oil spread
over the water in a flame."</p>
<p>A New York paper relates the following singular occurrence at the
scene of war. A sergeant had been engaged placing upon a number of
headboards the names of members of his regiment who had been killed in
the late fight. There was one board in excess, and in a sportive vein
he placed with a lead-pencil his own name upon it, and the date of his
demise, June 20, as his term of service had then expired and he was
about to leave for home. A day or two after, while bidding his
companions farewell, he was struck on the breast by a 20-pounder
Parrott, and instantly killed. The very headboard he had unthinkingly
inscribed with his own name was placed ever his grave, which, with
date, correctly marks his resting-place.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1270.004" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1270</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 91</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-23">July 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....A trial between two publishers reveals an unwholesome feeling
amongst the gentlemen engaged in that trade. Burly Sam Johnson, who
hated <hi rend="italic">his</hi> publishers with a reason, has a
burlesque line which will here apply:--</p>
<p rend="center">Who drives fat oxen should himself be fat.</p>
<p>Messrs. Sampson Low, Son, and Marston buy an American book,
probably <hi rend="italic">more Americano</hi>, rubbish. Nevertheless,
it is theirs, and they fairly advertise to the world the fact. Another
publisher receives an American copy of the work, and forthwith issues
the book at an eighth of the first publisher's price. Hence an
injunction, and, of course, irritated feelings; and, through the
stupidity of the lawyers engaged, the case brekas down, again to be
taken up, however. "Haunted Hearts" is the name of the prize for which
these gentlemen contend. Would not all hearts have been more at ease
if publishers made a compact not to touch books which others have
announced, and, while the Americans deny us the right of copyright, to
encourage English authors and leave Yankee rubbish over the water?</p>
<p>It is cheering to find that we have those amongst us who yet
believe in the possibility of mediating in America. A deputation of
gentlemen, with whom were Admiral Anson and Mr. James Spence (the "S"
of the <hi rend="italic">Times</hi>), waited on Lord Palmerston to
urge the propriety of such a step. The jaunty Minister quoted a
Hudibrastic couplet about the common result of interposing in
quarrels, and said that, although England was not afraid of the
"bloody nose" therein promised, still the time of mediation was not
yet come. Surely, a mesesge from over the sea by the Queen herself, or
a letter in her own Royal hand expressive of her own and her people's
sorrow at the excessive destruction of human life, would not meet with
insult, and might form a basis for the peace party in America to work
upon. There is nothing so heartless as red tape; could we not in this
extremity do without it?</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1270.005" n= "The Petroleum Oil-fields at Franklin, Pennsylvania." type="Article">
<head>THE PETROLEUM OIL-FIELDS AT FRANKLIN, PENNSYLVANIA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1270</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 99</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-23">July 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center">THE PETROLEUM OIL-FIELDS AT FRANKLIN,<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">PENNSYLVANIA.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">In</hi> this Number of our Journal will be
found a couple of Illustrations of the locality of the petroleum
oil-springs at Franklin, in the State of Pennsylvania, that wonderful
natural production which has lately given rise to a most lucrative
commerce. The qualities of petroleum, or mineral oil, are, indeed, by
no means a modern discovery, and its existence in many parts of the
globe, especially in some countries of Asia, has been proved by the
instances of spontaneous combustion which many ancient historians have
recorded. In the island of Trinidad, in the State of Virginia, and at
Enniskillen, in Western Canada, there is abundance of this valuable
product; but for a long time no efforts were made to obtain it for the
use of mankind. It was not till 1857 that operations were commenced
for the distillation of the bitumen at Enniskillen, and the operators
then speedily discovered that by sinking wells a similar material
might be obtained in a fluid state. Large quantities of oil were thus
procured. Two years later a well was sunk to the depth of seventy
feet, in Venango County, Pennsylvania. The oil flowed with such force
that for many weeks 1000 gallons per day were obtained from this
well. Other wells were speedily sunk, many of which yielded large
quantities of oil. In some districts the earth is saturated with the
oil, and, occasionally, a porous sandstone or limestone will yield
considerable quantities. More commonly, however, the oil is collected
in fissures in the rocks, at various depths below the surface. In some
cases an ample supply of oil is obtained at a depth of 40 ft., while
other wells are sunk as low as 120 ft. to 160 ft. deep. At Titusville,
Pennsylvania, there are wells of the depth of 590 ft. Usually, when
the oil is reached, the pressure of the gas in the fissure forces it
up, and it flows for some time to the surface. As soon as the oil has
ceased flowing, a pump is employed. Sometimes the oil continues to
flow spontaneously, and with such force as to defy every effort to
control it. The quantity of oil yielded by the wells varies, however,
considerably, some wells producing only ten barrels per day, and
others as much as 300 barrels.</p>
<p>The apparatus to be seen at Oil Creek is of a simple description,
consisting of large wooden cisterns sunk in the ground to receive the
oil which rises through tubes let down into the borings. It is then
drawn from the cisterns and put into barrels for exportation. The
cisterns are covered, to prevent evaporation, and their leaking is
ingeniously prevented by surrounding them with a trench full of water,
as the greater specific gravity of the water forbids the oil to escape
through it. The casks or barrels of crude oil are conveyed from the
Franklin and Titusville stations by the Atlantic and Great Western
Railway--a branch of which, fifty-four miles in length, has lately
been constructed for this traffic. The Atlantic and Great Western is a
line of 400 miles, to Salamanca, on the New York and Erie line,
connecting the great town of Cincinnati, and that of St. Louis, still
farther west, with the port of Cleveland on Lake Erie and with the
railway to New York, by which an immense export trade in grain and
salt meat is carried on. This important means of communication between
the most productive region of the western continent and the Atlantic
seaboard was formed by a company of which Mr. James M'Henry, of
London, and Senor Salamanca, the well-known Spanish capitalist, are
the chief promoters. They began their work in the spring of 1862,
taking five thousand English "navvies" to America for the
purpose. They obtained the requisite funds by mortgaging the first
section of the line when completed, allowing 7 per cent interest on
their debentures, and relying upon the high profits which a railway
passing through this district--the gateway of the north-western
States--was certain to yield. Their operations have been effected with
extraordinary rapidity and success, notwithstanding the civil war. Two
hundred miles of railway were constructed in as many days before the
end of 1862, and 145 miles were added in the course of 1863. The line
is now opened throughout its entire length, traversing the fertile
States of Pennsylvania and Ohio and enabling goods or passengers to
travel from New York to St. Louis, near the confluence of the
Mississippi and Missouri, without a change of carriage. The corn of
the Western States, the coal and iron of Pennsylvania, and probably,
when peace shall be restored, some of the cotton of the South, will by
this means find its way, along with the petroleum oil from Franklin
and other stations, to the main outlet of American maritime
commerce. The Oil Creek branch alone has just paid a dividend of 25
per cent on its first year's working. The New York and Erie, and the
Ohio and Mississippi lines, by the completion of the Atlantic and
Great Western, which links them to each other, have greatly increased
their traffic. For the readier conveyance of the petroleum oil to the
railway stations in the oil-producing district, the company is now
laying down iron pipes through which the oil will be forced from the
tanks at the wells by powerful steam-pumps. These parts of the
apparatus cannot, of course, be shown in our Engraving. During the
past year the Atlantic and Great Western Railway has carried more than
half a million barrels of petroleum oil, which is not one third of the
product of this wonderful region.</p>
<p>The petroleum oil is sent from America in a crude state, just as it
pours out of the earth. The business of refining and preparing it for
use is extensively carried on in England and France. The London
Hydrocarbon Oil Company, in their manufacturing establishment at
Southall, apply to the American oil a patent process of distillation,
by which the pure transparent liquid known as <hi
rend="italic">cazeline</hi>, giving, a most beautiful light, is
disengaged from the grosser elements of the petroleum, as well as from
the spirituous part, which yields an explosive gas. The latter
substance is largely employed instead of turpentine for various
manufacturing purposes, while the cazeline is burned, without the
slightest danger, in the lamps on our drawing-room tables, free from
smoke and smell. Nor are these the only uses of the petroleum
oil. Experiments have lately been made, by order of the French
Government, to test its value as fuel for the engines of their steam
navy. It has been proved that a given quantity of this substance will
generate, in half the time, as much steam as could be produced by
burning twice the weight of coal. It seems likely that the
introduction of this portablu fuel will have a great effect upon the
development of steam navigation. The Southall works alone refine fifty
thousand barrels yearly.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1270.006" n="The Petroleum Oil Works at Franklin,
      Pennsylvania.; Railway Station at the Franklin Petroleum Oil
      Works.--See Preceding Page." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1270</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 100</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-23">July 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv45p100">
<head>THE PETROLEUM OIL WORKS AT FRANKLIN,
      PENNSYLVANIA.; RAILWAY STATION AT THE FRANKLIN PETROLEUM OIL
      WORKS.--SEE PRECEDING PAGE.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1270.007" n= "The report brought by the steamer Wonder" type="Article">
<head>[THE REPORT BROUGHT BY THE STEAMER WONDER]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1270</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 107</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-23">July 23, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The report brought by the steamer Wonder of an engagement between
the Kearsarge and the Florida, off Jersey, is false, as we were able
to announce in a considerable part of our Impression last
week.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1271.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1271</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 110-111</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-30">July 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>The raid into Maryland has been brought to a close, and the
Confederate forces have recrossed the Potomac, carrying with them
immense quantities of plunder. On the 9th inst., the Confederates had
reached a position midway between Baltimore and Washington, and were
threatening both towns. An engagement took place with a strong Federal
force under the command of General Wallace, in which the latter was
defeated and forced to retire on Baltimore. Several of the bridges on
the railroad connecting that town with Washington were destroyed, the
telegraph-wires cut, and two trains captured, one of which contained a
general officer and his Staff. Having approached Baltimore
sufficiently close to burn the residence of the Governor of Maryland,
which stood within four miles of that town, the invaders turned
southward and made their appearance in the northern environs of
Washington. A demonstration was made against one of the outlying
forts. But on the 14th inst. the invading force withdrew from before
Washington and recrossedthe Potomac, carrying with it enormous stores
and a large number of horses. Such, briefly told, are the events which
took place in Maryland between the 9th and 11th inst. The Federals,
who, it is stated, have been reinforced by the arrival of two
divisions from General Grant's army, were reported to have also
crossed the Potomac at Edward's Ferry, in pursuit.</p>
<p>The Governor of Pennsylvania had earnestly appealed to the people
to volunteer for short service, and rather reproaches the
Philadelphians for not displaying more alacrity in responding to his
first call.</p>
<p>One of the correspondents of the <hi rend="italic">New York
Herald</hi> was in the train from Baltimore to Philadelphia, which was
captured by the Confederates. He says:--</p>
<q><p>At forty minutes past nine the express train to New York started
with passengers, your correspondent among the number. We reached
Gunpowder river all safe, and immediately after passing the long
trestle bridge, speed was incraased. About two miles from the bridge,
at Magnolia station, two or three pistol-shots were heard, when the
train suddenly stopped, and a cry was raised, "The rebels are on us."
But a few seconds elapsed before they entered the cars, carrying
pistols in their hands. The first question asked was, "Are there any
ladies in this car?" On being answered in the affirmative they ordered
every lady to sit down. This was immediately followed by another order
to "Clear out." It was while leaving the car that purses and watches
were taken from the passengers. The request to hand them over was
enforced by a cocked pistol held at the heads of the victimised
passengers. The prisoners were then placed under a strong guard, and
the cars set on fire, after the baggage and express cars had been
emptied. Steam was then got up, the engine reversed, and the train of
blazing cars run down to Gunpowder Bridge. A column of dense black
smoke was soon seen rising in the direction of the bridge, and when
the rebels who had been in charge of the bridge returned they said the
bridge was burning finely, and would be totally
consumed. Major-General Franklin was a passenger on board the first
train. He was dressed in citizen's clothes, and when the rebels
entered the car and asked him who he was, he replied, "Nobody of any
account." The guard passed on a few yards, when a Baltimore lady (of
whom there were o number on board) told him the General's rank and
name. The guard returned and demanded his papers, which were of course
handed over, and the General was taken from the car.</p></q>
<p>This correspondent notes the significant fact that a large number
of the invaders were Marylanders themselves, and knew not only the
country but the people. He says:--</p>
<q><p>They were under the command of Major Harry Gilmore, and
consisted of twenty-five men belonging to the 1st Regiment Maryland
Cavalry, and the balance belonging to the 2nd Maryland, Major
Gilmore's own regiment. From their conversation I learned that the
majority were residents of Maryland. They were armed with pistols,
carbines, and sabres. The lady prisoners were remarkably well treated
by the rebels, and it was somewhat amusing when the train was stopped
to see the rebel horsemen ride up to the car windows, where they were
greeted somewhat as follows:--"Why, Tom, is that you?" "How are you,
Harry?" "Oh! come inside." Small white hands were grasped by the brown
hard ones of the troopers and warmly shaken. Many of them dismounted,
and, on entering the car, were very affectionately kissed by theirlady
friends. It appeared to be quite a joyful meeting. The other prisoners
were treated very well, with the exception of being obliged to give up
whatever any of their captors fancied he would like to possess. One
gentlemen--a doctor, I believe--was compelled to draw off his boots
and exchange them for a pair of dusty cowhide riding-boots, or rather
leggings, as they were minus the soles. A rebel fancied my hat, and
took it, with the remark, "Here, I want that hat!" at the same time
giving me his tobacco-stained and rusty-looking felt in exchange. My
haversack followed next. It contained, among other things, a number of
despatches and a long list of casualties. The blanket followed shortly
afterwards, and soon I, together with the majority of the prisoners,
had no article of value left. The man who appropriated the haversack
very kindly allowed me to retain two photographs and a
toothbrush. Likenesses were in every instance returned to the owners,
as were also any other small articles of no value to the rebels. As
far as lay in their power, everything was done to make our situation
pleasant. I am but performing an act of simple justice by stating that
Major Harry Gilmore was not cognisant of the conduct of his men. He
strictly prohibited all stealing from prisoners; but the event proved
that the lawless troopers under his command could not be restrained
from filching a purse or a watch when a fair opportunity presented
itself.</p></q>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">Times</hi> New York correspondent reports
great indifference among the people of that city and of Pennsylvania
(our own correspondent's State) with regard to the Confederate
advance. He writes:--</p>
<q><p>Governor Curtis, of Pennsylvania, is both alarmed and indignant,
and utterly at a loss to account for such lukewarmness--he will not
call it cowardice--on the part of his people. In a proclamation
addressed to the Mayor of Philadelphia and the people of Pennsylvania,
he tells them candidly that they are not responding freely to his and
the President's demands; urges them to come forward "like men" and "do
their duty;" accuses them of stupidity in not understanding the
gravity of the circumstances, and "prays to God to enlighten them,
that the honour of their commonwealth may be preserved." But the
people make no sign. The poor attend to their daily work as if nothing
were amiss; and the rich send away their jewels, their plate, and
their greenbacks to safer cities than their own--some even so far to
the north as Boston, and some still further--to Toronto and Montreal,
out of Federal jurisdiction altogether. The Mayor of New York,
Mr. Gunther, in a letter to Major-General Sandford, commanding the New
York militia, endeavours to persuade that officer that the true place
for the militia is in New York and not in Washington. In this singular
document he states "that in these times of general and local peril
enlightened self-interest is emphatically the synonym of patriotism."
Taking this curious aphorism as the basis of his argument, he
furthermore states his "grave apprehensions" that the withdrawal of
any considerable number of militiamen from the city at this moment,
when the depreciation of the currency is bearing heavily upon the
masses of the people, "might tempt the lawless and evil-disposed to
avail themselves of what might seem to them a favourable opportunity
for arson and plunder," and for that reason "earnestly pretests
against any material reduction" of the local force. It is difficult,
in view of public utterances so significant as these, and of the
indifference, not to say the contempt, with which Mr. Lincoln's
appeals for assistance are everywhere received, to avoid believing
that at last the people are losing heart in the war, and that, if
Mr. Lincoln cannot repel invasion and conquer the South by the
abundant means already placed at his disposal, they are coming to the
conclusion that peace cannot be made too soon. There is no longer any
enthusiasm for the war, unless it be in the counting-houses of those
who are making money by it. Even the Churches have lost faith, and
Dr. Cheever sees nothing but ruin in the war if Mr. Lincoln is left to
conduct it.</p></q>
<p>The only news we have of the forces before Petersburg is that the
Confederates have made demonstrations on Grant's left, with the object
of getting in his rear.</p>
<p>Accounts from Georgia stated that the Federal General Sherman had
followed General Johnston's army across the Chattahooche Rover, and
had arrived within sight of the defences of Atlanta.</p>
<p>Mr. Lincoln had issued the following proclamation of his policy on
the question of reconstruction of the Union:--</p>
<q><p>Whereas, at the last Session, Congress passed a bill to
guarantee to certain States, whose Governments have been usurped or
overthrown, a Republican form of Government, a copy of which is
hereunto annexed; and whereas the said bill was presented to the
President of the United States for his approval less then one hour
before the <hi rend="italic">sine die</hi> adjournment of said
Session, and was not signed by him; and whereas the said bill
contains, among other things, a plan for restoring the States in
rebellion to their proper practical relation in the Union, which plan
expressed the sense of Congress upon that subject, and<pb n="111"/>
which plan it is now thought fit to lay before the people for their
consideration:--</p>
<p>Now, therefore, I, Abraham Lincoln, President of the United States,
do proclaim, declare, and make known that while I am, as I was in
December last, when by proclamation I propounded a plan for
restoration; and while I am also unprepared, by a formal approval of
this bill, to be inflexibly committed to any single plan of
restoration; and while I am also unprepared to declare that the Free
State constitutions and governments already adopted and installed in
Arkansas and Louisiana shall be set aside and held for nought, thereby
expelling and discouraging the loyal citizens who have set up the same
as to further effort, or to declare a constitutional amendment
abolishing slavery throughout the nation, may be
adopted. Nevertheless, I am fu;ly satisfied with the system for
restoration contained in the bill, as one very proper plan for the
loyal people of any State choosing to adopt it; and I am, and at all
times shall be, prepared to give the Executive aid and assistance to
any such people as soon as the military resistance to the United
States shall have been suppressed in any such State, and the people
thereof shall have sufficiently returned to their obedience to the
Constitution and the laws of the United States, in which case military
governors will be appointed, with directions to proceed according to
the bill. In testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand and caused
the seal of the United States to be affixed.</p>
<p>Done at the city of Washington, this 8th day of July, in the year
of our Lord one-thousand eight hundred and sixty-four, and of the
independence of the United States the 89th.  By the President,</p>
<p rend="right"><hi rend="smallcaps">Abraham Lincoln.</hi></p>
<p>W. H. Seward, Secretary of State.</p></q>
<p>Washington official records show that upwards of 150 female
recruits have been discovered during the war. Over seventy of these
martial demoiselles, when their sex was discovered, were acting as
officers' servants.</p>
<p>The Confederate steamer Florida has been committing serious
depredations on American shipping off the Virginia and North Carolina
coast. It is reported that she has destroyed at least ten vessels. The
Florida had also captured the transport-steamer Electric Spark, a fast
vessel of 800 tons burden, carrying a valuable cargo of assorted
goods, and bound for New Orleans. Several Federal gunboats have gone
in pursuit of the Florida.</p>
<p>That the Northerners should crow over the destruction of the
Alabama is but natural. The Washington Secretary of the Navy,
Mr. Gideon Welles, in a despatch to Captain Winslow of the Kearsarge,
sends him his promotion to Commodore, and does not forget to recall
the English equipment of the Alabama. He says,</p>
<q><p>You will please express to the officers and crew of the
Kearsarge the satisfaction of the Government at the victory over a
vessel superior in tonnage, superior in number of guns, and superior
in the number of her crew. The battle was so brief, the victory so
decisive, and the comparative results so striking, that the country
will be reminded of the brilliant actions of our infant navy, which
have been repeated and illustrated in this engagement. The Alabama
represented the best maritime effort of the most skilled English
workshops. Her battery was composed of the well-tried 12-pounders of
57 cwt., of the famous 68-pounder of the British Navy, and of the only
successful rifled 100-pounder yet produced in England. The crew were
generally recruited in Great Britain, and many of them received
superior training on board her Majesty's gunnery-ship
Excellent.</p></q>
<p>Secretary Fessenden had appealed to the bankers of New York for a
loan of 50,000,000 douls. until Sept. 1, to meet the immediate wants
of Government; and it is stated that the bankers will accept the
loan.</p>
<p>Gold, after advancing to 280&#x00BD;, closed on the 16th at
254&#x00BD;.</p>
<p>The State Convention of Maryland, now in session at Annapolis, has
adopted, by a large majority, a constitutional amendment declaring
that "hereafter in this State there shall be neither slavery nor
involuntary servitude, except in punishment of crime whereof the party
shall have been duly convicted; and all persons held to service or
labour as slaves are hereby declared free."</p>
<p>A collision occurred on the 15th inst. between two trains on the
Delaware and Lakawana Railway, in Pennsylvania, by which over a
hundred persons--principally Confederate prisoners, who were being
conveyed to the camp at Elmira, New York--were killed or
wounded.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1271.002" n= "Imperial Parliament." type="Article">
<head>IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1271</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 119</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-30">July 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">IMPERIAL PARLIAMENT.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">HOUSE OF COMMONS.--<hi
rend="smallcaps">Thursday.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Emigration (America).</hi>--Lord <hi
rend="smallcaps">Howard</hi> called attention to the subject of
emigration to the United States of America, in reference to the
prolongation of the war now raging in that country. The noble Lord
detailed a number of cases in which a great many mechanics had been
decoyed over to America, under the inducement of good work and high
wages in large firms in Canada. Instead of being conveyed to that
place, they were landed in New York, and there, having been surfeited
with whisky, deserted, without the means of subsistence; and
ultimately many of them were compelled to enter the Federal army from
sheer necessity to escape starvation. He looked with much concern on
the great emigration at present going on, and he advised large
manufacturers to do their utmost to stop the flow of skilled labour
from their several districts. The noble Lord then referred to the
circumstances that occurred a short time ago in Ireland, and
afterwards read extracts from letters written by those who had
unfortunately been deluded into quitting England for America, all of
whom advised their fellow-workmen to look with the greatest suspicion
upon all inducements to visit the United States at the present
moment. It might be that the wages given there would be larger then
those in England, yet the price of the necessaries of life were so
enormous that the lesser sum earned in England went further than that
to be obtained in America. If it were possible, he should like the
Government to give some expression of opinion upon the subject; but he
felt certain the Foreign Office would do all that was possible to
protect those who had been kidnapped from their native land to take
part in a dreadful war which was a disgrace to both contending
parties. The noble Lord concluded by moving for certain papers
relative to emigration.--Mr. <hi rend="smallcaps">Layard</hi> said the
noble Lord had done good service in calling attention to the subject
of emigration to America. He could not see how many of the
difficulties mentioned by the noble Lord could be obviated, but he
advised the greatest caution to be observed by all quitting their
native land. The Government had directed the proper authorities to do
all that was possible to protect English emigrants; but, at the same
time, he hoped that all those parties who went to America--it was idle
to suppose that emigration could be stopped--would exercise the
greatest discretion. The emigration officers, the noble Lord might
rest assured, would do all in their power to prevent unfair practices;
but he felt certain that blame was not to be attached to the American
Government. He would willingly give the noble Lord all the papers he
desired.--Mr. P. <hi rend="smallcaps">Hennessy</hi>, seeing the
Secretary for Ireland in his place, said the emigration from Cork to
enlist in the American army was going on at the present time to the
same extent as it was at the beginning of the year.--Mr. <hi
rend="smallcaps">Lindsay</hi> said it was of the greatest importance
that extreme caution should be exercised by emigrants. The present
value of the American dollar was certainly not 4s. 2d. To show the
extent of the horror of the present struggle and the sacrifice of
human life, it was said that upwards of a million of lives must have
been already sacrificed.--Sir R. <hi rend="smallcaps">Peel</hi>, in
reply to the hon. and learned member, said a proclamation had been
issued by the Lord Lieutenant, which he hoped would check the tide of
emigration from Ireland. The greatest efforts were being used to make
all persons well acquainted with the state of affairs in
America.--After a few words from Mr. P. Taylor, Lord J. <hi
rend="smallcaps">Manners</hi> thought that the Emigration
Commissioners should issue a warning, stating that it was not safe for
the humbler people of England to go to America to find a home.--The
motion was agreed to.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1271.003" n= "A story of almost unexampled horror" type="Article">
<head>[A STORY OF ALMOST UNEXAMPLED HORROR]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1271</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 122</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-30">July 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>A story of almost unexampled horror is given in the American
papers, being the substance of a deposition by a survivor of the wreck
of a ship called the Elvina, which left Calcutta on Dec. 22, bound for
Boston. Her crew consisted of about thirty persons. She was so
fearfully damaged in a storm that she sank, eleven of the crew
clinging to floating spars, but the rest, with the master and his
brother, perished at once. The survivors endured horrible
tortures. Tied to the spars, they lay down upon the sails, and the
seas washed over them. At seven o'clock the wind died away, and,
tearing a shirt in two, they raised a signal of distress. Two
pumpkins, sole relics of the ship's stores, were seen floating nigh,
but not within reach, and they looked longingly upon them as they
passed by. At noon the gale again sprang up, blowing as furiously as
before. The waves swept tumultuously over the raft, carrying away two
of their number. One, George Chase, swam back, and was assisted upon
it, but, soon turning black in the face from swallowing sea water,
died. All through that day and night the storm continued, moderating
towards morning. The sky was overcast the second day, but the wind
went down and the sea became more calm. The sun rose bright and clear
in a cloudless sky the morning of the third day, and his beams beat
most fiercely upon their unsheltered heads. Maddened with thirst, in
their agony, some of them drank the seawater and died. The fourth day
dawned with a sun, though not as lustrous and ardent as
before. Another died. The survivors cut off his legs, and ate for the
first time since leaving the ship. Not a morsel had they eaten, not a
drop of fresh water had they drunk, for four days. The clouds gathered
overhead on the fifth day, but the sun burnt them off and shone more
scorchingly than ever. That evening one of their comrades slipped over
the side, saying, "I am going home, I can stay here no longer--I want
to see my mother--come with me, we shall not be long away and soon
return." They were too weak to prevent it, and he swam away. Far as
their dim eyes could range did they wistfully watch him swimming on,
the sharks splashing their white fins by his side, till he was lost in
the distance. The sixth day came and went, and another died. The
seventh morning found them hopeless and despairing; too weak to stand,
spiritless and exhausted, they lay feebly clinging to the spars, and
another died. But three were left now of the eleven--and still through
the long forenoon did the burning rays of that terrible sun fall hotly
upon them. At the last moment relief came. The French barque Claire,
Robert master, discovered the raft, their signal fortunately flying,
and dispatched a boat to their assistance.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1271.004" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1271</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 127</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-30">July 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">When</hi> Mr. Gideon Welles goes out of his
way to assure Captain Winslow that in destroying the "piratical craft
Alabama" he destroyed the best maritime effort of the most skilled
English workshops and the best battery of England, with the only
successful 100-pounder yet produced in Great Britain, served by a crew
of superior English training on board H.M.S. Excellent, we are quite
aware of his meaning. We all know what a pointed aside means in a
tragedy or farce. When the swaggering captain tells his friend, in the
presence of the unmistakable peace-lover, "My pistols are loaded to
the muzzle, and I can snuff a candle at twenty paces," what can he
mean but to terrify the poor fellow. Of course, as may be expected,
poor John Bull shakes in his ironclads, and trembles even at
Wimbledon. But the recapitulation is as gratuitous as it is insulting
and untrue. Captain Blakeley's 100-pounder is not the only one we can
turn out, and the sinking of the Alabama had very little to do with
her guns or her crew--weak wooden sides are not calculated to resist
steel shot, or, as the late Mr. Selby said in one of his farces, "it
no use a tryin' to stop a cannon ball with a humbrella." Might we
suggest to America U.S. that it is undignified for their Secretary to
the Navy to talk at us like an angry woman at her rival, or to write
like Mr. Jeaffreson Brick, the war correspondent of the New York <hi
rend="italic">Stabber</hi>, when he addressed the "tyrannical despot
Victoria, seated, in the midst of her Guards, at her palace in the
Tower of London...."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1271.005" n= "The Constitutional Crisis in Canada." type="Article">
<head>THE CONSTITUTIONAL CRISIS IN CANADA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1271</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 127</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-30">July 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE CONSTITUTIONAL CRISIS IN CANADA.</p>
<p>....The Conservative party of Canada West, led by the Hon. John
A. Macdonald, and the Radical party, led by the Hon. George Brown, the
editor of the <hi rend="italic">Toronto Globe</hi>, dropped their
weapons and agreed to a compromise. Dividing the Upper Canadian share
of offices between them, they have formed what may almost be called a
Provisional Government on the aforesaid basis of a new Constitution,
the details of which are not yet elaborated, but which will, it is
said, provide for the division of Canada into three provinces, of
which Quebec, Kingston, and Toronto will be the respective capitals,
with Ottawa for the federal capital.</p>
<p>The Canadians are anxious to know how this intelligence will be
received in the "old country." We can only say, for ourselves, that
what pleases them pleases us. While we regard the resolution they have
just taken as an escape from an intolerable situation, we do not blind
ourselves to the fact that it is another step taken towards their
independence of the mother country, at the same time that it is one
tending to make more remote than ever the era of their annexation to
the United States. Anything that develops a robust feeling of Canadian
nationality is well received here, where we are much more desirous to
save Canada from being "swamped" by the United States than to make
sacrifices to perpetuate her political connection with ourselves. The
views of colonial policy first put forth by Adam Smith, and recently
revived with great energy by Professor Goldwin Smith, have certainly
made considerable headway since 1840, when, in the debate already
alluded to, they were championed by such high authorities as Lords
Ashburton and Brougham. The confession lately wrung from Earl Russell
in the Dano-German debate that the menacing aspect of our future
relations with the United States continually hampered the freedom of
our action and weakened our position in the European arena has not
fallen upon unheeding ears; nor do we fail to perceive that our most
vulnerable point of contact with the United States is precisely the
extended and exposed frontier of Canada....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1271.006" n= "The War In America.--Field's Texans
      'Straggling to the Front.'" type="Article">
<head>THE WAR IN AMERICA.--FIELD'S TEXANS 'STRAGGLING TO THE FRONT.'</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1271</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 127</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-30">July 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"> THE WAR IN AMERICA.--FIELD'S TEXANS<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">"STRAGGLING TO THE FRONT."</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Our</hi> Special Artist and Correspondent with
the Confederate army in Virginia, having joined the head-quarters of
General Longstreet's corps, has sent us a sketch representing the very
spirited affair which he witnessed in the outer line of their
intrenchments on the south side of the James River, about thirteen
miles from Richmond. When General Beauregard, on the 15th ult., was
attacked at Petersburg and obliged to collect his forces in that city,
a wide interval was left open between his position and that of General
Lee at Drury's Bluff. The Federals were thus enabled to take
possession of this line of intreuchments, and occupy it in force until
the arrival of Longstreet's corps on the 16th. "At first," says our
Correspondent, "General Anderson, who, in the absence of General
Longstreet from the field, commanded the corps, thought it necessary
to storm the position, and gave orders to Pickett's division to go
in. Immediately afterwards it was discovered that we could get a
better line without sacrificing the men, and the order to assault was
countermanded, but too late; for Pickett was already at it. Field's
division, however, was pulled up, as it was on its way to support the
other; and aides-de-camp were sent to recall Pickett. In the mean
time, Field's Texans got impatient. They straggled to the front by
twos and threes, despite every effort to keep them hack. At last, the
whole body, officers and men, gave a yell, and, with one rush, they
were in the works. The Yankees fled pell-mell to a line of
intrenchments beyond, leaving heaps of dead and dying." The Richmond
correspondent of a contemporary relates the same affair in his most
recent letter:--"Yesterday evening General Lee sent Pickett's and
Field's divisions to retake a line held by the Federals; but, as it
was represented to him by the engineers that a better line could be
secured without any loss of life, he gave an order to recall the
troops. It reached Field's division in time, but Pickett's men had
already 'gone in,' and were at work. The others were at a halt, but
when they saw their comrades engaged, the men commenced straggling in,
first by twos and threes, then by whole companies, then by regiments,
and the officers had no option but to follow. In a few moments the
position was won. The Yankees hardly made a show of resistance. Most
of them saved themselves by flight, but a few were captured, and
proved to be the 'one hundred days' men' who had been caught, to their
great disgust. How different the conduct of the Virginia reserves
drawn from civil life, and hurried to the field in defence of their
families and homes! When this incident vas reported to General Lee, he
laughed, and said that 'he had often heard of men straggling to the
rear in a battle, but he had never before heard of their straggling to
the front.'"</p>
<p>A letter from General Lee to General Anderson has been published
relating to this affair. The Commander-in-Chief warmly congratulates
General Anderson upon the conduct of these men; and remarks, "I
believe they will carry anything they are put against. We tried very
hard to stop Pickett's men from capturing the breastworks of the
enemy, but could not do it,"</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1271.007" n="The War in America: The Texans of
      Longstreet's Corps Retaking the Outer Line of Intrenchments on
      the South Side of the James River. From a Sketch by Our Special
      Artist.--See Preceding Page." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1271</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 128</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-30">July 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv45p128">
<head>THE WAR IN AMERICA: THE TEXANS OF
      LONGSTREET'S CORPS RETAKING THE OUTER LINE OF INTRENCHMENTS ON
      THE SOUTH SIDE OF THE JAMES RIVER. FROM A SKETCH BY OUR SPECIAL
      ARTIST.--SEE PRECEDING PAGE.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1271.008" n= "Current Literature." type="Article">
<head>CURRENT LITERATURE.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1271</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 128-129</biblScope>
<date value="1864-07-30">July 30, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">CURRENT LITERATURE.</hi></p>
<p>....<hi rend="italic">Rambles in the Rocky Mountains.</hi> By
Maurice O'Connor Morris. (1 vol. Smith, Elder, and Co.) Where is
Denver City? is a question which Mr. Morris--no doubt,
rightly--supposes very few Englishmen can answer. Howbeit, the events
of the last three years have tended to make "Britishers" better
acquainted than they were before with American geography; and it is,
therefore, not improbable that there are more Englishmen than
Mr. Morris imagines whose eyes have become familiar with the map of
what was heretofore the United States, who could point out "Fremont's
route in 1845," who could even put their finger upon the spot marked
"Denver City," and who could say composedly, "There it is, in
Colorado." Nevertheless, Colorado has certainly not yet been explored
by travelling Englishmen, and the traveller should prick up his ears
and snuff adventure or novelty from afar when Mr. Morris assures him
"that if any <hi rend="italic">fl&#x00FB;neur</hi> in London who is
weary of the perfumed airs of Bond-street, and has lost his taste for
moors and stubbles, will cross the plains and pay <pb n="129"/>the
Rocky Mountains a visit, he will return with a keener zest for the
pleasures of civilised life, and with his 'mens sana in corpore sano'
all the fresher for what he has seen and experienced." And we can
assure those who feel inclined to undertake the expedition not bodily
but mentally, not by land and water, but by paper and print, that they
will find Mr. Morris a very agreeable companion and guide "across the
green prairies of Kansas and the sandy saharas of Nebraska" to the
gold-fields of the Rocky Mountains.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.001" n= "Emigration to America." type="Article">
<head>EMIGRATION TO AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 133-134</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">EMIGRATION TO AMERICA.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Within</hi> twenty-four hours of the closing
ceremonial of the Session of Parliament, and in a House of Commons
consisting of far less than twenty-four hearers, a speech was
delivered which ought not to be allowed to pass into immediate
oblivion. It contained a solemn warming, founded on facts, addressed
to a class of the population of the United Kingdom whose value is
acknowledged in the very circumstance of that warning. Lord Edward
Howard, when he brought forward the subject of emigration to the
Northern States of America, and laid bare its true conditions and
incidents as at present existing, seemed almost to have felt a
presentiment of the new demand for 500,000 men made by President
Lincoln for the prosecution of the war which he conducts on the part
of the Federal States, the news of which was within a few miles of
this country when the remarkable speech of the noble Lord was
spoken. In the brief debate which followed its utterance it was
unanimously declared that the most effectual way of attaining the
object which Lord Edward Howard had in view would be the giving the
utmost publicity to his address; and pointed and distinct appeals were
made to those who control or contribute to the newspapers of the day
to aid in the dissemination of statements which commend themselves to
the serious consideration of those to whom they were specially
directed. Compliance with a request so urged, and based on such
grounds of acceptation, seems to us a simple duty; and it is with a
desire to do what in us lies to spread the information which was laid
before Parliament in a spirit of philanthropy worthy of a
representative of the people that, after the lapse of some days, we
deem it no more than right to revive statements of so much
importance.</p>
<p>As the legal representative of the youthful Duke of Norfolk, it has
been the duty of Lord Edward Howard personally to become acquainted
with the condition of a part of the population of Lancashire which
resides in or about the great Howard property in that district. As a
member of the Relief Committee at Glossop, which undertook to meet the
difficulties and distresses caused by the cotton famine, knowledge of
the baneful operation of the so-called emigration to America was
forced upon the noble Lord. It was made manifest to him that the
labouring population were suffering under a delusion, from which he
has done something to awaken them. The plain fact is, that a system is
in existence which, under the name of emigration, is nothing more nor
less than a base and insidious scheme of recruiting for the Federal
army. In the outset let it be said that, in the strict sense of the
term, we attach no blame to the Federal Government. There is no
evidence of complicity on the part of that Government in the infamous
proceedings which have been brought to light. Indeed, it appears that
the remonstrances of Lord Lyons on behalf of British subjects who have
been kidnapped by false pretences into the Federal army have been
attended to by Mr.Seward in an official manner; but, as everyone
knows, official action at the seat of Government does not necessarily
result in the redress of grievances which are connected with military
organisation in a time of war, especially when it is directed towards
the discharge of men from a force which loses soldiers by hecatombs
and in which the demand for reinforcements is enormously beyond the
supply. Still, the Federal authorities fully acknowledge the injustice
and the oppression of the practices of the recruiting which is going
on, which, in the very nature of things, has fallen into the hands of
agents of the vilest and most unscrupulous character. The military
commandant of New York, the chief recruiting d&#x00E9;p&#x00F4;t, in
his reports, has spoken of the circumstances under which men are
obtained for service in the field in no measured terms. He says "that
almost every imaginable form of outrage and deception has been
developed; the outrages practised on recruits are too unjust to be
borne, and in many cases too loathsome to be detailed. Many--indeed,
most--of these unfortunate men were either deceived or kidnapped, or
both, in the most scandalous and inhuman manner in New York city."
Doubtless, these candid observations apply to men of all
nationalities, including Americans; but it is in their application to
the men of this country that we especially propose to consider
them. It is undeniable that a regular <pb n="134"/> agency of villainy
has been established in this country, in the north of England and in
Ireland particularly, by which men are induced to abandon prospects of
steady though laborious maintenance in this country by representations
of large wages and more than corresponding social advantages in
America, who, immediately on reaching that land of promise, of
freedom, and of comparative wealth, are decoyed, cajoled, threatened,
and, as the last resort, drugged, until they find themselves enlisted
in the Federal army. They are at once conveyed to the
d&#x00E9;p&#x00F4;t at Long Island, where they are, under the pretext
of undergoing the training which is indispensable to military
discipline and the making of a soldier, subjected to cruelties,
privations, and outrages which no one has yet ventured to chronicle in
writing; and as soon as possible, but not too soon for their
sufferings, they are sent on to form parts of those forlorn hopes,
composed of the newest arrived recruits, which are recklessly hurled
at the fortified strongholds of the enemy, and to create ramparts with
their dead bodies behind which the main bodies may retreat.</p>
<p>Let it be well understood that every day, by means of the grossest
false pretences, married men, the heads of families, are going out to
America in the hope of avoiding distress at home, who in a few weeks
help to swell the fearful lists of the dead which are reported from
time to time from the seat of war about Richmond. According to the
statements of Lord Edward Howard--the authenticity of which cannot be
denied--men are sought out and offered work, as first-rate mechanics,
in Canada, at large wages, an undertaking is given to pay their
passages out on the condition (the insidiousness of which is to be
observed) that such expenses are thereafter to be deducted from their
wages; and they find themselves at the end of the voyage landed at New
York, where, penniless and friendless, they fall an easy prey to the
recruiting shark. Of the numerous devices to bring about this end it
is only necessary to mention drugging, which has been before alluded
to, the result of which is that the men awake from a stupor and find
themselves in the uniform of the Federal army, and with the usual
attestations of enlistment complete against them; contrivances to get
them into the hands of the police, who, acting in fraudulent unison
with the recruiting agents, threaten and cajole them into enlisting;
while, in the last extreme, the simple method--borrowed from the
practices of, and perhaps carried on by, slave-traders, changing only
the type of man whom they deal in, is adopted, and they are compelled
by mere physical violence to enlist. So complete is the organisation
of the system, that in the vessels of all kinds which run between this
country and New York agents pass to and fro regularly, who ingratiate
themselves with emigrants who have not been entrapped at home but are
voluntarily seeking new--and, as they believe, better--fields for
their labour; and in the result they land under the auspices of these
persons, and are led straight into the pit which gapes for their
ingulfment. As a rule, the men are enlisted in false names, so that
inquiries after them under their real designations are practically
useless; and, even if they should pass unscathed through the perils of
a war which is almost one of extermination, nothing can be heard of
them until that period, so illusory and so hopeless, shall have
arrived when peace is re-established in America. In the event of a man
once enlisted attempting to desert, he is shot as a matter of
course. The vigorous simplicity of this proceeding is obvious.</p>
<p>But, assuming that an English emigrant escapes from or does not
fall into the net of the recruiting agent; that he finds himself on
the shores of America under the conditions which attach to him as a
working-man seeking employment more remunerative and affording him a
prospect of more immediate comforts and greater future prosperity than
he could have hoped for at home, how does it really and truly fare
with him? Is it the fact that he is in a land where ample work, high
wages, and abundance of the necessaries of life are accessible at low
prices? The very reverse is the case. In the first place, a labouring
man, if he obtain employment, which is anything but a certainty, is
paid in dollars--that is, in the notorious green-backs, and he has
been led to suppose that a dollar is equivalent to 4s. 4d. of English
money. Now, the truth is, that a dollar is worth something less than
1s. 6d., so that a man nominally earning eight or nine dollars a week
is receiving in value not more than fifteen or sixteen shillings; and,
as several workmen writing to their friends at home have stated, they
are doing worse in mere money-getting than they were in England, while
the high prices of all sorts of provisions, fuel, and clothing still
further depreciate their gains, and they find that they have
exchanged, perhaps, a struggle in their own country for positive
pauperism in another and a strange land, which is in the agonies of
civil war, of revolution, and may be ere long in a state of
anarchy.</p>
<p>Such are the prospects of emigration to America at the present
moment; and it is well that every effort should be made to bring this
knowledge clearly to the minds of those whom it most concerns. This is
no case for rhetorical artifice; it is not necessary to dress it up
with fanciful garniture before it is presented to the consideration of
the public. There is an eloquence in the facts which will sufficiently
speak to the judgments of those whose duty it is (as in cases like
that of Lord Edward Howard it is their pleasure) to contribute to the
well-being of the working classes. The agency for evil and for
wrongdoing in this particular matter is widespread, active,
unscrupulous. Why should not some counter-agency be set up to meet and
to neutralise the vile operation which is notoriously going on in this
country? The law, trammelled by the rules of evidence, is, in the
main, powerless to deal even with detected offenders. The Executive
Government can only act by means of the law; but there is, as we
think, a remedy to be found in the adoption of that great principle of
association for philanthropic purposes which, almost peculiar to this
country, has so constantly supplemented and aided the law. Even a
small association for the dissemination in a readable form of the
facts which Lord Edward Howard laid before the House of Commons might
do much. Why should it not be tried?</p></div2>
 

<div2 id="iln45.1272.002" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 134</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>We have news from New York to the 23rd ult.</p>
<p>It has been authoritatively, though not officially, announced that
Atlanta has been taken by the Federals after a battle fought before
the fortifications on the 21st ult., which resulted in the
Confederates retiring with a loss of 600 killed and 4000 wounded and
prisoners. The Confederate General Johnston had been previously
superseded by General Hood. The Federals, it was added, had cut all
Hood's lines of retreat except that to Macon, and occupied Atlanta. On
the other hand, General Forrest, with 10,000 Southerners, was reported
to be menacing Sherman, and, again, General A. J. Smith, with a corps
of Federals from Memphis, was harassing Forrest. Atlanta is in the
centre of the State of Georgia, about 115 miles south of
Chattanooga. It is the point of junction of four railways: the railway
north, to Chottanooga; the railway south-westward, to Mobile and
Pensacola, on the Mexican Gulf; the railway eastward, to Augusta and
Charleston; the railway south-eastward, to Macon and to Savannah, on
the Atlantic. Atlanta is thus an important strategical point.</p>
<p>Nothing important has occurred at Petersburg. The Confederates are
stated to be engaged in an attempt to blockade the James River with
the object of cutting off General Grant's communications by
water. Grant is said to have contracted his lines, though still
proceeding with the siege of Petersburg, and to have dispatched
General Sheridan upon another raid on the railway communication with
Richmond.</p>
<p>The Confederates got off from Maryland safely with their booty, and
the attempt of the Federals to pursue them has been abandoned, not,
however, without having somewhat harassed them, and capturing four
guns and some stores. The militia called out in the midst of the alarm
have been dismissed.</p>
<p>There were rumours when the last mail left of a new Confederate
invasion of Maryland vi&#x00E2; Muddy Branch and Rockville. A Southern
force of 5000 men was said to have again crossed the Potomac.</p>
<p>The latest despatches also report the discovery of a conspiracy for
the formation of a North-western Confederacy, embracing all the States
in the Mississippi Valley. Several prominent citizens of St. Louis,
implicated in the affair, had been arrested.</p>
<p>News of a Confederate victory comes from Fort Hudson, on the
Mississippi, where the Federal troops under command of General Elliott
were attacked and routed with great slaughter, the roads for miles
being strewed with dead negroes, horses, and arms.</p>
<p>The bombardment of Fort Sumter, of which we have heard very little
recently, has been renewed with increased violence, from thirty to
forty shells being daily thrown into Charleston. The Confederates are
reported to have been successful in driving the enemy from John and
James Island to Morris Islands.</p>
<p>An attempt at negotiation has been made by some Southern
politicians staying at Clifton House, Niagara Falls. Mr. Clement
C. Clay and Mr. J. P. Holcomb, semi-official representatives of the
Southern Government, communicated to Mr. Horace Greeley that they were
willing to proceed to Washington for the discussion with the President
of peace propositions, although not accredited by the Confederate
Government for that purpose. President Lincoln replied, through
Mr. Greeley, by means of a note addressed simply "To those whom it may
concern," that the Federal Government would receive and meet on
liberal terms "any proposition embracing the restoration of peace, the
integrity of the Union, and the abandonment of Southern slavery."
Messrs. Clay and Holcomb emphatically declined visiting Washington,
Mr. Lincoln's answer precluding negotiations by pre-arranging
conditions. If peace could only be secured by submission to terms of
conquest, the generation was yet unborn that would witness the
restoration of peace.</p>
<p>The Confederate invasion into Maryland seems to have produced
considerable effect on the Washington Cabinet, for the President has
issued his order for 500,000 men to serve for one year, to be obtained
by draught, immediately after the 5th of September next, if not
previously obtained by volunteering.</p>
<p>Mr. Fessenden, the new Secretary of the Treasury, had declined the
terms required by the New York banks for the proposed loan of fifty
million dollars, and determined to offer a popular loan, the interest
of which is to be paid in gold.</p>
<p>Gold, upon the announcement of the occupation of Atlanta, declined
to 251. The last quotation was 254&#x00BD;; Exchange 271.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.003" n= "The Blockade-Runner Lizzie." type="Article">
<head>THE BLOCKADE-RUNNER LIZZIE.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 136</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE BLOCKADE-RUNNER<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">Lizzie.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">This</hi> steamer has been built, in the
Clyde, for the purpose of running the blockade of the ports of the
Confederate States of America. The vessels most suitable to this
hazardous employment are those of light draught and great speed. The
building of such vessels has developed a large trade, particularly
among the shipbuilders of the Clyde. The Lizzie was launched a few
weeks ago, from the building-yard of Messrs. Henderson, Coulborn, and
Co., at Renfrew, near Glasgow. She had been built to the order of
Mr. W. C. Deeley, of Liverpool. When completed, she took on board a
select party for a short cruise down the Channel, to test her
speed. The result of her performances was far beyond the expectations
of her builders and owners; it gave the utmost satisfaction to
everyone on board. The speed throughout was twenty-two miles an hour,
and that was maintained with the greatest ease. This speed is
unprecedented in the experience of steam-navigation; no steamer of
whatever size having maintained in open channel a speed equal to that
of this little vessel. The principal dimensions of the Lizzie
are:--Length, 230 ft.; breadth, 22 ft.; depth, 9 ft; about 300 tons
gross tonnage. Her engines are on the builders' patent diagonal
oscillating principle, and of 150-horse power, nominal. She has
feathering paddle-wheels and vertical tubular boilers. The same
builders have several steamers on the stocks, intended for the same
trade, and all of them calculated for a high rate of speed. Our
Engraving is from a drawing by Mr. Hugh Aird.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.004" n="New Blockade-Runner Lizzie, Built in the
      Clyde." type="illustration">
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol.45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no.1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 136</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>
<figure entity="ILNv45p136">
<head>NEW BLOCKADE-RUNNER LIZZIE, BUILT IN THE
      CLYDE.</head>
</figure>
</p>
</div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.005" n= "The War in America: Night March Through
      Burning Woods." type="Article">
<head>THE WAR IN AMERICA: NIGHT MARCH THROUGH BURNING WOODS.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 137-138</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE WAR IN AMERICA.--NIGHT MARCH THROUGH<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">BURNING WOODS.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">The</hi> Engraving on our front page is from a
sketch by our Special Artist and Correspondent with the army of
General Lee, in Virginia. Its subject is thus explained by a short
extract from his letter:--</p>
<p>"Stokes's division was one of those which were sent across the
James River to meet Grant on his approach to Petersburg. Its march<pb
n="138"/> formed the most picturesque scene I have ever witnessed. The
woods had caught fire in many places from shells thrown into them, and
the bright flames leapt up the tall trees, casting a ruddy glare upon
the faces of those careless warriors as they passed under the
fir-branches which were dropping flakes of fire. Now and then an old
shell would explode in the undergrowth; but this was looked upon as an
enlivening incident, with which the men were rather pleased. The woods
about Bottom's Bridge are filled with dead Federals, whom their humane
commander, General Grant, has left unburied. Perhaps the burning of
the timber in which these corpses lie will save Richmond from a
pestilence they would otherwise create. For miles outside the works of
Richmond you meet with such fearful traces of the slaughter which the
Federals suffered in their unsuccessful efforts to break through the
Confederate lines."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.006" n= "Though we did not attach much importance" type="Article">
<head>[THOUGH WE DID NOT ATTACH MUCH IMPORTANCE]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 138</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcaps"><hi rend="italic">London:
Saturday, August</hi> 6, 1864.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Though</hi> we did not attach much importance
to the reports which have reached us in reference to an alleged
attempt on the part of certain gentlemen in America to prepare a basis
for pacific negotiations, the mere hint that such a thing was possible
afforded lively satisfaction in England. Possibly, the majority of
Americans may hesitate to believe this, in the present state of the
public mind in North and South; but hereafter, when peace shall have
been made, justice will be done to the English by such of our
Transatlantic friends as may consult the columns of this Journal,
which we may fairly assume to represent the feelings of the best
classes in this country. We have never ceased to deprecate the cruel
internecine war, and we have all along urged that it might be ended
without detriment to the honour and character of the belligerents. The
statement that Mr. Greeley, Mr. Saunders, and others were to meet at
Niagara Falls and endeavour to devise some plan for terminating the
fearful struggle was listened to with pleasure, even by those who did
not believe that those envoys were precisely the persons best
qualified to shape out a course of policy involving such enormous
questions. The acceptance which the rumour met in America showed that
peace was no longer among the impossibilities.</p>
<p>This "conference" has been as great a failure as another which is
fresh in the English mind. The details are not of much consequence;
but it would appear that the war party in the North is very desirous
to discredit and repudiate the effort. It is sought to cast ridicule
upon the scheme. We see no reason for this. It can never be ridiculous
to try to stop the effusion of blood, to prevent men from being slain
by the hands of those who were but the other day their fellow
citizens. And, so far as we are informed, there was nothing in the
antecedents nor in the conduct of those who were concerned to justify
scoff and sneer. It is much to be regretted that the tone of the
American press generally is below the great occasion that should call
the best pens into existence for the common good. Personality, <hi
rend="italic">persiflage</hi>, swagger, are all easy enough; but the
public "guide, philosopher, and friend" should spurn the weapons which
the vulgar can use. We would bring no railing accusation against our
American brethren of the press; but we cannot help feeling that they
have not risen to the work before them, and have been too ready to be
mere repeaters of the idle and violent talk of the masses. Many of
them have yet to learn the grave responsibility attaching to those</p>
<q><p rend="center">Whose echoes roll from soul to soul,<lb/>And live
for ever and for ever.</p></q>
<p>Did the American press and the American pulpit assert themselves
more loftily, much would be done towards a pacification; and though we
do not address these words to fanatics, we believe that there are
numerous influential men in the churches and connected with the
newspapers who will receive in the spirit in which it is offered this
reminder of how much is in their hands.</p>
<p>In England an incident involving a failure often produces the most
fortunate results. An inadequate effort in a given direction turns
men's minds in that direction, if it can do no more; and at a happy
juncture more able men step forth, adopt the principle, and carry it
out with success. In Parliamentary matters this process is very
frequently witnessed, and the failure of weak men brings forth the
energies of the strong. It would be good news in the two worlds did we
hear that the end of the Niagara conference was but the beginning of a
congress with better prospects. What should now prevent it? It is the
custom to answer all British suggestions with the somewhat
supercilious remark that we "do not understand America." This is an
idle phrase. What is there in America or in American affairs that an
active, liberty-loving, practical people, akin to Americans, speaking
their language and reading their literature, should not be able to
comprehend. And when that comprehension is quickened by an earnest
desire for the welfare of the West, we must really be allowed to
characterise the allegation of nonunderstanding as a conventional
impertinence. There is nearly as much ignorance among our uninformed
classes upon foreign affairs as there is among the same class over the
water; but we have failed to perceive any mystery which cannot be
solved by those who are honestly desirous to discover the truth, We
believe that our journalists understand. American matters as well as
the journalists of America; and we are sure--we say it without
vaunt--that those matters are more gravely and befittingly discussed
here than there. The real reason why we are charged with a want of
comprehension of the case lies in the fact that there is a strong
disposition in the West to go on blindly and take the chances--a state
of mind, of course, which indisposes most persons to make or to
receive definite logic. Fight first and talk afterwards, is a maxim
which has its occasional value; but, in the present circumstances of
America, the rule may be deemed unworthy of toleration. Let us see
whether it is not the turn of talk, and whether the fighting may not
be dispensed with.</p>
<p>One thing is abundantly clear. The question of peace or war is in
the hands of the North. The South asks to be let alone. In this fact
surely the haughty Northerners may find an ample homage to their
pride. It is for them to say whether the sword shall be sheathed or
not. They are the arbiters of the situation. This they are bound to
consider. Then comes the question of honour; and although the Federals
affect to be too philosophical to admit that this consideration is at
the bottom of the war, and though they pretend to rest the struggle
upon certain principles, we firmly believe that they have too much of
the Anglo-Saxon in them to permit them to forget the idea of national
honour. They would like victory because it is victory, and they need
not endeavor to be better or wiser than their Old-World
forefathers. But there are such things as reason and moderation. There
is such a thing as knowing how to accept a situation with honour and
good grace. We have had to do so occasionally, and never more notably
than when George III. recognised the independence of certain
provinces. The nation would have liked to subjugate those provinces,
but it was evident that Destiny had ordained matters another
way. Therefore we consoled ourselves, as the Northerners may well do,
with the recollection that we had done, not our utmost, but more than
enough for our character and we smote hands with these who thenceforth
became our friends, and whose friendship we ore not ashamed (even amid
certain foolish taunts and menaces) to say that we have ever
valued. What need prevent the Northern States from following the
example of England? Will they place their point of honour higher than
we do? Surely, what England has done the North may do without
shame!</p>
<p>If the best class in America would rise to the work--would put down
the war party, who will protract the strife while there is a dollar to
be gained by the war, and will take the matter into their own hands,
beginning at the basis of satisfied honour--we do not see why we
should not, ere long, receive news of a new conference, and, instead
of such disappointing tidings as have just arrived, we should not
learn with hearty satisfaction that North and South had arranged a
peace. May we soon have to record such a consummation.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.007" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 139</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">Queen's</hi> Speeches are always held to be
the most empty of all human productions. There is generally little to
be said, and the many authors of these pieces are greatly troubled in
finding out the most grammatical way of "how not to say it." This year
they have succeeded, if not perfectly in accordance with syntax, to a
marvel. Nothing could be more empty than the little political exercise
which we heard at the end of last week. It failed to call forth even
one remark from our French friends. Denmark and her troubles are
dismissed in a sentence, and the great war in America, which has as
yet produced the largest crop of troubles both in this country and
across the Atlantic, fares no better. The "scare" in Washington and
New York seems, however, to have produced a better state of mind in
the North; and the difficulties of Mr. Fessenden, the unwillingness of
the merchants to come forward with a new loan, the evident reluctance
of the Northern citizens to recruit a wasted and an exhausted army,
and the rumoured resignation of Mr. Stanton, are items which,
combined, give us some faint hopes of a not very distant
peace. Mr. Horace Greeley and the Peace Democrats will, it seems, soon
supersede the War Christians; and even Mr. Bennett's organ, the <hi
rend="italic">New York Herald</hi>, writes of the war as hopelessly as
our newspapers have any time these two years. The North is slowly but
surely making up its mind to let the" wayward sisters go in peace;"
and the wayward sisters have only to hold their own a little longer,
to defeat Grant and put an end to the last attempt to take Richmond,
and to wait the sure revulsion of public feeling, to obtain their own
terms. It is but fair to say, that the Northern organs of the English
press show a firmness and faith in the great Republic which its own
papers do not exhibit; and we constantly see placards of Federal
successes to-day which either fade away into nothing, or, like those
brilliant sunny landscapes in a magic lantern, suddenly change to all
the gloom and honor of disaster and defeat....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.008" n= "Sketches in Parliament." type="Article">
<head>SKETCHES IN PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 142</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center">SKETCHES IN PARLIAMENT.</p>
<p>....On the Thursday a remarkable occurrence took place. It was in
the afternoon, and there were certainly not more than ten or twelve
members present, and the Government was represented only by
Mr. Layard, when Lord Edward Howard, who had placed on the paper a
motion, very modest in its terms, with regard to emigration to
America, rose, and in that simple but earnest manner which belongs to
him, and which gives every one who hears him the impression that they
are listening to an honest man of kindly feelings and warm sympathies,
delivered a statement of facts the relation of which kept the small
audience present, as it would have kept a larger one, enchained for
the whole time he was speaking. His disclosure of the system of
kidnapping Englishmen and Irishmen as recruits for the Federal army,
and his irresistible statements of the disappointments and sufferings
of emigrants who, escaping the perilous devices of crimps who have
learnt their business in the school of the slave-trade, attempt to
utilise their labour in what they believe to be a new and more
favourable field than their own country affords them, struck so much
conviction into the minds of those that heard this Parliamentary
speech, that Mr. Layard declared that the best remedy for the evil
would be the dissemination of that address amongst those whom it most
concerned; and Mr. Ferrand, in his impulsive way, asked if the
Government would not print and circulate it in the form of a
pamphlet. Lord Edward himself made an earnest appeal to th agents of
the "ordinary channels of information" to present him to the public in
the most unquestionable shape that their art could mould. For the
first time, perhaps, in the annals of Parliament the Reporter's
Gallery was directly addressed, the Speaker being for the time
ignored....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.009" n= "Prorogation of Parliament." type="Article">
<head>PROROGATION OF PARLIAMENT.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 142</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center">PROROGATION OF PARLIAMENT.<lb/><hi
rend="smallcaps">The Queen's Message.</hi></p>
<p>....Her Majesty deeply laments that the civil war in North America
has not been brought to a close. Her Majesty will continue to observe
a strict neutrality between the belligerents, and would rejoice at a
friendly reconciliation between the contending parties.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.010" n= "The Magazines." type="Article">
<head>THE MAGAZINES.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 149-150</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">THE MAGAZINES.</p>
<p>....<hi rend="italic">Fraser</hi> contains one paper of singular
beauty and interest--those reminiscences of Emerson and his social
circle--which we can hardly err in attributing to Mr. M. D. Conway. It
is a charming picture of<pb n="150"/> a society perfectly frank, pure,
and unaffected; of a friendly intimacy based on a community of
sympathies and untroubled by those wretched jealousies ordinarily so
fatal to the peace of philosophic and literary coteries. It seemed
from the first a happy omen that the centre of New England thought
should be located at Concord, and there are many not merely fanciful
advantages in the spot which is as yet America's nearest approximation
to the groves of the Academy. Secluded amid woods and lakes, Emerson's
friends enjoy whatever advantages flow from intercourse with Nature,
while Boston is near enough for the collision of new ideas and the
stimulus of the busy world. We are indebted to Mr. Conway for some
delightful sketches of--Emerson floating in his skiff on Lake Walden;
of the negroes welcoming Theodore Parkes with grateful tears as he
passed amid their poor dwellings in Boston; of Hawthorne escaped from
the party assembled to do him honour to a remote room, and there
discovered reading Defoe's "Ghost Stories;" of Alcott startling
Agassiz with the theory that tigers and snakes were created by man
"before he appeared in his present form...."</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.011" n= "According to the monthly emigration returns" type="Article">
<head>[ACCORDING TO THE MONTHLY EMIGRATION RETURNS]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 151</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>According to the monthly emigration returns from Liverpool, which
were completed on Monday by the Government emigration officials at
that port, it appears that though the emigration from the Mersey has
not been so brisk as in previous months, yet the exodus still
continues steady, and the majority of the emigrants, as usual, are
Irish. During the month just ended there sailed twenty ships to the
United States "under the Act." These vessels carried out 7310 steerage
and 267 cabin passengers. The nationality of the steerage passengers
is as follows:--1927 English, 4533 Irish, 239 Scotch, and 611
foreigners. To Canada there sailed four ships, with 421 steerage and
95 cabin passengers, of wham 235 were English, 64 Irish, and 122
foreigners were in the steerage. To Victoria there were two ships,
with 735 steerage and 8 cabin passengers, of whom 239 were English,
406 Irish, 55 Scotch, and 35 foreigners. To Queensland there sailed
only one ship, with 443 steerage and 1 cabin passengers. Of this
number 132 were English, 210 Irish, and 101 Scotch. Apart from the
emigration from the Mersy, we understand the emigration from the Irish
ports direct to the westward continues to be enormous, and this fact
will no doubt account for the apparent dulness at the emigration
offices in Liverpool. Of "short ships," or vessels not sailing under
Government supervision, there sailed to the United States eight ships,
with 500 passengers; to Canada two ships and 55 passengers; to New
Brunswick, one ship and 5 passengers; to New South Wales, one
ship. with 34 passengers; to Victoria, one ship, with 32 passengers;
to the West Indies, four ships and 29 passengers; to South America,
two ships and 34 passengers; and to Africa, one ship and 25
passengers--making a total of twenty ships and 714
passengers.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1272.012" n= "Immigration of unknown amount" type="Article">
<head>[IMMIGRATION OF UNKNOWN AMOUNT]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1272</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 154</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-06">August 6, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>Immigration of unknown amount would modify the effect of
emigration; but the return of the Emigration Commissioners show that
nearly 20,000 persons of English origin left their native shores for
distant settlements in the quarter that ended on the 30th of June. Out
of that number nearly 12,000 went to the United States, and 5000 to
the Australian colonies, The number of emigrants of all nationalities
was 86,783, of whom about 66,000, chiefly Irish, were bound to the
United States. The emigration to that part of America has not been so
great in the June quarter since 1854. Almost nine tenths of the Irish
emigrants left for the United States.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1273.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial Intelligence: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL INTELLIGENCE: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1273</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 158-159</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-13">August 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL
INTELLIGENCE.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p>By the Damascus we have intelligence from New York to the 30th
ult., at which time Sherman had not captured Atlanta, though he was
reported to be drawing his lines more closely round the city. We are
now told that the battle which commenced on the 21st ult. had been
continued on the 22nd, but that General Sherman had repulsed all the
attacks made by the Confederates, whose loss was estimated by their
enemies at 7000 men, while the Federals were alleged not to have lost
more than 2500 men. The dead of the two armies were buried during a
truce on the 23rd; and a Washington despatch states that fighting had
not been renewed up to the morning of the 25th. The Confederate
commander, General Hood, alleges that the battle of the 22nd resulted
in a victory for the Confederates, who on that day captured twenty-two
guns and 2000 prisoners. The Federal forces on the side of Decatur
have also been routed by Wheeler's cavalry, with the loss of their
camp; and General Hardee is operating on Sherman's rear. Rousseau, who
was recently detached with a strong body of cavalry to cut off the
Southern communication with Atlanta, has rejoined Sherman, after
destroying about thirty miles of the Montgomery Railway.</p>
<p>A demonstration was made by General Lee on the 26th ult. against
General Butler's position at Bermuda Hundred. General Grant dispatched
a large force to the north bank of the James River; and these troops
drove the Confederates from their breastworks and captured four guns;
but fighting continued, according to New York accounts of the 29th
ult. A New York despatch, dated the evening of the 30th ult., states
that General Grant had moved two corps to the north of the James
River, was intrenched in a position ten miles from Richmond, and was
reported to have abandoned the siege of Petersburg, and to intend
demonstrating against Fort Darling.</p>
<p>In the Shenandoah Valley, the Confederates who retreated from
Maryland, under General Early, suddenly turned, and defeated part of
General Hunter's troops, under the command of Generals Crook nd
Averill, on the 23rd and 24th ult., in the neighbourhood of
Winchester. The Federals retreated to Harper's Ferry, and the pursuing
Confederates occupied Martinsburg and busied themselves in destroying
the Baltimore and Ohio Railway. By the latest accounts we hear that
the Confederates have renewed their invasion of Pennsylvania, a large
body of their cavalry having entered Chambersburg on the morning of
the 30th ult.; and Mosby's guerrillas were near Edward's Ferry, in
Maryland. The Governor of Pennsylvania had issued a proclamation
declaring that the invading force was larger than he expected, and
that arms would be furnished to<pb n="159"/> the citizens for the
defence of Harrisburg, the State capital. All the negroes in Baltimore
had, it as stated, been armed by the Federal authorities.</p>
<p>Secretary Fessenden has opened a subscription for a loan of
200,000,000 dols. in Treasury notes, bearing 7 3-tenths per cent
interest in "greenbacks," and convertible at the end of three years
into bonds bearing six per cent interest, payable in gold.</p>
<p>Gold at New York on July 30 was 255&#x00B7;.</p>
<p>A board of naval officers had decided that the men rescued from the
Alabama by the Deerhound were prisoners of war, and the Washington
Government had approved the decision.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1273.002" n= "Latest News from Abroad." type="Article">
<head>LATEST NEWS FROM ABROAD.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1273</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 159</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-13">August 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">LATEST NEWS FROM ABROAD.</p>
<p>The following telegram has been received through Mr. Reuter's
office:--</p>
<p><hi rend="smallcaps">America.</hi>--New York, Aug. 1.--On the 30th
ult. General Grant blew up a Confederate fort at Petersburg. He then
assaulted and carried a line of Confederate intrenchments. An entire
regiment was destroyed, together with the fort. The battle was still
progressing on Saturday at noon.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1273.003" n= "Echoes of the Week." type="Article">
<head>ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1273</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 166</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-13">August 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center">ECHOES OF THE WEEK.</p>
<p>....As usual many of the accounts of the drought have been
exaggerated, and in the north and south eastern parts of England it
may be said to be at an end. The harvest will be an average good
one. The droughts we find from letters and advices, has extended not
only through Europe but to India and also to America, except, perhaps,
to that celebrated Shenandoah Valley, the produce of which the
Confederates have so kindly reaped for the Federals. But if the crop
of wheat in that quarter is not good, the crop of troubles springs up
finely. Mr. Fessenden appeals from the bankers to the people
themselves for a loan to pay the arrears of the
army. Mr. Vallandigham, "with several thousand others," is, we are
told, concerting measures for establishing a North-Western
confederation; and, which touches us more nearly, a court of naval
officers of the Northern States have, after due deliberation, decided
that Captain Semmes and the crew rescued by the Deerhound are
prisoners of war, and, we presume, as such must be delivered by Great
Britain to the United States. Here, then, is a very pretty little bone
for John Bull and Uncle Sam to amuse themselves in
picking....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1273.004" n= "Current Literature." type="Article">
<head>CURRENT LITERATURE.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1273</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 174</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-13">August 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">CURRENT LITERATURE.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Cruise of the Alabama and Sumter.</hi> (2
vols. Saunders, Otley, and Co.) The name of Captain Semmes, first of
the Sumter, afterwards of the Alabama, has gone forth into all lands
wherever printed news can penetrate or the trumpet-tongue of fame is
heard. Henceforth the name of Semmes is historic, and "290" is a
charmed number. Sympathizers with Confederates and sympathizers with
Federals were equally moved with wonder and admiration as they read
first how the Sumter, and then how the Alabama, defying and eluding
pursuit, suddenly pounced upon their prey. It seemed that a second
Paul Jones had arisen; the story of the "Phantom Ship" seemed to be
realised. The Federal cruisers were as much at a loss "as if they
dodged a watersprite," and their commanders must often have cursed in
their hearts the laws relating to "the marine league" and to "the
twenty-four hours' start," which gave their active and audacious foe
so many chances of evading capture or destruction. But neither Sumter
nor Alabama was to go on for ever causing joy to friends and despair
to enemies. A day came when the Sumter was "laid up," and a fatal
Sunday morning dawned upon which Captain Semmes, in the opinion of
some people, lost his head and fought the Kearsarge, and the Alabama
sank stem foremost in the waters of Cherbourg. The adventures of the
two far-famed vessels are now recounted in two volumes, the contents
of which are compiled "from the private journals and other papers of
Commander R. Semmes, C.S.N., and other officers." The account, no
doubt, will be eagerly perused; but the lovers of excitement, the
revellers in naval battles, and the admirers of "fire-eating" will
find very little to entertain them. The only fight (except that fatal
one off Cherbourg) in which Captain Semmes was engaged was one off the
coast of Texas, when he, with a superior weight of metal, sunk the
U.S. gun-boat Hatteras. For the rest, it is a story of eluding
stronger vessels, of weathering storms, of capturing and destroying
defenceless ships, of disputing about the laws of neutrality, and of
quelling mutinies. That there should have been mutiny is not
surprising when Captain Semmes says of the Alabama's crew:--"Many of
my fellows, no doubt, thought they were shipping in a sort of
privateer, where they would have a jolly good time and plenty of
license. They have been woefully disappointed, for I have jerked then
down with a strong hand, and now have a well-disciplined
ship-of-war. Punishment invariably follows immediately on the heels of
the offence. It has taken me three or four months to accomplish this;
but when it is considered that my little kingdom consisted of one
hundred and ten of the most reckless from the groggeries of Liverpool,
this is not much." Joining the last few words with Captain Semmes's
remark, "The modern sailor has greatly changed in character; he now
stickles for pay like a sharper, and seems to have lost his
recklessness and love of adventure" (vol. i., p. 296); and with the
notorious fact that the majority of the Alabama's crew were
Englishmen, one is inclined to think that "hatred to the flag of the
old Union" (vol. ii., p. 295) was not likely to have been amongst
"their chief active passions," and that the only union they were
particularly anxious to keep out of is that which is synonymous with
workhouse. That they were attached to their captain there is no doubt,
and that they fought gallantly is equally certain; but their
antecedents make it more probable that they fought on "Harry Smith of
the Wynd's" principle than on any other; and, though "one who was
hailed from the Kearsarge with the offer of a rescue declined it
civilly and made his way for the neutral flag" (vol. ii., p. 294), it
is more likely that his conduct was prompted by fear of being made a
prisoner than by a chivalrous "detestation of the Yankee." Of course,
all sorts of excuses are made for the defeat of the Alabama; for even
at billiards the defeated player discovers something in his cue, or
the table, or the pockets which was peculiarly unfavourable to him,
and fully accounts for his failure; but it is clear that if Captain
Semmes was aware of the disadvantages under which he would fight--and
he must have known most of them--he ought to have declined the
engagement. Besides, it is not very magnanimous to quote Captain
Winslow's statements (vol ii., p. 291) when they are favourable to the
Alabama and to doubt them (p. 279 <hi rend="italic">et seq.</hi>) when
they are not. We read, also, "a year previous to this meeting the
Kearsarge had laid (<hi rend="italic">sic</hi>) at anchor close under
the critical eye of Captain Semmes. He had on that occasion seen that
his enemy was not artificially defended." It appears, then, that the
Kearsarge was quite willing under these circumstances to fight the
Alabama; and as she had been "constantly in pursuit," it seems very
unlikely that Captain Winslow should have had either inclination or
time for getting "iron-clad." It is not pleasant to read paltry
excuses for the misfortune of a gallant gentleman. Captain Semmes
fought and lost, and there is an end of it. Insinuations against the
truthfulness, fairness, and humanity of his enemy cannot mend the
matter; a dignified silence would have been more becoming. Captain
Semmes has done wonderful damage to his enemies and has been of
wonderful assistance to his cause; it is only to be regretted that his
exploits were not as glorious as they were numerous. His province was
to cripple his enemy's commerce, and he did it to a miracle; and if it
makes the philosopher almost weep to think that so much produce of
human labour--so much subsistence for human beings--should have been
ruthlessly sunk in the barren sea, Captain Semmes is ready with a
justification....</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1273.005" n= "The custom-house authorities" type="Article">
<head>[THE CUSTOM-HOUSE AUTHORITIES]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1273</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 175</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-13">August 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p>The custom-house authorities at San Francisco discovered a Chinese
trick, which led to the seizure of another lot of smuggled
opium. Among the cargo of the barque Ceres were 400 tubs, invoiced as
eggs, value stated at 1 dol. each. The eggs were varnished to preserve
them. One of the officers, in examining the eggs, scraped off a little
varnish and disclosed a metallic case, egg-shaped, filed with
opium. Each egg is worth 300 dols.</p></div2>

<div2 id="iln45.1273.006" n= "The Government Emigration Commissioners" type="Article">
<head>[THE GOVERNMENT EMIGRATION COMMISSIONERS]</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 45</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1273</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 178</biblScope>
<date value="1864-08-13">August 13, 1864</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<p>The Government Emigration Commissioners have issued a notice, as
follows, warning emigrants to the United States against the traps laid
for them by Federal crimps:--"Information for emigrants to the United
States.--On arrival at New York you will be landed with your luggage
at Castle Garden, where you will obtain, free of charge, good
accommodation and instructions as to the beSt mode of reaching your
destination. This establishment is under the supervision of the
Commissioners of Emigration for the State of New York (one of whom is
the president of the Irish Emigration Society), and affords every
facility for obtaining inland passage-tickets by railroad and
steam-boats to all parts of the United States and Canada. Be cautious
in buying in this country, or on board ship, 'Inland passage-tickets'
for travelling in the United States, as you may find them useless on
your arrival in America. You will obtain them cheaper, and run no risk
of imposition, by getting them at Castle Garden, New York. Do not
trust to strangers, whose object in offering you assistance is either
to entrap you into enlisting, or to gain your confidence for the
purpose of defrauding you of your money. Do not accept invitations
from strangers to drink, and be especially careful not to get drunk,
or in any way to lose control over your own actions. Be very cautious
as to the engagements you enter into for work. Remember that an
American dollar is nominally equal to 4s. 2d. English money, and a
cent is one halfpenny, but that under the present circumstances of the
country they will not buy more than one third as much of the
necessaries of life as they would formerly buy. By order of her
Majesty's Emigration Commissioners, S. <hi
rend="smallcaps">Walcott.</hi>--Government Emigration Board, 8,
Park-street, Westminster, August, 1864."</p></div2>

Mr. Antrobus, Third Secretary to her Majesty's Embassy at

Paris, lisa been appointed a Second Secretary of Legation at Washington. Mr. Sirkpatiick, Third Secretary at Copenhagen, has been appointed a Third Secretary at Washington. Mr. Gosling, Third Secretary of Legation, has been isfecrnl from Stockholm to Copexthaen. Mr. R. C. Isi. Stevens, Vice. Consul at Constantinople, has been appointed Consul at Jeddah. The office, lately held by Mr. Stevens will be abolished-The Queen approved of Mr. C. Daniel as Consul at Port Louis, Island of Mauritius, for the King of the Belgians; and Mr. Nicholas L. uniphrey 58 Consul at Trinidad for the United States of America.
AMERICA-NORTH AND SOUTH.

INTo that spirit of partisanship which has characterised mdividualfeeling in this country in reference to the contest waging between the hostile States of America we have never been able to enter. In the reasons given for warmly espousing either cause we have not found enough to justify their entire adoption. It has always seemed to us a fallacy to assert that the North is contending purely for the abolition of slavery, or that the South is battling merely for liberty. It would be much nearer the truth if it were laid down that both are struggling for political ascendancy, while the South is, besides, fighting for what has always been held to be property. Something may be set down, also, for difference of race, always an important element of animosity between belligerents. But what we have

ever contended for, in dealing with the American question as it exists, hasbeen strict impartiality, not only of action but of opinion, on the part of this country ; a rigid noninterference, moral as well as physical, and a public feeling expressive only of earnest hope of a speedy cessation of a civil war unparalleled in its magnitude and terrible in its accessories. Holding these views, we conceive that we are entitled to review the position of both parties as it stood when the latest intelligence left America, and. to draw deductions from that examination, without laying ourselves open to any suspicion of partiality or bias. Our first, indeed our only, wish is that the war was over; and it is mainly with reference to the realisation of that 'wish that we from time to time consider the relative situation of the armies opposed to each other and dwell on the details of these battles

which are periodically fought with a curious similarity of circumstance and result.

Although operations are being conducted in several outlying districts, principally in the South, and we hear of movements of army corps here and there, since the siege of Charleston has practically ceased the chief interest has been concentrated on that small space which lies between Washington. and. Richmond. The country between, the Potomac and the Rappahannock has become as familiar to the mind's eye of the English public as the space between St. Paul's and South Kensington is to the real vision of the general metropolitan population. Under whatever General-

 M'Clellan, Booker, Burneide, 'Meade, or Grant-the ground traversed by the Federals has been nearly the same, and. the object
