<!DOCTYPE TEI.2 PUBLIC "-//TEI.2//EN" "iln.dtd"
[<!ENTITY % iln-entities SYSTEM
"/Beck-files/ILN/ILNCVS/ilnxml/iln_entities">
 %iln-entities; ]>

<TEI.2>
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated London News
Perspective</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Compiled and edited by</resp>
               <name>Sandra Still</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent/>         
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Emory University</pubPlace>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine>
            </address>
            <availability>
               <p>2005 Emory University.
Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce,
distribute or display the contributions to the work claimed by Emory
University for non-profit educational purposes, provided this header
is included in its entirety.  For inquiries about commercial uses,
contact the Lewis H. Beck Center, Woodruff Library, Emory University,
Atlanta, Georgia 30322</p>
            </availability>
            <date>2005</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated London News
Perspective</title>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Compiled and edited by</resp>
               <name>Sandra Still</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent/>         
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Lewis H. Beck Center</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Emory University</pubPlace>
            <address>
               <addrLine>Atlanta, Georgia</addrLine>
            </address>
            <availability>
               <p>2005 Emory University.
Permission is granted to download, transmit, or otherwise reproduce,
distribute or display the contributions to the work claimed by Emory
University for non-profit educational purposes, provided this header
is included in its entirety.  For inquiries about commercial uses,
contact the Lewis H. Beck Center, Woodruff Library, Emory University,
Atlanta, Georgia 30322</p>
            </availability>
            <date>2005</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Civil War: The Illustrated
London News Perspective</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Illustrated London News</title>
               <biblScope type="volume">Volume 43</biblScope> 
               <date>July to December 1863</date>
            </bibl>
 </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p/>
         </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	<change><date>September 2005</date>
          <respStmt><name>Robin Conner, </name><resp>Beck Center Staff.</resp</respStmt>
          <item>Encoded text according to TEI guidelines.</item>
	</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
<text>
<body>
<div1 id="iln43.001" n="Illustrated London News: Volume 43" type="Volume"> 
            <head>Illustrated London News: Volume 43</head>
            <docDate>July to December 1863</docDate>

<div2 id="iln43.1211.001" n= "Foreign and Colonial News: America." type="Article">
<head>FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS: AMERICA.</head>
<bibl>
<title>The Illustrated London News</title>
<biblScope type="volume">vol. 43</biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue">no. 1211</biblScope>
<biblScope type="pages">p. 2</biblScope>
<date value="1863-07-04">JULY 4, 1863</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>

<p rend="center"><hi rend="italic">FOREIGN AND COLONIAL NEWS.</hi></p>
<p rend="center">AMERICA.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcap">CONFEDERATE INVASION OF THE
NORTH.</hi></p>
<p>The rumours which had for some time been current that General Lee's
army was about to act on the offensive were, it turns out, well
founded. The Confederate General has advanced with great rapidity
northwards, pushing a portion of his troops, consisting of cavalry and
mounted infantry, far forward, so as actually to enter the State of
Pennsylvania. General Lee's advance commenced on Saturday, the 18th
ult., and the total force with which he is making his combinations is
estimated to be but a little short of 100,000 men, of whom 30,000 are
said to be cavalry. They were divided into three bodies and seem to
have made but slight work of the opposition that was offered to their
advance.  At Winchester, General Milroy attempted to arrest their
progress, but the outworks which he had constructed were stormed, and,
after spiking his guns, he retired upon Harper's Ferry. An attempt was
made to cut off his retreat, but this he seems to have
surmounted with a loss of 2000 men, and eventually made good his way
to Harper's Ferry, to which point the Federals at Martinsburg and
Berryville also made their way in retreat. At one time, Harper's Ferry
was abandoned but the Federals have resumed possession of it. All this
was on the Saturday and Sunday, and on Monday morning the Confederates
had crossed the Potomac, and were at Hagerstown, in Maryland, with a large force, of which it was said 15,000 were
cavalry, divided into three columns of 5000 men each. On the
Tuesday they advanced to Greencastle, and then to Chambersburg, in
Pennsylvania, where, according to one report, a force of 2000
Confederates rested at twelve o'clock that night. The Nova Scotian
brings a few hours' later news to the evening of June 20, to the
effect that the Confederates had advanced to Centreville and defeated
the Federals there. Longstreet was threatening Leesburg, and Hill was
at Dumfries. On Thursday night, the 18th, the Confederates transported
their stores across the Potomac to Hagerstown, and it was said that
they intended to make it their headquarters for raids into
Pennsylvania. One important rumour is mentioned in the news brought by
the Nova Scotian. It is that the Unionists in Eastern Tennessee and
Western North Carolina had raised a powerful force to hold that region
against the Confederates.</p>
<p>At Harrisburg, the capital of Pennsylvania, distant but fifty miles
from Chambersburg, there was naturally consternation, and the State
archives and all public property of value were removed. The Governor
issued his call for troops for State defence, and the President united
in this by summoning 100,000 men to be mustered into the military
service of the United States to serve for six months. Of these, 50,000
are called for from Pennsylvania, 30,000 from Ohio, and 10,000 from
Maryland and West Virginia respectively. The volunteering for a short
period has been generally warmly supported, but in Pennsylvania it has
been necessary to assure the men that they were only called up to
resist invasion. New York has raised fourteen regiments in four days
for service in Pennsylvania, and Harrisburg and Pittsburg have both
been strongly fortified.</p>
<p>Hooker meanwhile has abandoned his position opposite
Fredericksburg, and is moving on a line parallel with that Lee has taken
northwards. His base at Acquia Creek is also abandoned, and his
supplies have been removed to Alexandria, his new base. At Warrenton,
about the same distance from Washington as Fredericksburg, a little
west of north of the latter place, he has his headquarters. Lee is
supposed to be at Front Royal, twenty-five miles north-west of
Warrenton.</p>
<p>It is a moment as critical as any in the war. As to Lee's plans
nothing, of course, is known--whether he will turn towards Western
Pennsylvania, supposing he eludes Hooker's main forces, or whether he
will direct his way eastward towards Baltimore or Philadelphia. Hooker
divined the intention of his adversary to make this advance, and had
for some time held his forces in instant readiness to follow. The
Government, too, made such preparation as they could by creating two
military departments for East and West  Pennsylvania and appointing
officers of high rank to command.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcap">Richmond Threatened.</hi></p>
<p>On the Yorktown peninsula there are signs of Federal activity, as
we learn from Richmond accounts. The Federal gunboats have pushed up
the Chickahominy, within fifty miles of Richmond, and	a considerable
force is co-operating with them. General Keyes's command, which has
for some time been posted at West Point, has lately advanced to New
Kent Courthouse, about forty miles from the Virginian capital, and, in
face of those demonstrations, the Confederates have retired behind the
Chickahominy. It is said that Richmond is very strongly defended and
fully garrisoned.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcap">Vicksburg.</hi></p>
<p>From Vicksburg we have news to the 18th ult., at which time affairs
were, according to Northern accounts, favourable to General Grant. The
Federals had pushed their approach within twenty yards of the bastion,
whilst Pemberton is said to receive reinforcements and supplies,
during the night, from the other side of the Mississippi. The Federals
yet hold possession of Black River Bridge, and their opponents are
declared to be at least thirty miles from the rear of Grant. One
despatch stations a body of Confederates, to the number of 5000, at
Jackson; another of 5000 at Yazoo City; and a third of 15,000 at
Canton. The Richmond papers state that General Johnstone had cut his
way through Grant's army, and that the siege would in consequence be
raised. This report, however, was not credited. The besieged appear to
be reduced to short rations.</p>
<p rend="center"><hi rend="smallcap">General News.</hi></p>
<p>In Tennessee there are said to be signs of Confederate
movement. Contrary to the general opinion, Bragg has been reinforced,
whence is not stated, but he is believed to be about joining with
Buckner to invade Kentucky.</p>
<p>The Indiana enrolment excitement continues. A general
disinclination to submit to the draught is apparent all over the
country.</p>
<p>A military board has been appointed to settle this claims of
Generals Butler, Fremont, M'Clellan, Banks, and Dix for military
precedence of rank.</p>
<p>President Lincoln had sent a reply to the committee who forwarded
him the resolutions passed at the Albany Vallandigham meeting. The
President says that the ordinary law courts are inadequate to the
emergency. He continues:--" Military arrests and the suspension of the
Habeas Corpus Act are constitutional wherever public safety demands
it. Mr. Vallandigham was arrested by the military because he was
warring against the military, by labouring to prevent the raising of
troops and encouraging desertion." President Lincoln states that he
does not know whether, in his own discretion, he would have arrested
Mr. Vallandigham, but he thinks commanders in the field better judges
of particular cases. He will discharge Mr. Vallandigham as soon as he
can by any means believe that public safety will not suffer by it.</p>
<p>There are now about 30,000 coloured troops in the Federal army and
5000 coloured men in the Federal navy.</p>
<p>The <hi rend="italic">New York Herald</hi> says:--"Since July,
1862, 57 steamers and 91 sailing-vessels left Nassau for the rebel
ports. Fifty-one of the former and 45 of the latter landed their
cargoes, affording immense aid to the rebels and realising vast sums
for the speculators. Forty-four steamers and 45 sailing-vessels
reached Nassau from the Confederacy during the same period."</p>
<p>The privateer Clarence, the tender of the Florida, has captured
seven brigs and schooners off Virginia Cape. The captain of the
Clarence transferred his guns to the barque Saxony, which he had
captured, and burned the Clarence. Twenty-five Federal vessels have
left Northern ports to capture the Saxony and the Coquette. The
privateer Japan has captured the ship Dictator.</p></div2>

HOUSE OF LORDS.-T1rEsDA.
iCOP aDo LIEnS roeeuanu .Li]ii W, .Jw.ue V11- U 1-
In answer to Lord Stratheden, Earl Russell said the French Ambassador bad
called upon him that afternoon, and informed him that there was no truth in
the rumour that the Paunch Government Intended tomake any conununjeation
to bar Majesty's Government in reference to mediation between the Northern end Southern States of America.
Th]L..1 P 4- -1 dV.,	h1.. ....I 	IlL L..&.. Ll,..L
HOUSE OF OOXMOS.-TmtsDAY.
bad a		albumr. athi,mh ,a,,,,
T
MI.	ard, reply to Mr. Faster, stated that no commuatcatioll bed been
I	received tram the Wench Gotecurnent since last autumn In roferedothe inter-
	ference in the American war. 	-
	1	at-. r		i.i.t . ILL.L 1)111 sleet . tbe math
	Mr MOEJflrC mçcm't an address to the C ipreylog that her Majesty woald bsgeeiooal).pleased to enter into negonanono with the great Powers of Eeeoie or the purpose of obtaining their cooperet1eu in the recognition of the Independents of the Corifeekicoto States of Worth America. He contended that the South, by their gallant defence, and even by their victory over the North, bad earned a rig u to a iecegnIUon of their independence, arid Ms en even ground of international polity. Those States ought to be because it was their right, and alto because it was =to do so In reference tothe supply of cotton sugar, slot teilmatco to this coon. ThThtitoI States unto becoming tho btlllce of e wosia, and be we cajoles to eat the baimito at power oqsusllecel on
the A continent by the recenatriection of the Union.	Ire urged
that abS thee bad coats	recognition by Prance end England, whiob
would pitt an end to the wit,	He stated that be wee poroonally
	anthesiord by the ruler of Prance to oxpreet his feelings on this qnssttre,
	Which were enoagel then ever to fame of recognition of the South; end lie
	was asencad by the, ROOM= himself that he had desired Eaton Guns to corn-
	aseesicato that Opinion to the English (lovornonunt, although tItle eomrntint-
cetinO wee not fenneL	The Emperor stated his ecasor, for not snaking a
	ftamsd eeunnsun$oauon, because his drepaith en the seine euhlect 010 a former
	coonskin bad teen sent bathe liogliob Government to the United States; but
be nutbocired blur. (lie. mwsouek to theta to the House that he wt v;
=Min
	In aM thiugø with England, and especially in the matter of the recognition of the gcuthern Statee. After thes, what excuse could be made by her Majesty-9 Government for not taking that step?
Lord B. Moce'rAGt moved a_a an ameedmona that the House earnestly desires
that an impartial neutrality should continue to be maintained by her Mujosty'e
Government during the present unhappy Contest in the States or ifortli Ameri
Mr. CX.IFF0RD supported the amendment.
The CEAEORLIA)B f the ExemlQUEit objected to the motion in the first
place beea000 it put into the honda of the House a function of the executive
Government; because it was at this moment oapcially inconvenient, looking to the military situation of America while the speech of Mr. Roebuck, couched as it was in a spirit of partisanship for the South, was Ill calculated to promote the object he had in view. Recognition would not relieve Lancashire. and it was ill-advised to try down that 08 a doctrine when ft was clear that this cenntry, to produce such results as were implied by Mr. Roebuck, could not stop at recognition, Almost every Man in England wished the war to come to a close, but he denied that recognition would promote that and. There was acareely any case of recognition, paneling a contest, which was not followed by war in order to carry it cut. Me eoxitonded that France and England, situated as they were in reference to the States of Mnorlea, conieS mot represent in the eyes of the world the principle of impartiality in any interference between the contending Parties.
	Mr. W. K Foeos'ricut urged that the motion. if it meant anything, meant war-war to be waged for selfish consideration; war which would be pro. ducttve of every possible disaster to the commerce and the welfare of this country. In reference to Mr. Roebuck's alleged communication to the House from the Emperor of the French, he (Mr. Lorater) deprecated the poiioy at joint action with France, which inevitably led to war. d war with America, which might and probably would ensue upon our intervention, would be one against our kinsmen for slavery.
Lord It. OEctL argued that the conduct of the Thaited States in oases of
recognition precluded them from objecting to the adoption of that course-, and
he urged action in reference to the re-establishment of peace in the Interoete of
a large population of our own, which was desolate, owing to the teilitixo of the
cotton supply. 	-
	Mr. BRIGHT said that the motion, token in connection with Mr. Loobaek' character, his speech on this occasion, and speeches elsewhere might be taken so on addreae to the Crown asking for a declaration of war, wofie he asked the Moose to accept the lead of the Emperor of the French in this matter, a potentate In whom not long ago he declared he had no faith. Ho contented that the feeling which dictated this motion rested on a moon jealousy or a base fear of America. Re denied the power or the will of the United States to act aggressively towards England or any other European nation, and he protested against Mr. Roebuck raising a cry calculated to. bring on hostilities, between this reentry and a friendly nation, whllat he would seek alliance for Ids country In a slaveholding State.
	Sir ta GREY, in reference to a statement by Mr. Roebuck of the readiness of the Emperor of the French to act in conjunction with this country for the recognition of the South, stated that no communication whatever on that point lead been made to her Majesty's Government.
The debuts was adjourned to Thursday.

-	HOUSE (11? flCthflTCthTS		csvsn a v
- Rival companies of Americana aM Italians have settled
Parratone Island, In the FeotSo, e$rty '- '	° 	Prenelsec, for the
purp000 of collecting valuable blrde eg'e there, A desperate fight recently
took place between the ci vale, In Which meny were mortally wounded.
- 'vl,a ni reePEib announood of Frbnxee Anna VMS 11 ire tisa
nrgitlOx.
TIM CONFEOEISXT5 ONVA050X OF TnP NORM.
	We leave reports-eat, however, vet precise-o the movements of (loners! Lee to the 27th tilt. This conch seams certain, that a large portion of else Confederate forces had passed into Pennsylvania and
.3laryleod, seed that General Lee was endeavouring to isolate Washington from the north end east as well as from the west. Thus far General Leo has been enabled to carry out his plans without receiving any material cheek. One division of General Lode army is said to be altvsncingto Bisdd'e Tarry, fifteen miles below Weohingtoo, where, with the aid of the pontoons the Confederates 1mm carried with them, the passage of the Potomac can, it is stated, easily be effected. This division would probably march upon Fort Washingtoss and re-establish the batteries which formerly commanded the Lefrer Potomac and affected the sea communications of the Federals. Soothes- body of Confederates fret proceeded to Maetfnahnrg, a town distant only a few miles from Harper's Ferry, and thence they proceeded along the Baltimore and Ohio Mathcad as far west as Cumberland, a part of Maryland which almost unites Pennsylvania and Virginia, and is at the sauce time brought near to Ohio by the great railway systese of the Middle and Western States. According to the Baltimore correspondent of the Nine Merle Herald General Lee was in strong force at Frederick City, Maryland, on the 25th of June, and thence would either move on Washington or Baltimore, or pass to the railroad between Washington and Baltimore. General Hooker was also moving, and the right wing of his amay was said to be at Hageretowu.
	So imminent is the peril that is supposed to menace Baltimore that the most cogent appeals are made to the people by the Government, the Mayor of the city, the councils of the military authorities, and the newspapers, to toes act to work on the intrencloneets which are being hastily erected for the defence of the city, said to enlist in the various military orgeensahano.
s-	The despatches complain that there is universal indifference amen
	I lee people of Pennsylvania regarding the invasion. The due Tsr
	Tfcrsld says that "the inhabitants scent to have lost oil spirit, said
el	either retreat rapidly at the epprmch of the Confederates or exhibit
Ii	a strange apathy. Bran the troops from New York or New Jersey
	ore net received with cordiality or enthusiasm, but the inhabitants
el	ecdeavnnr only to profit pocuniarily by their presence."
is		Immense mischief scams to have been done to the Northern cause
)f	by the defeat and retreat of General blihny from Winchester, that
d	lecy of the Shenandoah Valley which has so often changed owaara
t,	daring the last three years. The flenthemers claim to have ceeptoroel
)f	front Milroy 6500 prisoners, 2100 horse,, 100 waggono, and stores t'
5	ties value of 2,000,001 dnle.
5		The Weshington correspondent of the Nets Thr'lc Hereld gives the
55 	following seminary of the Confederate strength and movements
ey General Lee, for a week previous to msvisg from Oalpepper in his last mye-
dc	tenses movement, cave orders, which were sirirgeselyonfarced, that no perfien,-
Ce)	soldier or citisee, shield be allowed to mace or leave his lines. It Is said that
	his army commenced 10 move on Oalnrmlar, and cautioned to pass throngs
	Calpeoexeer fining all the intervening period see to Thursday of the succeeding
	tomb. His force to said to leave consisted of Basil's corps of 15,000 men, evbo
	msrehed out first, Laegseeeet's corps of 42,000 men, and Mill's corps of 20,000
	moo, who brought VP the rear. General Stuart's cavalry, 18,000 olrasg, pre-
en	eceted the flank and rear, while Jeahico, with 1000 aces, accompanied Ewahl
Id	into Maryland, the destination of the main nertise of the army. The artillery
	is said to be In superb condition and very numerous. Staanl's command is
'U	said to consist of nat divisions of two brigades each, three regiesoati to a
	brigade, and 000 mm the average maximum number to a rogimeni. The 4th
	Virginia, the largest of oil, on a recent review, numbered 714, bat every man
	that could be obtained was preseol on this occasion.
e			'rise following are other fragments of cows telegraphed on the dates
	,		given
		blow York, Time 26-The Confederates under General Jones, with eavahl
	and arhllmy, have, after a covers skirmish, driven the Federals nader kidney
ad	out of lisccosnoliahargsad occupied that place. The Federals haeseraeested
	Carlisle, and fallen back to Harrisburg. The Confederate advance in Pan" -
in	sylvania is said to be 10,000 strong, The Governor of Pennsylvania has
he	-celled for no,ooo - militia for defence for three months. The Governor Of
of 	Illinois bee offered 10,000 men to twist the Invasion.
Jose 27, Morning- General Ewsil entered Ohamberabnrg on Wednesdal',
51 sad hosed on order forbidding the Inhabitants to sell liquor to the soldiers
th also admonishing persons not in military service to abstain from acts 5f b5
met.,. telsty.-einalng that,wmieimroam in the demands of the miliesry antherltIeewa5i
	f	lessen th0110211 goea of ware	General Ewe OPs mala form is behsved tn have halted
	he	In the rear	Ohsaenboeebnrg, hsldicg all the rssds ama psaseo In the viola, ty,
		sad aeseathig xslndsreemeaea.	Gsssral lOnely's ddvloisa of Lengeleesi's csrp
	Laq		o,
		consisting of ten regiments of infantry, -with cavalry and artillery, oeeor
		Geetysbnrg yesterday. 	It is supposed that General Early will strilie the
lIt ,Nsrtsimn tatreral BolIrsod at Hanover Isuetien or Pork, tbimy miles distant.
